The boys caught her by the town
border, commander.
She has no permit and won't speak.
-German?
-What else.
Leave us alone.
Bitte, Schwester.
I can speak Czech.
-Where are you going, sister?
-I help people in need.
Do you believe that?
Why, what do you believe in?
Not in this.
Then I feel sorry for you.
Here, this is your permit
valid for two months.
Fill in your details yourself.
I would prefer not to see you
around here again.
So would I.
God bless you, sister.
Jump on, I'll give you a lift.
Where are you running?
What a silly moth.
Go!
-Whoa!
-(in Polish) Hello, Gusta
How are you?
What are you carrying, tobacco?
No tobacco, Florian.
Not even saccharin.
Just some oil and nails.
I myself am dying for a smoke.
Come down then, let's
have a drink
I want to be at Berhof
before the night falls.
Why are you shaking?
Weird things are going on
around here, Florian.
-You know what I met at Hartl's
oak? -No.
A nun.
So it goes.
Some see bats, you see a nun.
Go, Bob, go!
Close the windows for the
night, Florian.
How did a nun get here?
There is hardly any work left
here for Jesus's servants.
When did it happen?
In the afternoon, after the rain.
Nobody was with her.
Nobody?
-You left her alone?
-I had to clean the yard.
So...
This is how we'll all end up.
Open the window!
What are you staring at?
The soul must leave the body.
I want everything proper.
The ceremony, the guests,
we'll heat up the fire.
Close her eyes, Ulrika.
I don't know how, daddy.
Whoa!
What held you, man?
Here, this is for you.
-Hm, a good smoke.
-It's for you, eh?
Old Florian was begging for some,
but got nothing.
You are a good man, Gusta.
-You'll have more work today.
-Today? No way.
Look, man!
The girl is almost a woman now.
Where does she sleep? Here with you?
Don't look at the girl, look there.
O Virgin Mary...
-She's gone.
-You'll get a drink,
and ride to town, for the priest.
When did it happen?
-People, don't! Stop it!
-Come on! Let's break the door!
-Don't beat me!
-(in Polish) What are you doing?
-Please!
-Don't yell when thieving
-Where are you from?
-I got lost.
At the Breslaw train station.
There was an air raid.
And what are you doing here?
-I am going home. To Ostruzna.
-That's a long way.
Come. You can sleep in the stall.
I'll wake you up in the morning.
I will chop the wood
and bring water for you.
Look at yourself, no strength
in you.
What about the shoes? Have you
been with the army?
Not me sir, never. They wouldn't
take me anywhere.
-We are these volkspeople.
-Good for you.
It would be worse,
if they took away your soul.
Wait here.
-Son? Where are you?
-Here.
There.
Good night.
Prr!
Welcome, pastor.
Come, let me help you.
Who is this?
-Will you help me too?
-We need to hide her.
Image, they wanted to shave her
head clean in Kolstejn.
So i figured it would
be a shame, eh?
-Tylda.
-Tylda...
Here... come.
-Eh?
-Good.
-Take the coat off, it's wet.
-I'll close the window.
This is Tylda, Ulrika. She
well help us wash your mum.
-What about the pastor?
-God knows, my girl.
The Germans took him to
a concentration camp.
Tylda: Man, it's cold here.
There. It will warm you up.
Get some water and go to bed.
I will not be inviting a German
pastor to my house.
-I will spend the last night with mum.
-Right.
Here, drink with us. To your mum.
Are you deaf, damn you?
-Get out of here!
-I don't want to!
-Let's get her clothed before she goes stiff.
-Rena! Get her!
-Don't let her touch my mum!
-Get out of here!
Now.
Sit elsewhere.
Rena, come.
Damn you, Habiger, have
you gone mad?
Ulrika! Open the door!
My girl. My little girl.
Forgive me. Forgive me, please.
Look, I have, I will have new
clothes tailored for you.
[polsky]
Is that you, son?
-Gustl?
-Yeah?
You go ahead.
You stay here, Ulrika.
We take the bottom way,
through the moor.
Come here! Rena! Rena!
Are you deaf?
One more howl and I will kick you!
Florian?
[polsky]
Hey dog!
They will steal you one day.
You did not understand
what I said?
-Is it worth it, beating her like that?
-Leave that up to me.
Someone has to teach her obedience.
Alfred, the cart will not fit in.
Don't worry.
We'll carry her. She was not heavy.
Do not fear me and do not worry.
Maybe I can help you.
Here, put a nail in this too!
Florian would never have prayed this.
He was a Seventh day adventist.
Come, Krasula, come.
-Hi.
Andenken an Gr?lich?
[in Polish]
Gr?lich. A remote monastery.
Up the on the borders.
They prepared their hideouts there
before the war ended.
They've got food and guns there.
Some of these hideouts must be here, too.
The forests should be searched.
It goes like a red blood line.
From the direction of Wroclaw.
-We don't have the manpower for that.
-Neither do we.
-Roll call!
-The men have no food, lieutenant.
I hope we'll be back for diner
before dark?
Where do you think you are, sergeant?
In a restaurant?
Go!
-There is no-one to comb my hair now.
-What about the new one?
-I'd rather cut my hair and die.
-Don't talk blasphemously.
-How does one pray for the dead, Sister?
-Do you want to pray for your mom?
And for us, who are left, too.
We all are orphans.
Lord allmighty,
accept the soul
of your servant Elfriede...
-Lord allmighty, accept the soul...
-...that has left the sinful body,
-to return to you in joy.
-...return to you in joy.
Would you like a drink, lieutenant?
Not a living soul in the woods,
yet these flowers are fresh.
-You come from this place?
-From around here.
And you lieutenant?
On my horse
I will ride
My sabre by my side
For the one
I love the best
My heart is waiting...
Beautiful. Like a falling star.
Where do you come from, Sister?
Have you ever been to Gr?lich?
Mom used to go there. To pray to
the Virgin Mary for health.
-She died anyway.
-Stop the blasphemy.
She's better now.
Sister, your feet hurt, you don't
know your way in the mountains.
Where else do you want to go?
Some celebration. What's
wrong with him?
Alfred, eat! You have to eat!
-She hit me right in the heart.
-What is he saying?
Lizards, snakes and werewolfs,
not one's own children.
So.
His hands are shaking.
Leave me alone!
Come, let's go up to the bedroom.
A guy whose hands are shaking,
is finished. Come!
-Stop it!
-Alright!
Let me tell you something.
Maybe people would like to know
where you're hiding, eh?
My hands are shaking,
but I can still squeeze you
like a snake, you bastard!
Did you come to laugh at your
own father?
-Get out!
-Let her here, Alfred.
The girl is sad.
I would like you to forgive
me, daddy.
-And you too, missis.
-Look at her!
Laughing at one's
own face.
Stop it Gustl! I don't like this!
Man, I got carried away a bit.
I am no "man" for you, I am
a honest farmer!
On the Czech land!
Mobilised for the army, twice!
I'll kick you out to the cowshed
you piece of shit!
-Tylda: Alfred! This is a funeral!
-You shut up, too!
Or I'll smash your face!
-the nun: Here, Ulrika.
Virgin Mary protect us.
I can take lots, but you, you'll
go straight to heaven.
-Will he go on with this?
-Until he gets exhausted and fall asleep.
Sometimes all night through.
Take me with you.
-Where?
-To the monastery. Gr?lich. Away from here!
You won't see me here again, bastard!
Damn!
Nothing! No booze, no tobacco!
You can rot here, with that bitch you
inherited from the German SS!
The villages are on fire
and so is the heart
of a dying gipsy...
Come... come!
-Come.
-Alfred!
Tylda: Stop it!
Alfred, leave me!
So what do you want here?
Go and wash yourself first.
How can you live here, in these
dreadful hills?
I was born here.
-Have you got any siblings?
-A brother. He lives in town.
Dad drove him out.
For a lonely girl, there is
no good in this world.
We had this picture at
home, over my bed.
I could watch it for days long,
when I was sick in bed.
-I used to sleep like this with mom.
-This can't be, Ulrika.
Why?
I can't.
Doesn't matter.
I'll lay down on the floor.
-Where are you going?
-To bring a blanket.
and so is the bleeding heart
of a dying gypsy
who was he, the gypsy...
-Sister...
Sister?
Alfred Habiger?
What's wrong with you?
Still sleeping?
I buried my wife yesterday. I had
a reason to drink.
You always do.
Shame on you, Habiger.
Such a pighouse here.
Look after the cow, it's pregnant.
Old Florian was killed yesterday.
-Polish Florian?
-Right.
Thank you, mr. Lasica.
You have an understanding for
fellow men.
Watch out, Habiger,
A new gang has come from Silesia.
And your wife was a German.
So what?
I kicked my son out of the house when
he came with a nazi flag.
-My wife has nothing to do with it.
-I'm warning you.
In this weather, they'll be attracted to
farmhouses like wolves.
Did he look for me?
-They killed Florian.
-Whom? -Get dressed.
Let's go before someone steals it.
Florian had 300 kg of potatoes stored there.0
German?
-Bist Deutsch?
-I can speak Czech.
How did you get here?
What do you care?
-Quiet!
-What are you afraid of?
-They'll kill me if they find me.
The soldiers?
You have a high fever.
Don't worry, I'll hide you here
and get you some food.
How far is it to Ostruzna? Do
you know where it is?
Two hours by train, at least.
Do you know someone there?
-What is your name?
-Ulrika. And you?
Stop staring and help us!
God bless.
-Light the watch candle.
-Don't worry.
That's the right blanket for winter.
I'd rather go to bed.
Ulrika...
-This is for you.
-Someone's outside, dad.
Blessed be our lord Jesus Christ.
-Man, what is this.
-Will you let us stay overnight?
If you are a christian. Just
until the storm goes away.
I will not deny those in need.
Come!
Put your stuff over there
and join us here.
It's warm here, you'll get some
food and we'll talk.
That used to be.
We're tired. Send your daughter
with the food.
-Where are you from? You speak Czech
so well.  - from Gr?lich.
Gr?llich, I know it.
We were building the bunkers there
before the war began.
And my wife used to go there for prayers.
Let us change our clothes.
''Judita and Herman.''
This must be stolen from the Jews.
What kind of a man would reject
a shelter for these poor things?
They have a bag full of it.
-Ah!
Anything wrong?
Have you got food?
-I'll help you.
-Leave the light here and go.
Who could that be?
I'm deaf, I am going nowhere.
Have you locked the door?
Let's welcome the guests, then.
-Who is it?
-Ulrika!
[in German:]Quiet! Or I'll shoot you dead!
-Where is your dad? -Upstairs.
-How come you don't sleep yet?
We we weren't expecting you, mr.Lasica,
in this kind of weather.
You weren't? Who were you expecting then?
Nobody. Come on in.
I'll refill the oil.
Come and dry yourself. You're all wet.
What scared you so much?
You're having a good time, Reno, eh?
This is old Florian's Bible.
Dad was plundering, eh?
Do you have any visitors?
There was light in the old bar room.
-Mr.Lasica...
-Ah!
Is that you?
How did you get here, Tylda?
Come, I won't bite you.
Believe me, mr. Lasica. I've quit
doing that thing with men.
-It's all over, I want my peace now.
-Good for you.
Be good to the young one, will you?
Or else...
What's with you, Habinger?
Why haven't you prepared any food?
Do I have to do everything by myself?
Get some smoked meat and bacon.
How come you're coming so late?
The storm caught me on my way to Stolny.
So?
Is this your praying book now?
-You won't do what I told you?
-I am afraid to go there.
I'll get going.
Once the storm is over.
Why? Where would you go?
We'll sit, drink some, sing some.
You can stay overnigt, if
you want to.
We're the same people, aren't we?
Well.
You know how to sell your
goods, man.
What was that?
What would it be? Mice.
There's plenty of room here,
if you wanted to...
I'm on business, Tylda.
-So long, then.
-Uncle... -Yes?
Uncle, stay with us.
Take it easy, girl.
Don't worry.
You shouldn't go, mr. Lasica.
Not in this kind of weather.
I am used to.
-Are you planning to open a pub again?
-You'd be the only customer.
Aim the light here!
Don't talk like that, Habiger.
It's peace now. New people will come.
You have always had great beer here.
-You'd make money here, man.
-Why should I?
My wife's dead, the boy is god knows
where and Ulrika will leave, too.
Are you crazy? What's wrong with you?
Don't know.
I got burnt .
So, there is light at Berhof too.
It used to be a great pub here.
I remember that.
Those were some days.
I may be too kind.
You be good to the girl, alright!
Of course, mr. Lasica.
She's the only thing left to me.
So long then.
Good night.
Reno, quiet, quiet.
[German]Lord bless you, friends...
[German]Someone is lying in your yard.
You better hide him somewhere,
[German]or you'll be hanging for murder.
[German]Got a cigarette, daddy?
Let us pray.
We were visited by wild beasts,
not by men.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
[German]Blessed art thou amongst women
[German]at the hour of our death, Amen.
Habiger: Our Father,
Who art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name;
Thy kingdom come;
Thy will be done on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread;
and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those who trespass against us...
[German]You better let your god sleep!
... but deliver us from evil.
Amen.
[German]Say goodbye!
-Daddy!
-My girl!
Forgive me...
I myself, always by myself
on my horse, my horse
riding my horse...
-Miss!
-Just a minute.
A horse so fast
A girl so pretty...
May I?
I don't dance, miss.
You don't like this shithole either,
do you, lieutenant?
-They know how to have a good time.
-Rednecks.
Sergeant, you were assigned here
as a part of your punishment.
-That's...
-Weren't you?
We all were, lieutenant.
I'll catch you!
Hey, bro.
-We know each other, don't we?
-Hardly.
Not hardly, I know!
From the prison in Mirov.
They were beating him up with a rubber
hose but he never said a word, right?
Wait, wait...
Don't run away!
We'll have a shot together.
Drunk: All has been stolen from here.
Houses, cattle, whores.
[Polish] It's forbidden to
enter the kitchen
May I open a food can in here?
Provisions?
-I have got Camel fags, too.
-How much?
I'd do you for free.
Not married or engaged?
What good is it for?
What do you yell, you drunk.
It's half past four.
Policeman Lasica has been killed.
-Got to go.
-God.
Let me through the back door.
-[outside] Where did you find him?
-You didn't even tell me your name.
[outside] Don't look at him, you'll
be sick.
There is no point in that.
Sorry.
I'll get them for this.
[In German]Hey, young one, can you
wash my bra too?
Detlev!
Drink.
Don't bury me here. Promise me.
Stop it. You'll be alright.
My name is Helt. Erich Helt.
-Will you remember it?
-What is this?
[In German]Help me!
Untie me!
[In German]Untie him!
We have a family house in Ostruzna,
right across from the pub.
Number 32. Will you remember it?
You'll be fine, Erich.
-I'll get medicine from town.
-Promise you'll take me there.
Even if I died.
There.
Ne.
Wimp.
You can only kill people. An
animal is too much for you.
[Ulrika sings in German]
A German song. Did you mother
teach you that?
We had to come here.
For Erich. He'd die in the woods.
I don't trust you anymore.
Nuns wear a crucifix on their
neck, not like you!
My dad had always wanted a son.
He wanted an army officer.
He never forgave me for being born.
But I'm no worse than a son.
I did it.
I must take them to Germany.
They'll learn a different life.
They'll forget.
Do you understand?
Habiger: Come on, let's eat
before they finish their prayer.
Eat what you can, so that
it's over faster.
We'll kill the kow before winter,
And after Christmas we'll be
dying of hunger.
It makes no sense, Ulrika.
The tea won't help him.
He needs medicine. Without it
he'll die.
Habiger: Attention handgrenade!
[In German]Should I kill you straight away?
Stop it, boy. I am too tired.
[In German]Your fathers have lost the war
and you're trying to fix it?
[In German]The war is not over yet.
[In German]Hitler is dead. Germany is no more.
You wimp.
-[hudba]
-Ulrika: No! No! No!
No! No! No! No...
What are you doing? Why are you
provoking them?
The little puke makes me want
to stop shaving.
Talk, talk, thas all you can!
Ouch!
[In German]The cripple is nothing but a burden.
[In German]I want away, away from this house.
[In German]We have to find our troops.
[In German]God knows how many of them
are hiding in the woods.
[In German]Guys, take me home.
[In German]It's just a few
kilometres. Don't leave me here.
[In German]Home?
[In German]I have no home!
[In German]We were swearing that, remember?
[In German]Until our troops come back.
[In German]Shut up.
[In German]Calm down, Erich.
[In German]This is your Mercedes.
[In German]I will not take it from you this time.
[In German]Don't cry.
[In German]What do we do with him?
[In German]We'll accept what comes.
[In German]I still have saccharin.
[In German]Bedtime, children.
[In German]Sister, tell us again
[In German]the fairy tale about how
it was at home...
[In German]Blessed house in the middle
of wide fields.
[In German]Sand all the way to the horizon
and the lakes...
[In German]An oak tree stands on every
crossroad.
[In German]And there is bread and butter
under it.
[In German]A jug of milk,
[In German]for every passer-by.
You will receive medicines and
brith certificate. Don't forget.
Ulrika...
[in German]
[in German]I'd rather be dead, my dear girl.
[in German]These are messages from the underworld.
Are you all right?
[in German]Is anyone with you?
[in German]Injections, sulphanamides,
calcium, ethanol.
[in German]The bike, put it somewhere
away from the shop.
[in German]By noon, there will be a basket
prepared for you in the church. Right?
I will know when the bells ring.
[in German]They won't ring.
[in German]Our troops took them, they
left only the funeral bell.
[in German]The end of the world is coming.
[in German]They have stopped the clock, too.
[on the radio]
The Lucerna hall is crowded
and there is a national flag in front,
by the side of which, a Soviet flag
an English one,
American and French...
-Hens for sale.
-Any bigger ones? -No.
-Buy this one, it's pretty.
-How much?
-88 Crowns.
-That's too much.
Do you like them, miss?
-How many are you buying?
-Let me go!
The Lucerna hall in Prague
is now full of young people.
-And there are streams of new...
-Come in.
The Czech youth association has
called for a meeting,
to show their support for the
Czechoslovak flying corps...
Are you hungry?
Take some.
Don't worry..
Nobody will hurt you here.
I don't know what you want.
-I've just come to buy bread.
-Hm.
Take a seat.
-You like it in the hills?
-I was born there.
And you don't bake your own bread?
Would you like to do something
for us?
For whom?
Sir, there is blood on your door.
Oh, that's nothing.
Somebody hit his nose.
Close your ears.
Listen, seargant, you are on your
way to court martial!
I don't care if he hits his head
against the wall by himself!
Have him taken to Olomouc, now!
You can listen now again.
What is your name?
Ulrika.
You have beautiful eyes.
I like them.
What do you know about werewolves?
About what?
The retreating Germans have put
together gangs of killers.
They call themselves werewolves.
-For them, the war is not over yet.
Understand?    -Yes.
The bread will be sold at eleven.
May I go now?
You have half an hour time, Ulrika.
Want some chocolate?
-He is a nazi, Ulrika!
-Let me go!
-The real preast was sent to KZ-camp!
-Let me go away!
[in broken Czech]You let the girl go?
She will the the werewolves about me.
It has been coded under my supervision.
[German]I have written the report
[German]like you have ordered me, lieutenant!
You can go now.
But, wait, lieutenant, sir!
Get the medicines. Do it.
Even if you were to steal them
from the army depot.
They don't have them. Not even
for our own men.
You have 70 minutes!
Father!
Did you like it?
Our teacher never played like this.
I believe you.
Today, people dance to this.
Boogie-woogie. You know it?
Come to the saturday dance.
I will teach you.
I can't, sir.
The war is over, Ulrika.
People want to have fun. They
need one another.
Will you be here now in
place of the priest?
The priest,
the teacher.
What do I know? Whatever is needed.
Did you know mr. Lasnica? The policeman?
When was the last time you saw him?
I don't know. I don't remember.
How many of them are there?
Speak!
Where are they?
Do you know what they did to
your neighbour, old Florian?
They nailed him to the door!
And the burned the woodcuter in Stolne!
None of this is Erich's fault!
Who's Erich?
A cousin... from Ostruzna.
He's at our place, for the holidays.
I know. It's nobody's fault here.
I have gotten used to it.
Take it! Take it to them!
Let them pack it up and go!
Let them go to hell and stay there.
Is it possible?
I just want to get them out of this
district. I just want peace.
Are they here with you or
waiting in the forest?
I am alone here.
It will be dark before you
get all the way there.
I can go by night. By the brook.
Ulrika...
[In German]Stop!
Bebebe!
Ulrika, who have you met
down there?
Me... nobody.
I spoke to the priest.
Look into my eyes.
-Who did you tell about us?
-Nobody, sister.
To lie is a sin, Ulrika.
I's alright my girtl. Everyone
becomes a traitor, one day.
I didn't tell anyone!
I said the medicine is for
my cousin!
They believed me!
Having one's own fatherland is
the greatest sin.
Would you like to pray with me?
Here?
For the last time.
So God will forgive you,
and save both you and Erich.
I can pray with you.
Our Father which art in heaven,
Hallowed be thy name.
[in German]They replied!
[in German]God knows how many more of
our men are still in the woods!
[in German]Maybe thousands! If we unite...
[still in German]
Sister! Sister!
Sister!
[in German]Sister, they replied!
[in German]Take it, boys.
[in German]Go back to the room.
Milka lies sleepless at night
thinking about her love
Oh my god, how beautiful he is
Black eyes, black hair
Who vas it,
gypsy, black gypsy
[In German]Not for sale.
-Look at that!
-That's from France.
[in German]Keep playing, daddy.
House is burning, house on fire
Smoke rising through the villages
A heart in love is a wounded heart
As the gypsy finds his death
Who was he, gypsy, black gypsy,
How handsome, the girl cries
Her heart is broken,
and a shadow passes by
A shadow passes by the window
Who is it...
[in German]Give me the harmonica!
[in German]Careful, it is a precious one!
[sings in German]
Don't cry my girl
Give me a hug
Give me a kiss
And farewell
Lalalalala...
Lalala lalala
Erich: Sister!
What are you doing?
soldier: look there!
-Miss, come with us!
-see that?.
Excuse me, I...
don't even know your name,
I forgot to ask.
It doesn't matter now, does it.
May I come to see you after
the service?
-It's the dance. There is too much work.
-I know.
Starting from tomorrow, there will be
peace again.
[in Polish]
Peace?
I promise.
Good luck.
Let's go!
Move it!
Move!
Go!
Ulrika, it's time.
Quiet, Rena.
Farewell.
Nein! Aaaaah!
-Stop!
-Lieutenant: Don't shoot!
[hudba]