Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Karel Zeman to children.
Tale about Honzik and Marenka
Breathlessly we examine work of old chroniclers.
With an admiration we look at pages
touched by their diligence.
They wrote about magnificent battles,
great kings and exceptional generals.
Winners often led hand of chroniclers
by strong hand.
And these wrote on pergamen so colorful,
that their acts were crowned
by an immortal fame.
They wrote all chronicle about great of greatest,
and there was no pergamen left
for the little ones.
That's why we don't know
almost nothing
about the smallest.
Our little hero had a name Honzik.
There was nothing about him in old chronicles,
however, we know that
he was born on the same day,
when another Honzik,
great knight and king John I of Bohemia,
fell bravely at the battle of Crecy.
And on the exact day near Buchlov,
huge oak fell.
It was healthy and strong tree.
A poor sheperd made a cradle
for his little Honzik from that tree.
And so it all began...
There were standing
three weird sisters next to the cradle.
That was a habit then.
In addition to blessing
he got a present from each of them.
First weird sister gave him little guardian dwarf
in the form of white mouse.
Second weird sister
gave him a black mouse.
And third gave him
a gray mouse.
When weird sisters were gone,
mice changed to dwarves,
and they should have protect him
for the whole life.
First dwarf was very good
and saw the world only good and beautiful.
The black one was an imp and trickster.
And the last one was a little smiley and
a little easy-going.
Since then Honzik was under their protection.
But only he saw them
when they advised him what to do.
They were invisible for other people.
Even when he had grown up,
the dwarves were still looking at him.
They watched each of his movements,
each of his thoughts.
Honzik, do you see?
The world is big and beautiful.
What are you waiting for?
Home is best.
You'll get rotten at home.
But you'll keep up
your worried parents.
You won't help them
out of poorness here.
Honzik, you're their only joy,
don't leave them.
When you're back rich,
you'll give them plenty of money.
The world is full of traps,
you can encounter some unhappiness.
Or hapinness.
Nobody is waiting there for you,
what will you do there?
Look at his nose
how beautiful it is after sting.
I got him, see.
Oh, my nose.
Mercy, generous man,
don't give me to soldiers,
have a mercy.
Just give the rascal to them,
he threw rope on your neck.
Be merciful, forgive him.
Mercy, I have a wife
and children.
See, you have an oportunity
to do something noble.
Give him to them, don't think about it.
They're coming.
Boy, we're looking for
a dangerous thug.
Haven't you seen
someone suspicious?
Somewhere here at the big tree.
He kills wanderers.
Hold the horses.
We'll look through
the bush around.
The rascal has to be there.
Quickly on horses.
We'll run away.
They can't catch us by foot.
And thug on the horse...!
We'll be masters of all roads.
Honzik, don't go a wrong way.
It leads to hell.
We'll be companions.
We'll share.
We'll have plenty of money.
You can't!
Let him try.
It's only a little ride on horse.
Nobody's here.
Let's go back.
Don't hesitate.
Quickly, until it's time.
Have some.
Honzik, hands off the can,
brandy is a doom.
Small gulp
is good for health.
No, listen to my voice,
before it's too late.
Let him sleep,
he has no fun with you.
You don't let him
even one gulp.
I hear a wagon.
I see it now.
A chariot of nobleman.
We're lucky
at the beginning.
To catch so fat loot.
We'll surprise them
after they enter the forest.
Hold!
Money or life!
Welcome master knight.
Everyone out! Quickly!
Just come here master knight
and you precious lady,
so I can ease you from gold.
Your turn, beautiful.
Jewels, trinkets, bracelets, all to me.
Honzik, it's still time to stop it.
Remember your good education.
Hurry up arrogant chicken,
or I'll dress you off.
Honzik, don't let hurt the weak lady.
Poor woman.
Here you have, rascal.
Give it here,
or you'll get one too.
Master knight, commander of guards
reports to your protection.
Too late,
I handled it alone.
I drove the bunch of thieves to escape
and I beat up their commander.
She has canceled engagement.
There will be no marriage.
Turn it back and go home.
To mummy.
Guards, tie the thief up.
So that he can't escape.
He's innocent.
I swear he's innocent.
What will be with him?
He'll be hanged.
Hunted knight and his company
quickly ride to the safe castle Beranov.
Everyone there expects impatiently
arrival of young knight and his bride.
Cresty knight Matej Beran from Beranov is looking
forward to his son at most.
Desired bride should provide
continuation of famous house.
House which is
as famous as indebted.
Old knight is very worried
and he should be.
He indebted family castle so much,
that only rich bride could save it.
They're coming.
There was no bride
and so there were no guests.
There were only last two descendents
of famous house of Beran.
Noble father, I've returned from bloody battle.
Thousands of poisonous arrows hit my face.
Where is your bride, my son?
We were attacked by thugs in the forest.
I fought, I beat them.
I captured their commander.
But when the bees helped him, he escaped.
With your bride?
Our standard must not get dirty.
We have to capture him, dead or alive.
Arms!
Do you hear? Hunting horns.
This is how hunt for a fox begins.
You got it.
But the fox is our Honzik this time.
Whose conscience is clean,
must not fear.
I know better one.
Who escapes, wins.
Don't worry Honzik.
We're with you.
Advise me then.
Where can I find the one I love?
You are all silent now.
Where can I find her?
I'll tell.
She lives on an island of dreams.
But common mortal can't get there.
Unless he has wings.
Lend me your wings.
My wings?
You would have to be an angel.
Or a devil.
So lend me your wings you, imp
But the wings will be black.
I don't have other.
I don't care the color.
Great, since now you're mine
and you'll listen only to my advices.
Don't listen to him.
You'll subsribe to bad powers and you'll pity it after.
She worths it.
She doesn't. She's nymph, fairy,
she can't do cakes or dumplings for you.
She'll learn it then.
Nobody wants your advises, grandad,
stop the lectures or I'll pluck up your beard.
Send the two away.
Get out.
I don't want to see you anymore.
You're banishing your friends, Honzik.
Pity.
I follow you through day and night.
Look, my shoes are cracked.
What's up with the wings?
What are you waiting for?
When the time is right,
you'll have them.
Choose, so you can be showed
as true knight.
What do you want to do with the flower?
A fight is coming, Honzik.
Very well, Honzik.
In the distance there
a crystal palace rises up from fog.
The palace of dreams,
place of forest nymphs.
There you can find your beautiful.
I beg you only for that.
Why do you want to leave us?
I would like to return among people.
I want to be a living being.
I don't want to be
only a fairy tale being.
You're living like in a beautiful dream
among us.
And the world you're hasting into
is an evil world.
I know, but in the world
is also a joy
love and happiness.
And if they last a short while
it's worth to live there.
Let it happen according to your wish.
Live and suffer.
But you can't return
among us.
On your way among people
I give you a beautiful girl name.
Marenka.
I want to have wings
immediately.
You will.
But don't forget our deal.
I agree.
I want to be near her.
In her world.
Thanks dear friend,
I'll try them now.
Wave the wings.
Don't fall down.
She has turned into human being
and has gone to seek you.
You can't follow her.
Look.
Stay with us.
You belong
to our world now.
You can't go back
among people.
They would be affraid of you.
Stay.
Imp!
Devil!
Where are you?
Come near,
you traitor!
Come here, come.
Why do you call me?
I'm not supposed
to protect you anymore.
Now you're a being
from the other world as me.
We're colleagues.
Give me back my human look.
That's not possible.
No one can change face as he wants.
You've got what you wanted.
I've done it for my love.
Help me once more.
I want to be a human again.
Surely, it can't be done.
The only thing that
can help you is a miracle.
That is out of my power.
Honzik!
Welcome, good people.
Haven't you seen Honzik here?
We're looking for him too.
Bandit!
Introduce yourself,
he'll accompany you to the castle.
We'll handle you there.
I'm singing my singing
the most desire i know
after the first meeting
with full-moon and with him
I'm singing my singing
into the clouds and far
after the happy meeting
with one who took my rest.
I'm singing what i know
I won't tell you more
I'm singing my singing
how much I love you
under the star pot
you're not alone
I'm singing my singing
before I fall asleep
my heart is on my palm
it's the most anyone can give.
For the eternal fame of our house,
we'll organize a tournament.
A big chivalrous tournament.
We'll invite all famous knights
to fight for the most precious gem we have.
For Marenka.
Marenka.
She's got a beauty of a flower
and golden in her throat.
You prepare a horse
and an armour too
so you'll show yourself.
From a castle to a castle flew a message
about the great tournament
and about a beauty of a charming girl
for the winner.
Noble knights of the whole kingdom
seddled horses
and sharpened swords
to fight about a win
and a knight fame.
Ones came with full shine of their armour
sure of winning before the fight.
Others, more carefull,
was saving strength of their horses
until the decisive moment of the fight.
Look.
The most brave knights of the whole land
will fight about you.
Everyone in hope of adding some fame
to their coat of arms.
The winner of the tournament
will gain you
as a first prize.
Look, it begins.
Quickly, up.
Quickly, pull.
Noble sir father
sends you a knight armour.
Against falling stones?
For the tournament, sir knight.
I won't go.
No?
I'm injured,
wholly stabbed.
They're waiting for you
at the tournament, sir knight.
Borrow me your armour,
quickly.
Finally, my son is here.
Hooray.
My brave son,
knight without fear and shame
has won.
Is there anyone next
who dares to overcome famous house of Beran?
Clapping.
The best knight of the tournament
has won.
My brave son Ignac Beran z Beranu.
Long live Ignac!
Are you calling me,
my noble father?
I'm in the bed, you know,
sick, stabbed.
Close the gate.
Catch him!
Shoot!
Shoot him down! Shoot!
Look. He's flew down there.
There.
Noble sir knight,
I report dutifully
Rascal!
Coward!
Dodger!
Chicken-heart!
I report dutifully
that shot enemy fell into wood.
We hit him.
Injured?
We'll get him now.
We'll have our revenge.
I'm calling you all to fight,
brave knights.
That will be forever written down
and immortally famous
who will kill the arrogant kidnapper.
Hooray to the fight.
Hooray!
Hooray.
Honzik, we're back.
Honzik and Marenka, come.
The best of the whole kingdom
were chasing the fugitives.
With thud of heels, with clashes of armours,
shields and coat of arms
ran for their chivalrous fame.
So that chroniclers
could write about something.
And they were writing and wrting
until they ran out of parchments.
That's why in the old chronicles
love and human hapiness
didn't get its place.
Brave Honzik and beautiful Marenka
got written into another books.
Into the most beautiful in the world.
Into childy fairy tales.
subtitles by kostej (2008)
Watch more movies for free on
www.FlixTor.to