[an airport report in french]
I don't like when someone's
talking me out of something.
I liked about you
that you've never tried it.
Until now.
I didn't say a word.
But you're looking this way.
If we haven't said something
to each other in 30 years,
now we're not gonna make it.
I have to return because...
...because I can't do it.
You'll be better without me,
won't you, Jenda?
How can you say that?
Monsieur le Docteur Meluzin
de Prague?
Qui Monsieur.
Encore votre signature
s'il vous plait Monsieur.
Pardon.
[music]
Come, doctor.
I see you're going out
like to Stromovka.
Here. So that she
wouldn't be bored.
[music...]
[...music]
[music]
Look around meanwhile
before I'll get someone,
who'll make you feel like at home.
It's always hard on Saturday.
[music]
voice of Vlach: If they at least
would come with some new trick.
They're too lazy for that.
Wait, how I'll deal with them.
They'll remember it
as there was an earthquake.
Be welcome in our
village of Vetrov.
I can see you've
shortcut it.
-I'm Lojza Vlach.
-Kacenka.
How would doctor find you?
Gather the water and swim away.
No Kacenka for you.
Jan Meluzin, nice to meet you.
Frankly, I didn't believe
that you exist.
When I read,
where were you coming from...
It's against the human nature,
to go from worse to better.
Why?
This is supposed
to be the worse?
I don't know.
Not for everyone, probably.
That depends on a character.
And on demands.
You share a bathroom with your neighbour,
otherwise you're on your own.
[music]
You've got it all
under one roof.
You can go in slippers
to the ordination.
I won't be a nuisance here.
For whom?
For those next door?
Kodetovi must be glad
that they're glad.
The whole stock belongs
to the center.
If you would have come with your family,
they would have been gone.
And I would have been
looking for a replacement.
Thank goodness
you're alone.
Are you?
Let's put it this way.
Voice of Ema: before you'll
decide to do something
before you'll make a first step...
Oh God, Jenda,
how can you only run a clinic?
Ema...
So that I can be a head physician,
docent of the faculty,
so that I could be invited to symposia
and conventions, it was your wish.
-But...
-It's your world.
I thought I know you.
You're the new doctor?
How did you know?
I've got a feeling for people.
Especially for doctors.
We're colleagues I guess.
Whatever you do
every one of your patients
will it make to me in the end.
I have this as a bond,
I once digged here. Halva.
I work at the Tejno cemetery too.
I wouldn't earn too much from one.
There's too many flame burials nowadays.
See, in Tejno.
Your predecessor lies there.
-Doctor Horacek?
-Yes.
He ended at mine as well.
What's the point of your
famous medicine?
-You were never sick?
-True, I've got a plenty of diseases...
-I'm still sick.
-Come to see me then.
Oh no, my colleague,
it would do harm to me.
Until all my sickness are
in a balance,
I'm ok.
But if someone goes away
so that a gap'd stay there,
I'm on the slab immediately.
Oh no, doctors can't
get me into underwear.
You've got a typical doctor shape.
You'll have an authority
by patients.
Doctor Horacek hadn't?
The doctor was
a good-natured man.
I was here for
the discipline.
He has known since the beginning
he could count on me.
I'll need a stamp.
I had made one.
Do you wish to start?
Please.
Good day.
Who's first today?
Ah, mr. Hybs.
-Children...
-You guessed it eventually.
Before you're off to school on wednesday
I want to have your urine here.
Please, get undressed.
I've got down here...
-I mean...
-Wait, granpa.
-Mr. Hybs has come...
-Give me his card.
We haven't made one.
You're here for
the first time?
For many times.
So get undressed.
We'll check the leg too.
I'll come
some other time then.
Doctor Horacek wasn't
too big bureaucrat, I guess.
At times it wasn't
too important for us.
It's a matter of opinion.
I would like to have files
in order in a week.
Please.
Next.
What do you miss?
Me?
I've got all fine.
Nobody's here.
-Do you have the stamp?
-Yes.
I've put your
suitcases upstairs.
And the wieners
will be tomorrow.
Stop recruiting the fire.
Is this your dinner?
[music]
Ema:
Is it worth to return?
It is, if we have
something to return to.
-What do you return to?
-To myself.
To what I was.
Or I still am.
Hopefully...
What are you
doing there, man?
Put the fire off!
What did you
want to prove?
[music]
I'd like to thank you.
Come in.
Don't be angry,
but it was open.
I've got nothing
I would have to worry about.
Please, sit down.
-Is it warm now?
-Yes, it's pleasant.
I'm doing pancakes right now,
Petr likes them.
Try.
[music]
What's above us?
An attic.
Wait, she is...
more like here.
I've seen some
dormers from outside.
No, there's nothing there.
Pity.
[music]
Would you like some tea rather?
-No, thanks, I would try, when...
-Have some, till they're still warm.
Our mother makes them
with blackberries.
As boys we had
to gather them.
[music]
Do you know how honey
is made from dandellions?
Good evening.
Will you have some too?
Thank you, it was very good.
Really.
[music]
-Why is he sneaking here?
-He's come only to thank me.
I've invited him in.
If Vlach imagined it like that,
he's wrong.
-Why didn't he send his wife here?
-Petr, she has a little child.
-I won't serve to anyone.
-Nobody wants you to.
And neither do you.
[music]
[noise of a saw]
Wouldn't you mind doctor,
if we'd take a little detour?
I'll be back in a moment.
-What are there the nets for?
-For the sparrows.
Are you from hygiene?
Well, too.
Kacenka left a moment ago,
if you're waiting for him.
-How many dies?
-10 or 15 out of hundred.
What are you doing?
Marketa!
Marketa, where are you going?
Marketa, let be!
Marketa!
I'll break her
the crock once.
We're done here, aren't we?
Please.
[music]
You really went mad
because of Marketa, Ota.
How come you lent her
the service car when you know
that the girl even doesn't have
a driving license?
Moment! We'll deal with
it tomorrow. Get in.
Get in!
Push the brakes.
More.
Do you feel bad?
Yes.
-I would like strawberries.
-I can't do anything about it.
Leave me alone then.
Distance...
Good.
Beacon...
Windshields.
I see...
-That'll be 50.
-Because of a damn windshiled?
An unlocked car and
worn-out tires.
-I told you last time.
-I don't have. I don't steal.
Please.
I assume
you're here because of duty.
Sure.
Tomorrow at 8 report at me.
Asshole.
Next time we'll
avoid these rides.
[children cry]
Vasek!
Come.
[cry from the waiting room]
Thank goodness,
we're done.
I've got to calm them or
they'll destroy the center.
Come.
What's up here! Silence!
I was embarassed
when you left.
I'd like to make an apology,
doctor.
You don't have to.
My husband was sorry
how he had treated you.
Of course, he hasn't brought
the coal again, rascal.
-He's supposed to come long ago.
-Say good bye.
Bye.
Be glad you don't
have any children.
You're exaggerating
a little, mrs. Simon.
-Ota is no child anymore.
-I know.
Do you think I'm a gossip?
If you had your own children,
you knew
what worries are there
in this age.
Maybe it's not so
unknown for me.
Good day.
Good.
[music]
I don't even know, colleague,
if any of my patients ever died.
Ah!
-For whom do you dig it?
-In advance.
-A man never knows.
-Isn't it silly?
If you want only work with a shovel
someone could use you elsewhere.
Oh man.
That's not from your head.
Kacenka, what?
He knows nothing.
In winter when the soil is frozen
it is hard to dig a grave.
Why do you still
think on the worst?
It's always like that in life,
colleague.
The early a man someone prepares
the longer he's not needed.
Oh, not again.
Because of this hag I took
the Tejno cemetery, because it's too far.
She bought a bicycle and
was here in a week.
She has to have her dead
around whole Europe.
What's up, mrs. Pulpan,
don't you need to pump your tyres?
She doesn't hear if he doesn't want to,
she plays offended.
Good that you're here.
Otherwise she would invite me
for an apple roll.
You know it from Bible, don't you?
About the apples?
I'll go so I wouldn't
stand in your way.
I've got to get her a lover,
so that I can avoid it.
Wouldn't you know someone?
She's got a cabin.
Good evening.
I need to talk about something,
doctor.
Well, please.
Please. About what?
It concerns my wife.
You should know,
that we've always lived with Pavla
in a proper marriage.
It started to creak
just recently.
-But I don't...
-I enjoyed the time before the wedding.
Today I am rather for a family.
And I don't mind Pavla graduated
and that she's a teacher.
I don't mind such things.
There are other things
to care about in marriage.
When a woman wants a child
and still doesn't have it
she wants it still more.
But...
Don't think
I don't know how to.
Some of those
I met before Pavla
got married and had children
afterwards. Even two.
So I say to myself sometimes
if I did choose right afterall.
How long are you together?
Over two years.
I'd wish her the child.
And me too.
But... what if
it's not possible
Because her female things
are not alright
how they need to be.
Tell your wife to see me.
I mean in the ordination.
I don't know.
I don't know if he'll come to you
if it concerns the female things.
Some woman gets undressed here
even before she says hello.
-But Pavlina...
-A doctor is only a doctor.
But you're living with us.
So it's a little different.
Come in, mrs. Kodet.
What do we miss?
-Something serious?
-No, I'm fine.
I mean... nothing serious.
-Good day.
-Do you wish mrs. Kodet's file?
Yes, of course.
Please.
You can put your clothes here.
I'd go to buy some lamb
in the meantime.
I guess you'll manage, doctor.
No need to get undressed.
No need to check you neither.
-My husband said...
-I've changed my mind.
So you don't want to help us?
So I could examine you properly
I don't have proper equipment.
I'm not a gynecologist.
It'll be more reasonable
to send you to a specialist.
I know some.
It won't be a problem
to write a recomendation for Prague.
To you and your husband.
-But why would my husband...
-Both of you should go.
It doesn't concern Petr.
Maybe it's because
I'm older than him.
I've got a feeling the difference
is every year bigger.
what's between us.
But Petr has never reminded
that to me.
That's why I don't want
he had any problems because of me.
[knocking on the door]
[louder knocking on the door]
Doctor, you've got to go with me.
-What's that?
-Mum's bad. She's dying.
Heart, maybe.
She got an outbreak.
How did it happen?
I'm to blame, I guess.
Mum sometimes quarell,
she doesn't know why herself.
When she fell, I thought,
she were playing that, but it was for real.
Why did you quarell?
When you mention to old Zitova about the highway,
what they'll build over her
she can explode, how he acts.
The girl is nuts as her.
Once she'll fell
of the crock.
It's broken again.
It'll be better to stop.
Mum thinks that since we have this,
as a farmer girl,
I've got better chance to get married.
Do you understand it?
Look for yourself
how it looks at our place.
Everyone can laugh at us.
I would like
to see your mother now.
She's fine.
I'd like to see her anyway.
It can wait.
Now, I need you myself, doctor.
Will you help me?
And won't tell anyone?
The medical secret
involves you too.
So what is it?
C'mon...
I'll have a child.
And what's next?
I don't want it.
-How next?
-Why don't you want it.
I won't tell.
How hard is it
to understand that?
I've brought you here to see
what sty it is here.
If I had a child here
I'll be single forever,
and that would be
insane.
What month are you in?
I don't know.
Second I guess.
And who's the father?
-No one.
-I see.
You have to have it with someone.
I don't.
So when you figure out the name,
come to me to the center.
Marketa! What does the man wants here?
She thinks you're here
because of the highway.
I'm a doctor, mrs.
I've come to see
how are you.
I didn't beg for anything,
I'm healthy.
And I will be!
So that you all could be angry.
Marketa, throw him out!
If they'd get
some good advocate,
he'll make some proper money
from the house.
Is Marketa going
out with someone?
I'd say no.
She's not too into boys.
She dated only me.
[music]
Let be, I don't beg you for anything.
It was very well thought
with the Prague.
-How could I know...
-Maybe not you.
But he... He surely does.
-Doctor!
-Please, don't cry, he'll hear you.
So be it!
Who knows if you're
not conspiring against me.
And I fool didn't looked through
what were you making me into.
You know well,
it's not like that.
No?
And how it is then?
Do you know what
do you want from me?
So that people could
point a finger on me.
-Look at the capon. No!
-Petr, be reasonable.
-It's silly after all.
-Silly?
Nobody knows about it.
-It'll stay between us.
-And what about him?
Doctor.
Please, don't make a scene.
Abortionists!
Petr!
-Where do you want to go like that?
-Don't touch me!
You can't do that to me.
Does it hurt?
And now?
What have you eaten?
You wasn't worried before,
don't be now.
Do you still want strawberries?
-How much did you take?
-I really don't want a child!
-More?
-No it's alright.
-You won't get rid of it like this.
-And how? When you don't want to help me.
It's too late.
I can help you.
To have a healthy baby.
-Screw you.
-What's up?
Nothing, usual percipidis.
-She ate something.
-Salami, yes?
People eat salami today.
It's simple.
Say, you jester?
She would use a free day,
so that she can get out of it.
Why not.
When you'll take for her,
doctor...
Making conductor in this hole,
a man will find his things.
One is getting married,
Kodet ran away...
And now the salami epidemy.
Could you find something for me
so that I could lie for a while too?
[cry of children]
Where did he go?
Kodet?
He's riding the buldozer
on the highway.
He got a good job
and I lost a worker.
-With your help.
-Is she better now?
Yes. How come?
-People talks a lot...
-Something chronical?
Maybe Kodet talked himself.
Come here you patsy.
So...
You're said to pick
in his privacy somehow.
-This is yours?
-Yes, the eldest.
I've got one more.
And a little girl.
-But she's not counted as a child, is she?
-You don't live here, do you?
A mile from here.
I'd like to see him.
I've got a cold ear, don't I?
-It's such a dead bird.
-C'mon.
According to you, as soon as someone
is not like here and there, he's a dead bird.
You know, doctor, our Mirecek
is slower than other children.
But he was never ill.
Do you like to travel,
young man?
What would you say
for a trip to Hradec?
For, let's say, 14 days, 3 weeks,
mrs. Vlachova.
It's nothing serious,
a tiny innate defect.
For a child, it can be removed by a common
single surgery nowadays.
No, thank you.
I don't drink.
When you're back,
you'll chase boys like nothing happens.
[cry from the football field,
noise of a motorcycle]
-If you're going to the football,
it's over. -Yes?
What nonsense are you doing?
Motion in fresh air
doesn't harm to anyone.
Motion surely not.
But this could hurt you.
And when I drag crates with junk
when mum decides to
or sacks with feed on the farm,
that's alright, isn't it?
They wouldn't force you to,
if they knew you're gravid.
Pregnant I mean.
You're worried
like you were my father.
Am I alike him?
I don't know,
I know him only from a photo.
-Mr., please, kick.
-Go on then.
Do you believe
I would like you to be my dad?
You could be younger,
but else you're ok.
But you wouldn't like to have such daughter,
would you, doctor?
I'm not too good with daughters.
What happened to your father?
He ran away.
I wasn't even two,
so I don't know anything about it.
But mom's not to blame.
You would do wrong to her.
She started to be weird afterwards.
I don't want to end like my mum.
-Why don't you tell her?
-You've seen her, right?
-If you want, I'll tell her myself.
-No. Rather not.
Now it's only my business.
You're telling me it
so calmly, you bitch?
Wait, you animal,
I'll beat you up!
Wait, you whore!
Wait, till I'll find...
-Mrs. Zitova, I understand...
-Why are you sneaking in here?
Go away! Or is it yours?
-I think you're not behaving reasonably.
-Let go!
-Please, go away.
-Let go, you vulgar!
-Mrs. Zitova, you can't...
-I can beat my child whenever I want!
-You're wrong about that!
-Get out or I'll call the police.
-Do it or I'll do it myself.
Realize you're a threat
to pregnant woman.
Yes, take care of your
children as I do.
-Take this before sleep.
-Get out.
[music]
The whore.
You're glad, aren't you?
You did well.
Come then.
[music]
Come in.
It's very warm in here.
Shall we sleep in one bed?
Let me do some things.
I mean all of them.
[music]
My husband did it from matches.
That's awful.
I wouldn't be patient.
Petr was.
Won't I stand
in your way here?
I'm alone here.
To have own flat,
that's a dream.
You can stay at me
how long you'll want to.
If you'll like it here.
We'll make something
good together,
we'll watch the tv...
Or we'll go to the cinema.
It'll be fine.
Only if I wouldn't have the child.
With whom do you have it?
With the doctor.
When he forces me to,
I'll gave the birth for him.
But then he has to take care.
I won't be the one.
[music]
It's kicking again.
Do you want to touch?
[music]
Can you hear?
A boy.
-Good morning to you all.
-Good day.
What are you doing there?
Don't just stand there.
Put the robe off.
I won't get undressed
in front of her.
Do it.
You heard what the doctor said.
Mrs. Zofka, pls.
What's up?
-Why is she here?
-Why do you think?
She'll have a child.
Isn't she stupid?
Don't be so stubborn.
Now you're upset
but once you'll have to say
to the child whose its dad.
-And then what?
-I'll say you're the one to blame.
Mrs. Zofka.
Go upstairs for now.
Pardon?
Write down a ticket to gynecology
for Marketa.
-For an examination?
-For an intake.
[noise of a typewriter]
Finding?
Did you say something to her?
Some things are
not told to patients.
Exactly those who can't
make them better.
Please.
[music]
Well it's nice.
We'll talk about it on the way.
Let go!
-Don't touch me!
-Mr. Simon.
-You shouldn't treat Marketa like that.
-Stay out of it.
-Let go!
-Marketa!
[music]
Don't go there now,
I've been thrown out.
No smoking here,
you're not at the cemetery.
You're really rough.
Of course she blamed me.
Mater semper certa,
pater incertus est.
So here you are, colleague,
come in and get undressed.
-Whole?
-From the waist up.
-What the doctor meant by that?
-Marketa didn't say that you're a father.
And who is, then?
Had she someone else?
She's very homesick here,
she wants to go home.
Out of the question.
-Good day.
-Good day, doctor.
Next sunday we can come
here again.
Together.
You'd make her happy,
he's fond of you.
[music]
I like it more than Marketa.
I've got a stroller booked,
but it hasn't be bought in advance
so that it wouldn't bring bad luck.
Do you know my life gets some
sense now?
Yes, but...
we have a situation here
with a tendency to be
interpreted somehow.
We all live under
one roof after all.
[music]
Mrs...
Pavla.
You're a dead bird.
Tomas.
Well...
-Can he go out?
-Sure, he's got a lot to catch out.
Mirek!
Mirecek!
Doctor, it's a miracle
after all.
Not today.
I've got the same thing as Mirek does.
Since I was born too.
But...
these procedures
wasn't common then.
So I learned to walk slowly.
Like a dead bird as you say.
What place a man reaches
is more important.
That's right.
-But you've reached only the pond.
-And that's too little?
-It is like a sea.
-An ocean, exactly.
Doctor, isn't it beautiful?
A plenty of fish here, I guess?
2000 cubic metres last year.
Well, that's a sea.
I fished here as
a little boy last time.
Frankly, me too.
With a fish hook, exactly.
I'll go.
I'll come back to check Mirek.
Where would you go?
Nobody is waiting for you at home anyway.
Come, doctor, come.
Lojza...
-Couldn't it wait?
-It couldn't.
You'll put it out.
[cry of children from outside]
-Wait!
-Let me be, Karel!
-Wait, wait...
-Let be!
-Ah haha!
-I can now!
What bait shall we use?
A buck's back with raisins.
That's the best.
-I can now.
-I'll show you! To the bed.
-Let him be!
-Let him be, Karel.
-Hooray!
-Let's go!
-He went over the floor. Is he gone?
-Now he can.
-Do you know the paragraph 7, Lojzik?
-I've never heard about it.
Come here, Karel.
Take it from them,
so that you'll do something useful.
Wait!
I see doctor prefers fish
before the teacher.
You're starting with it too?
I'll pour it on your head I guess.
Why on mine?
I didn't move him to Kodets.
In your age, Pulpan, it is
good to have a doctor in a cabin, isn't it?
Wait a moment.
If I knew you better from this view
you could live here long ago.
And all would be calm.
You know, locals aren't
acquainted with it.
Oh, now hang in there.
I see, colleague, you fell in it
like to a sewage.
Come have some too, Jaros,
so that your veins aren't shorter.
Give a finger to a hag,
she'll eat up you with boots.
I'll make warmer
myself with a shovel.
I'm not fond of a female visits.
I see your destiny
in black color, colleague.
-Why did he do it?
-I don't know.
I've always thought,
you understand each other.
If he'll come here, I'll ask him,
and then I'll tell you.
Maybe it was because of me.
He thinks so that I can go
somewhere with the child.
He's worried for nothing.
I'll keep him here anyway.
Don't speak like that.
If you knew, how am I,
between the empty walls.
-I wish you were back finally.
-You're still better than me.
Come. Come then.
Look at the hennery.
I'm going mad from
their babble.
And all the snoring
in the night.
Now I'll be able to go
into the garden at least.
Here it is.
End of visits.
We're ending here.
End of visits, ladies.
Will you put it
to your room?
Show me.
What did I say?
Ending, ending.
End of visits!
[music]
Petr?
Oh God, where are you coming from?
I thought my husband is back.
How come they let you go?
And how did you come?
I escaped.
-You walked by foot?
-No car passed me.
Please, turn the light off,
it's stinging terribly.
Thank you, I'm better now.
Are you still here?
Yes, sleep.
Don't go away.
-What's up?
-Is Ota at home?
-Why?
-Marketa is going to give a birth.
-How come? They called from hospital?
-No, she's here at me.
Damn!
-The rascal is not at home.
-Should I get someone else?
The doctor first.
Go!
You surely knows
where he lives now.
No... Ah...
Go away!
I don't want you here! Not you!
Not you...
-Not you.
-Well well...
You'll be good.
Just patience.
Doctor will be here in a moment.
And he won't allow you to suffer.
When she was taken in the gynecology
in the sixth month,
it wasn't because they had free beds.
Or that I wished it.
-I didn't knew it was that bad.
-It wouldn't if she stayed there.
-I know she's headless.
-That's not headless
but a suicide.
And you gave her a knife.
I couldn't do nothing more.
It's a girl.
Where are the keys
from the ambulance?
[music]
Turn the siren on, doctor.
I can't find it.
[music]
I'm sorry.
[sound of a siren]
I touched something and
I don't know what it was.
Show me, I'll go there myself.
Mrs. Zitova!
Open up, please.
Don't hide.
I know you're at home.
Mrs. Zitova.
I'd like to speak with you.
As in private or oficially?
Can you turn it off?
But briefly.
I don't have time for babbles.
[cry of babies]
Go.
-You can.
-I'm getting nuts too.
Nice girl.
She's all Marketa.
Subtitles by kostej (2010)