If the land had force to back.
All areas associated with gold
Who died in expeditions stranded on
the continent.
All they had been through, these
years.
Not because of money, because they
know what they mean money.
During the territory.
Not because of its debt as current
debt in the nature of man
Rather than verbal formulation.
Not for the glory.
But because of what the unknown, in
the name of which conceives and
runs.
Individual human life.
City.
Mainly geological management of
north-construction.
5902 km from Moscow.
For the last three years the
extraction of gold from river fell
sharply.
In 1958 we brought down the yield of
500 kg.
And last year lost a ton and a half
of gold.
New reserves are not found, growth
stocks of gold-negligible.
And if that continues, will fly
heads and first mine
And all you waiting despondent and
happy retirement.
We have a plan to optimize all
expenses except the cost of gold.
For example, territory, Comrade
Finches.
About what we lead the territory?
Case.
- In fact, gold mining.
He will write gergusheva companion,
journalist from Leningrad.
So.
I stopped what?
- What is our lead-complex.
Indeed, what we lead the territory?
Available there to close geological
management.
For him I do not care.
Territory is one of the seven
departments.
We can stop it.
More that it's lead-mining province.
And no one here believes
gold-territory.
In ideas you can believe or not
believe.
And gold, commodity-material
entirely.
We know of the existence of gold, we
can not know
But we unfortunately do not know
anything there gold complex or not.
Finches not heard more.
He remembered the smell of cedar
slannik,
Forgotten smoke fires and victorious
faith in happiness.
They thought that was the end of
finches, and he even never started.
Now is the time.
-time.
Will not give you the territory.
Ilya Nikolayevich,
I want to write about-gold complex.
I am happy, but you just heard, that
it does not exist,
And you can not have it.
I will write about gold complex.
Nobody and never seen gold really
comes from territory.
T is p and t p o her.
Settlement.
Headquarters complex geological
controls.
1410 km from the city.
Here such summer upon us this year.
And to the south in the mountains
larch blossomed already.
Henry furdetski was appointed Head
of the complex.
Only a month ago.
The tops of severstroy thought if
furdetski is vanity,
Then at Finches management of the
population will die down.
And in case that person is then
useful to own.
Opposition of finches.
I hear you, Ilia Nikolaevich.
- Stay.
Now inform you, right?
And so I remain in the government,
It means that we will work together.
I'm glad.
- If you bother me, I will destroy.
In your interest to go to my team.
What do you want?
- Little.
Not playing behind me.
All messages town after
consultation.
For me remains the implementation of
production tasks,
We guarantee their.
Plus business part, housing supply.
Basically, everything in the
statute.
I advise you not to think, but
directly to agree.
Darmed.
And what is the phenomenon?
I walked into the dorm, the girls
already two months tundra.
Ice corners not yet melted.
Not boys, and geologists.
And this will be the concern of
chief management furdetski.
Of course!
Where you have a great care.
Projects!
Laureates and banquets.
Come fall, will return the boys
I would choose for himself chairman
of the union,
And I will announce to you padishasi
war.
I thought his rusty fool, nothing to
surprise me.
Kutsenko tell that tomorrow we go in
mongolov.
Rejoice, as you see there.
Ilya Nikolayevich Minkov, nicknamed
Buddha
He ended up in the river, as a young
engineer.
Right there Finches created the
foundations of the coming legend
Where ruthlessness to themselves and
to others, was multiplied luck.
His expedition discovered the
largest gold mines in the country.
But before six months, unexpectedly
passed the leadership of severstroy
report.
Finches asked to shift in geological
supernumerary management.
Complex on the banks of the icy
ocean.
River Valley Elga.
Eastern investigative Party.
270 km.
Population.
I wish health, Comrade Chief.
- How to you?
Nothing in this hole except my
salary.
Where do you stand?
- To eighth m.
My little pierced.
Morning wash them.
Comrade mongolov, based nearing
two-outer.
Go insulting and in their packs have
alcohol.
I do not see.
- Comrade commander
We will drink a cup-and-danced.
Indian dance, called Ganga.
How your child?
All washed samples, carry the base
to 12.
A, Head, samples will have them.
Vladimir Mikhailovich!
I'll bring everything.
Hello, Ilya Nikolayevich.
- Hello, Vladimir Mikhailovich.
Meet, climate Chizhov kutsenko.
Best dishwasher in severstroy.
Appliances our kutsenko, tea and
fish soup.
Vladimir Mikhailovich
Could you believe for industrial
gold complex?
I do not believe in industrial gold
here.
Trite nonsense and manipulation.
Lunch!
Comrades geologists come to lunch!
And trousers should not put, right?
Will excuse me, there is only one
bottle, so.
I hope for your deep-alcoholic
decency.
Nobility come.
I saw them.
And what now, Vladimir Mikhailovich?
Do not you think it necessary to
perform search-top.
Check-gold.
See both flow.
I do not think.
Party has an approved project for
lead. There is no gold.
The here amount of gold we find and
around Moscow.
Lead-mining province.
And gold and lead are incompatible,
even if students know.
But still I am not a student.
I Finches.
Painted tool used in vain.
Worse withstand sample.
- Yes, really painted.
And how you
- and when completed,
Not water it in the corner and
rotate it through panels.
Yes, I pour it in the corner.
So like.
Not them golden sand.
And I think we should have them
here.
3 years ago, my old friend mouse
Kinski led the group of a river.
A devil threw him into the pits
three samples with gold
Mouse wrote a report about the
group's reorientation towards gold.
Then, he never found gold.
Then ruined it.
Nice soup.
And where are your people?
- Baklakov should return today.
The group then went to the foreman
Salakhov in multi-day route.
They will actually return in region
of Latin, if you're interested.
I just want to figure out where
disappeared siderite.
East of our area of the river wool
p,
For it we do not know anything.
- In relation to this,
Do not you want to go behind the
river wool p?
For example, for ten days,
Send intelligence baklakov.
- For passing boats need.
And the expedition should go
whole-group.
Then to well-lived.
I was a machine, border guards gave
it to me.
And a mare named fondle.
Was nice mare.
Only that can not wash.
Are ye baklakov?
- I am.
What do you think about individual
route for 15-20 days?
We can do it.
Normal.
It is not possible to do normal.
The route goes on granite masses.
You will have to take a lot-samples.
River wool p, and then in katunsko
nagorie.
To 500-600 km.
I will do.
- How do you plan to cross the river
wool p?
I do not know, you should see.
Yes, yes, judging by everything,
this route is all you need.
Go to go to bed.
Comrade mongolov we will make a
decision.
Vladimir Mikhailovich!
I want to talk.
- Fir.
Vladimir Mikhailovich, I agree with
your decision.
Send baklakov in multi-day
expedition.
Right decision.
Seryoga, get map.
Drawer.
Under the table.
Red.
What is this circus?
- I worried that would-mind.
And they decided to put before the
fact.
Could just take advantage of the
order.
Then I would take responsibility and
management now they do not need.
Accidents associated with my name.
Afraid of responsibility?
- Do so, Vladimir Mikhailovich.
Look, surrounds us severstroy.
And people like me, they do not
condemn.
I'm buddha.
What you that route, Elijah?
Hold.
Where from?
- Washed up on the river you.
Kutsenko has a rare talent.
This sense, Vladimir Mikhailovich
That in your pits must have gold.
For their washers bet.
Check.
You are right.
Salakhov worked at Katyn two
seasons.
Katyn just did it-washer.
Source of the river.
Cerro. The old base of the Katyn.
Three years ago here Salakhov
washed-known samples.
Gold samorodki Katyn.
These samorodki broke the fate of
Katyn.
Salakhov felt guilt about.
Why stand on rusty place?
Blank-here.
These are the latest samples.
As do-go.
Suffer a little, the fire god.
But what I I stand.
A cold-bit only.
You will draw?
The upper part of the river.
Elga. 67 km. Base of mongolov.
This place given him noticed.
As we walked to the base.
This is my personal request,
caraway-Chizhov.
I understand.
Mee until you run out of water.
To-last.
Then goes to the cheek mongolov.
There'll wait.
I get you, I will personally come.
Just do not tell anyone.
Heart just counted its sixty beats
per minute.
Blood evenly and powerful run-veins.
About him already formed that
special coziness everywhere with
bum-.
Tundra is beautiful with its
multicolor, dark mountains, and
sky-faded.
Great loneliness of middle scout
unknown valleys and mountains.
It is wonderful that will never die.
And in that it is immortal, he
maklakov not doubted for a moment.
There are no restrictions and no
limits.
Run normal-eternal life.
Serrano River, 92 km.
Base of mongolov.
For the first time in my life
kutsenko performed not order
And the personal request of finches.
So we try very.
Fate he met with Chirkov after the
war.
Three years Finches him mercilessly
trained.
Forced before rinsing know there
gold here or.
But also kutsenko began to like the
work
Not separated from the rain washing
dreamed rivers, sandbanks
Processed materials, and
shale-brushes.
Luck shone upon him when he did
control route influx hope.
Other prospectors recognized this
influx empty.
Kutsenko remained inflows more than
double the normal, and discovered
gold.
With lev hand Finches, he has been
with caraway Chizhov.
Now if there was a glass of alcohol.
And a piece of venison.
Because of this spirit itself cut
off.
I now live with a promise.
Treating you?
No, I gave.
After my wife died
Then finished.
Will begin again?
Not.
Children should look.
I have two.
Mouse and tosya.
I took them longer than orphanage.
Live with my sister.
All the money they send them.
Write me: Dad, come already.
Ilya Nikolayevich was right,
Country of great opportunities.
Will not give you territory.
River vatapá.
98 km. Base of mongolov.
The confluence of the Danube River
in Cerro Elga.
57 km. Base of mongolov.
The fire god tormented by the
imperfection of his life.
He had no son and daughter tosya
mouse.
And she has never been married god
of fire.
But the dream of life, under all
normal people was so great
That he confused with reality.
Why there are so many people who.
Want to live,
But failed.
Camp shepherd kyae.
Somewhere territory.
Long years of life, past kyae have
passed many people.
He liked to think about them, what
they say words.
Some people smelled of sweat.
Of what seemed
Even their thoughts smell of work.
He respect them.
Others smelled of money.
Kyae them regret.
He was angry when life saying good
or bad.
He just has a different.
It is ridiculous to think that money
can improve it.
In memory of which is kept aromas of
herbs, ice, spring snow
Fields of icy cold raven and his
guttural cry over land.
Fall from hit with rifle wolf, the
taste of venison.
And more memory kyae kept daily and
hourly sad recognition.
Of inevitable change of snow, rain
and lives.
More than anything kyae boggles of
the irreversibility of change.
Impossible to stop it.
Mikhalich.
- How are the samples?
Chief engineer was here.
He showed me the gold that was found
in the upper part of the river us.
At Katyn same thing happened.
- Five days of his old washed-base.
Nothing.
Our gold, our lead.
Finches sure
We must have gold.
What's wrong?
Say straight.
When he arrived finches,
In the seventh sample went 3-gold
plates.
Honestly, I do not know how it
slipped gold in his pocket.
I thought mine,
To put it in an envelope and send it
to Sonia.
Sonia we studied together in school.
Then I became a circus school.
I thought to impress.
And she tells me: you also become a
waiter.
She liked the characters of Jack
London.
Why I'm here.
Immediately I wrote her a letter of
gold that work with urea and pelvis.
And suddenly she began to write me
long letters.
Misfortune stuck for that gold in
his pocket, just before you come.
But to back it was too late.
Generally Sedona called me scum.
Because.
Plates and threw it in the river.
Ashamed.
Bogatashcheta,
Samorodkite they will throw into the
river.
Motherfuckers.
Is your gold?
That gold is the state.
Criminals.
I am ready to bear the punishment.
What?
You condemn? To ruin your life?
Well.
We know we only.
- No need complicity.
It turns out that it's complicity in
the crime.
Go away!
You will cover his work.
Tamara.
I heard the shot?
I do not know.
Maybe.
That shot came from distant
hills-time.
And built many years ago.
And now returned.
Or come from the future.
Maybe so.
The next morning mongolov walked in
the valleys of the river Elga.
It was confirmation of all searchers
famous thesis:
When the area is empty, we have to
work three times more
To prove that it really is-empty.
Birthplace of mercury accidentally
stumbled.
Mercury nobody thought and did not
expect.
Mongolov found mercury deposits of
global significance.
Does anyone live here?
I-geologist.
Is sick.
Geologist Do?
Well.
I am a shepherd.
I know you're sick.
I heard a shot.
Look
- tent.
Morning nobody out.
No night-out.
Understood.
Is sick.
Is it far to the flock?
If you walk
- and a half-hour.
Maybe I should go.
If left alone
- will die.
You will surely die.
My name is kyae.
River-scrap Sinaia.
-party remote gold mining.
316 km.
Population.
What do host?
Or keep icons in the house?
No what to ask then return.
Tired.
Do not take a bath?
Coffee with a cigarette also would
give.
How about opryaten?
And it is good to understand
sleeping with whom Jeanne now Baze.
What is heard about flying saucers?
Here the skeleton of a man, and
that's what.
I think it's second expedition
Union-gold.
Do not forget to send radio.
Maybe call the militia?
- Should?
I myself would commit ritual.
Tomb of an unknown martyr.
Mystery of tundra.
Clay went in clay-back.
This is the sad end.
Tamara sat naked,
By ancient custom of women in the
tribe.
Naked body was common in their way
of life.
It was rational and good for health.
Kyae liked that his granddaughter
observe ancient customs,
And allows the body to breathe.
Eat, eat.
Eat morning,
Eat during the day, evening-eat.
Night.
When you feel the power
- Go.
My granddaughter will lead you to
the path.
Deer walk
Bears walk.
And geologist will passages.
Head of remote gold mining party
zhora April
Before people try to respect
established by imagination-perfect
image.
Nemnogosloven always arms.
Zhora April
- polar wolf.
Nature really create people in the
image of Viking
Somewhere in the middle, distracted.
And all remaining
finished-grandfather.
Famous geographer, explorer of
Central Asia.
The ward, opryaten.
- Skeleton found by Guri.
Tell him Major.
I want results.
- What results?
Helicopter will get you there?
- Without charge is excluded.
Walk?
- Two days.
Major, did you get a solution?
- Let him bury.
Make-act.
Work is clear.
Yes, please check how keep
explosives-based.
What can you say about gold mining
in your area?
Janjic chosen region drunk something
like
- I do not care what chosen
Janjic,
This is not a ground for research.
Listen order opryaten.
To autumn will you do plan report
for your area of gold mining.
Party has an approved project.
- I do not care project. Close it.
What goes dispute?
We conduct work mainly in the upper.
We must descend into tundra.
To shake tributaries of the main
rivers.
People to move elsewhere.
Stop here, and send them there.
Two or three lines of the main water
arteries, and there's nothing to
argue.
Reasonable.
- Please never shout at me.
Secondly, I want precise
instructions to search for gold.
And also want a written instruction
to cancel the project.
Without it I can not change the
schedule of work.
Engineer-geologist is not only an
engineer,
He must have a code of honor.
Your colleague killed in demand for
gold in the territory.
Results of his work are unknown.
And to run.
Plain friendly debt, you want me a
piece of paper?
This is demagogy.
- Demagogy ye.
Your order is clear.
How can run it will tell Guri.
And your grandfather should feel
shame for you apryatin.
Beautifully played, George.
Here it is said boss.
There savvy, has a purpose.
And absolutely no prejudices-called
ethics.
Bad person.
- They spanking. Take it like a man.
Dodgers manifest in everyday life,
And the martyrs are kept in memory.
Where to put the cross?
Judge alone.
Cynic his Andrei. Sucks.
- I'm not a
cynic.
I'm single philosopher.
Katunsko nagorie 214 km.
Base of mongolov.
308 km.
To-population.
Management of the territory was
known for one
Geologists thought he was
staroobredna geology.
Means of transport
- feet,
geological hammer
- a method for
learning.
Everything from evil.
Here holy adhere to the principles
of severstroy, chief of which.
Principle formulated long before
severstroy of Joseph Conrad.
He sounded like a short order the
world: do or die.
Half of them have in their hands 2-3
deficit professions.
Half jewelers at work.
When not drunk.
Grab those who give you.
And most importantly,
There was still such a case with a
stick can compel a man.
To be a man.
Delivered materials noted in the
book, accommodation me somewhere.
Seryoga arrived!
Twenty-fifth week after.
Not yet fully ready.
Nothing will live construction.
Write direction, while take-clothes.
Come with me, get you home.
Will provide salary.
Will pull his wife.
Surely dreaming naked women
constantly.
Many roads leading to the capital of
Soviet Lithuania,
And go from the city to its suburbs.
From east and west, north and south.
Everywhere I see is typical for the
surrounding area of Vilnius,
landscape.
And always, descended into the
valley of the mountains surrounding
Vilnius
We admire the lovely city and its
surroundings.
Head to dig pits in the fall when
frosts come.
To take and they put in this clay
And keep you there one day.
Phoenix
Only plebeians considered happiness
to keep your ass up and do nothing.
And is not I a plebeian?
Plebeian'm.
Work in the Arctic.
Arctic no-plebeians.
And pits you think, who stacked
them?
No princes of the channels-shoot.
Not-chief.
Most idiotic orders do not
understand.
Tomorrow last day will work.
In the vicinity of Vilnius.
Long.
I think this is an ultimatum.
Finished the night.
Go to bed.
To.
What's wrong?
What you need?
Since we are the only ones living in
this unfinished building
I would like to.
Are you throw compote?
- I had a jar, I.
Tea in a jar-do.
Completely different taste.
- Who
are you?
Sergei maklakov.
Geologist. Today returned from the
field.
To me every night invaded various
types of brandy.
Today will not invade.
We will defend.
I'm hungry as a stray cat.
Or dog-like.
As a stray cat
- dog.
What's your name?
- How do I say that?
Dear comrade gergusheva.
Here's who I am.
Go for compote.
Man, you either come or hang there
already.
Vasilychikov Konstantin Sergeyevich.
Tester-tanks. Former.
Finches Ilya Nikolayevich.
Prospector.
And what?
Come you fed up there?
No, thanks.
We as liberated Austria from the
Nazis,
One year I was there in special
groups.
Assembly technologies.
Hozyayka lodgings Frau Louisa
Every morning she brought me coffee
in-room.
And cream, of course.
In a separate pot.
Incidentally real china.
But women are wives.
In short, makes coffee in Vienna.
My son would have turned
twenty-today.
The war started, and I here looking
for gold.
I could not get back to him in
Leningrad.
Vicissitudes of life.
How to know where our lurking.
Hidden trouble.
Her little need.
Must be fried without oil.
In any case not to put a lid and
remove it immediately,
After the venison becomes white.
Well you is prepared.
I did nothing I.
This is called venison-pasteurized.
In fact related to the geological
profession kitchen.
So why you staring at me?
Yes, I'm hungry.
It is embarrassing to hear people
when he eats.
First appear as a cook for someone.
Nice when just out-engaging.
I feel better.
Tell me something better-heroic.
Have you stand next to a grove or
river
And dream that this city has ever.
I'm not the emperor?
Our brother in the best case can
daydream this:
Here will serve three drilling rigs,
ten tents.
And fifty-man.
Good evening.
- Why are you so tense?
Order to arrest you wear, or decree
for 24 hours?
You will fly?
- To.
Try a sleek quickly leave everything
else.
Mini-morning.
Keep in mind that you'll get about 5
days.
Goodbye.
People zhora apryatin floated down
the river.
Losinaya rubber-boats.
In late fall, shortly before spring,
when all the irregularities of the
tundra.
Snow-covered and covered by cold
weather,
Party leads in the mountains with
aircraft.
In autumn, when the aircraft can not
land on rocks,
There are only two outcomes.
Party transported by tractors and
trains, if possible,
Walk or go to the rivers and down to
the ocean,
Where they take all the available
vehicles.
The last option is the most
dangerous.
Many environmentalists tragically
died
Thus ending the season.
Once finished with the removal,
kutsenko walked to the base of
mongolov.
As Ilya Nikolayevich said that there
will wait, then wait for him.
Rapidly cooling to minus-30.
Rivers froze overnight
Zhora apryatin sting of cold and
awareness
That the work is not done well.
Exemplary study of the beautiful
territory not get.
Idiotic order of finches is filled,
but nothing was found.
Zhora knew severstroy not recognize
objective difficulties.
Therefore he must be responsible for
omissions map.
Draft party practically interrupted,
and nothing in return.
I understand from lead
Lifetime deal with cassiterite.
The issue of mines was agreed.
But this will not happen, nor leave,
nor mini.
Here needs you.
I suggest you to front for
intelligence-bulk gold.
It is frivolous, Ilia Nikolaevich.
I will not do.
I will not participate in this
adventure.
If I order?
For the first time in my life, to
meet the order with medical
conclusion.
Do not force me to do it.
Heart thing worries me.
These days will travel to Moscow.
I'm going to the doctor.
And will not ask you to provide a
report on childrens plase oven,
Before returning.
Mercury thank you.
Well, I'll wait for your return.
Vladimir sem?novich.
Thank you.
Forward!
Inmates of Jupiter!
Hold on, guys!
Guri was not in the boats-April.
He performs a simple debt-friendly.
Bury the remains of geologist.
And then moved into a single route
to the ocean.
Cape of whalers, where you have to
take them Eskimo boats.
Hello people!
- Hello, Evgeny Alexandrovich.
The whole party is here.
The route is completed without a
single casualty.
Who said that we can not?
We can!
We really.
Poleem to the end of the season?
Then I and the water will jump.
Drink us, Doctor.
You're strong personality. Finches
and your strong personality.
But what will you do without us, the
workers.
With your permission, Head, then.
Alone.
Once in middle Asia's Rising.
Three days a ridge, almost
inaccessible,
For there to drink 50 grams of
cognac,
Look above the ground,
And to think of the time-being.
Why I did it?
The answer is easy.
Centuries-delusion.
Desire, whatever it cost you to
prove your originality.
That I am not like other.
Will die.
What you mean?
So your face is sad.
Nonsense.
It is important to keep the
distance.
Follow the rules of the busiest
places in sadohodstvo.
The secret.
Boats come.
By the unwritten laws of severstroy,
geologist, returned from the field,
His allotted three days for
free-bath.
The same unwritten law, on the
fourth day,
It has to come in at 9am management
shaved
Well-dressed, and completely sober.
Hello, woman.
Welcome.
You will live here?
Abalakov?
- Baklakov meanings.
Baklakov.
He went to his family home in the
village.
He your friend?
- I have friends.
I only known, as all our time.
And with baklakov-lived last winter.
It is convenient.
Ordinary man.
Busy with muscles and geology.
Wonderful not to speak
Women also.
- Yes, it is very good.
He is a wonderful.
Soviet-ordinary fan.
- And you?
And I'm penultimate adventurer.
- Penultimate why?
It would be insulting to-last.
Cognac?
Cognac.
Cognac should be drunk from cups
gilded.
Only gives color.
Where did you get such a cognac?
- Acquaintances send me.
Books, drinks, plates.
Care to keep up-time.
I only smoke cigars, as Churchill.
I want to live to a ripe old age,
and to see how all this will end.
What exactly?
Sorry that so resembles the
interview.
Do what?
Respect journalists.
What will you do?
Universal satisfaction.
Apartments, clothes, cars.
Users conquer the world.
And to hell.
To drink your career.
To drink.
And you want to create a matrix of
all correspondence local theme?
Listen.
Track storm enthusiasm
Snowy expanses, a young worker,
adult-nomad.
It is now my profession.
- My respect. Work-esteem.
And my neighbor, my neighbor
respects baklakov work.
Here we all respect the work.
- All-you.
I'm not all.
I am separately.
Bum, that's who I am.
- How do you manage to be a bum?
Postdoctoral am.
I know profession level of average
doctor.
Speak two languages.
With such a load anywhere I welcome
guest.
If I get bored here, I will find a
place on the map, and will go there.
Movements allow you to not have a
lot of luggage.
It is more convenient.
And do not you empty?
- Sorry I.
Previously conquered land
chingizhanove, Tamerlane,
Macedonian,
Now tightly and shaken him
conquer-users.
They are everywhere.
Lake Titicaca to Mozhaisk.
Most ruthless conquest.
So adore adventurers.
Users put them outside the law.
Therefore adapt.
I want to protect their
self-satisfaction in general.
I do not want anything to possess
but themselves.
Horrific man.
Startling men walk in cafes and pull
port through a straw,
Portraying the squandering of life.
I am still penultimate adventurer
But work not worse than those
polar-supermen.
You want to see them?
I. But how?
- Evening geologists.
Heroes of the tundra with a bottle
of wine.
Strangers are not allowed.
It is a treasure trove for
journalist.
- Invite me?
Do you?
On the evening of geologists?
You know, Ivan egorovich,
This birth.
Of global importance.
Mongolov claims that hill.
Almost entirely composed of mercury.
Brought one t.
Just like that, they passed from
there, loaded, and brought.
Because you flew to Moscow?
Robin twice already calling me.
You do not believe me, do you?
What is this?
See for yourself.
That is gold does not exist.
With chute you wash it?
What you need, Elijah?
Money.
Large. And once-money.
Secretly flown?
- To.
And gold also found a secret.
This is not a primer is not like the
river.
There is a lot of work and without
much intelligence nothing to find.
Money will find a new birth.
Another winner looking for?
Another laureate of course, is not
bad,
But you know Vanya, what I want.
Before I die, when I catch now the
third attack,
Tell myself that I'm not ashamed.
For his life.
And what was intended, all I filled.
Or at least I tried to do it.
Right?
Why spend jug.
Just so, or.
Where disappeared Finches?
Second day I can not get him.
End.
SUVs received fully justified itself
in the polar conditions.
The pole thank you, Comrade robikin.
End.
Where Finches.
She went to hospital because of
heart.
All field parties returned safely.
End.
Furtetski, autonomy you did there?
What autonomy, Comrade robikin.
Send preliminary report after week
you personally.
End.
I wish the management team success.
Baklakov late.
His father died three days before he
arrives.
All the things his father gave them.
For myself left a large family photo
album.
Now baklakov with irrefutable
clarity understands that now,
The only thing is, this is a room on
the shore of the icy ocean.
And his home territory is.
Good-bye.
Here, read-Wrangel. It will benefit.
Andrew, let's talk.
Problems with the report?
- Almost.
Logic is easy.
Your situation is not sad, but
rather joyfully.
Because you have the right to write
custom report
I will be serious.
Have you read the reports of the
classics?
Of mushketov on Obruchev,
Bogdanovic?
You are not?
And what you studied six years?
Classics wrote novels geological.
Essays are written by private
variations hypothesize.
But not too lazy to describe the
landscape so as to penetrate with
atmosphere.
With their way of thinking.
- Well.
And what to do with Section
minerals?
What can not you take, it's
stubborn.
I suggest you to write an essay
geological.
The free play of the mind.
With your personal concept device of
the globe in our region.
And then minerals alone will come
into place.
Try to understand why Buddha seeks
gold.
And mind you, Buddha will do a
step-vain.
He is the only smart person among
you, Superman.
Stop nagging.
- But if you see the sacred fire
Thoughts in your eyes, take
I-petrography.
I agree.
To, inter alia,
I lost a bet with our friend-dozen
champagne.
Try to come over tonight.
- No, I will work.
As you want.
- Maybe nine will go.
Baklanov whole festive week spent in
management,
Working on your report.
Color paper, there was a four-world.
In conjunction with the earthmoving,
With its cracks, with blasts of
depth magmas,
Boisterous insanity of volcanic
eruptions.
Purple field of Triassic, Paleozoic
predpolozhitelno array-east.
South extends line of
Tunguska-nagorie.
He had imagined history.
Faults inexplicably my thoughts
constantly returned to faults.
They pass them on ridges-failures.
Them pass and river valleys.
Steep ridges.
In them passes magma
They form the relief.
What are its faults?
And suddenly thought, no need to
deepen the sea of facts.
He can not now hide behind giblets.
The power of prophets in their moral
confidence.
It should create a base.
Details will come later.
Gold they have at least so that the
signs are springing up everywhere.
This is a fact.
It came with granite.
And this is a fact.
Nor one of the granite massifs, no
one has seen gold as ore.
This is the third-fact.
Baklakov took a piece of paper, a
pen,
And suddenly instead of thoughtful
list of questions began to write a
letter.
He started writing silly letter.
For an acquaintance who once got
drunk, he lit a cigarette.
Magnifying glass of the Northern
Lights.
For cockroach salmon
Who lives in a crack above his bed.
She wrote the letter, he realized
quite clearly,
There is a special type of granite,
yet unknown to us.
In this case, we should expect
birthplace of gold
In all the rivers of the territory.
That night he discovered most
importantly, intuition and
confidence.
He knew he was right.
Good morning.
- Is good.
Where have you been?
Why not go?
Guri left a note.
He asked me to tell you.
He is now with me.
Busy report.
Some cheerful and son.
Somehow-color.
Which is Tamara?
- Tamara.
Today I had a good night.
Suddenly woke me joy for the coming
summer.
If it believes the mongolov then
reduced amount of evil on earth.
My God, under the influence of Guri,
will soon become a philosopher.
And you must not become such.
You understand plain Superman.
For it should write in newspapers.
- Go to the tundra, look people.
Now workers at mongolov as screws,
Our hammer to beat us with pliers to
pull.
They must write.
Not these thy screws any other.
Such should not write.
Should those who come here for
romance,
To have clean and smooth-past.
I bad journalist.
Otherwise I do not is prepared.
Yes, they are not smooth.
Are special.
They are the first in those places
where then will be coming for
romance.
Maybe there really will be a city,
and not one, but understand,
City of empty space is not built-.
Here should appear worker nicknamed
kefir.
Biography of kefir is not holy, but
not without hard work kefir,
And kefir gone without hard work.
Perhaps this is his holiness?
You know.
Your duty to be a very good man.
Why?
There are people who are more
serious than others.
Some of them all goes without
consequences, but to them it.
And they are required to be better.
And if he has decided to live your
dreams, then double-bound.
Why?
- Because the majority.
Afraid to live your dreams.
Mouth of the river.
Elga. Intelligence-eastern section.
Depth 10 m.
Ah, your boss.
I've taken the lead,
Vermouth or port, Tips.
And rested peacefully.
But rule production does not sleep,
Measure the work you constantly
worry is.
How you sleep here?
Soon everything will fall.
And producing what is Sedona?
Exactly.
It is a tree.
It grown-workers.
Superiors gone -
Calm-worker.
We do guys.
I swear to God that we.
There still there?
- You have a happy eye.
Go down below.
Workers!
Salute with the right hand!
March at the word, start with the
right foot.
Rockets fired-up.
And guys are trying in vain not
laze.
Here Vladimir Mikhailovich.
Where?
- Line 430.
Eight-pit.
Exactly the tenth-meter.
Maybe you alcohol?
Forbidden us.
Will frighten luck.
Law of diligent.
Kefir!
Boiler let go.
We must promiem.
Spring-washing.
The summer can not traem.
Washing line gave nothing.
Pits proved futile.
Mongolov ordered to spend the boiler
to the next line.
The second line did not give
anything.
Hunters hung over the plight of
Misfortune.
Where is the logic,
thought-mongolov.
Samorodok big as an egg is no longer
considered a sign.
This can not occur accidentally.
Only not with samorodkite alive gold
industry.
It is alive with sand and dust.
Sand, and dust of gold is detected
by washing.
Mongolov fluency gambling.
He knew
That the ideas of the chief engineer
must reach much farther from Elga.
I read your report, Sergei
Alexandrovich.
In your reasoning makes sense
unconditionally.
I suggest you to specify route and
the organization of the main party.
I suggest to you the chief of the
party.
The task is to pass over land
management, and to write a report,
Which will give a forecast for gold
mining complex.
Will co me.
For dishwasher will give you
kutsenko.
Substitute for grab-Guri.
I have no contacts with forests for
personal reasons.
Valley of the ELGA must have exactly
this example,
Which is described in a report.
You guessed.
But actually I think that you have
known for throughout.
I suggest you the most complex and
important party in the government.
Project I need a week.
Baklakov remember, whatever is
complex and longer route to invent,
He still will not be enough.
And another council.
After clarify the route the aircraft
hold.
And discard the provision in
barrels.
Results meet personally.
Methods to use to perform the work
They do not care.
- This is my concern.
The care you have hot brain to give
ideas
And immediately reconcile them with
reality.
Among people know wisdom.
Obligate you to be ruthless and wise
in everything
That case-gold complex.
And your future depends entirely on
the summer.
I wish you success.
And not force me to be disappointed
in you.
I believe in your ability.
Find a nice place to camp.
Provision so the next trip.
To load-detonator.
Head, there is still room.
To load food.
Food with a second-rate.
Transportation detonator is
vzrivcheto substance along strictly
prohibited.
Respond in-law.
Let me go.
Head, lest your new?
Confused plane donkey?
A donkey will load whatever you
want.
End to stop-loading.
Yes, well-finished.
But what is?
- It is the food.
In tundra everything happens.
Last year two weeks waiting plane.
You do not go there to eat, but to
work.
Aircraft and successfully went back.
But the evening was played blizzard.
Seryoga, wait!
And only the seventh day was good
with good-prognosis.
Arriving at the airfield, opryaten
realized that the only aircraft
capable.
Baklakov-captured.
April remained his only pray.
Baklakov his route not ruin plane
And those two have the courage to
wait.
Salakhov food and the fire god-no.
Opryaten nobody told about
Although I understand that if
Salakhov and fire god to die
It will remain only to shoot.
Six barrels of provision and a
rubber-boats.
To recapture the upcoming heroic
route of maklakov,
They were filled, stitched with
wire, and loaded on the plane.
Baklakov transferred from the card,
the navigation map.
Pilot bardikin fight, all the places
where to throw barrels.
Kutsenko week before it went to the
mail plane.
He must employ or buy a boat there.
To spend a tractor carriage to the
mouth of Serrano River,
And book-base there.
Now quickly landing take kutsenko
and immediately go.
Holy shit.
This damn nose never know.
There wind, will not you hello!
Of management are.
Land!
Senja-slacker.
At least he was tied to the
stake-pants.
Give a ours.
A fire.
I will do another circle.
Engineer.
Plane with a coworker today nasal
baners suffered disaster.
All live.
When will fix it is not clear.
Now you can not hang here.
Sick
Visitors have.
Command.
Generator operates to 11: 00.
I'll bring kerosene lamp.
Well, talk her.
How did you know?
When will you meet 18?
Will you marry me?
Next year.
Will marry.
You're good, strong.
Although now not at all beautiful.
And what are you waiting for?
Time did not allow.
I have no plane.
I thought a lot about you-April.
My grandfather asked me.
If your people have died, will give
you a court.
Go to the radio and send on behalf
of my radio in the city.
That urgently need en suite 2-ski.
Do you believe in God?
Komsomolets I.
These days I prayed.
Pray opryaten pray.
Salakhov.
Will you eat me?
- Where hanging, Chief?
What do you need?
- Katyn died.
Michael Arkadievich.
Quiet!
Katyn died.
Katyn mouse.
He saw the world of wondrous heights
of high moral truths.
And we.
Live, die-galling.
And many evils of this world.
This means that the overall task of
the people
And especially yours, this evil to
eliminate it.
In wartime clearly we felt automats.
And in peace-time.
Honest work,
It should serve to remove this
universal evil.
This is the highest-sense.
What is the likelihood that the cat
Vasya, pressing, where fall with his
paw.
Will print the tale of King
somersault typewriter?
One-to-three billion.
Possibility to leave in my party
About this possibility.
And no editorial tasks will help.
There is cold, from which you can
not hide, mud, grim.
Eventually, sometimes nothing to
eat.
I can.
Not suppress.
Look at everything with new eyes.
It starts with something useful.
Write a novel.
For us supermen.
I give you the first-row.
On the banks of the icy ocean,
watching the sunset, and melting
ice,
Stand-two swords.
- Go already.
I love you, like diving into an ice
hole
- fun and creepy.
I love you with the same benefit to
wait yesterday.
I love you is like to catch the wind
in the field
- as useless.
I love you is like an iron will to
trust the cliff-.
I love you, I forget other, what is
better than this lot.
And in secret from you from the pain
of eternal pain to howl like a wolf.
I love you is like water in the
desert swallows without quenches
thirst.
And in tune with your desire,
suddenly was rejected.
I love you like to swim in the sea,
where they showered and waves.
Voistinu to love
- not generosity
License.
I love you so dangerous as to climb
mountains.
But my God, you're so beautiful,
Yes, impossible not to love.
Ngan-hills.
POS-circular station.
305 km.
Population.
Congratulations arrival boss.
And mountain skiing?
- To.
King of Ghanaian hills I am.
- To the south you went?
Of course.
Now dividing found granite fragment.
Maybe just not tip not pushed magma.
Wonderful contact.
Laboratory-ready.
But it should be clear.
Wait counsel-word.
-check everything in detail.
Take Sedona with her.
He training for mountain running.
And remove these aggregates.
I'll get tired.
Three ice-valley.
158 km. Population.
The plane that brought him back to
the base, took his young wife in the
party.
After a few days in the population
it back Uncle Kostya.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
How are you?
Froze it?
And you worry.
Here.
Coffee?
!
- Of course, not the same as in
Vienna.
God, I've grown up in Sokolniki.
10 years know everything about
humanity.
And I've seen happy people.
if any deluded man was found clever
and strong man,
Then humanity is worth nothing.
But humanity is worth something.
Fish where the fish swim?
In the water is dark.
They do not know where to swim.
It should kindle fires.
To see.
How else?
Nobody should.
Nobody has the right to live in the
dark.
Ignite fires in the ocean.
Uncle Kostya was injured in February
1945 at the battle of Budapest.
With debris from bombs.
A tiny left-ribs.
And a larger samples of silver, and
the heart-stopping.
He did not bother.
Only during strong concerns
Slight wiggle in the heart.
Listen.
Do not be afraid.
They will seek.
They will necessarily find.
Survive better?
Tractor drivers are prohibited to go
on the road without a tent,
Torch, sleeping bag, and weekly food
supply.
Sergei Alexandrovich.
Guri-breaking legs.
- How so?
With these units.
Sedona returned, he said skis are
broken.
And both legs are broken.
Backbone supposedly healthy. We
must-go.
Arctic foxes, like rats will eat
him.
A gun?
- I took him.
Guri is not of itself.
Shouting, roaring.
Sedona put it to sleep, two hours
have to go.
Baklakov much hated Guri at this
time.
He decided.
To the radio must be running alone.
170 km.
Two days will pass through to keep
the feet of his colleague.
Valley small-china.
168 km. Meteo-up.
As always, when a decision is taken
on his baklakov relieved.
And now very sorry Guri.
If Guria lost their legs end with
him.
It is not those who can stay a man
without legs.
Kyae!
God-sent.
- Did you forget?
When he was on the plane, we agreed.
Everything brought.
I left the base.
My engineer broke his legs.
- I know.
Based told me.
Of Meteo must bring him.
The passageway 170 km.
From there will viknem plane.
Will drive.
Valley small-china.
51 km. Meteo-up.
Guri legibly see myself removed.
In a set of actions, words,
coincidences, laws, facts.
Foreign and his aphorisms, proud
demeanor.
Andrei ignatyevich churin specialist
high-end single-philosopher.
Ultimately, now lies in the valley
stupid, silly River
And completely illiterate shepherd
tired deer to save him.
Now for baklakov it was important to
remove the borders with route of
apryatin,
And methodically, without sudden
movements, to work without grant.
But to withstand this double-summer.
Marau-hills.
Replace the stack of routes baklakov
April.
Go for two days.
Wait-April.
All people-are doomed.
We are doomed to our work.
Fathers
- workers, women
- Host
beauties and millionaires.
All they destined for his role.
We are doomed to work.
And this is the best and largest in
the world-doom.
Sedona!
Plans change.
Found gold.
We will wait for opryaten, and
return to base.
Of where you are?
Seryoga!
Welcome.
- And so, Vladimir Mikhailovich
Money and additional people will
have.
Barikin but continues the fight for
the eradication of management.
Instead they want to create an
extended party search of lead.
But boss wants you to appoint.
Moored nodes must immediately
logging.
I will continue the search for gold.
We will use all our experience of
mountain engineer.
Gold complex there, and I know that.
And still know
He would find.
I wish health, Comrade Chief.
A man of extraordinary decency
alcohol.
He found samorodok weighing 350 g.
Is that heroism, Vladimir
Mikhailovich.
Say that refused alcohol
Not to frighten luck, not ruin
monetary power of the state.
Heroic departed spirits, which I had
proposed.
So was it?
- So so!
You have rich fur coat!
With such a fur coat, and Broadway
All American chicks will lie.
The first human flight into space!
Our Soviet pilot Yuri Gagarin into
space!
Hurrah, comrades!
Hurrah!
Talked Moscow!
Give notice TASS first land.
Flight of man in space.
On April 12, 1961, in the Soviet
Union.
Into orbit around the earth the
world's first spacecraft.
Vostok companion with a man on
board.
Finches assumptions materialize.
They found a knot of gold-bearing
placers on territory.
It all happened in another century
and another land.
If the land had force to back.
All areas associated with gold
Who died in expeditions stranded on
the continent.
All they had been through, these
years.
But not for the money.
Because they know what they mean
money during the work-area.
Not because of its debt as current
debt in the nature of man
Rather than verbal formulation.
Not for the glory.
But because of what the unknown, in
the name of which conceives and
runs.
Individual human life.
Perhaps the idea is there, they keep
minutes of doubt in previous years,
If not trivialize, and realized the
beauty and harshness of the real
world.
He lived as man should live and man.
Today is a consequence of the day
yesterday,
Why tomorrow is created today.
Then why not been those tractor
sleds?
And not your face that freezing cold
February wind.
Where were you?
What you've done all these years?
Are you happy with yourself?
Dedicated to our parents, who
finalized postwar dream.
A large and peaceful happy life.