What's up Jacobi?
What does this mean?
As long as he is in Turkey, he is protected by von Pappen!
Today, he is passing through Prague.
He is on the way to Berlin; he will be there 9:10 PM at the main railway station.
Engage Görke for this!
Main railway station Prague. Orient express from Istanbul, Sofia, Belgrade, Budapest, Vienna...
Colonel Horst?
Yes please?
Colonel Horst from Abwehr?
Guard! Come here!
Let it be, this is not for you.
Security service (Sicherheitsdienst).
Come with me.
I am not interested, mister...
Görke, Sturmbannführer Görke
You have no right.
My superior is Admirál Canaris.
My superior is SS Oberkommand Fuehrer Heydrich.
Give me your gun and make no stupid moves.
Take care of the Colonel's luggage!
It's in the third compartment.
Shall we go?
I am expecting him... Come in!
Colonel Horst was arrested in Prague!
Poor Horst!
That's unbelievable!
Heydrich never dared anything like this before!
Arresting our man!
Calm down and help yourself.
Good Turkish tobacco.
A gift from Horst, from our meeting in Switzerland.
How do you like it?
Excellent.
But Horst will never bring any more, Admiral!
Oh, this Heydrich!
He has no right to throw mud on the army.
Calm down, general.
Look, if Heydrich was sure
who is behind the trace from Istanbul to England,
he would not arrest the colonel,
he would bring Hitler a fatter chunk,
right! An Admiral.
He is not this far yet.
And never will be.
You will travel to Prague.
The fate of the Abwehr is in your hands.
Horst must not talk.
You will pay for his escape,
or death.
Heydrich is truly an unlucky guy.
Where ever he comes to make order,
they hate him.
In Germany, Norway, Netherlands--
and now in Prague.
Because he is such an extraordinary executioner.
He is in Bohemia only two months
and he executes two thousand people.
Right!
He brought about such a personal hate for himself
in an occupied country,
it is, at the least, not cautious.
Not cautious.
And it's life threatening for him,
General.
Try it yourself, you moron!
Gentlemen, Flemming prepared a trap for me.
A Gestapo behind the tree, but I caught him.
You want to kill me too, you fool?
Look,
He got a hard time;
He needs to lose some weight and he will be our man.
I heard the command is interested in you.
They need a piccolo for the marching band; will you take it?
My boys could have been orphans.
That Scottsman hit me really hard; If I were a hunchback, he would have straightened me up.
Well, not much damage. You're not a soldier anyhow.
You are thinking too much, intern.
Our old man in Hranice knew nothing that once we will have porridge for breakfast.
That a Scot with bent legs will bash us in dirt.
He did not know about more things.
Like, what is the real war.
Bring me the cards of group "Silver A"
I brought the command from London.
With the better weather, the first paratroops will jump.
Group Silver A is ready.
They have the Protektorat IDs in names Sedlak, Tolar a Tousek.
Give me the training reports of the whole group from the recent days.
It is urgent. There will fly several groups one after another.
Why this rush?
I don't know. But it's good for us.
The boys are nervous, the long waiting, nothing good in more waiting.
What tasks will they have at home?
It varies.
Contact the local resistance,
Radio communication with us,
Sabotage...
Have a look at this.
Select two men.
They will be assigned a special task.
They will fly without a radio, but be well armed.
Pistols, sting guns, bombs.
We need sharp, bright men, and prompt shooters.
They are named "Group Anthropoid."
They will fly with Silver A.
Soldiers,
You were chosen for the task, which is the ultimate goal of all your comrades in training.
I assume you will be brave, loyal, and follow the commands.
Remember, you are making history.
Accomplish your tasks without hesitation,
even if you have to sacrifice your lives.
Fall out! Get in!
Are you OK?
I am. I cannot find the freight parachute No. 2.
Joska did not show up yet?
Perhaps landed behind the forest. What about the radio?
We will see. Where are we?
A dog; there must be a village around.
Quite a nice barking, that dog.
God, we are at home.
First, bury the parachutes and overalls, then look for Joska and No. 2,
We will meet here, all right?
Stop!
I have a bad day, Görke!
My pleasure, Obergruppenführer.
The revenge will be bitter!
What is that?
It was found in a forest near Podebrady.
- with a foreign weapon.
Gauge 9 millimeter.
Stun gun, English make.
- Do you know anything about this?
- Not yet.
Again - nothing?
Nothing!
You never know anything!
What's up with you, Görke?
What about Oberst Horst,
did he finally start talking?
I had to interrupt the interrogation.
He has a weak heart.
What does it mean, weak heart?
I had to hand him over to doctor,
yesterday, after interrogation.
Remember,
a living colonel of Canaris
is 1000-times more valuable than you!
Jacobi speaking.
Doctor, what is the status of Oberst Horst?
Thank you.
Colonel Horst is dead.
What a pig you are!
And you are not?
Jacobi!
I will interrogate you myself.
Hey!
Anybody out there?
What are you doing here?
Just looking. Surveying it here.
There should be a quarry re-opened here. Don't you know about it?
The footprints are yours?
Who are you?
The gamekeeper.
This is my area.
-Where is the second one?
-What second one?
There are two footprints.
Sir, I found a parachute behind the cemetery.
It was not buried well.
I did not report anything. Don't worry.
Do you want to help us?
Gentlemen,
This is why I came.
OK, we trust you.
Did you fly in from England?
We have to get to Prague.
I will arrange that.
Remove your hat.
- Why?
- You have to.
Proceed further to the car, please.
Down on the street, our people are patrolling.
They are armed.
- Nobody gets out of the house, in case you would be not...
- What?
Real paratroopers?
Good evening!
Excuse me.
This is Zdenek, I am Ota.
I also have my customs, if you allow.
Ota Radovec, you saw his wife, and this is Vita, the son.
I am Ondra, last name Havelka if you wish.
- Why did they send you here?
- It's our business.
Well, not really anymore.
We cannot disclose our task yet.
We are the soldiers.
And who are you?
It is just a coincidence you got here.
We have nothing about other groups.
What do you need from us?
Accommodations in Prague.
Zdenek broke his toe when landing; he needs to treat it.
You will stay here.
My wife is a Red Cross nurse.
We will get the food stamps for you; you cannot exist here without them.
And they will also need work permits, right?
- You have to get accustomed to the new German order.
- We will send it to hell.
They arrested and executed lots of people.
For less than harboring the paratroopers, but you must know it in England.
A collection of wool and fur items for the German soldiers in the East.
This collection proved how tight is the bond of the Motherland with the front line.
From the first days, the results exceeded the expectations in the town and country.
German troops at Leningrad.
German artillery shooting at the fortresses of Soviet field fortification.
The assault troops of Waffen SS preparing for the attack.
It seems that the crew of the fortress is fully exterminated.
Ice cream! Thank you! Who else please?
That's him.
If you get over there to the closet, I will have you always in sight.
- Vasek.
- Sedlak.
Do you know Cpt. Holz in England?
I do.
He is about 40, tall,
He is from Moravia, Hodonin - I think.
Dark hair, lots of gray hair by now.
That is right.
Come in.
Do you have the radio connection with London?
The radio is not working yet.
We will help you with the repair,
and you will request the bombing of SKODA factory, ok?
We will help you with the repair and you will request the bombing of SKODA factory, ok?
Only afterwards, we find our comrade who jumped with us.
- We don't know about him yet.
- We will get you together,
If he is not in Gestapo's hands.
I don't know about your task
but don't do anything without us.
You are lost alone.
- Joska, Jirka has got London.
- Great!
They will call us shortly.
- So what?
- I will now see deep into your privacy.
I have the first question for you from London.
Report your position.
Respond.
We landed in the area of Podebrady,
Material and group are OK,
Station located provisionally.
Bures and Kotrc arrested in Chrudim.
Send the new addresses.
The domestic resistance demands bombing of SKODA factory in Pilsen.
Considered top priority for the domestic situation. End.
Hand this over to London. Let them decide how they want.
SKODA is not mine.
Anthropoid still silent.
Are the boys in Prague at all?
Prepare the next group. Three people.
Operational area Prague.
Gentlemen, will you board.
Oh God, they really mean it.
A beautiful cathedral.
I forgot the name of its saint.
Saint Vitus, please.
Where are we going at all?
I want to show you something.
A secret?
- Almost.
Maybe a gravestone of Oberst Horst?
So what did you want to show me at all?
Czech coronation jewels, Admiral.
Look at this...this great sapphire.
It is uncut, 40 carats.
You are an expert, General.
You know the value of the things.
And people, too, Admiral.
Great.
A local tale says,
he who puts this crown on his head illegitimately,
dies within a year.
Are you superstitious?
Did you like it, Admiral?
Beautiful!
And how do you like your task,
assigned by Fuehrer?
I consent.
My Abwehr and your
Reichssicherheitshauptamt,
make up together
unbelievable power!
It depends only,
who will lead it.
The Fuehrer will decide.
The details remain open.
Do you count the case of
Oberst Horst there?
It was a painful mistake
of my officer.
But it cost Horst his life.
Providence fixed the mistake.
The interrogator died
in a car accident.
Poor Görke.
He valued so much the cloth he used to wear.
You knew even this?
In our work there are many things
which we must keep on mind,
General.
Can I announce to the Fuehrer
that we made a deal?
General,
You know that the Fuehrer's wish
is my command.
It was always clear to me.
I think it will be best
if we prepare the draft
and bring it to the Fuehrer personally.
Together, agree?
Definitely.
I got a great company. One lost on jump and the other lost his nerve.
Not that bad, but it does not work so well for me here at home.
I found my girl,
She had a child born in 1939, right when I got to Poland.
They are in Kolin.
- How do you know? Were you there?
I was not. I would need few days break.
You are a funk anyhow.
What a fireworks!
But they drop it far away. Don't you need the fires, damned?
- Where are they dropping it?
- Somewhere in the fields.
Far away from the factory.
Bullshit, the visibility was quite good.
I know what the real bombing looks like
and you too, anyhow.
We saw it together in France.
Maybe you're right. Maybe it's a too high politics for us.
- I don't care for such politics.
- Don't shout on me, neither do I.
I wonder why we care, our job here is different.
What do you mean?
Assassination of Heydrich.
Man, there must be plenty of pheasants here.
There is one right there. Ready to get shot.
- Are you holding the handle bars tight?
- So far I do.
1-2-3-4-5-6-7-8-9-10.
Don't be fool, Joska.
I thought we would need a 12-15 meters of steel rope...
...when Heydrich coming
- I say it's nonsense.
Sit down and don't show up too much.
Look around; not a hare would hide in these fields; what would be next?
Only a fool like you.
Eat, play nice, and don't disturb when the adults are talking.
He's coming.
Here.
Or not?
You know Prague better than we do.
It's a good place; you won't find a better one. But...
What if he's coming with the escort?
He is driving alone already one week.
We have an exact action plan.
Zdenek with the automatic gun here.
Ota as a back-up with bombs here.
Joska here.
He will give a sign with the mirror when Heydrich will be coming
And cover our back.
You and I, we will patrol the surrounding streets.
What do you think?
Don't you like something?
You know what will follow the assassination.
Our prestige in the world will rise.
What is that?
They will seek revenge for this.
Arrest. Execute.
Did you think about it?
I did.
But this is the war and we are fighting.
We have no right to retreat.
It's not my way.
I cannot command you.
But I ask you for one.
Keep this secret.
- There is one more option.
- What is it?
If London will recall the assassination; will you obey?
I am the soldier.
I will obey every command.
No questions.
- They are here.
- Don't transmit right now, wait.
Read the message once more.
The central command of the local resistance requests delivering the following message:
Assassination of Heydrich would not help the allies
and would have immense consequences for our nation.
It would open the nation to enormous reprisal
and destroy the last remnants of any organization.
Therefore, we ask for a command
to recall the assassination.
Very urgent; issue the command immediately.
Correct?
Correct; send it.
Then you have a light, please?
Something else, Jacobi?
Your signature on seventeen
death sentences.
It must be sorted out
before you leave.
Only seventeen?
Seventeen.
You revoked the martial law.
What is the schedule?
The driver is waiting in the car.
11:30 your aircraft is departing.
1:25 PM you are in Fuehrer's headquarters.
He is expecting you 5 PM.
You have the paperwork
in your bag.
Yes?
Berlín.
Assistant of Admiral Canaris.
Standartenführer Jacobi.
Yes...Thank you.
The Admiral will be with the Fuehrer 4PM.
He is pleased that by chance,
he has some more dealings with him.
How nice from the Admiral.
I can ensure you, Jacobi,
this was his last trick!
Not him, I will say to Fuehrer:
Either Canaris, or Heydrich.
One moment please.
Things came so far,
that I will hand you over
the statement of the dead man.
You may find a use for it.
I worked hard on it
last few days.
The advantage is that Oberst Horst
will never revoke this statement.
I will call you
right after the meeting.
Shit!
Today, May 27, around 10:30 AM,
An assassination was committed
On the deputy Reich protector and the police general
SS Obergruppenfuhrer Reinhard Heydrich.
The deputy protector was driving from Brezany to Liben.
He was going to turn into V Holesovickach Street.
Here a man stood in front of the vehicle
and attempted the shoot from an automatic pistol at the persons in the car.
Simultaneously, another man threw a grenade,
Which exploded at contact.
After the assassination, one perpetrator ran to V Holesovickach Street,
probably towards the city.
The second perpetrator escaped on a bicycle towards Old Liben.
He was a man of average height,
Dark grey suit, dark hat.
The other perpetrator wore dark brown suit,
and brown shoes.
The reward for capturing the perpetrators is 10 mil. Crown
to be awarded to a member of the public
that provides the information leading to the arrest.
(the sound of Czech radio from London)
Based on Article 1 of Emergency State declared Sept. 27, 1941,
Martial Law is pronounced, effective immediately
in the area of the whole Protektorat Bohemia and Moravia.
Based on Article 2 of the law referenced above, I dictate that
any person harboring perpetrators who took part in the assassination,
providing them support,
or having knowledge about their identity or whereabouts,
and does not inform the authorities,
will be shot dead, including the whole family.
- Signed, the ...and police to Reich Protector, K.H. Frank.
- Close it.
Why are you looking at me?
What are you looking at? it's not my fault it did not work out!
We got him, that is what's important.
- Ota got him; I was useless.
- Zdenek!
Does it hurt?
- What do you think, did he turn up toes?
- Just sleep.
If he only went off.
They won't say anything, bastards.
He is not happy, you can be sure.
- You did all right, just sleep.\
- Why don't you sleep?
Are you sleeping?
Where is Karel?
- Mom!
- Jesus Christ!
- The cause of death?
- I read the report of Professor Hamperl.
Some sepsis in spleen.
He got some infection
with the shrapnel.
May he rest in peace.
He was a great man.
Please write the suitable
condolence letters.
To Fuehrer, Himmler,
Bormann, etc...
Sit down please!
I see that the sadness is exhausting you.
What does it look like at the funeral?
Three days from now,
from the Reich chancellor's office.
Himmler left for Prague; meanwhile,
They want to enjoy
some post-mortem fame there, too.
Frank does what he can
to preserve the position of protector.
He has not the slightest chance.
The Fuehrer does not like him.
The book seller from Carlsbad
is only good for dirty jobs.
His brutal measures after the assassination
only hardened the nation.
I don't think they will produce the assassin.
A sad event.
One graphologist told me
when I showed him
Heydrich's hand writing:
This is the hand writing of a
fanatic and dangerous man.
He will not restrain from anything.
He is a mastermind villain.
History is relentless,
but history also needs a hand who knows how to steer it.
The Prodigy has
repaired an error.
Let it serve to Czech's fame
and our profit, General.
All exits from the city
are tightly closed.
Nobody leaves or enters Prague
without our knowledge.
We will search neighborhood by neighborhood,
house by house.
Each person will pass
our checkpoint.
And you believe we will catch the felon
with the checkpoints?
You have no idea about this place
and its population!
Take off the uniform
and walk the streets.
You will get the goosebumps!
The fallen comrade Heydrich
could not realize his plan:
To liquidate the best people
of this nation,
to move away or re-educate the rest,
and ultimately wipe the Czech nation
from the map of Europe.
Both Staatssekretar Frank
and I believe
that this Czech pack
must be exterminated without exceptions.
Executions...
Hundreds...
Thousands...
That's the only way
to revenge Reinhard Heydrich
and destroy his killers,
wherever they hide.
Forty-eight
Forty-eight again.
What's up? Where are you going?
Go lie down.
- Send here Sedlacek.
- Not down there.
At least it's warm here.
I don't need a patient, I need a patrol.
Go.
Sedlacek, go up there.
What's the rush Josko, you have an hour.
Oh God, what this one looks like.
Oh man, you have the fever like a baby.
You need the bed and sweat.
- In this ice cave, it is just to...
- To die, just tell it.
I will make you a nice fake tea, I still know how.
The hospital is just behind the corner.
Ota will get a nurse for you and you can stay here;
- we will go to the cinema. That might help you.
- Don't babble and give me some water.
If it did not work out for you, you have everything you need here.
The priest is up there.
Stupid jokes. He is not interested.
A sip of rum or plum brandy.
That would help him get on his feet.
So what? White or black?
Whatever. Black.
It does not matter.
White or black.
Where are the boys?
Do you hear me? Where are the boys?
Your commander is sending you a message
that you must not stay here at home.
Gestapo is tracking all families with someone abroad.
Gestapo is tracking...
Where should I go?
In martial law, you did not get any advice from the dear lieutenant, right?
I will take you to join them.
But where?
Where are they?
A place.
In Prague.
Vitka...
- You don't trust me, do you?
- I do!
But Kral said nobody can be at home or in any apartments.
There are searches everywhere; they were in our home too.
But we hid them elsewhere.
These three paratroopers, who landed in April near Krivoklat, too.
They are all well hidden.
We bring them food with mom.
But where, hell?
Vitka!
You became a soldier.
But I am frightened.
Will you go with me to Prague?
To join them?
What should I say to the commander?
Go, Vitka, return home.
People must not see you here.
Greetings to the boys.
Tell to the commander,
I know what to do.
Attention.
Special news.
During the search of assassins of Obergruppenfuehrer R. Heydrich,
There was found that, with no doubts,
the citizens of the village of Lidice
provided the support and help
To the identified perpetrators group.
Evidence was found without help from the local population
although they were questioned.
By supporting the murderers of Obergruppenfuehrer Heydrich,
they trespassed the law in the profoundest manner.
All adult men were shot dead,
women were transported to concentration camps,
and children were handed over for re-education.
The buildings in the village were razed to the ground
and the name of the village was erased.
That is impossible.
It is not their fault!
Bring me the ladder!
Did you hear me? Ladder!
Are we still soldiers or not?
Closer to "not", if you don't see!
How are you talking with me?
We have to stand it, boys.
When it gets quieter here, they will send us an aircraft from England.
Nobody gets out of this tomb alive, you know it!
Lieutenant,
I killed Heydrich. I cannot hide when Germans shoot innocent people.
- What do you want to do?
- Go outside.
I will write who I am and what I did.
I will sit down in the park and...
Don't worry, they won't get me alive.
I will go too (talking in Slovak).
I cannot let you go.
We have only executed the order.
Our conscience is clear.
Reward 10 mil. Czech Koruna for information on Heydrich's assasionation
They are expecting you behind the altar.
What are you looking at? You don't like me, right?
It's not too genteel here. We play no poker or billiards.
Do you have something for us?
A message from London.
Mr. [Czech] President [Benes] expresses his appreciation.
Thanks.
I will convey the message to the boys.
What about the aircraft?
When are they sending for us?
- They say June has short nights.
- Short nights; Every moron knows that!
So, we found the right address for us anyhow.
Right?
We will get you out of here.
Vasek is fishing for a funeral car.
We will load you into coffins and drive out of Prague.
And is the funeral home confident?
Well..
So when will they come?
Just come in, young man.
Did you hear that, urchin?
The second one is coming!
- Go, open the door.
Where is mom?
Sorry, it might be a mistake, I am - next door.
No mistake, we are waiting for you.
Don't come in!
Bastards!
No! No!
- Where are they (German accent)
- I don't know.
You. Ask him where they are.
Vitka...
Where are the boys?
I don't know.
Where are they?
Please, Vitka.
Wake up. Germans are here.
Wake up!
Get down there and wake up everyone.
Give them my greetings.
Shoot only when you are sure.
And come back.
They must not get anyone alive. Wait!
Last round.
For yourself.
Remember, Jozka. The last shot is for you.
It's not fitting well into my schedule today, but I will do my best.
What are you waiting for? Clear off!
Barricade the stairway!
They will be back here in a while.
Shouldn't they have come for us today?
It does not matter anymore.
Carrying seven coffins...
That is a great business.
What's up with you?
Nothing.
I am fine.
Stop it!
Do you hear that?
Silence.
Guys! Give up!
Nothing will happen to you.
I am OK, too.
Give up, boys!
It's Karel.
He betrayed us.
You rat!
Stop the fire immediately!
The Fuehrer wants them alive!
Yes sir!
I have a feeling that it's all gone down the drain.
Imagine, we are now the most expensive people in the world.
There is a 10 mil Crown reward for us.
You have the fever again.
I won't make you a tea; you would not have time to drink it anymore.
He sold us.
He sold us like a Judas.
So what, black?
Or white?
Man, you need the warmth!
Leave me alone; it does not matter anymore!
Stop!
The street is closed.
Go back!
Get the explosive here!
What are we waiting for?
We ask you to give up!
Give up and nothing will happen to you!
Give up!
How many?
Just one.
The last.
Give up. Nothing will happen to you.
We will never give up!
In memory of Josef Gabcik and Jan Kubis, May 27, 2010.
Subtitles by Marian, postcom@azet.sk