Based on the novel "Oms en s¨¦rie" by Stefan Wul
She's stopped moving.
Now we can't play with her any more.
Careful! It's Master Sinh.
Look, father.A female Om and her baby.
Is she dead?
I'm afraid so, Tiwa.
Why is the baby making a noise?
Maybe because it's frightened or hungry.
We can't leave him here.May I keep him?
Let me, father. I'll take care of him.
All right, Tiwa,we can't let this animal die.
That was my first encounter with the Grand Master of the Draags.
Mother! Mother!
Look at the little Om. Isn't he sweet?
His mother's dead. I want to keep him.
He's very pretty, Tiwa.
Tiwa, you've disturbedyour mother's meditation.
If you can't discipline that animal, I'll have to take it away from you.
But Father, he ran off. He needs a collar.
Learn to use it. Watch.
Now put the animal down.
It's fun. Let me try.
Not so fast. The animal is delicate.
You might hurt it.
What are you going to call it?
Tiwa, like me.
That's not an Om's name. Call it Trusty or Speed.
Look at him wriggle, the little terror!
I'm going to call him Terr.
I was forgotten.
A baby om is nothing compared to meditation.
This strange ritual to which my masters devoted most of their time
and seemed to be their main concern.
Despite our forecasts, the housing unit factory on our Uva at Goham
has not met production levels.
The machines show unusual wear
and this seems to have caused the delay.
- Master Taj, can you explain? - We don't yet know the reason.
In the meantime, we'll use reserve machines to meet the schedule.
I don't understand.
The machines have worked perfectly up till now.
Have you had the same problem on other Uvas?
Only machines from our space flight to Planet Antax 4
had some trouble completing their program.
Master Sinh, our scientists
explain this loss as a break in the sensory compensation system.
Our scientists also note animals brought from Planet Terra
have a high level of savibon and intelligence.
I am not sure that is true.
It's clear that this animal adapts rather well.
But is that intelligence?
The little pet you are stroking between meditations
may well surprise you one day.
Films made on Terra show many traces of organised life.
The ability to adapt, Master Ka,
may indicate an advanced evolution.
Oms have a much shorter life span than us.
But they reproduce much more rapidly.
If this animal is intelligent, Master Sinh
we haven't yet been able to establish this.
What we have established, however, is the considerable damage
caused by Oms on the Uvas of Jext and Telez.
The number of tame Oms is easy to control.
But wild Oms probably exist
in much larger numbers than is generally acknowledged.
We de-om the enclaves of wild Oms every three cycles.
But I wonder if that is often enough.
Few weapons have a long-term effect.
Drastic measures must be taken.
New ways to fight them are currently being researched. 73
But I doubt that they will suffice.
Tiwa, go and play somewhere else.
I'm very sorry. Imagination was so rich today too.
This animal is a pest!
Not at all. Our children all love those animals.
I grew up fast in that slow world.
A Draag week was equivalent to one of my years.
I was just a live plaything who sometimes dared to rebel.
Tiwa loved me.
Terr loves Tiwa. Repeat
Tiwa received her education through a headphone.
Its lessons cut directly into the brain,
and were engraved in the memory for ever.
"Our planet Ygam has just one satellite:
"the Savage Planet.
"It is uninhabited and is used for meditation.
"Ygam is divided into several Uvas.
"Two Uvas, Strom and Yot, are natural and symmetrical.
"Urtana is the longest Uva
"and is completely covered with blue assanic blocks.
"Its temperatures range from 8 to 243 laiks
"making it impossible to exploit.
"Our Uva, Goham, has a fepular inland sea
"stabilising the openosh at about 20 laiks.
"Fixation blocks offset pontic rebation.
"Er-shaped globes regulate pressure.
"All Uvas undergo a cycle of three seasons of equal length.
"The season of garus crystallisation..."
Due to some fault, I was also able to acquire the Draags' knowledge.
"When the earth peels, an intense vegetation replaces all nosks
"with similar nosks."
I liked the lessons.
I tried to get the most out of them.
"The cliffs on the fepular sea
"are eroded by rains that often last for a long time..."
Tiwa, bring your animal over here.
Jurgal has got his here. We can have some fun.
I don't want him hurt. Jurgal's animal is insane!
He nearly tore his ears off the other day!
No, he won't damage your Om. Come and play!
Come and see!
Let's get Terr to fight, it will be more fun.
Terr will win. He's really wild.
Go fight!
- He can sing. - Terr sings well too.
Go on, sing, Terr!
- He'll strangle him! - I don't know what he's doing.
What a horrid animal!
"It is simple to see a tark's flayed muscles
"because the animal is easily skinned."
Can you hear the Om?
That's Tiwa's lesson.
She loves Terr so much that they are never apart.
Do you think he understands what he's saying?
I don't think so.
Anyway, I'll forbid Tiwa to keep the Om during Infos.
She has to take her studies seriously.
"Let us look at the liscinian muscle of a tark's leg.
"The liscinian muscle is a fleshy, fuliform vilok..."
"The molog is an enviparous animal.
"It has more than half a billion lucons
"and the entire surface of their walls
"is made up of tiny cells
"separated by very thin sheets of organure.
"Today some scientists believe organure is not present,
"but gambous amalga, an artificial structure..."
Have you still got Terr with you for your Infos?
I told you not to.
Go back to the Omerie!
But he's not disturbing me, father. And he's so happy.
The Infos are for you. Go on, back to your work.
It was time for the Draag children to do their first meditation.
The initiation ceremony was a major step
on their road to knowledge.
For some time now Tiwa and I had been growing apart.
As she grew into her teens she gave up her playthings.
Deprived of the lessons I decided to run away.
Mother! I can't find Terr!
And my headphone's gone.
Use your bracelet then.
But if he's a long way away, it'll hurt him.
Put your bracelet on maximum!
Oh, no!
You're not very bright! Like all tame Oms.
- But you have a collar too. - It's a fake, to fool the Draags.
What's that?
The Draags invented it.
What?
The Draags made it.
Listen.
"Valio cycle, info 4.
"You will observe that Aklon research
"into pernetrope in space
"was carried out in the same way as on land.
"Importantly, we are looking not only for festation groups..."
Don't be afraid, it's not dangerous.
Where are you taking it?
- I don't know. - Come with me.
My new friend took me to her people who lived hidden in the Big Tree
deep in an abandoned park.
I was a silly tame om
and my first contact with wild oms was not a great success.
Don't touch that case, it's a trap.
Since I had brought the headphone of knowledge to the Big Tree
the wizard opposed me from the start.
We've brought five cases, Chief.
What? Is that all?
One of the cases was a trap and Speed is dead.
He knew the case was a trap.
He's a tame Om, Chief.
He ran away with a Draag device. It taught him to read Draag writing.
I'm sure he can't read.
Does the tame Om know what's in these cases?
- In that one? - Yes, coloured powder.
"...temperatures range from 8 to 243 laiks
"making exploitation impossible.
"Our Uva Goham has a fepular inland sea
"stabilising the openosh at about 25 laiks.
"Fixation blocks offset pontic rebation
"and er-shaped globes regulate pressure."
"The two other Uvas, Jext and Telez, are full of craters..."
- Why did you stop the Infos? - Draag knowledge is bad.
We Oms don't need it.
We are not tame Oms. It is a grave offence.
You must fight as the law stipulates.
Bring the combat animals.
You are the winner.
Stay with the Oms of the Big Tree. You can be of use to us.
Tomorrow we set off on an expedition.
It was my first expedition to the Draags to steal food.
We came back loaded up.
Take heart, we're not far from the Big Tree now.
The Hollow-Bush bandits! Look out!
Why did they attack?
They're the Hollow-Bush bandits. Beware of them.
They're thieves from the other side of the park.
"The Great Zarek, 3000 cycles before Krowp
"created the first pyramidic civilisation.
"From his tomb, so legend has it, he still animates the ball of life.
"Projectiles pierce his body but he does not change.
"His mind regularly travels through Ygam's skies
"ever since he led the Draags to victory against the Jankos.
"Some experts believe this is how meditation came about.
"Others believe that Zarek is immortal
"and that from the flames of time he reappears
"in infinitely varied, whirling reality
"to fight the Draags' will to die.
"In fact..."
"After the pyramidic civilisation the Draag people fought invasions..."
The Oms are learning.
If only we had more headphones.
You are as knowledgeable as the Draags.
I'm only just learning to write.
Look.
Are you sure?
Are you sure you read it correctly?
Yes, "De-om" is written on all the park walls.
- What does it mean? - The Draags want to kill all the Oms.
Long ago I saw them de-om the park. It was horrible.
But we're not in any great danger in our tree.
What will we do?
- It had to come. - Anyway, we have time to prepare.
We'll post sentries.
The Draags are going to slaughter us.
They want to punish us for having stolen their knowledge.
Let us pray to the Savage Planet.
The sentries will warn us of the Draags' approach.
We shall see tomorrow.
What were you doing on our land?
I came to warn you. The Draags intend to de-om the park.
De-om! You don't say! How do you know?
One of us read the writing on the walls.
Can Big Tree Oms read Draag writing now?
Don't listen to him!
It's a trap to get us out of the Hollow Bush.
You have to believe me! The Draags will de-om.
Take him away!
Someone go and look at the walls.
- Listen! Draags! - Quiet!
- It smells of Oms here. - They're vermin.
The Masters should decontaminate the area more often.
It's fine to keep Oms as pets, they're fun.
But all those wild Oms, they fight, they're dirty
and they reproduce at an alarming rate.
Look there's a nest in the gutter.
Look! A whole colony of them! Come on, let's exterminate them.
Chief is dead.
Stop blubbering like children.
We must go where the Draags can't find us.
I know a place. I'll take you there.
This road leads to an abandoned rocket dump.
We'll be safe there.
I regret that we de-om only once every three cycles.
Recent events have shown this is unacceptable.
A Draag murdered! It's unbelievable.
Are we so weak that Oms can kill us so easily?
Wild Oms are much more numerous than we thought.
An examination of the body showed a large number of bites and wounds.
According to the Draag who managed to escape
the Oms were very numerous.
Every day wild Oms become bolder.
They reproduce at a terrifying rate.
Master Sinh, it is disturbing that Telez Uva
was not the only place that was very difficult to de-om.
Two other Uvas, Goham and Urtana,
have experienced similar problems.
In the de-omised park
we found two surprisingly well-organised lairs.
Most disturbing of all was that in one of the lairs
the boxes were sorted according to their contents,
but they weren't opened.
How could the Oms know what they contained?
Master Sinh, it's high time we instigate efficient measures.
I suggest we de-om the parks twice per cycle.
I also request that the breeding and sale of tame Oms
be strictly regulated.
Too often they return to the wild
and swell the numbers of Oms living in the parks
and other isolated areas.
We must use the much discussed de-oming devices.
All wild Oms must be exterminated.
And I put it to you - should we keep our tame Oms?
It's wrong to believe Oms are merely vicious animals.
If we do, we may commit an error that has serious consequences.
Three seasons had passed on Ygam.
That was the equivalent of 15 years for us.
The Draag rocket graveyard had long been abandoned.
There we built our city.
But it was the Savage Planet that we wanted to go to.
Many tame and wild oms joined us.
Knowledge acquired from the headphones
enabled us to use sophisticated technology
to reduce Draag rocket components to our size.
"Trinur is a white metal that palsifies Matwar.
"Top-grade reculid gives it a remarkable metallic shine."
We have succeeded, Terr.
The first two rockets are ready for testing.
We just need to spend some time working on the others.
We must hurry. Many tame Om informers have warned us
that there will be a large-scale de-omisation.
They may know where we are.
We must send up our two rockets at once.
We have to see if we can live on the Savage Planet.
We can't wait any longer.
It's a pity I can't go with you.
But I'm not afraid. I'm sure you'll succeed.
I know you will build a world where Oms can be happy
far away from the Draags.
The Savage Planet will be our planet,
a world for our children.
You must go.
You must hurry.
You must...
We had discovered the Draags' secret.
The Draags used their meditation spheres
to meet beings from other galaxies on the Savage Planet
and to hold strange nuptial rituals.
This union gave them the vital energy they needed
and guaranteed the survival of the species.
We were gripped by fear.
The statues' huge feet might damage our rockets.
By chance we had found the Draags' only weak point.
The de-omisation was halted on Ygam.
Never have the Draags been in such great danger.
Our entire civilisation is threatened!
The Oms are taking revenge.
They have incredible scientific instruments.
- They must be stopped! - They must be exterminated!
It may be too late.
Neither Oms not Draags will profit from destruction.
We must try to make peace.
"Since the Sinh era, the epoch of the Masters of Ygam,
"the Draag civilisation has undergone a remarkable evolution.
"Instructed by Draag philosophy and technology
"the Oms now provide the Draags with dynamic vitality
"and a new way of thinking.
"Our planet now has two satellites: one natural and one artificial.
"The natural satellite, the Savage Planet,
"is kept for Draag meditation.
"The artificial one was made by the Oms.
"They named it Terr..