It all began under the Frankenstein
castle.
It was my tenth year with this circus troupe
and we were passing through a bleak
territory of vampires,
will-o'-the-wisps, and water sprites.
Hurry, as quick as you can!
The ring master whipped
the anxious horses.
But I had other things on my mind.
Lazy bones!
Keep cleaning, and do it right,
you have to earn your bread!
I sensed an opportunity
to run away.
They'd been getting on my nerves
for quite a while.
They used the fact that I was an orphan.
They never paid me
and they even made me do girls' jobs.
This is a dangerous place!
Hurry up or we get stuck her overnight!
Gee!
Miriam!
We feed him, this kid...
And look what he did, the bastard!
Witch!
You'll go hungry for this!
No dinner, and no food tomorrow either!
- He bit me!
- Don't you dare beating me!
- Just you wait!
- You're not my mother!
She cared nothing for you,
and I should rack my nerves
trying to raise you?!
I don't need you to raise me!
I'll put you in an orphanage
the first chance I get!
I'll find better guardians!
First you'd have to run away!
Let him try!
Go if you want to run into a vampire.
Come back, you darn kid!
- He ran off, the little bandit!
- So what?
- Who's gonna feed the horses?
- Devil may care!
I said good-bye to the circus.
And that was the beginning of the craziest
adventure of my life.
Don't be scared. I won't hurt you.
Is the water fairy still at the circus?
What water lady?
The beauty up front, at the wagon.
I don't know.
Are you very hungry?
Eat!
But it's still alive.
You don't like fresh fish?
Come, we'll find something to eat.
The Slovak Film Institute
presents
FRECKELD MAX AND THE GHOSTS
Based on Frankenstein's Aunt
by Alan Rune Pettersson.
Screenplay by:
Count Dracula! Your brain! Got it?
Excellent!
Enough talking! Let it cool!
Henry Frankenstein had waited years
for this moment.
Script editor:
Directed by:
Friends! This day will enter
the annals of human history.
- Brain!
- Here.
Brand new and fresh,
Doctor Frankenstein.
My goodness! You left it to freeze?
The count told me...
I said let it cool,
I didn't say put it in the freezer!
I've waited for ages for
Professor Sedlmayer to die!
I am sorry, sir Henry.
He was one of the greatest geniuses,
and you freeze his brain to stone!
What if you damaged some
important section of it?
- I'll try warm it up.
- Scalpel!
Here you go.
Telephone, please.
Telephone!
I can't work like this!
Dashing. What're we going
to call him?
I suggest Henry II, after you.
Thank you so much.
But he will beat us in significance
and intelligence. Hopefully.
My favorite apprentice has
a fitting name. Einstein.
The Joseph who visited here
during the holidays?
No. Einstein's name is Albert.
Fascinating. Very original!
May happiness be his companion
in all his life!
May your name be Albert!
Zipper!
Careful, countess.
I have to attach it right,
otherwise he'll be a leftie.
What is it, Igor?
The electricity will kick in soon,
the antennas are up!
Now, we wake up his
nervous system.
The further the worse, Alojz.
See that liver? Go, don't be scared!
No trout!
Ok, two beers then, that's all.
- Three. Pilsners.
- No!
Do you want to drink yourself to death?
- Touché!
- Dame!
I'm taking that.
This too!
Help!
Guys, we got a problem!
What's going on?
Terrible things are happening
at the castle.
Give him some liquor!
- Plum brandy!
- Coming up!
Wake up!
It was a vampire.
Up at the castle.
Count Frankenstein put together
a horrible monster.
Just like his uncle five hundred years ago.
I saw it myself. Look!
He let the dragons out.
When the lightning strikes them,
the monster comes alive!
Nonsense. Nobody can construct
a human being.
It has happened in the past.
My grandfather saw it.
We cannot let it come to that!
I must go to the castle right away.
I'm coming with you!
You came to see us, brother?
You decided to do some work?
Later, Berta. I don't have time for this.
I have to show them
who the inventor is around here!
They are going to see one Hufschmied!
It won't be long before I get married!
Never again will I touch a hammer!
Until then, you just keep picking it up!
You work! I'll be famous!
My name will be in all the papers!
Excellent!
And now let's see if everything works
like it should.
The hand... the fingers.
And now the major stuff:
Speech and sight!
The sight is perfect, but...
Come on, what's wrong with you?
Say something!
It should work!
Everything functions!
Wait! Say something!
Say it loud and clear!
Here I am!
Are you in the netherworld?
I'm in the channel!
Is that you, Alojz? What's going on?
You should be ashamed of yourself!
Getting drunk and make a mess!
There's something I've got to tell you.
The whole town is on its feet.
The men are coming here.
Now you'll see what my invention
can do!
Don't go! Come back!
A child speaks when you
slap his butt.
That's very unscientific.
Let me think!
Think fast, those people will be here
any minute now.
A scientist cannot act in haste.
We'll set the castle on fire!
Beat all the spooks!
Why won't you talk, stubborn thing?
Lie on your belly! Turn around!
Don't you dare! It's unscientific.
People do it - you said so yourself!
My goodness! Look at how ugly he is!
It's not beauty that counts!
But his strength will save us.
It works! Welcome, Professor!
How do you feel?
Fantastic! Excellent!
Are you all right?
Come on, guys!
We'll deal with the count
once and for all!
Albert will win them over,
you'll see.
Professor, once again!
Welcome to the castle
of Count Farkastein!
Frankenstein.
We hope you will...
have a pleasant visit!
Open the gates!
Open, or we'll break it!
Let us in and hand over the monster!
Open, otherwise we'll use
heavy machinery!
Quiet, citizens!
Welcome to the castle
of Count Frankenstein!
We hope you will have
a pleasant visit!
That's him!
Welcome to the castle
of Count Frankenstein...
He's trying to fool us!
Albert knows no fear.
Calm down, Albert knows no fear.
You, butcher, give him,
you're strong.
What is fear?
Be sensible, I made him for you!
- He doesn't feel anything.
- He's not human.
He's a monster!
It's a terrible misunderstanding!
Step aside now!
I'll start my fireworks.
Be reasonable, people!
Think!
You still want to know fear?
Is this fear?
Welcome to the castle
of Count Frankenstein...
Throw it away!
He can't throw it away! He's done!
No answer.
And he promised he would call,
my famous nephew Henry.
Pack my suitcase, Charlie,
I'm going to the castle!
It's time to see the ghosts.
I was a little girl when they sent me
off to school.
But I remember you, Countess.
So you're from Frankenstein, Miss?
Call me Claire.
And now you're coming back.
A lovely, educated young lady!
How long are you visiting for?
I'm coming back to stay. I'll work
with my mother at the pharmacy.
Come see us at the castle...
if you're brave.
I'm not sure. I think I am.
Frankenstein!
- Claire, here I am!
- Mom!
Good-bye,
Countess Frankenstein!
Don't forget to come visit us!
I'll introduce you to my nephew!
I won't forget!
See you later, Countess!
Watch out, after that scandal
everything is damaged.
It's in desolate condition!
There used to be a door here. Open!
It's destroyed.
I should sell the castle to the government.
Why? It needs to be reconstructed!
- Waste of money.
- It's a great castle.
What if he's hiding here?
Are you here, Henry?
He's not here. Let's proceed, Madam!
I don't like this.
This is where it all happened,
at the lab.
This used to be the armory
of Count Theodore.
You've done some work here,
dear ghosts!
The Countess never found her nephew
at the castle.
Then she invited all its inhabitants
to a dinner party, which was nice,
because they behaved strangely here.
Nobody gave me anything.
I was worried that my spooks never eat.
A raw steak for Mister librarian.
He likes it bloody.
Bread and water for the White Lady.
I'll make an exception.
I'll have the fish.
Sorry, I didn't see.
Enjoy!
You're not wearing you glasses!?
Have you gone nuts, Sepp?
What are you doing here?
I don't know this gentleman.
"I don't know this gentleman."
I'm Fiery Sepp!
I'd shake your hand, but mine
is too hot.
Sir Henry made a slight mistake
when he calculated energy.
Are you Henry's creation too?
When he tried to fix me,
he almost burned himself!
Igor! My sherry is gone!
Sherry. I've never drunk that before.
- What's your name?
- Max.
- And?
- Just Max.
Everyone has a surname.
We're friends, I'll give you a name.
I'll call you Freckle.
Max Freckle Frecklenini,
like Paganini.
- Frecklenini?
- A great artist!
I have a name!
Max Freckle Frecklenini!
- Want to go for a ride?
- Sure!
Careful, Frecklenini!
Good evening! Welcome home,
Countess!
You're still alive?
I'm immortal. I got news about
your nephew.
You know where he is?
At your house in Yorkshire.
- How do you know?
- I got my bats.
I send out signals to other bats,
they forward the message...
Us bats, we have a perfect system
for communication.
I'm amazed, Count Dracula.
I feel something now.
Certain vibrations.
Henry wants to call you.
He's walking to the telephone,
he's calling the operator...
He's giving your number.
They just connected him and...
This is Henry, Auntie! How are you?
I want to tell you that you turned
the castle into ruins.
That's the risk of business.
I've been working on a new idea.
It needs focus!
The castle needs to be renovated!
You have to come back!
The line is bad, I can't hear you.
It's a terrible connection!
You no longer want to sell the
family castle.
- Who said such nonsense?
- Igor said!
Igor spreads gossip and panic.
- Ladies and gentlemen, to the castle!
- And to the Countess!
May she forgive us our sins
ans be with us for a long time yet.
Until the end of the world.
Stop!
Everybody, over here! I found Albert!
He opened his eyes.
He's alive!
Wake up, old friend!
Welcome to the castle
of Count Frankenstein.
Welcome back to the world!
And we have a pair of hands
stronger than ten others!
I'm thirsty! Give me something to drink!
Albert, that's not whipped cream!
- Brush it strongly, Max!
- Is this your way?
So, Albert was born again.
With the soul of a child
and the strength of a giant.
Soon, the castle was like new.
But the Countess did not let him rest.
Without mercy, she ordered
his humanization.
Poor thing! I wanted to teach him
about the world,
but she sent him to the library,
as if books could educate you
how to live.
This is a man? He looks like me.
That's correct, that's a man.
And what's this?
A w-o-m-a-n. That's like you,
a woman.
What, me? Me, a woman?
A woman is something beautiful,
ethereal, and mysterious.
She offered him her lips.
Lovely... her lips.
- Max, will you be all right?
- Sure!
Has a woman ever offered you
her lips?
My mom.
But then she disappeared and I never
saw her again.
And is this not your mother?
No. She's the kind...
that goes with anybody.
Enough! A am a grown up man!
I have the right to a woman!
I want a bride!
Don't hurt me!
- Do I know you?
- I came to help you.
I know a woman
who would give you her lips.
- She likes to kiss?
- Why not? Yes.
And she's strong, and pretty,
like you.
Here, sit down.
You have a lovely zipper on your head!
You are the only person who
really wants to help me.
But don't tell anyone.
It's going to be our secret.
Help! I'm drowning!
Could you be a little more quiet?
- But I'm not doing anything.
- You're disturbing my peace.
- I haven't said a word!
- Do you want to argue with me?
What's all that sighing and whining?
- I apologize. Should I leave?
- Yes, please.
Or stop whimpering!
It makes me nervous!
- So what am I supposed to do?
- Look for a bride yourself!
Myself?
Every decent man looks for
a wife himself.
You don't want to be my bride?
You're talking nonsense.
I feel that I like you.
He passed through the wall!
- Watch out, man, step aside!
- Me?
- Oh my goodness!
- Wait!
It's the monster from the castle!
Alarm!
Into the shelter!
Inside, now! It's the monster
from the castle!
Look how horrible he is!
He's like a child.
Just you wait!
Let it be, I'll take care of it!
Albert! Come and see
if I can fulfill my promise.
- You know what I mean, right?
- Our little secret.
You and I - we're friends, right?
I am sure you will like her.
This is my sister.
You should get to know each other!
- I'm Albert.
- Albert who?
Just Albert is enough.
He's a good friend of mine, right?
My name is Berta.
Is this my suitor?
Isn't she pretty?
She weighs at least 300 pounds!
Are you as strong as you look?
He has to go!
He'll destroy our houses!
Go, kids!
- What's he up to?
- He's destroying our town.
I just wanted Berta to like me.
We have to tie him up,
or he'll kill us all!
Calm down!
He hasn't done anything wrong!
That's my tree! I told him
to tear it out of the ground!
Albert may not be coming back.
Don't worry. We cannot have everything
we'd like.
Easy for you to say,
but I don't have anybody.
- And whom do I have?
- The Countess and the ghosts.
But there are things I will never have.
I cannot sleep.
I lie awake at night, eyes open...
That's how unhappy I am...
And it's getting worse.
- But why?
- I'm cursed.
- Have you done something bad?
- Yes. It's hard to talk about it.
Something terrible. With Elisabeth,
the White Lady.
Can anybody help you?
Yes, but I cannot say how.
We are in the power of the Iron Man.
I can save you, and Albert too.
So, how about you, genius?
You haven't learned much.
You must get better, if you want to
make an impression on Berta.
Will she offer me her lips then?
You'll see.
Why does your sister need
so many sleeping pills?
It's not just for her.
I can't sleep either.
- How can I help, Mr. Hufschmied?
- Isn't that too much?
Give him what he asks for.
He's the customer.
What are you looking for,
little freckled freak?
- Who are you?
- Iron Theodor.
I forbid you to sniff around
for our secrets!
You're not my father,
you don't tell me what to do.
- So, Berta?
- Good... I had a drink.
What, you too? Get up!
You silly cow, you drank from it?
Berta, wake up!
They're drunk.
You have to help me!
Wake up!
I'm worried about Albert.
God knows what happened to him?
It was his decision to leave.
He's like a child, he could get hurt.
Igor says...
Enough of Igor!
He's just a servant.
- You don't like him?
- Pay attention!
Albert went off to look for love.
- At the blacksmith's?
- That's where he chose to go.
You want to get rid of him.
Like my mom wanted to get rid of me.
- Alojz!
- Here I am, Freckle!
- Start!
- Yes, sir!
I have a bad feeling about Albert.
Now you go.
Don't worry, they were all fast asleep.
Except for the blacksmith.
What? The blacksmith
is up to something!
- Go get help!
- Just sleep!
We'll take a look
at Frankenstein's secret.
Lalali, lalala,
your head opens up, lalala!
Wake up! You have to help us!
Your brother wants to hurt Albert.
I'm Siegfried Hufschmied,
the greatest inventor of all times.
- Open!
- Come, Sepp!
Let me warm up! May I?
I want to use my invention.
- What an invention!
- I call it laser.
Attack! Out of the way, Max!
Help! Quick!
Igor, quick! I think Albert is hurt!
Go back to the castle!
Leave the chains!
- I can't untie him!
- You shouldn't be here! Stop!
- The chain won't let go!
- Let's see that!
That's gunpowder!
Help!
Albert is on fire!
We have to untie him!
Water!
Firefighters! My workshop is on fire!
You idiot! Go to hell with
your stupid inventions!
It's that monster's fault!
It was arson, he's a criminal!
And you have to pay damages!
- Put him here.
- Careful!
- You'll pay me for this!
- Off the carriage, Huschmied!
Claire, save him!
He needs help immediately.
He could die.
He's running a temperature.
We have to beat the fever down.
- What is it?
- A zipper.
Albert is a modern man.
We never learned at school about this.
When I was little, mom would
blow on it when I was hurting.
Shall I try?
It always helped me.
It worked - the fever is dropping.
- He's better.
- It always helps.
Can you hear me, Albert?
I'm Claire.
Can you see me?
- He's pale, he lost a lot of blood.
- Young, fresh blood.
He'll sleep for a long time,
sleep is healing.
I'm glad you are here.
Would you like to stay overnight?
No, thank you. My mother cannot
find out that I was here.
I sneaked out, she doesn't know.
I'll send Igor, he'll take you back.
- Your coat.
- I'll take you home.
I will! I will!
- So who's going to take me?
- Me, me...
Gentlemen, what is this
supposed to mean?
You're bothering this lovely
young lady.
To your service, Madam.
Count Dracula from Transylvania.
That's the monsoon in India.
And this is the Opera La Scala.
And if I stretch out my arms,
it plays in stereo.
That's impressive, but...
Just a moment... Do you recognize
this voice?
Claire! We're waiting for you!
Mr Hans is here!
My mother!
The mayor's son is here!
Open up! He brought you roses!
Please, take me home right away.
It will be my pleasure.
But the sun is still high!
I'll take counter measures.
We're flying!
Faster!
What was that?
You're safe in my hands.
A fireball!
- A fireball, Fiery Sepp!
- Shouldn't we land?
For that nobody?
We'll fly higher instead.
People of his rank
cannot follow us there.
- What's going on?
- She locked the door and won't talk.
- I'm worried about her.
- Miss Claire!
Leave her alone!
Who will help Albert?
Careful! You'll break the door!
You'll help us. Let's try together.
She wouldn't harm herself,
would she?!
Quiet! She's alive!
Go out! I have to close the window!
Claire!
Albert, what are you doing?
Get out!
Hello. I was just coming to see you.
I saved you a trip then.
Can I borrow your bicycle?
It will be my pleasure to run
beside you.
I'm going far!
Doesn't matter. I'd follow you
to the world's end.
You have to run faster then!
- Not to the castle!
- Why?
Come back! Aren't you afraid?
Yes, me. How did you know?
You have the softest hands.
You must be beautiful.
I'll remove the bandage and you'll see me.
- How do you feel?
- Great, when you are here.
I called you.
Now sit quietly! Don't move!
I think I'm in heaven. I see an angel.
...on my bicycle, to the castle.
No way! She's in her room.
I talked to her a minute ago.
- Can I see her?
- Of course you can.
But calm down a little first.
We're closed, come back later!
In the afternoon.
It was horrible,
but I feel better now.
You'll see her. She's taking a nap.
I think Claire is up now.
Claire, where are you?
Come!
You see? Do you still have
a headache?
You look pale.
I had a terrible dream.
You went to the end of the world
on my bicycle.
If you came by bike,
it must be outside.
Outside!
My bicycle!
I'll come again!
If the mayor finds out,
everything could fall apart.
You're nursing such a monster.
It will cost you such a husband!
Albert is not a monster.
He even likes poetry.
I can't take this anymore!
You're driving me crazy.
Who's disturbing my sleep?
Is it so late already?
Your tea, my lord.
- What do you think about those two?
- You don't want them to be happy?
That's not the point.
You know what happens if
the two lovers have to be separated?
There will be two more ghosts
wandering around the world.
Why ghosts?
When someone ends up alone,
he turns into a ghost.
Is that what happened to all of you
here at the castle?
No. To all people walking the earth.
- So you too were Ionely.
- Your tea is truly delicious.
Put your hand on your heart
and start with yout left foot.
It's just a question of will.
Try!
I want to pass through the wall
and I can do it!
Albert, did you see that?
I passed through the wall!
I want to pass through the wall
and I can do it!
What's that going to be, a cradle?
I wanted to make something nice for her.
So that she would see how clever I am.
A cradle for Claire?
Is she expecting a baby?
There's going to be a scandal!
Is that you, Albert? How handsome!
I almost didn't recognize you.
I came to thank you
for all you have done for me.
- And please accept this small gift.
- A gift? For me?
A cradle?
That's so nice!
Did you do it yourself?
Let's take it inside.
My mother is not at home.
Do you like it?
- Why is it so big?
- It's for two.
Come one then.
You are so serious as if you were
ready to declare your love for me.
That's why I'm here.
First you just wanted to thank me,
then there was the gift,
now you want to declare your love.
What's next?
You'd make me extremely happy...
if you offered me your lips.
My lips?
They're right here!
What's going on here?
Do you hear me? Stop that!
This monster dared to kiss you?
- Albert is not a monster!
- Go to your room!
He brought me a gift!
Don't be mad at Claire.
It's all my fault!
Out! Get out!
Get out! You monster!
- Albert, I'll help you.
- How?
- We'll turn you into a dandy.
- Hardly.
The relationship between a man
and a woman is based on dance.
Graceful steps will lead you to love.
Shall we dance?
Doctors cannot cure love,
just like the flu.
The ring master said that nitwits
marry soon and the prudent never.
Unfortunately, our Albert fell
into the first category.
And we just had to help him
on his way to hell.
We taught him how to dance and coo,
because women like the looks and talk
more than the man's heart.
And because I know the world,
I gave me a piece of advice:
First, you have to charm her mother.
Dress rehearsal!
Albert, you're at the pharmacy.
Let's try a compliment.
I am under your spell. You look young
and pretty. Prettier than...
- Than who?
- Than your daughter.
A real Casanova!
I hope you remember everything.
Don't worry.
- Good luck!
- Thank you!
I'll keep my fingers crossed for you!
Good luck!
And remember to kiss
the lady pharmacist's hand!
He acts like he's at home!
- Inn-keeper, treat him to a beer!
- I should invite the monster?
I'll pay.
Young master! A word!
- Why don't you join us!
- Me?
Cheers!
He's nice and tipsy already.
I have to go pay a visit now.
You wouldn't do that to us!
Cheers!
Say hello to Claire for me!
Claire! It's me! I'm here!
- Claire! You got a visitor!
- I... I love you!
The gentle young man is here,
the one who reads poems.
I want to hear your sweet voice.
Come to me, my angel.
Let's dance. One... two...
Mom, tell the drunk I never want
to see him again!
We've been waiting anxiously.
I see him!
If I weren't curious,
we would still be waiting.
After Albert was rejected,
he wanted to end his life.
It was good luck that the count
taught him to fly in the daylight too.
You studied philosophy just to
start jumping off rooftops?
Life is colorful and exciting!
Not for me it isn't!
Sadness descended on the castle
and the clouds were gathering outside.
The public prosecutor, feared by all,
was coming for a visit.
And nobody knew what he was up to.
They must not find Albert.
Mr prosecutor!
Welcome to Castle Frankenstein.
Good day! I'm Dreyfuss,
public prosecutor!
Here Professor Švajcer was
Professor Sedlmayer's best friend.
We investigated that the Professor's
brain is at this castle.
And according to the testimony
of blacksmith Hufschmied
it was transplanted here into
the head of a certain Albert.
Here's the search warrant.
- The prosecutor is at the castle.
- He won't help me.
He's looking for the Professor's brain.
- And where is it?
- In your head, you silly boy.
- I am a professor?
- No, but you have his brain!
- We have to hide you.
- If they find you, we all go to court.
I know the perfect hiding place.
No one will find you there.
- What is it all for?
- Quiet! I hear voices.
And what's over there?
The underground jail and
the torture chamber.
But here, this is a fine collection.
- We'll take a look at the jail.
- Nothing stops him.
Put your hand on your heart
and stop breathing.
Say: I want to pass through the wall
and I can do it!
Please.
Come on!
Give me your hands!
Let's try together.
Quick!
Who are you?
Professor, check his identity!
Run, Albert!
He's too big!
Sedlmayer was a lot smaller!
But we only care about the brain!
Dear Eugene!
- My name is Albert.
- Damn it!
Albert is not an artificial creature.
He's a member of our family!
You would have to prove me that!
I have no reason to prove my innocence.
I can prove it!
Look at his head, there's a zipper!
That's where they inserted
the stolen brain into his head!
That's unquestionable evidence.
Lie down, Albert.
Where is it? That's impossible,
I saw it with my own eyes!
Hufschmied! I'm warning you!
The countess can sue you!
- It's not worth my while.
- Accept my apologies.
I'm closing down the investigation.
There's no scar and no zipper.
How about a glass of sherry?
What happened to the zipper?
The day I saw Claire for the first time,
I knew we were destined for each other.
When she said she didn't want me
anymore, I got very scared.
You were scared about losing love,
and that made you human.
Because there is no love without fear.
The two of us could write a novel
about that, couldn't we?
That would be a sad book.
Poor Albert, it was all in vain.
I'll buy the rings and my father
will buy an automobile.
It's a four-seat vehicle.
They'll bring it on the railway.
May I explain to you what is
an automobile?
It is a...
I don't understand.
Is it something you eat?
- No. It's a...
- Crinoline.
Or a musical instrument?
Maybe some kind of animal.
Let me explain.
He's been learning to drive for weeks.
Do you have me for a complete idiot?
I saw hundreds of automobiles
in London!
I even drove one myself!
That picture has live eyes.
What's the secret?
And who's that on the gallows? Igor?
And there, that's going to be Elisabeth!
That's just me.
If you're brave, at night we can
learn some of their secrets.
Are you sure you're that brave?
I'm scared but I have to help Igor!
Wake up, Theo!
There's someone to see you.
You'll never discover our secret.
Igor will never have my Elisabeth.
Why?
How dare you touch Count Theodore?
- Watch out, Max!
- I'll cut you into pieces!
Run, Max!
Thanks, Sepp.
As long as I exist, there will be
no human love blooming here!
We'll see that's stronger.
That's easy to say.
I haven't found out Igor's secret yet,
and the engagement of Claire
and the mayor's son
who is smaller than me.
Really! Charming!
Poor Albert! As if he knew!
Why else would he set out
into the world on this very day?
She can no longer like me.
You have no clue about life,
you need my experiences.
I will wander around the world.
I don't want to meet another woman ever.
There was still hope.
I sent Fiery Sepp to look at the car.
For the journey, Alojz lent him
his wet coat.
Here it comes!
Mayor, your automobile is coming!
My dear lady, dear Claire,
esteemed citizens!
This is the very first automobile
in our town.
May it be the token of happiness
for this young couple!
Smile!
- Take me with you.
- My little teacher...
I know everything, I crossed
half the world with the circus.
And who will take care of Auntie?
Who will free Igor?
We have to say good-bye.
Wait until the morning to tell them I left.
Something's going on! Let's go see!
Hold on tight, ladies!
He's no good at this!
That happens when backing up.
Goodness, what speed!
Slow down, mom doesn't like speed.
What are doing? Stop!
That's Claire! Look!
Stop!
Quiet, woman!
Help! Murderers!
Albert! Stop, you'll get hurt!
- Out of my way!
- I will sue you!
He saved them!
Claire, you're not mad at me?
- But I'm all wet!
- You saved my life!
And now we have a wedding to deal with.
What wedding?!
Just you wait!
Excellent!
I've always liked them together.
Esteemed audience,
may I have your attention?
Dear bride, dear groom,
dear Countess, and my fellow citizens!
I stand here before you as an honest man
and an ordinary blacksmith.
All my life, I was an enemy of the castle,
but I want to set things right
and make up with you.
Quite a transformation!
As a sign of my respect, I will light
the candles on the wedding cake.
Friends till death parts us!
And now nostra magnifica Miriam!
Homer sang praises of her beauty!
Miriam, is that you?
The servant stood under the gallows...
Who let you take the cake?
I bought a house with a fish pond.
It's over three feet deep
and it's full of fish.
They invited the whole town,
so we came too.
Darling, where are you?
I can't find my brother. I'm worried
that he's up to something with a bomb.
He was here a minute ago.
Let's go find him.
Take the cake away!
Violin!
To the peace between the town
and the castle!
May it last forever!
From now on, we are a pair.
We were never really scared of you.
Sure, he's nice and clever.
Cheers!
I'll let him help me out
at the slaughter house.
He is now the Count at the castle.
- Where are you? Come have a drink!
- Sure, why not?
But come on outside!
We'll drink in the yard.
You're up to something.
Where is that bomb?
What do you mean? What bomb?
Go with that fiery dwarf and let me be!
Here! See? He's lost his mind!
Bombs is all he thinks about!
I'll take you!
Watch out! There's a bomb!
Disturbing me again, earthly worms?
Draw your sword, Hufschmied!
No!
I haven't even dreamed of such
transformation.
He just conquered gravity.
He'll be orbiting around the planet
until the end of the world.
The blacksmith's bomb destroyed
the Iron Knight.
These pieces are all we have left.
That's Elisabeth!
She needs help.
This used to be her cell!
- Here I am!
- Elisabeth!
- We are free after all.
- And happy.
We'll rest together.
I revealed their secrets.
Young Countess Elisabeth
fell in love with her servant Igor.
When a child was born to them,
they got rid of it.
For their terrible deed Theodor
had her walled in and Igor hanged.
The two lovers were cursed.
Only a child without parents
had the power to free them.
Are they dead or are they sleeping?
- They fell asleep.
- For how long?
Nobody knows. Perhaps one day
they'll wake up again.
All the arguments and fights were over.
Love, that powerful magician,
defeated evil
and brought peace to the castle
and all the townsfolk
and turned Albert into a man.
A husband, actually.
And I put on my vagabond shoes again
because life is change.
I'm coming with you!
To the end of the world!
And I'll buy you an automobile.
I chose the profession of a comedian,
because deep down, I never stopped
wanting to do just that.
Is that sherry? I stopped drinking!
The woman won't let me!
I'm not saying good-bye!
I'm coming with you!
Excellent! Long live Frecklenini!
The ring master welcomed me
differently this time.
With magic I learned at the castle
I am the star of the circus now.
The people love it, they applaud me,
and I say: Watch out!
Because every one of us could be
a big or a small ghost one day.
Cast:
Sound:
Music:
Editor:
Executive Producer:
Director of Photography:
Directed by:
Made by: