Film by Filip Rence
No, no, no!
Daddy, please! Let me go!
Please, let me go!
Daddy, please! No! No!
Requiem for a Maiden
Starring:
Based on a reportage by Josef Klima
Script: Filip Renc
Script Assistant: Igor Chaun
Production: Vera Kopecka
Sets: Ludek Koril
Sound: Vaclav Voundracek
Editing: Jan Mattlach
Music: Ondrej Soukup
Camera: Juraj Fandli
Directed by Filip Renc
Yes, come in.
Take your hat of.
Sit down over there.
Take your boots off.
In the evening,
In the evening, she came...
Come.
This film was made according to
actual events which took place in 1984
- Can you wee on your own?
- What?
- Can you wee without help?
- Yes.
You can do it over there.
Come on, go pee.
Come. I'll show you.
You will sleep well.
Lie down, do you understand me?
Lie down. Like this.
Lie down. Close your eyes,
Close your eyes.
Lie down and sleep.
Do you understand? Close your eyes.
- What do you want?
- You'll stay here with us.
No. I am here only for tonight.
- So you're not here for long?
- Sure, not for a long.
- Quiet! Be quiet!
You should be sleeping!
- She is right, we have to sleep,
we have to sleep.
You are going to stay here.
For sure...
- I'd become an idiot as the rest.
Marika Farova, born in 1970.
Her mother died when she was 4.
Lived together with her father,
who in winter 1983 brutally ...
Come here.
Be quiet now, don't make noises. Put
your hands behind you. Do you hear?
We're waiting for breakfast.
Don't get dirty Prackova,
don't play with the jam.
Don't pick your nose!
- New one.
Please, don't play with the jam.
Behave!
Why are you murmuring! Eat!
Say thanks, shut up and eat!
- There are only rolls?
Take that in your hand!...
- Will there be any proper food?
...with your hand and eat, eat.
Jesus Maria.
Come on, quicker, quicker!
Walk faster, faster!
Up, down, up, down.
Everyone is doing the same.
One, two. One, two.
Down, up. One, two.
Get up, get up!  Quickly!
One, two, one, two!
Up, down. One, two, one,
two, one, two.
Keep up with the rhythm.
Can you hear, can you hear!?
I won't act like a clown!
- You will do as the others, and
I won't dispute with a moron.
- To hell with you!
One. Two.
Good.
Put your clothes on.
Sit.
What does this remind you of?
- A butterfly.
- A butterfly, good.
And this?
- I don't know,
maybe a bird with ears.
- A bird with ears,
that's very good.
And this one?
- Fire.
- So they're right, well done.
And this is your file.
If you won't stay in your room,
you won't get better.
No?
- But there is something bad going on,
can't you hear?
- There is an ill girl in there.
I'm always looking out for everyone.
And if you slept like last night,
you wouldn't hear anything.
- How does this open? Maybe she fell
off the bed, or maybe she is thirsty.
- Go to sleep Maricka,
you mustn't listen to this.
If you're kind girl,
you'd be liked here.
- Good night.
- And if you can't sleep,
you can count sheep.
When I was little,
I would count them every night.
First sheep walked over the bridge.
Second sheep walked over the bridge.
Third sheep walked over the bridge.
Get in your place!
Well, you see?
You're a proper girl.
Looks like you'd like this?
No?
You need to breath it in.
You made clowns out of yourself,
all by yourself.
Look closely, keep working.
Lenin, Lenin you fool.
I've told you ''Lenin''
This will go first ...
Come on. Empty it here.
Let's go.
Did you draw this?
It's pretty.
Why did you draw a door-handle?
Open it, come with us!
Please pick up those tools.
And soon we'll go
to clean up ourselves.
Give me.
Wear this.
A princess lost her beads
when she was at the ball.
And such a neck...
A princess lost her beads
when she was at the ball.
Her father, a powerful king,
called Honzik.
You're called Honzik
Find the beads for us!
...There aren't any bigger ones
You ate them on Sunday.
Quiet! It's evening!
It smells here, like...
Show me.
What do you have there?
What did you put on?
Take it off. Surely, you can't wear it!
Where it is! Where is the clasp!
Who has helped you put this on!
Where is it for god's sake!
Show me! You could get hurt!
Do you think it's safe!
Give it!
A princess at the ball,
lost her beads.
Here you are, eat this.
You will calm down.
It will make you feel better.
Marika.
I am sad.
- Come...
- Thank you.
Is there a phone here?
A phone?
That thing you put in your hand.
You talk to it.
You can hear someone in it.
- Who?
- The one you call.
- Quiet, quiet! I need to sleep!
- It's safe, come.
Good evening.
- What are you doing here?
What are you doing here?
Quiet, quiet!
Quiet, be quiet!
Be quiet! Be quiet!
Wait, wait!
Wait!
This burns.
- Yes, it's strong.
You come here for what, exactly?
And I don't know how you will
explain that you wanted to
sneak in to the bar.
I needed to go to the bar
to clean my hand.
Otherwise I'd need to spend
the night untreated.
That's bad. -
- Gently.
Let's not forget about him.
- There are things to be done
that don't require supervision.
- You know that girl?
- Are you ready, girls?
Go to sleep.
- I need to make a phone call.
- Who do you want to call?
- An adviser in Hradec.
- Well, the phone is over there.
If only they pick up.
- This is an internal phone,
it can't be used to call outside.
If I can't call,
I will talk to Procházková.
What did you just do?
Did you hear me?
What did you do?
- We're doing all we can
with what is happening here.
We don't want any publicity
And these, psychiatric drugs!
Are being misused.
We used this many all last summer!
- You think we don't
know that, Doctor?
Just so it is clear.
Someone with authority,
who is in charge,
can decide what medicine
to give to which patient.
When there is a new chief,
they can do it their way.
Everything sucks.
- This is a big mistake, lady.
You can't just create here
any regime you wish!
And you don't dare to
use drugs as a punishment!
Understand - these are sedatives!
- No way. Only those inmates
who are on your list
are subjected to (punishment) showers.
- 2 years ago there was
only 4 girls, on that list,
and now there are 35 of them!
- It increases.
What am I supposed to do.
Ask that governess, I am not
responsible for everything here.
And in the punishment-record
you write whatever you want.
- If you punish one in a week.
I said, in a week,
another one in 3 weeks, and
don't tell us how to treat them!
- You, Francisek.
I have a test here,
completed by one of your girls.
I put it in here not a long ago.
- You know, we never
treat anyone carelessly.
- For example, if some girl has
serious problems & nothing works? Eh?
- Stay well Francisek.
- So everything is fine, yes?
Come in, Jíra  come, come, come.
Look, what a deal! I exchanged one
Aero car for this wonderful buggy.
It is 2300 model from 1984.
look at these lights!
I was chasing it for 10 years.
- Good afternoon.
- What are you doing here?
What do you want?
Did someone send you, or what?
- I came here so you could...
I'm watching people here and I don't
belong...If you could examine my case
I am Marika Farova.
- What? - Farova.
Farova Marika, well, I don't know...
Yes, you've been placed in this institution,
because you've been abused,
there's a date.
Jesus Christ!
Who has sent you?
- I came by myself,
because I am not like
the other girls here...
Johanka, are you there?
Yes, so come, here, quick!
You should look after your pupils better
one is just standing in front of me.
you'll do like this
If you sin, if you do something wrong,
you need to be punished.
Please, like this.
Wait.
I know that you're different.
Look, her hands are tied up.
- Yes.
I will help you.
Johana?
Where are you supposed to be?
And who are you supposed to obey?
Your tutors, us, or your friends?
You will have to be punished,
yes?
- What will you do to her?
- She will get a lesson.
- Help me.
- Me?
- You won't help me?
- Come on, what are you waiting for.
Sit down
shoes come off, like this
legs on the top
like this
let's take off that hair clip
now sleep
Good night.
Get up, you can make a call.
That's because you kept quiet,
today she gave us the keys,
- Why?
She usually calls her mate in US
- And tonight she will not?
- Maybe as an patient.
Like this.
Hello, is that Hradec?
I am Farova Marika.
I'm calling because I was supposed to go
to you but I am in the Shanci Institute
I was supposed to be with
you, under social care...
I know that it's late...
But this is not right...
- Wait, be quiet!
Wait.
- What's going on?
- Prohazkova! - Who?
- hurry up! - Wait!
You, hurry!
Wine!
Let's celebrate, let's drink!
- Mrs. Prohazkova, today I can't.
- Oh come on, I am a cool girl
I'd like some more
What are those keys?
Who do you need to call?
Complain?
- Well, I wanted to call already
in the morning about Farova,
as you weren't here.
I took the papers
I will do it now.
I'm a cool girl.
What a prick.
- Boss, where did you
learn English so well?
- We're sorry, don't be angry,
we needed to make a phone call
The phone is locked away,
apparently every penny counts,
but it's perfectly fine to
call US, that's just great.
- Very good, isn't it.
- Yes it is.
- But how come that you have
such a tomcat only for yourself
such a nice rooster, on the bed...
You've hid yourself from me
there? Come out!
Farova, come out.
You can have a good bye
drink with me
- I didn't want to...- Don't worry.
- Thanks, - Thanks.
Lets celebrate!
Enough!
Well... Marika...
You have a rather vivid imagination.
The social institutions aren't
haunted castles after all.
- But she says that they're
weird things happening.
- There are all of these,
various idiot children.
- How can you talk in this way
about your friends?
I've checked here and no
Farova is mentioned.
- But how come? - None.
- I have to be on the list.
- Maybe they forgot about you.
- You know what, girls, go to
your room, and then after dinner
we will see. Yes?
- Thank you. - Bye. - Good bye.
Hair up. - Yes. Here.
Like this.
Do you like it? - Yes.
- You know what.
You can have this.
- Thank you.
And what is this for?
- This? That Spray?
Wait!
- I never believed in anything
she said. Bye.Thanks.
We're looking for a girl
- Go upstairs, then left.
Get in.
- Where are we going?
Where are you taking me?
It would be nice if you could
tell me where we're going.
- They're looking for you.
- But I am not going back there!
I am not going back!
Stop the car! Stop or I will
jump! I will jump out!
- What are you doing! What are
you doing! Close the door!
You almost killed us.
- Pity.
- Have a seat.
Miss!
- Yes?
Bring us two tonics, please.
- Yes.
And coffee for your young lady?
- For my young lady?
- Yes.
- Sure. Vienna coffee, right, honey?
You know what I think?
That you're acting up a little bit.
If it was really as bad as you say,
it would be known to everyone already
or everyone would say what you do.
- That's not true. Not the same
things happen to everyone there.
- Do you know what Krocova
did once? She...
Better finish it.
Wait here.
Let's go, I still have some things to do.
- Where?
- To meet a friend, come.
I'll just pay.
I'd like to pay. Can I have
these chocolates as well.
Thanks, bye.
Where is this.
You're a pig.
- I changed my mind, I realized
that this is better for everyone.
- You mean better for you.
- But listen, if you don't provoke,
nobody will punish you.
You have to go back,
you don't have a choice.
And what would I do with you?
They'd lock me up.
There you have
a comfortable space to live.
They're responsible for you.
Not me.
Do you understand?
You can't do anything about it.
Here. I will write you
down my work number.
And if something happens,
give me a ring, yes?
Come.
Everything will go well. And if
something comes up, call me.
You will get used to it.
Wait, I almost forgot!
Give it to them as a gift.
Give it to some teacher,
you will know which one...
They'll take it, you'll see.
- Ok, bye.
Good luck.
Take care.
We need to solve this in a good
and a positive way, not like it
happened in Viechove...
Ms. Prohazkova couldn't keep
her authority over her patients,
but on the other hand, she had
a different approach to every girl
and we need to design and
establish one approach for everyone.
For example Miss Farova...
- Marika?
She needs to be handled
in some special way.
Ms. Sukova, think about it and
write down in the punishment - list.
- This is illogical.
We can't punish Miss Farova
just because we'd like to.
She made an effort.
She came back.
And we must forgive her,
it's our duty.
And in terms of your
educational punishments...
- Our punishments?
- We are all responsible for
the order here. - No?
- And Farova is here temporarily.
- I know, but she will be treated
exactly like the other girls.
I think that covers it.
Thank you all.
I'm sorry that I ran away,
I brought you a gift.
- Beg me.
Come on, have one.
Better that we have it anyway.
Go on, don't be afraid.
Thanks.
I got it from that gorgeous prince,
in a great castle,
everywhere was just chocolate.
and with that prince, under his spell
and this was my first...
Farova, what is going on here.
Don't you know that sweets
are forbidden in rooms?
What are you doing!
Show it to me.
Show it to me!
You're a pig.
Clean yourself up.
Can you hear me?
- No...
- No?!
Just you wait you fucking shithead.
Close the tap.
Holy Jesus! It's Mrs. Sukova.
I mistook her for a patient.
Look at them now,
Anyone who eats sweets,
won't have dinner.
- Eat.
You've already been punished.
Let's go, hurry up.
Come on, quick, quick.
One, two, get down, one two!
Run, run, properly! One, two!
Hit the ground with your foot,
one, two...
- Please, can you talk to Viktor?
He said he'd call somewhere
to transfer me from here...
- Look, I was in a big mess because
of you, try to talk to Volfova,
she decides about it now.
Not Viky, he is only a waiter.
- What I am supposed to do
if I can't write or call anyone.
- You should be glad that we got you
from Hradec, do you understand?
If cops brought you here, you'd be
locked in a cage for a month, right?
Don't you know where
you're supposed to be?
What you're supposed to be doing?
- So here you have those two girls,
Ms. Krocova.
You think that you
can do as you wish?
I keep my eye on you.
Let me go!
She has a seizure !
I'd like to see what you've
injected her with.
We couldn't find it.
She made such a mess here.
- How long has she been tied up.
It's four hours since she
had the seizure.
- What is this from?
-Can't you recognize a bruise?
- Farova is one of the worst
behaved patients here.
And we need to get through it.
You know it doctor.
- It is stated in the Social Act that,
every occurrence of physical
force must be noted down.
It must be contained in the patient's
personal file! Did you do it?!
- These things, it's always our fault!
Why don't you take her home!
They're not our children!
If you ever have to deal with them,
You'll see what it's like.
- Where are you going?
Are you going to
leave her like this?
She needs to move now.
Who is this?
It's me, Marika.
Please. Please, come,
I can't take it anymore.
I really don't know what
to do anymore. Please.
- Tomorrow evening.
- Tomorrow evening? - Yes.
- I will be waiting.
I'll show you something.
- Go on.
I'll do it prettily.
How do I look?
Very delicate.
Hide it among your things.
I'll hide it.
Bye.
- Bye.
I just... a little, little bit...
Show it to me.
Show me, don't be afraid.
Pretty.
Who taught you this?
- I found it. I just... I found it.
- Now you need to be locked up...
Won't you tell me?
It is mine!
It's my make up!
Hello!
Wait.
Is Zdena here? - No.
- That's good. Very good.
You called, so I am here.
- What are you looking for?
I look like a pig.
Wait a moment,
I need to wash this off.
So what's up.
- Aren't you afraid of them?
- Afraid of whom? Those here?
You think I am afraid of them?
That's a good joke.
- Wait.
I only trust you.
I want to give you a note,
a very important one, read it.
- You have such sad eyes.
What are my eyes like?
- Like water.
- Water?
- Were you surprised when I came today?
- No.
I believed you when you said
that you will come.
- You believed me.
You're a golden girl.
You're so beautiful.
If you were older...
Someone's here!
Our Farova has a young man here.
Let's admire her.
- Good evening.
- What are you doing here?
Do you have something to do, here?
Is that what you really like Viktor?
Marika is one of the most severely
ill girls in this institution.
- That's not true, not true!
Don't believe her. She is a moron.
It's her! She is not normal!
- Wait.
- I came to see Zdena.
- Zdena is not here.
She had a morning duty.
- Come Viktor.  I will see you
out to the front door.
- So... bye!
That Marika, it wasn't her fault...
I got in by the window.
It is my own trick, you see.
- Well, you know...
- I guess it's difficult to recognize
if someone is a nut-case. Or not.
For example they call me
a loon since my childhood.
- What did she talk about with you?
She must've said plenty of nonsense.
- Who? That girl?
- She said some stuff,
like she does not like it here, etc.
One cannot trust everything...
Right?
- Did she ask you for any favors?
- No...
Well, to take a note to her family.
- Do you have it?
- No, she didn't give it to me.
Where is that note.
- Hands.
It's mine! No, no!
I always new that she's dangerous.
Come.
What is this bruise?
You need to be strong.
The evil gets punished in the end.
Always.
You need to trust your gut.
You need to believe in yourself.
And you have to know that
there is a higher power
that can see us at all times.
- What are you doing here?
Don't you know?
It's forbidden to be near her
without the doctor's permission.
This is a violation of discipline.
Get lost! Quickly.
I am telling you to stop.
I've seen many things here
but now, I've had enough.
You know that.
You will have an opportunity
to say what you want.
- Farova doesn't belong here.
You should be praying that
this girl never starts talking...
What kind of staff do you have.
Without qualifications!
Tht's why the mortality rate is so
high! And you're responsible!
- Enough!
- I'll demand Marika's adoption.
You know well that Marika never has
been stripped of her legal rights.
And I will make a complaint about you.
- Very well Ms. Sukova.
You're still here?
- Where are Farova's papers?
- I don't know.
But here is a letter.
-What letter?
- From the district methodical center,
that if we want to transfer her to
a normal children's home in Hradec,
we have to write some expert opinion.
Do you know her?
Is it a difficult case?
- Quite. Show me.
I will take care of this.
And where are you going, Mirek?
Oh... To Madrid. Imagine...
To the conference about institutions
for disabled/handicapped youths.
I will even hold a speech there.
That is something, right?
Social institute in Sanci here,
how can I help you?
Yes, yes.
- What is going on?
What is happening?
- I don't know!
- Quickly. Quickly! Hurry up,
make sure everything is in order...
Hide all the...
Oh this is here...
Good Afternoon.
- Ms Sukova. Is she here?
- Yes, it's me.
- Security police.
Please come with us.
Next.
What do we do here?
What is this!
Let's go, quickly!
Quiet. It's better if we go.
Marika, do you hear me!?
Open up!
It's good that nothing has
happened yet! But hurry up!
Marika, listen,
open the door so we can talk,
you don't need to be afraid,
Open up nicely and
then we will see, yes?
We will go away, yes?
Marika? yes?
Open the door and
you'll go to bed.
Open up by yourself, yes?
We'll be far away.
Where are you?
- I am here!
I am here, you heard me!
And the girls are here as well!
Come here, come here!
Vera, Vera!
Wait here! Stand here
and don't do anything!
Come quickly!
- What is happening!
You need to get out of here
or you'll die. Understand?!
Come on, come on!
Looks like it's everyone here!
- Wait! Not everyone!
There's still someone upstairs!
We need to wait for everyone!
Johanha, dear, please.
Stay here and don't go anywhere.
Understand? Stay here, yes?
Be careful!
Why don't you go there?
So why did you come here?
There's still people there.
- Can't you see the bars in the window?
- The keys are in the cupboard!
It is possible to get there!
- Go then if you're an idiot!
Don't go there! Come down!
Don't risk your life for these morons.
They won't get better anyway.
There are various kinds of them
upstairs, aren't there.
- What did you say?
You idiot, they're screaming!
Can't you hear!?
Do you hear me?!
Let's go upstairs!
Let's go!
During the fire of the institute
in 1984, 26 patients died.
In the judicial report teachers
Volfova and Prochazkova were
sentenced to 1 year in prison
as punishment for their abusive
handling of patients.
Teacher Krocova was given 9 months,
with the conditional suspension.
Marika Farova was convicted of
arson and imprisoned
for 5 years without parole.
Starring: