The Slovak Film Institute
presents
WOLVES' LAIRS
Story:
Script:
Music:
Conducted by:
Sound:
Editor:
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Role:
Production manager:
Director:
Made by the Slovak Film Production
The film includes footage from
the Slovak National Uprising
and the triumphant advance
of Soviet troops.
Janko, Hanko, find me!
Go!
Attention!
Forward march!
- Can you read?
- Yes, I can.
Come along!
FIGHT FOR FREEDOM!
What's the news again?
Read it!
- Good morning.
- Good morning Mr. Teacher.
Who started the war?
The Germans.
Who makes you a beggar?
Who's your enemy?
The Germans.
Impudence!
Who posted it up here?
Who saw him?
Me.
Fools. You're driving the whole
village to disaster.
I won't protect you from the Germans.
Who would you be able to protect!
He's right!
They shouldn't do things like that.
Dad, come home quickly,
Samko was beaten up by Germans.
What?
Partisans are behind the village!
DEATH TO FASCISM!
Down!
You have to leave this region
by tomorrow.
You didn't bring anything,
You won't take away anything.
I don't understand.
It's nothing.
Someday you'll understand.
I'm here. Ondrej!
Bless you mom.
I'm hungry as a wolf.
Just a moment.
I was writing to Matus.
Put it away. The food is right here.
Stem!
Where are you going?
Show me some ID!
Yes, I'm...
Let's have a look! Matus Svrcina.
How was it in Germany?
So.
And what now?
I go home.
I couldn't stand it any longer.
And a permission from the German
authorities?
Ok. I've already seen it.
Well, go! We'll see each other later.
Good night.
Good guy-
Just a bit miserable.
Don't go home, wait for me
at the chapel.
You cannot stay here.
Partisans chased Hitlerjugend
out of the district yesterday.
The Germans are furious.
Moreover, your age group is the next
to join the army.
I doubt you want to
fight for Germans.
No, indeed, I do not.
What shall I do then?
Your brother is a lumberjack
in Pusta Valley.
Hide there.
Yeah.
I just want to see my home.
Take a quick look and then off
to the mountains.
It won't disappoint you.
Our teacher has also something
to do with partisans.
It is said, this artful tinker visits
him very often.
Mr. Teacher is clever,
he won't do anything stupid...
And the tinker Joiko?
Why should such a goodie-goodie
meddle in things like this?
He's a chatter-box!
My Son!
How did you get here?
I wrote you just yesterday.
You look pitiful...
Welcome brother!
Thanks.
I thought you were on the Russian front.
I was.
But I got wounded so they
sent me home.
Now Jane is there.
We haven't heard about him for
more than a year.
Well, take a seat.
I'll give you something to eat.
And Stefan?
He's studying. He should come tomorrow
for a vacation.
And you, how have you been?
I escaped.
Escaped?
I couldn't stay with the Germans.
Nobody means anything to them.
You cannot imagine what sort of slaves
they would like to make of us.
Hey slackers, papers. Where are you
coming from and who are you?
Stefan Svrcina, student of philosophy.
Eva Lieskovska, student of medicine.
The daughter of the local teacher?
Yes.
And you, where are your papers?
Look. calluses.
Where are you coming from?
- From Bratislava.
- For a holiday.
You'll have an exciting holiday.
- When does it start?
- We are just waiting for you.
Wipe that smile off your face,
we can even be useful for you.
For example?
For example... you can get ill and...
Excellent! You'll bandage me up,
when a German bullet makes
a hole in me, Miss. Medico!
Almost a medico. But I know
how to work with bandages.
So, see you in the field hospital!
Bye!
- Bye!
What did you read about?
That Germans were able to get free
of the enemy.
Russians knocked the spots off
them again.
- Where are the Russians?
- They allegedly taking over Kiev.
If they press forward like this,
they'll be here at any moment.
I wish they were already here.
I wish you didn't regret it.
If you knew the front and katyushas,
you'd be feel differently
about the Russians.
It's true. We like it that way.
What would happen if the Germans won.
Did you ever think of that?
Don't you know that the German
respects only the German.
My friend had a terrible accident
in the dock-yard.
He died immediately.
You know what the supervisor said?
At least we'll have one less
Slavic dog.
And our companions fight for this nation.
Don't worry, you'll also go,
if they call you.
I'm not arguing.
But if I get a gun, I'll know,
where to go with it.
Perhaps to join the partisans.
Guys, put out the fire!
It might rush us into danger.
Water, Ondro!
Step on it!
Jump on it!
- It was German.
- It was Russian.
They drop it for partisans.
Let's go!
Watch out in the valley!
- Do you belong to us?
- Yes.
My name is Matus.
I'm Nikita.
Would you be so kind to bring me
some water.
I would.
I'll also bring you something to eat.
It's not necessary.
But come back alone.
Do you understand?
Don't be afraid, Nikita!
Greetings to you!
- What's the matter with you? Are you ok?
- The leg is ok.
Who are you?
The woodman, from the valley.
This is Matus, my friend!
I would perish without him.
They threw it down by mistake
over your fire.
The next time you hear a plane,
put out the fire.
- Do you understand?
- I do!
Thanks. you helped him.
- What's your name?
- Matus Svrcina.
Why did you escape from Germany?
It's none of your business?
How do you know I was in Germany?
It's none of your business!
It's all about something else.
We've got wounded people.
we need bandages and plaster.
- Do you understand?
- I do.
It is necessary to go to the village
and to send
a reliable woman with this to the teacher.
He already knows what to do.
A rucksack with bandages and other stuff
only a women could carry,
a guy would be conspicuous.
But I cannot leave my work.
You can leave at night and return
early in the morning.
You'll do it, you belong to us after all!
I'm Marian.
We'll see each other later.
'En
Who?
It's nice you came.
I've already heard you were at home.
Don't worry I didn't come for your sake.
We just need your help.
We've got wounded companions,
partisans.
You get up early, go for
the teacher and give this to him.
It is necessary to take a backpack
with bandages and other stuff up.
A man would be conspicuous.
I'll wait for you under the glade.
Be careful and not a word to anyone!
So, I...
Go to bed, I'll go.
Did I offend somehow,
that now you talk to me like that?
Do you know where Matus is?
He went down to the glade.
Probably to the village.
Who the devil would drag him
to the village for the night?
Most likely a she devil.
Does he already have one?
Old love never rusts!
Maybe he was pining for his mum.
Or for Anna.
Hope he didn't go there in vain.
Stop with this... saw!
You're a disgrace!
You're worse than a woman!
- Good morning!
- Tastes differ.
Didn't you sleep well?
Of course. I did. it's better to sleep
in the chalet... than in a room.
Of course, it's better.
Wait! Where were you?
In the village.
What the hell were you doing
in the village at night?
Are you a priest asking me
to make confession?
- Where were you?
- What is it to you?!
You!
Have you gone out of your mind?
Greet the boys and hurry up.
It's ok, it's well positioned.
Your Anca is bringing medicine
for partisans.
I'll go and meet her.
Tell it to Ondrej,
so he's not out of his mind about it.
Can't you tell him by yourself?
No, he can't control himself.
Watch out in the valley!
Don't release it!
It can kill me!
Ondrej, the timber is approaching!
What's up?
My leg!
Go away, it'll kill you also!
Leave me alone! You fool!
I'll be crippled for the rest of my life.
He should have let me been killed.
It's not like that! He saved your life.
What shall I do with such life,
I'll be a burden to everyone.
Don't worry, I'll...
And how about my brother?
He sends his best regards to you.
He asked you to forgive him
and that he'll never come home again.
He's lost his mind.
He's taking up with partisans.
Ready, you can start!
You have to hold it strong!
This way!
Shoot. the whole cartridge.
He's pierced like a...
I wouldn't like to be your target.
He's a devil. not a man!
Look, commander what did this
greenhorn do!
You've got good eyes.
- Weren't you a poacher?
- Me not, but my father was.
He was a woodsman, but he strayed
to hunting grounds that were off-limits.
Like all the guys.
Once he came home riddled with bullets
just like this board.
Commander Marian!
Liaison from Bystrica!
'MW.
How are things going?
German traders are loading wagons
in Malobrod.
150 head of cattle.
The train departs tonight.
In Lukotin there is platoon of infantrymen.
They going to start ridding the mountains
of partisans in the morning.
That's all.
You take twelve companions.
These cattle must not leave.
Neither these traders.
Yes, Commander!
I myself will go against those foot soldiers.
Commander, I'd like to go with you.
You can.
Well, let's go guys!
Just like we agreed.
Stay within sight, is it clear?
- Yes it is.
- We do understand.
Let's go!
Mr. General, do you have a match?
Here you are.
You almost smoked you fingers.
Here you are one Russian.
Thank you.
Stop guys!
I'm partisan Marian.
They sent you to fight against us
because we want ones just like you:
to chase Germans out of our country
and to help truth and law win out.
I didn't come with a gun in my hand.
So, you've got only two possibilities:
either to go back or to join us.
If you come as a friend, we'll be friends,
but if you've come as an enemy,
we'll be enemies.
In this region all the trees
are shooting at us.
So. what guys?
Where are we going boys?
To the mountains!
We all felt that the Germans lost
on the very day that they attacked Russia.
Ok, you all felt it, but kept silent.
Now you are here,
so don't argue all the time.
It's not a quarrel.
It's a political discussion.
Thank you.
- Good afternoon.
Today you won't avoid us.
Here you are, run for home.
Ondrej has returned.
His wound has perfectly healed.
He'll get an artificial limb and he’ll probably
be able to walk like before.
Come, he'll be glad.
I'd rather not, I'm afraid.
You know how he behaved
to me in the hospital.
If you had known
how eager he was to see you.
One who loses his reputation,
he loses sympathy too.
I just lost a part of my leg
and so many people forgot me.
Look, who came to see you.
Stefan, come in the room!
- We haven't seen each other for ages.
- it's true.
A lot has changed.
You're only imagining things.
I'm not. I saw it.
I thought you greeted
me differently.
Wait!
Do you swear to tell the truth?
Did something happen between you
and Matus?
You know we were in love and
he went to Germany just because of you.
I'll come back when you are more rested.
Stem!
What are you carrying?
Check the registration number!
- Matus, what are you carrying?
- Eggs.
You'll need them.
Today a German general and his escort
was shot by our people.
- It will be chaos...
- I've already heard it.
Hey man. answer respectfully!
What's up there?
I asked him what he's carrying and he...
that eggs.
And moreover he laughs like a hyena.
Oh...
'ml Mm
Where are you coming from?
They sent us to the Italian front,
meanwhile I jumped out to have some water
and the train had already left.
I thought I'd pop home.
Aha. what are you carrying.
All right! Drive on!
So. what are they carrying?
Don't be angry but they're really
carrying grenades.
Janko, stay until tomorrow at least.
Here you are, eat!
Could you pack me something,
I'll eat it on the road.
My children, don't leave me.
How can I get you back together again?
He has to go!
As long as he' not in the army,
he is in a safe place here.
What kind of safety is it,
if they give him a weapon?
He won't shoot at himself.
I know, at the enemy.
And is this good?
Does the enemy's mother
love her son any less?
Each mother is worried about
her children.
I saw in Russia how children were
killed in front of their moms.
Only tit for tat helps!
What's your perspective if
you want to knock the eye out
of an enemy forty times more powerful?
Don't worry!
You know how David defeated Goliath?
He slung a rock into his forehead.
From a long distance!
That's what we are also going to do.
One by one. That's why we're partisans!
They'll crush you like ash!
Would you like to fight against tanks
with machine guns?
You've all gone mad!
What is it all for?
What's the use of the war for us?
Who did you hurt?
Absolutely nobody.
You don't know what would happen,
if the Germans won.
They'll surely run away from you!
So, goodbye mum!
We'll be back in few days.
I know, you are with us but
not in front of mom.
Svrcinas always know where they
belong.
Mrs. Forester!
Jane has come.
Well, I'm going-
I just wanted to see Jano.
For the homeland!
Nothing for me?
And it's already here.
You've already finished playing
the partisans.
The leader has invited German troops
to protect the inhabitants.
Just wait, they will give you
national committees!
They'll give you “Death to fascism...
They'll set you straight.
They're eating us out even more.
Shut up!
I forbid it!
I'm not only your father,
but also the commissar of this village.
We're finished with partisans from now!
Partisan, German, partisan,
German, partisan,
German...
You cannot be German.
You're too small to fight.
Go to the partisans.
Partisans, on my side
Germans beyond the road!
You see my father.
He doesn't allow me to tune in
any music.
I've got a headache
from this strumming.
It's a very serious time, my son,
we guys take it differently.
Clear. everything is clear.
A step to Berlin, from Vienna
to Hungary two steps,
The Russians will be here in a month.
Don't tamper with this radio!
I haven't been able to tune in Bratislava
since morning.
It's a very serious time, my son.
It may be a serious time,
but we can handle it.
Dad. just a little music.
Here you are!
- Were you also stung?
- Right in my face!
For this, as of today, the power
in Slovakia is assumed by
the Slovak National Council and
it's subordinated organs.
Children come here, it's already here!
Revolution!
For we ask soldiers and
Fighting-competent men
to report for duty at
the nearest barracks.
We request officers, gendarmes and
the treasury guard
to rise up and protect
the country.
Citizens and soldiers,
stop the progress of the army
of occupation from Germany!
Fight hard and wisely
against the invaders,
keep strict discipline
and obey you commanders,
who lead you against the Germans.
Slovaks, go to war
against the occupants and fascism!
Be ready to fight for a better future!
Fight for the right of workers,
farmers and all of working people,
fight against domestic conspiracy,
which plunged the Slovak nation
into war against fraternal Russia
and other Slavic nations.
Long live our just cause,
long live the Czechoslovak Republic!
Death to the German occupants!
MOBILIZATION ORDER
Now we have to act.
Yes, Stefan.
Look!
Good-bye!
Goodbye Dad!
If you need to, then go,
but I'm not sending you.
If everyone goes...
And then we'll be together forever.
Yes. my dear, my only one.
Stefan, come on,
they're waiting for us!
Good bye, Evicka and Mr. Teacher!
- Good bye Stefan, and be careful!
- Good bye!
Not goodbye. but so long!
I also was a soldier and I returned.
Goodbye!
Make a report on the situation after the
artillery support!
Yes, I'll connect.
I'll tell you Mr. Doctor,
two wars in one human life are
too much.
The Fuhrer says something else.
Well, sleep now.
I'm surprised how humanly
you treat them
after all that you've been through.
The doctor doesn't differentiate
between nations and race.
He doesn't have to cure only body
deformations,
but also the distortion of minds
and hearts.
With fanatics like they are
we'll still have much to do.
I don't understand. What did he say?
The southern part of the front was
invaded by German forces
two kilometers deep.
The enemy wasn't successful in breaking
through the front in other sectors
because of strong resistance from our
positions.
More information in the
morning news.
Death to the German occupants!
What's going to happen to us?
We've got to hold out until
The Russians arrive.
Where is the front?
All around us.
The Germans are surrounding us.
Somehow like this...
is our belligerent territory.
It's like we're in a trap.
I predicted that it would be a lost war.
While we have bastions like Telgert,
Svaty Kriz, Tisovec,
we shouldn't be discouraged.
But where will we be
when the Germans come?
You don't have to run away,
you won't be hurt.
My son also fights against
the Germans.
Give thanks to God he went to save
your name and reputation!
Germans are superior in number,
but we don't have to be scared shitless.
In the end we will win, even though...
Tisovec has fallen!
Get out of the way with this instrument!
Our guys will be here at any moment.
It's the same for me.
Hitler can lick my...
Jesus Christ!
- Good Lord, where will we put them?
- Don't worry nurse.
It is the last transport.
Serious cases.
I asked about this Svrcina.
Nobody knows him.
And those 15 Czech gendarmes who
came to the front the day before yesterday,
they were all killed.
Yes, it's me.
They got me.
They've riddled my belly with bullets.
Repay them with interest
once you recover.
Not until tomorrow and
tomorrow they'll already be here.
They plowed into us with tanks
against machine guns
Don't speak, you'll hurt yourself.
Not any more, Miss. Medico.
We'll examine you in a moment.
I'll bring you a painkiller.
We sort out easier cases.
they'll go to Headquarters.
Those who are able to walk,
leave on foot.
They all have to be gone
by tomorrow.
If you want to go home then go.
Tomorrow will be too late.
- And you, Sir lieutenant colonel?
- I'm a doctor.
I also want to be a doctor.
Don't be angry, I thought...
I forgot you should leave first.
Excuse me, I'm also a doctor at first,
and then...
You should leave.
You know, what the Germans are like.
You need to know all sorts of things
to understand,
I don't have anything to lose.
The last time I saw my mom, was when
she was taken to the gas chamber
through the yard.
And once the man gets there...
it's all over in two minutes.
We call Daffodil!
Halloo, Daffodil!
Halloo! Daffodil?
I cannot hear you, speak louder!
Halloo, who's speaking? Svrcina?
Is that you, Jano? What's up?
The whole unit was disabled...
Halloo. Jano!
What's going on?
It was my brother! I've got to
get him out of there!
Marian greets you.
- Good evening Sir.
- Good evening.
Please do something for
my friend.
He's probably got pneumonia.
Maybe something worse.
You are allegedly a friend of ours.
Calm down, we are going to take
care of him.
Thanks.
Save their young lives
and keep danger away from them.
God Almighty, take care of my children
and protect them from Evil.
Home...
Sieg heil!
Lieutenant Colonel Bukovsky
reporting on the condition of the hospital.
Three doctors,
six nurses...
All of them are partisans?
Soldiers.
I understand.
Check the personnel!
- Good care?
- Thanks, quite good.
But Franzl there in the corner
told me...
Put on your clothes!
You're being arrested!
Stand up!
Hell!
Jew. As usual?
Of course!
The Gestapo will come,
and they'll ask you who was a member of
the national committee,
who had his son in the army
or with partisans.
Please, don't let anything slip.
It would be better to tear out your tongue
than to betray.
I didn't send my son against them
it was your government!
And where is he now?
My only son, my good...
The Lord gives and the Lord takes away.
Others were killed too.
It's up to you now to prevent
there being any more victims.
You belong to them, you'll be asked
eventually.
The rest of us we know,
what our is duty.
To push on and help those
in the mountains.
Wait, don't smoke. It'll stunt your growth.
I don't understand.
Why don't they answer?
Call Kiev once again!
Kiev has not answered for three days.
- Nothing?
- Nothing.
Are you crazy? The man can't even
warm himself?
You'll get warm soon enough just wait.
Put out the fire!
While we're waiting for other orders,
we'll pitch a camp in Jastrabie.
We'll stay in a lumber camp.
The entrance to the valley is narrow.
If I'm not mistaken, there is also
an antitank barricade.
There is.
- Do you know it?
- Od course.
It's 5 km across the hills to
our village.
Even better. Just to be
ready against Germans.
Two will guard the entrance of the
valley of the WOLVES' LAIRS.
Who volunteers?
Me.
Me too.
Good.
You'll get ammunition.
the rest is up to you.
Get ready!
We'll have a lot of work to do.
The password is: Wolves' Lairs.
Where are you going?
OK, 909 go" '
Is everything ok?
I succeeded in passing over.
There were only two down.
Happy-go-lucky!
What? With partisans?
Well. all right.
Shoot twenty civil citizens!
Yes!
Boys, look!
A telephone!
Let's find the other one and
we can call each other.
Kn“
But let's first swear an oath
that we won't tell anyone.
Welcome!
How about in our village?
Nothing, Germans sometimes
appear in the village.
Mom is more satisfied since
she found out your brothers are alive.
A bread...
Ondrej is moody as always
and Anca is sending you a... sausage.
I hope you share it with me?
Be careful, don't let it run dry.
You have.
I know you have.
So, have you already had
German visitors?
No. Germans didn't like
the Wolves' Lairs very much.
Look what Marian sent me for them.
Show me!
I'll shoot the cigarette
from your mouth at 100 paces.
Nice...
Come here!
Help for partisans!
- Damn thing! They're only children.
- Nice kids!
- Stop!
- Have you gone mad?
Matus, I swear to God
they are coming!
You always wanted to have skis,
now you can immediately have four pairs.
Tell me when I have to shoot.
Not with a machine gun,
don't waste the ammunition.
Senseless rattle.
Take a riffle!
None of them could return,
he could remember the place.
What are you looking for here, gents?
Who called you here?
The Rulers of Europe,
who shoot at children!
I never thought I could shoot at
an unsuspecting man,
but at you, yes, for you don't respect
anyone or anything.
I'll take those two on the right.
Me the rest.
- Mud
-31
Whistle!
When they stop, shoot!
You see, how they were stunned.
Let's go!
Bungler! Shoot with this one!
Wait until he comes down.
He runs like a scared puppy.
So, hold your breath...
Right. it's for those kids.
Poor Janko and Stefan they probably
haven't eaten anything warm for a long time.
Stop whining.
If it was my fault they're,
not at home.
Who is coming over here again?
- For the homeland!
- Good afternoon.
All right, I'll stay here.
They would like to stay overnight here.
.0.I...
Well. guest in house, God in house.
Would you make me some warm tea?
We don't have tea. but I'll heat up
some chicken soup if you want.
That'll be fine.
Invalid?
- The Russian front?
- Yes.
Very good.
Her sons'?
- Yes please.
- Where are they?
One is at home, the others,
I've no idea.
Ok.
As you know. four of us were killed.
I could give an order to kill the
whole village, but I won't do it.
I want to have the guilty ones.
You've told us how many men
are missing in the village,
you should also tell us where
they are in hiding
I don't know it.
I'm sorry, but you must remember.
- Come back in half an hour.
- Yes, Sir!
Nice guys.
Tell your sons they can
come home.
We won't do anything to them.
Mr. Officer, they're only children,
who could hurt them?
Sure, nothing will happen to them.
Ok, I'll come back again
tomorrow around lunchtime.
Maybe not all Germans are
the same.
I can't even imagine they could
kill children.
You'd better not mention it to anybody.
Three kids haven't been found yet.
They could just be wandering
around somewhere.
It just came to my mind.
He said he would bring my sons home.
Good man.
- What's his name?
- Herman Thiele.
He can go.
He didn't see or hear anything.
It's not true... I...
it's they're...violators!
Murderers!
Is there anybody called Svrcina here?
His mom is waiting for him.
So none?
It's a pity, he could have gone home.
It's me... I'm Svrcina.
You can go.
Go!
Attention!
Come here!
I know him, he is a deaf-mute.
He is an idiot.
Idiot?
He can hear!
Stem!
Damned guy! Stop!
Put down this box!
So. It was him...
Well, this will have implications.
Look!
Go!
That's enough! Let's go on!
Don't cry, I also have such
little a boy at home.
- Let's have a look!
- Aha, a joyful widow.
Are you afraid?
I'm not afraid but you're German and
my father has to hide!
I'm not a German. If I were,
you wouldn't understand me.
So why are you friends with them?
Germans are bad!
Very good. It tastes very good.
Everything's all right.
Here's your son as I promised you.
My son...
Go, go...
Can I have some more.
You don't even cry
and it was your son.
My God! Father!
Our Father who art in heaven...
Be quite! Stand up!
My father!
My goodness, don't kill him!
You can't kill him! Let me go!
Tell my daughter
that her father died like a Man.
- Long live liberty!
Yes, it's terrible that I'm not able to
snipe at the Germans
and then watch restfully how,
they hang old people and beat women.
Those, who know how to do it are Men
and Heroes. I can't do it.
But I'm sure that they have on
their conscience the death of our Jano,
Stefan and all of those, who...
What is it?
What happened?
What's with Joiko?
- He' 5 dead.
- Jane and 'Stefan are dead.
- My father is dead.
- The teacher is dead.
Eighteen dead men in the village
and in sheds!
Now go, before it's too late and donVt
show up in this house any more!
Go away!
You rush us into danger!
Think of your mom!
You're talking like a sick man!
If there were no mothers and you,
whom Germans could pour their anger on,
then you would see
how many Germans would die daily!
I have never expected anything
from you!
Don't give me a lecture, just go away!
You are responsible for everything!
No!
God, why do brothers hate each other?
What's going on with you?
Till just recently you were playing and
having fun together.
And suddenly your heart is
full of hate.
My goodness, Germans!
Matus, hide!
No, no!
Go! You are Slavonian.
Allegedly somebody entered the house.
Me.
Let's have a look.
Don't shoot. I'm Polish.
I've got a wife and two kids at home.
Go.
- So, what's up?
- Nothing. Nobody is here.
Matus, my son!
What's the name of the one
who gave the order to kill our men?
Hands UP!
Don't be scared. I won't shoot.
I'm not with the Germans voluntarily.
I had to.
I'll go with you.
- Do you know where Herman Thiele lives?
- I do.
Come!
On this very day they were buried
in a mass-grave.
Poor father... Poor Stefan.
Where does Herman Thiele live?
Allegedly somewhere in a small town.
Why don't people understand that violence
breeds violence and death only death!
Go guys!
Arrest him alive and he'll be
brought to a partisan court.
Nikita, take command and control.
I accept command and control.
You can rely on me.
The Germans will remember it!
Damned boy!
It's my turn now.
- Nothing?
- Nothing.
Then slowly burn his tongue.
Ready!
- To the Partisan Court!
- Let's go!
What is it now? Another killed?
My goodness! Alarm!
They're already coming, the devils!
Let's go!
Don't be afraid, nothing will happen to you.
Mr. Doctor, won't I have a limp?
My spouse wouldn't be able to bear it.
I think she would.
You'll get tea in a moment.
Call headquarters,
Tell them I'm seriously wounded.
- Is it him?
- Yes, but evil herb never dies out.
He's got only frozen legs.
I've got to go to the city
in the afternoon.
Good morning.
- Where are you from?
- From here.
I treat Slovak soldiers.
Something else?
Yes.
Drink.
Man never knows what the future
holds for him in this damned country.
Help!
Come!
Matus has been seriously wounded.
They somehow got into the Wolves' Lairs
together with Joiko.
Those who were with them, all died.
Also Marian and the others in the valley.
Allegedly, there were too many Germans.
My God, I can't leave him
without help.
I'll go for him, I'll take only
the most essential things.
Have you gone mad?
How do you wanna go there?
- I'll go there first.
- You're not going anywhere!
If we need woman nursing,
I'll let you know.
Give me some bandages.
Go and stay at our place and don't say
a word about Matus to mom.
Always have some food ready.
And if possible some alcohol too.
Let's go! Goodbye!
I'm afraid he won't survive it.
That man can bear a lot.
He has five bullets in his body,
then it's not a little thing.
If his temperature goes away,
he’ll be hungry.
I wish Anca could have been here with
this medicine earlier.
None of the Germans will get through!
When I was hallucinating,
I always called for my girlfriend.
A hungry horse dreams of oats.
- He called your name again.
- I can't help it and neither can he.
He doesn't even know if he's alive.
He hasn't opened his eyes for a week.
I know, you can't help that.
It won't take so much time for
you to be able to return.
- What is it now?
- Nothing.
Water. water...
What are you looking for here?
Just calm down,
you'll find out everything.
Anca is our liaison,
supplier, lady help, doctor...
in short, someone for everything.
And Ondrej is also with us.
Look, what a clever partisan he is.
Excuse me, brother.
Now I know what I've got to do.
Matus, happy Resurrection!
Don't forget that the path under us
connects the Hron and Liptov
and the Germans will need it
while retreating.
We blast the bridge in the valley.
Block up the road with rocks, and if
necessary we batter down the whole cliff,
but not even a half German will
get through the Wolves' Lairs.
That was the order from our deceased
Marian, and we'll carry it out!
Guys. come have look!
My word, they are coming.
- A woman is coming with them.
- it's Anca!
She': leading them.
They're leading her.
Are you blind?
- Somebody betrayed her.
- That one in the black uniform.
Give me that machine gun!
- No, you can't.
- You'll hurt yourself.
I just want to see who they are.
We have to get Anca out of there.
Nothing else can help other than to
just aim well.
Clever girl. They thought she'd
lead them behind us,
and she's leading them directly
in front of our rifles.
Steady and aim your
guns at them.
The one behind Anca is mine.
Dico, that black one!
Attention guys!
No, Matus!
Shoot boys!
Tanks went round the mined bridge
and are heading towards the Wolves' Lairs.
You've got to disarm the first tank
and block the road.
Not even a mouse could get
through the Wolves' Lairs!
Come on everyone, open fire!
- Take it to Matus!
- I have to stay with you.
Just go, he'll need you more.
- What do you want here?
- Ondrej sends you ammunition.
Go to hell with that ammunition!
What the hell is Ondrej doing?
Grenades, grenades!
Our Ondrej has stopped them.
Goodbye!
Don't cry mom,
Everything’s gonna be alright!
We're bringing home peace!
Don't cry mom, we've won.
Cast:
Watch more movies for free on
www.FlixTor.to