A man of country woman was hanged.
He didn't fight against anyone.
They killed him for warning,
he stole a few sacks of cement.
She buried him the same
night, the front was coming,
who knows how long
would else they waited.
Before dawn two soldiers
came into the house,
they didn't know what had happened.
They commanded to widow to.. horses to
coach and go with them. Yes, she said,
it's the god sign. She prayed so she would have
strength to fullfill the justice.
Don't be afraid
You'll be alright,
I'm not a german.
I'm an austrian, from Vienna.
What's up?
Aha.
Machine gun! Fourtytwo...
Do you hear it?
Shit.
To the left! Go to the left!
No!
To the left!
Here, to the grass.
Do you understand?
It won't make any noise here.
Where is Znojmo?
Do you understand?
Znojmo.
How many kilometers?
Fourty? Fifty?
Hold..
Are you mad?
Let me do it!
- As soon as you're supposed to shoot, I'll give it to you.
- Give me the gun.
Don't be afraid, I'll give it to you.
- Do you know who you are?
- Lie calmly.
You're swine! Common swine.
And you look like a jew!
What are you staring at?
Go on!
Hold!
He's ill...
Heavy wounded.
Why aren't we moving?
What's up with the horse.
How big is the forest?
Aha.
Wait!
Moment.
One or two?
I should be a countrymen.
I think I would be a good countrymen.
How do you name it in czech?
Ten minutes break!
Good taste!
Thanks!
Go on!
Bells
Bim bam, bim bam...
Hitler is dead!
War is over!
Bim bam.
Gunthere!
War is over.
Do you understand?
All is over.
To the Osterreich.
My mum.
Mama.
My father
brother...
We live here.
My girl
Anna.
The ring is from her.
Are there bandits in the forest?
Ano?
Speak!
Partizans...
Don't worry.
Is someone here?
Here...?
Also not?
Here it has to fit.
It's narrow, I understand.
The chain! Of course!
The chain and the horses
and then hee...
Great!
And now Znojmo.
What city is it for?
We have to go to Znojmo quickly.
We have to go to the first austrian village.
Do you understand?
Are we going well?
Znojmo.
If we see Russians, then quickly away.
It is terrible cold in the siberia.
It's yours.
Good clock, made from gold!
All is gold!
For you
I don't want it!
Everything for you! It's yours!.
Take it!
Don't be ashamed!
Weak.
>Thanks!
Are you sick?
Do you want to drink?
I was riding horses in Prater at ours too.
It was on sunday,
who paid, could ride.
I took with me my mother.
She was afraid, but I rode well.
Like the right postillion.
On the left or on the right?
There or there?
Ok, go on.
I've always been lucky.
Even in the school,
I got of everything.
I shouldn't talk you over.
You didn't.
I wanted to desert myself.
- What's the name of the city?
- Znojmo.
Znojmo...
Do you know I've never been to country?
First in Russia and there...
in Poland.
Where is my gun?
Next to you...
you don't need it now.
Try to sleep.
War is over.
There were ringing bells
and music played somewhere.
From some village.
It's the second or third may today?
Third.
On the third may didn't ended any war...
The thirty years war ended
at 24th may,
Prussia-Austrian war
ended 22nd Juli.
French-Prussia
26th February.
The world war
on 11. 11.at 11.
Where is the gun?
- Fuck the gun.
- I would like to have it by myself.
- Don't you have it in the bag?
- No, I've took only ammo.
Why is she staring at us?
I don't know.
Maybe I've got it in the bag finally.
You didn't give her the watch?
You have to know
that you took my gun.
I don't look for the gun.
Do you think she really doesn't know german?
- Not a word.
- How do you know?
I tried to speak with her.
But she understand a shit.
All russian women are whores.
You can't figure out what...
Have you sleep all time?
What time is it?
Almost four...
Look at the trees and the crust.
We're heading to north.
- Where is my compass?
- Give me at least the bayonet.
Give me it to the hand!
Do you hear?
Don't worry!
Hold!
Get up!
Hold or I'll shoot you.
One, two...
What do you think, swine.
Don't go near her!
Tell her to turn out.
Shit, tell her to raise her hand.
Hands up!
You haven't loaded.
Down! Quickly!
Back up!
She has a bag under chair.
Can you reach it?
Back up!
Where have you put the gun?
Shoot her...
Where have you put the compass
and the bayonet?
Don't let the hands down.
Wait.
Take of your coat.
Will you?
One..
two...
She throw all away.
And she would like the rifle
to throw away too.
Move! The skirt too!
Shoot her, bitch...
Let's loose her. Go!
Why can she go? Are you mad?
Go!
Go home!
Jesus..
Help!
- She's gone.
- Do you think?
I don't see anything.
If she... bitch.
Accomodation prescription
for occupied area excludes
Don's speak! It exerts you.
In the Ukraine and similar
shit holes...
to be under one roof with
local civilians.
The bitch is after us, remember.
She has russian eyes.
She's gone long time ago.
When we'll be out of this forest?
Aren't we go out of it after all?
We'll go.
Be quiet, please!
Hold!
Wait a moment please.
Go home!
Go or I'll shoot you!
Gunthere?
Gunthere! Gunthere!
Please, shoot me!
Don't scream!
She never wanted me to go to forest.
Could she know?
We'll be outside soon.
Quicker! Run!
Hello?
Come here.
Is someone here?
You can take the horses.
And the coach too.
Money and other stuff
is on the couch.
My pal is dead.
Take all.
Thanks.
Brave horses.
You won't kill anyone anymore.
Neither me.
Do you see me?
Mum?
Mummy!
German..
Do you hear?
Don't you understand what am I saying?
Get up!
Get up! Up!
Get up! Get up!
I'll kill you like a dog!
Like a dog!
Go away!
Go away, rascal!
Not there. There!
There is your Osterreich!
What do you want? Go away!
What are you waiting for?
A judgement day?
Don't stare! Go!
Don't cry.
Do you want some more?
It's still here.
War is over.
It's fourth of May.
On the fourth of May there were
Beijing's events,
Bourbon restoration,
decret about working time...
and my brother was born.
For a memory...
Do you understand?
Hans...
It's my name.
Go away, german.
No, german.
Shit.
Geez. Could I erase them?
Could I erase the Hitler and the bitch?
Imagine, they're asleep.
Like there is no big deal.
Is he a SS man?
He cut off everything.
Even buttons.
Geez, they're...
they're here...
Do you believe it's possible?
And we fight.
What's up?
- Go on.
- Careful, bitch.
Please, sirs, I'm innocent.
- Shut up.
- Ruhe!
There was no point in torturing him.
Finally, we are not nazi.
subtitled by Kostej (kg)