Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Filmexport Home Video
Presents
The Long Journey
Story by / Script by
Director of Photography
Music by / Conducted by
Assistant Director / Film Editor
Set Designer / Artistic Advisor
Sound / Make-Up Artist
Cast
Directed by
Produced by
Germany lies before us.
And Germany is Hitler.
The truth.
All we want is the truth is always
being said about Germany.
The truth is getting increased
by creative art of modern political
campaign which unveils new, strong,
beautiful, proud and really happy life.
A life which we can present before
an international public anytime.
Wherever we look constructing is in
process and new order is being built.
The national social justice
is foundation of our state.
The nation which neglects the purity
of its race will perish.
JEWS GET OUT!
Long live national socialism...
Long live Germany...
Doctor Kaufmann!
Miss Kaufmann, assistant surgeon
is expecting you to come.
Just a moment.
- Going for an injection?
- Yes, I am.
Remember the things for room 13.
The 2nd Republic, dear colleague, must
correct many mistakes.
And must accept many requests
presented by a new period.
Professor believes that you'd better
precede the measures
what sooner or later you'd be
ordered to do anyway.
You can still practice medicine
elsewhere,
unless you want to do
another job.
For example some trading,
Miss Kaufmann.
JEWS GET OUT!
- Hanka...
- No, Tonik.
It was a goal! The goal!
It's not true!
The dog crossed my line!
What you mean?
She's tided up!
Miss, that doesn't count.
Because of dog.
You're not right, it's 4:2.
Quiet, Honzik.
Hanka, where have you been?
- You children will be death of me.
- Wait a minute, so come on!
I am definitely leaving.
I'm not waiting for Hitler to bring
his racial laws also here.
And what are you going to do abroad?
I'll finish my studies.
I can be a waiter, a porter. I can sell
newspapers. It's not important.
But I'll be free.
Hana, come with me.
- Zdenek, please...
- Hana, doctor Bures is here.
Please come in, doctor.
What a surprise, welcome.
Come in.
My friend for many years
and our neighbor Zdenek Klein.
Please meet doctor Bures.
What a pity.
And you are not going to leave?
Hanka, please, marry me.
- What's got into you, Tonik?
- You might need someone besides.
Is that the reason to get marry?
- I didn't mean it like that.
I know.
JEWS GET OUT!
I want to look great for the theatre.
- You really like nice things, don't you?
- Yes, I do.
I love getting dressed up.
You know, Tonik, I couldn't say
good-bye to all this.
May I?
This is my grandpa and grandma.
And auntie Amalia.
Uncle Karel and their children.
And this is uncle Adolf.
- Good evening.
- Daddy.
Mummy told me
that you've already come, doctor.
My dear, you know we are not allowed
to come to the theatre since yesterday.
NO ENTRY FOR JEWS
FORARYANS ONLY
STRONG RULES FOR JEWS
IN PROTECTORATE
JEWS NOT WELCOME
NO ENTRY FOR JEWS
JEWS NOTALLOWED IN THE PARK
NO ENTRY FOR JEWS AND DOGS
Jews have also been thrown out
of the state offices.
Jewish lawyers can't practice.
Our Honzik can't go to the sport clubs,
probably not even to school shortly.
Life will be hard for all of us...
I won't wait for my death here.
- And where do you suppose to wait?
Refugees are still being accepted
in Brazil.
The Pick family has left for Canada. One
of our relatives lives in Puerto Rico.
JEWS GET OUT!
What language they speak in Puerto Rico,
children? - Spanish, Mummy.
I'll write to uncle Richard
in the States. He will help.
Uncle Richard in the States,
but I think... - To America!
Don't be upset, Daddy,
but I'm not going.
Hana, it's because of that doctor?
No, Mum, I just belong here, it's my
culture, language, people, everything.
You mean it's not the same for me?
It's not easy to leave. But to stay
will not help to anyone.
And you don't mind the doctor
is a Christian?
For me she is a Jewess!
I've come to say I'm getting marry
and I don't like you talk like that.
You shouldn't have come at all!
Dad will think it over, Tonik.
He is a good man.
Yes. And what are you doing now?
Me?
Well, just be careful, man,
be careful.
They say you have got some cloth
for Jews.
Cloth?
Have I got any cloth?
Show me.
- And you want to buy some?
- Maybe. Maybe, I would buy some.
- You won't like it.
- If I don't like it, I won't buy it.
It's precious stuff.
So, do you like the new cloth?
Will new dress suit well to your
daughter for Chanukah?
The Middle Ages.
Where's Mummy?
Mummy!
They distribute call-up cards again.
Doctor Meixner, Kohn, Walla, Kraus.
- Transport.
- They want to send us to Poland.
- They prepare transports.
- To Terezin.
It's transport.
- You, too, Zdenek?
I wanted to keep it
for the end of the war.
- Hana will come in a minute.
- It's year 1929, Tonik.
There is a music school upstairs.
Sometimes I compete with them.
Today you can, Honzik,
today it's allowed.
My cousin hid it into a toothpaste,
I'd try the same.
They wouldn't check it, would they?
What you mean, professor?
So, children, let's make a toast.
- Wedding turkey will be served after war.
- Let's hope, let's hope it will be.
To safe journey.
- Do you remember, dear...
- Mummy.
Just a minute, Honzik. When Emma
was getting married you remember...
That'll be my parents.
- Hello.
- Hello, Tonik.
Dad has not come, has he?
No, he hasn't.
Listen, wasn't there any house
search at your place?
- What you mean?
- You know, they are after me.
We all have our own worries.
It's Pepa, what a pleasure!
It's nice you have come.
Cheers, Hana!
- Dad has not come?
- Daddy sends his greetings.
You know, he's got a lot of work.
- Shouldn't we already leave?
- To leave...
We've forgotten about cup.
Cup must be.
Stand up, Tonik.
For good luck.
What happened?
Don't you mind working
in a factory because of Hana?
- Of course, I don't.
- You don't...
It's the transport, Hana, isn't it?
- Yes, Mum.
We expected it sooner or later.
They've already taken Plesner as well.
- Your wife doesn't leave?
- No.
The wives of Aryans
don't have to... yet.
Why haven't you shown your wife
to me yet?
Because the German lords have forbidden
to Jews to use the train.
The German lords...
So, you want double-soled shoes
to hide money in. - Thanks, Daddy.
Don't you know anything about Pepa?
...they were condemned
to the death sentence...
Broken china means good luck.
And the sofa what Honzik used, will it
stay here? - Get out!
But we will be back again.
Ruhe! Los!
- What is it?
- Your authorization to Germans.
You provide it of your own accord,
without restraint, it's your free will.
- And you confirm you're mentally fit.
- Was ist denn los da!
Achtung!
Heil Hitler!
Sie lacht.
Verfluchte...
Weiter!
- Are you doctor Kaufmann?
- Yes.
I'd like to talk to you.
- Please, come in.
Who's that man?
He is my husband.
I'm serving in Terezin.
Do you know anything about parents?
Have you any message?
They said to write you everything.
Please, come and sit down.
But I have some more messages
to deliver.
If you wish to send something,
I'll stop by next week.
Yes, please, come again.
Thanks a lot.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Look, Tonik, here is...
It's very dangerous, doctor.
- Well, we'll see.
- Thank you. Thanks a lot.
Please, I don't want my wife knows
about. I'll tell her I'm going home.
They need money.
Tonik, have we already sold
all the jewels?
Only one Grandma's ring remains.
I hope you won't mind to sell it.
Not at all, don't worry.
But I don't understand this. Why does
Daddy need black hair dye?
Black hair dye?
Did you see my family?
- They're sending their greetings.
- How are they?
They are fine.
They only wonder why you need
black hair dye.
They are sending us further.
To Poland.
Transports.
They kill old people straight away.
- Are you sure?
- And do you know who?
- Madler, Brychta.
- And Kohn, Kohn as well.
Do you hear that?
It's here again.
You bastard, let me be.
- Where did you get it?
- You mean the bread? I nipped it.
With kisses H.
Do you see that?
Oh, my dear...
Los!
Weiter gehen!
Weiter!
Nicht umdrehen!
Come in.
- Do come in!
- I'm already here.
You didn't turn, so I knocked
once more.
You must be Mr. Noha.
Cheguered cap, heart of gold.
Tonik has already told me about you.
- Please, take a seat.
- Thank you.
Tonik says he would be lost without you
in a factory.
It was bad in the beginning, but now
he's already making good rejects.
- Barytosis?
- Yes, exactly.
You know, Tonik wasn't in a factory
today.
And someone has brought an important
message from his home town.
Has anything happened to Pepa?
The lads who come here
from Borek told us
that yesterday evening Gestapo
came to the house.
They brought handcuffed Pepa
with them.
They turned the whole house
upside down.
And have left in the night, taking Dad
with them.
One man - back from work.
Weg!
Aport!
Was hast du?
So, ein Saujude
muss doch immer was haben.
Excuse me, please.
Please, is the Kaufmann family
living there?
Ich begresse nicht.
Please, don't you know
the Kaufmann family?
Kaufmanns? I don't know them.
Excuse me, the Kaufmann family?
Do they live here?
eges gojier kopf.
Please, don't you know where
the Kaufmanns live?
Oskar and Hedvika Kaufmann.
Get away!
It's you, Bures...
Explain to Hana that I couldn't.
God knows I couldn't keep them here.
But you seem to have a great
influence here, haven't you?
Well, maybe a little.
You think it was easy to save myself,
my mother and brother?
You say to save.
Quiet!
I know.
The one who has no own experience...
Bondy,
537.
Let me smoke a little.
Where did you get it?
You want me, don't you?
- What are you doing here, Margit?
- I just wanted...
What's that?
- Where did you get it?
- Let her be.
It's mine, I've got it!
- Leave her.
Are you mad?
- A cig here means gallows or Oswiecim!
- Be quiet.
And have a cigarette as well.
Don't be surprised.
I don't want to get into transport.
And where are all those transports
going?
Oswiecim, Majdanek, Treblinky.
I've got to switch off the light.
- What if I...
May I hide somewhere here?
To hide? Here?
Lie down here.
...Oswiecim, Majdanek, Treblinky,
Oswiecim, Majdanek, Treblinky...
Thank God you are here.
- Thank God.
- What's the matter, Hanka?
I was so much afraid.
You know I was...?
- Noha came and told me everything.
- What you mean?
About Pepa, searching the house.
And about your Dad as well.
I was so afraid they'd still be there
waiting for your coming.
No, they all were away when I came.
Do you know he took five people
yesterday?
Including fifteen year old boy
in Löw family.
- Who? Müller?
- Because they had a beer at home.
As if they couldn't have done
without a beer.
If it wasn't a beer, they'd have found
something else.
They took Stastny family
because of newspapers.
Next for an injection!
Bures!
Are you doctor Antonin Bures?
I'm a policeman.
The Czech police.
Why you still keep to blame
yourself, Hana?
Because of me, my parents and Honzik
did not leave.
- Now even Tonik, just because of me...
- You know nothing yet.
Work camps for Aryan husbands
may just be a nonsense.
If Tonik got...
If he got a divorce,
would he have to go?
No, he wouldn't.
But you would be sent to Terezin.
But you know Tonik well.
He won't divorce.
No, you are right.
It's not the way.
It wouldn't work like that.
Sir, may I have few days off?
Of course, Hana.
We'll manage without you.
- Excuse me, doctor!
- Just a moment.
Hello. Yes, she's here.
It's Tonik.
Hello, Tonik.
Where are you calling from?
From a phone booth.
Well, Hanka, listen...
Are you busy now?
There's no one here anymore.
What happened?
Nothing. I just wanted to talk
to you, you know.
You are going straight home,
aren't you?
I don't know.
I would like to be alone for a while.
Hanka... Hanka, hello!
Someone still keeps knocking here.
Hanka, are you on night duty today?
Night duty?
Yes, I am.
- See you, then, Hanka.
- Tonik!
I'm just looking at the balcony
opposite.
There's a child playing there.
Such a lovely child...
Good-bye, Hana.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, Tonik.
Sterbeurkunde: Mauthaussen 1304
Josef Bures
Rudolf Bures 1302
auf der Flucht erschossen.
Hanka...
Hana...
Tonik...
Hanka...
Let's go.
We'll go together.
But I have promised it to Tonik.
I'm telling you, my wife is waiting.
Pack your things and move to our place.
The Germans will not find you there!
Aren't I right?
You'll have a nice room there.
We'll take care of you as Tonik wanted.
Believe me, you'll see.
And how you got known... Who told you
that I am to leave for Terezin?
Tonik has managed it at Jewish office
before they took him away.
No, Mr. Noha, forgive me, but
I'm not going with you.
They all have already gone, even Tonik.
Why should I stay here?
- But, madam, you know...
- And moreover...
You know what would expect you
in the case they would find me.
But what about Tonik?
He wanted you to stay.
No one is alone.
Los!
Weg! Weg!
Weiter! Los!
Komm! Komm!
Geh mal!
Komm, komm! Schnell!
Go to sleep!
Next one!
Excuse me, please.
Here you are, we don't want you
to starve. - Thank you.
I've got a date later, you know.
Shut up!
- Where did you get it?
- This?
Some woman left it here.
She went to the gas chamber.
With kisses H.
Are you mad? Hanka!
Hana!
It's you, Zdenek.
- How long have you been here?
I knew you'd end up here.
Why did he let you go?
I told him not to let you go,
in any case.
Whom did you tell?
I said it to Tonda when he was here.
Tonik was...?
Come with me, Hana.
What are you staring at?
Make off!
What's going on?
I'm waiting if they close the door.
- Did they close?
- No, they didn't.
What are you doing here?
They must be expecting international
inspection.
Hana!
Move to my place.
Do you hear me?
You'll get another work.
Are you mad?
Achtung!
Melde fünfzig Frauen
zur Verschönerung!
Weiter machen!
Weiter!
It's OK!
Yes, OK.
What's this for?
He's asking what is this for.
Why should I know?
And why are you bricking this up?
What?
Why are you bricking up?
He wants to know why are we
bricking this up?
Transport.
What did you say?
Transport with children
from the east has arrived.
Transport?
Take your clothes off.
Get undressed.
It's gas, it's gas, gas!
Stay! Stay here!
Gas!
You're building a gas chamber!
We are building a gas chamber!
Did you hear that?
It's gas!
I knew that, do you hear me?
Do you hear? I knew that!
Ours are back!
No one returns from camp alive.
It's transport with typhoid victims!
Don't go there! The plaque will spread
over the town!
Hana!
- Transport.
- Gas!
- Transport has arrived.
- There are dead people! - Transport?
It's typhoid. Typhoid transport!
- Don't go there!
Freedom!
There are tanks!
Tanks over there!
Mankind has won.
Oswiecim, Majdanek, Treblinky,
Golnov, Ravensbrück, Oranienburg,
Bergen-Belsen, Buchenwald,
Lodz, Terezin,
Gross-Rosen, Mauthausen.
Seven million of people
died in concentration camps
of fascist Germany.
Over 140 thousand of people from
the whole Europe went through Terezin.
And just a few of them
have survived.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org