FILMEXPORT HOME VIDEO
Presents
PETERAND PAVLA
Story and Screenplay
Cast
Also
Music
Played by
Sung by
Set Designer
Assistant Designer
Costumes / Wardrobe
Make-up / Sound Effects
Camera Operator
Assistant Editor
Lighting
Stills
Assistant Production Manager
Continuity
Associate Director
Sound
Editor
Production Manager
Director of Photography
Directed by
Production Unit
Processed by
They played it this morning.
- This morning?
Yes at 5.15 when
we're leaving for work.
It was so nice.
- Come on, play it once more.
They play it when we're asleep
or when we're out...
Where is my comb?
Where did I put it?
Don't come here boss we're changing.
I've seen hundreds of bodies
like yours!
Not like mine!
- He's used to his fancy bit.
She's got a big arse.
- And he's got a big gut!
But that's all I've got left!
Listen, there's a new trainee
starting today, so watch your language
in front of him!
I know your big mouths!
What do you take us for, boss.
Has anyone seen this trainee, girls?
- No. - I wonder what he looks like.
I bet he's just a kid! He's only 16
if he is an apprentice.
Nothing for us then.
Don't worry Peter,
you'll soon learn, don't worry.
We are a self-service store.
I'll tell you exactly how it works.
We have complete faith
in our customers,
we do believe them, in 100%,
you know.
But of course some of them will still
from time to time steal something.
Your job will be to keep an eye
on our customers,
and have your wits about you.
But they can't know
that you are watching.
They mustrt know
you're watching them.
Nothing wrong in that!
You're just preventing
those customers from stealing.
We're simply educating them!
Look Peter, I've never caught anyone
while wearing a white coat...
If the customer sees that coat,
he knows you're part of the collective,
so he's careful... he's careful.
But without the coat
you'd catch one or two magpies.
May I put it here?
- Of course you can, Peter.
Understand, Peter?
So, okay.
- Yes.
Peter, like I said already,
this is not the way to do it.
You're tailing these people
like a cop. You peek in their bags.
They are not going to put anything
they steal on top.
Easy does it and be inconspicuous,
do you understand?
I do.
- So try it once again.
Excuse me, I had a feeling that
the man has just stolen something.
Which one?
- He's outside already.
So run after him, hurry up.
- But I'm not sure that he has...
It doesn't matter, go on.
Where have you been?
- At work.
At work?
- Yes.
I really was at work.
Where?
At the shop, where else...
Do you know your boss?
- Of course.
So what was he doing here,
looking for you?
I guess he doesn't know you then.
Of course he does but something
happened. - What?
I had the feeling one man
stole something.
So I followed him.
I see... You were being a detective.
So you thought he'd stolen something.
So what did you do?
Then I followed him around.
And that was all?
- Yeah.
What was the point of following
him around?
Did you identify him?
Did you see what he took?
No I didn't. And what would you've
done? I just followed him.
What would I've done?
I'd call somebody.
To stop and identify the man.
And search him.
But just to follow him around
that makes no sense!
I tought he'd give himself away.
But how.
Why didn't you get his name?
You can't do that.
- Why not?
I'd call a policeman or someone older
and get his name.
You had the feeling he'd shoplifted.
- Yeah, but I wasrt sure.
Then you should have stayed
in the shop.
I couldn't.
I told about to our women
and they said to follow him.
So I did.
Why didn't you tell your boss?
What's the point to tell some women.
I mean the sales ladies.
- I see.
So what was the final consequence,
the final result?
Nothing.
I just followed him all day.
You followed him.
So you werert at work?
But I was.
- Just for a while.
And what did you do after that?
So tell me. Just answer.
I went home.
Did you? So, you went home.
A bit early!
Werert you supposed to go back?
Why home?
How you dare?
Or do you think everybody can
just up and leave his job
and go home?
There were many things
in my life I didn't like.
But I had to face them,
often against my will.
That's what made a man out of me.
That was that!
Come on, Dad, let it be.
Peter is still a kid.
I'm not some little kid.
Of course not! And you should have
realized that a long time ago!
Here, let me warm it up for you.
- Forget it.
But it's cold.
- It's alright.
It's not!
Warm it up.
If you look around
these shops nowadays,
what do you see?
Nothing but women.
No men...
they're as rare as goldust.
And in the end, what are the women
good for?
They get married
and the workplace is empty.
So who does it all depend on?
Who stayed then?
Men!
Men.
Put up with it for a year or two...
and then you'll be the boss.
You know what that means?
You'll be somebody!
It's just up to you...
to become that boss early!
God forbid
there wont' be another war.
As the saying goes...
Stay near the food
to keep far from the grave.
But don't think about that.
Don't think about that at all.
Look.
On Monday, you'll go back to work
and apologize and everything
will be allright.
Understand?
Do you understand?
When we were twenty
you wanted my love
I was getting married
but you went to the army.
When we were twenty
you wanted my love
I was getting married...
...or if there was a fire at least.
So you could go and put it out.
No, they've got plenty
of firemen already.
Don't look at me.
See, I'd just be saving lives
if the fire was at night.
At night?
We'd haul the women
out of their beds!
Oh, yeah!
- Sure!
Lmagine the flames
licking Pavla.
Lucky flames.
See, now I pushed out
all the air.
All the air pushed out.
But if my chest is up like this...
It's like you expect what a girl
wants to say...
and she's just got her breasts
like this...
How are Pavla's breasts?
I don't know.
Only Mara knows, huh.
I don't know why she's
going out with him.
He thinks he's so cool,
but he's a bad influence on her.
I met them for many times walking
by the river.
They go... she goes...
I'm standing there looking at her
and she doesn't even glance at me.
I get the feeling I am not there.
But you are, you are.
- I know.
You are a virgin.
- Yeah, yeah.
Tell me, oh lovely maiden...
A little higher!
- Why do you laugh?
Not everybody can sing like you.
Do you know that?
It's a parody of Othello.
- Yeah.
Now he leaves... Wait a minute,
then she tells him:
My sweet Othello, I love you so.
Oh, my sweet Othello, I do love you.
I declare my love for you!
- I can't hear you. Louder!
Oh, my sweet Othello,
I love you so.
Now Casio comes in...
- What? Who?
You never saw it?
- No, did you?
I did.
Wait, so he says:
Good evening, my lovely lady,
sorry to disturb you.
Othello is to report
to court immediately...
Othello is to come immediately...
cause two guards are fighting
over their posts.
And he says goodbye to her and leaves.
Now Casio is alone with her...
and he says... I can't remember
what he says, though.
Listen.
- What?
That isn't a very good song.
- Wait a little. How does it go?
Peter!
Is Peter here?
Is he not here?
Peter! Seems he is not here.
And it goes on.
Your husband, my lady,
is a great hero,
and he loves you faithfully...
What are you looking at?
I'm not looking, I'm thinking.
- About what?
I can't tell you.
- Why not?
You'd think
I had a dirty mind.
I already know that!
- What?
Not really.
What are you thinking about?
I really can't say.
I know it anyway.
- So say it.
I can't.
- Come on, say it.
Actually, there's nothing dirty
about that, you know.
Some girls wear swimsuits
even tinier than mine.
And some little girls
walk around totally naked.
True, but only the little ones.
- Yeah.
I really hate the girls
who show-off and then...
Come on, row! Go ahead and row!
- I am rowing! - I can't see!
Those girls are in my class.
- What about those guys?
I don't know them.
- Some bums...
Get lost!
This is not a show.
Her hair was all locks
and curls...
No! That's wrong.
Her hair was all she ever thought about.
- Stop, I beg you!
Don't' beg me.
- It's like this...
Her hair was all locks
and curls...
When she stood by...
But sing it all.
...by a window...
Her hair was all locks
and curls...
She didn't think about anything else.
So, do sing.
What are you looking at?
- The grass.
Why the grass?
- Green colour soothes the eyes.
That's why the cows are so calm?
Sorry... I didn't mean it that way.
- You bull.
Look, those boys are staring at us.
- So let them.
If I were them, I'd never run around
in my boxers.
You can't help the way you look.
Could you go out with them?
Not really...
- Why?
They're kind of weird.
That's what I think too.
And anyway, I don't know them.
Do you know me?
- They're coming over here.
Just let them.
So do you know me?
Look, they're coming
and still staring.
It doesn't matter.
So do you know me?
Well, yeah, I do.
What are you doing tonight?
- I don't know yet.
I would go out.
Would you go with me?
Hey you, get up!
- Didrt you hear?
Get up!
- Why?
I said get up!
- Why? I don't want to.
But we want to!
- Do you want a bloody nose!
Do you want a bloody nose!
- Why?
- Why? What's your problem?
What you mean?
- What the hell were you
staring at us before. Like idiots.
Just take a look at yourselves,
guys. You're white as babies!
What the hell you mean?
That's normal! We're bricklayers.
- All bricklayers look like this.
I knew you were bricklayers,
but the girls don't care
for creamy legs.
- Watch you don't have creamy face!
I still think you look like bums.
Bums can hit back hard.
You're not going to hit a girl,
are you?
Don't be so sure!
I don't believe it. I saw you
with your girlfriends earlier.
Those werert our girlfriends.
We don't give a damn about them!
I didn't do it on purpose, honest.
I was just about
to put one on him.
Believe me, please.
- Screw you!
So what we were talking about?
I don't remember.
How come?
I just don't.
- So will you come out tonight?
She's sitting there, staring.
Watch this!
Are you watching me?
Are you?
Hello.
Hello!
Where are you looking?
I told you to look at me.
Why don't you look at me?
- What's up?
I said, look at me!
- Where are you going?
Can I, please?
Thank you, thank you.
Thank you, thank you very much.
Hey, did you see it?
- Yeah, I saw it.
Good, eh?
Hello! Hello!
Who is it?
- That guy from the beach.
Hello.
- Let's go.
Where are you going?
Over there.
- Where?
Let's dance.
- It's so crowded.
So what. Come on!
- Arert you thirsty?
I'm not.
- I am, I'll get a lemonade.
Hey, you! Wait! I said hello!
I said hello, too.
Yeah, but how. Look, I...
Wait, wait! You stay out of this!
Wait, I'll show you the difference!
- Leave her alone!
HELLO!
You said: 'ello...
Do you hear the difference?
HELLO! 'ello...
What a nut!
- Don't you hear it?
You're crazy.
- Hello.
Stop it. Let's go.
- Do you hear that? Hello!
It has no sence, let's go.
- Hello!
Hello.
Let's go! Please!
Can I have this dance?
But they're not playing.
- They don't.
So I'll come back.
Hello, Pavla.
- Hello.
Shall we dance?
I don't want to dance with you,
Mr. Mara.
What are you doing here then?
- Waiting for a lemonade.
And who's getting it for you?
- I've got to go now.
Hey, you! Come here!
Have you got it now?
What? - Is that clear?
- What you want again?
Is that clear? - Please, take it.
- You wait. Just listen.
Hello.
- Let's go please!
What you want?
- Wait! Hello!
Hello.
- It's not the same. Hello!
- Hello!
Hello!
Good evening, boss.
That's wonderful, really.
- It's not like that. It's just...
If I were your dad, I'd push that
cigarette... down your throat.
You shouldn't be smoking, kid!
What's up with him?
What did you do to him?
- Why should I do anything to him.
Don't lie!
- I didn't do anything to him.
I am his best apprentice!
What did you do?
Nothing.
- What did you do?
Nothing I swear.
- Wait, wait!
You don't believe me.
Don't you believe I am the best?
Zdenek! Zdenek!
I do believe you.
- Zdenek!
I really do believe.
Wait, wait!
Come here, come over here.
Come here and tell them.
- What's the matter?
Just tell them.
- Tell them what?
What the boss said.
- About what?
About what... about me.
- That you are drunk.
He said that?
- He did.
No, he didn't!
He didn't say that!
Let's go!
- He didn't say that.
You couldn't loan me twenty?
- What for?
Don't worry, I'll give it back.
- When will you give it back?
Shortly... believe me.
Don't do it!
- Don't worry, don't worry.
But I want it back.
Yeah, sure, sure... don't worry.
Let's go, Zdenek.
Look, that bricklayer
spilled our drinks.
Who cares, let's dance.
I'm not thirsty anyway.
I'll get us new ones.
Don't you mind? I'm going.
Don't let her get away!
- I won't!
Look!
- Miss, Miss!
I've got it arranged with her,
do not worry.
Watch me.
Hey, you.
- Hello!
Hello!
Hello! Shall we dance?
- Hello.
Where is he?
- Well, since you spilled our drinks,
he had to get some more.
Well, yeah, I know...
You're right.
So when he comes back, tell him...
No, nothing. You watch me.
And you watch me as well.
And when he gets back,
tell him to watch me too!
Does he always drink so much?
- He doesn't.
I can see he's drunk.
It's because he likes a girl here.
Does he? And which one?
- She is already left.
Is that why he got drunk?
- No, he got drunk before.
But why? - Because he was going
to tell her tonight.
I see. And did he?
- I said she already left.
I know that, but before?
- Before he wasrt drunk yet.
Does he have to get drunk for it?
You'd have to know him.
And aren't you pals?
Why didn't you tell her for him?
I can't. I had hepatitis.
Hepatitis, did you?
You guys are so weird...
She's weird...
she even doesn't know him.
She could have asked me and I'd have
told her why he got drunk!
So what would you say?
- How great he is!
Great?
- Boss let him build a corner already.
A corner?
- Yeah.
You mean a toy one.
- No, a corner with two walls.
With two walls.
- Made of stone.
Yes, with two walls, well.
I'm sorry to tell you,
if it was me
and he was drunk,
I'd ignore him too.
Okay, let's go.
- Where?
Let's dance.
- Okay, let's do it.
You watch me, do watch me!
Hello, hello!
- Hey, what's up.
Wait!
Will you dance with me?
- Show me!
Hey, Zdenek, come here!
You didn't see her, did you?
Who?
- The one wearing the blue...
She was sitting at the table...
Did you see her?
Boss, did you by any chance see
a girl in blue pass by here?
You've got a girlfriend already?
- Not me, him.
Cenda!
Let's go! She's already gone.
Look, do you know what?
To hell with her.
She's dumb.
So, did you find her yet
you two Romeos?
What are you staring at?
Boss, do you think that I'm ugly?
My dear, don't ask me.
You must ask the girl.
But I'd like to hear it
from you, boss.
Go home and sleep it off.
Okay.
But are you still proud of me?
- Right now, not really.
I know, I know...
But how are you proud of me
other times...
Don't bother me,
and go home to bed.
Okay, I'll just sit down here
for a moment, boss.
Look, Cenda,
I like patting you on the back,
when you deserve it,
but you must understand,
no-one can praise you all the time,
over and over again...
I am sure you understand that.
It's sure thing...
Cenda...
- Let him be.
This is the best for him.
Good evening, mum.
- Hello, darling.
Come here, what's this stain?
Just have a look.
It seems there are more stains...
You should take care of it.
It's your new suit.
Are you hungry?
- No, I'm not.
I can warm up the leftovers
from lunch. - No.
Well, tell me something.
How was it there?
Nice.
Which boys did you go with?
There was a crowd of us.
And were the boys fine?
Not some hooligans, I hope.
- No.
And were the girls there too?
So have you found yourself
a girl yet?
No, you haven't. It's good.
You've still got plenty of time.
And what do you boys drink?
- Just a lemonade.
Do you?
- Really, nothing else.
Don't tell me
you don't take a beer.
Who did you walk home with?
Some other boys or alone?
- Alone.
And the boys stayed there?
Are you deaf?
Mum asked you something.
I had a lemonade,
then we danced,
then I came home.
Nothing happened.
Good night.
Wait, wait.
Look at this.
It's quite interesting.
It's about a boy like you.
They don't give him a name,
that's not done anymore...
But...
But it's all true.
You can read it yourself.
It's something like...
You're a man now, so you'll
work it all out. Just read it!
I know it.
I read it already. Good night.
"What every boy should know
about his body"
What are you doing, dear?
- Chopping noodles.
They're here already.
What are you going to tell him?
What should I say?
Call him. So, call him.
Franta!
What do you want?
- Come here.
- Will you come here!
You come here.
Go there. So, you go.
What is it?
Nobody else should hear this.
What do you have there?
Some paintings.
So unwrap them.
- They're for the shop.
What's on them?
- Maybe Jan Hus or Jan Zizka.
I told you this is for the shop.
- I see.
What was on Saturday?
- I got a bit drunk.
Bullshit.
- It's true.
And what about her?
- Mara was there and...
And what?
- I got a date with her for today.
What time did you get home?
- At about eleven.
And what did you do?
- What... all kinds of things.
And the tongue is a problem, eh?
- Well, yeah.
Don't tell me you two kissed.
- I've got a date with her today.
What about the sell-by date
on these?
I hope they're still allright.
- And these oils here?
They have three more weeks to go.
Good. And these?
- This is the latest delivery.
These should be completely fresh.
- Yes.
And they actually are.
- Good, it's good.
Peter, what are you doing?
Get the stuff in and shut the door!
Now the cooking fats.
- They are all fresh.
That's the last delivery, it's fresh.
- Thank you. That's okay.
I've seen them. Now the rum.
- Two, four... sixteen, eighteen bottles.
It says twenty one here.
That's yesterday's count.
So we've sold three since then.
Here we've got
the five-star brand.
What are you doing!
Don't be lazy! Don't cut that rope!
Untie it! We can always use rope!
So how many five-stars?
Two, four, six.
- Yes, six, that's fine.
And the pure spirits.
- Two, four, six, eight, ten.
Ten, yes.
Boss, please...
- That's fine, Peter, that's fine.
Paintings, paintings!
The toilet is blocked,
our stepladder is busted,
the fan hasn't worked for years.
Cognac.
- Two, four, six, eight.
Eight, that's right.
And rums?
Three, six, nine... thirty.
- Thirty one!
So we've sold one since yesterday.
Boss!
- Well, that's good, Peter.
Bitter herb.
- Two, four, six... nine.
Yes. Here we have...
The five-star cognac.
- From Georgia!
Two, four, six.
- So six.
A painting has to be viewed
from the distance.
I don't have the right glasses...
Good lord, it's beautiful.
Look at her eyes, they're closed.
But she knows what she's doing.
Make a little funnel,
so those bottles stop
distracting you.
Look at where she has that hand!
No, no, that's perfectly normal.
Look at the kid, look at him.
Save a little bit for tomorrow!
What are you looking at?
If the women could go
shopping naked,
our hiring troubles would be over.
And you know it's a serious problem.
You can count the boys willing
to work in a shop on your fingers.
They all want to be
astronauts, engineers...
And when we do get a man in here,
he's surly defective.
Let's go on to the wine.
- All right.
So here is the Sylvaner green.
Two, four, six... ten.
- Agreed.
Then Mostar. Three, six,
nine... eighteen.
That's right.
What did you have in the can't
near the train station today?
I was carrying some paintings.
What you mean?
What paintings?
- For the boss.
You see, for the boss, paintings.
Who can buy paintings nowadays?
- Come on, Dad...
They were not really paintings.
They were more like prints...
Prints, prints.
- It was a reward from headquarters.
You see, a reward.
- Well, reward.
What was on those paintings?
I did ask you a question.
Answer me.
Awoman.
- Awoman...
What kind of a woman?
Damn it, answer me.
I asked you a question.
I have to pry every word out of you.
Completely naked.
Peter!
Aha, naked.
You see, dear. They all talk about
socialism and then
they use our boy to deliver filth!
You should talk to them.
My God! What's so horrible
about seeing a naked woman?
After all, he is a big boy now,
he can see things like that.
You should be ashamed.
And you too.
You're saying it was obscene.
Actually she was a thousand times
prettier than the one we have.
Don't be impudent.
Take a look.
Just take a look.
Look at her eyes.
That's what I call beauty!
You walk this way,
she's following you.
Walk that way,
she's following you again.
What a beauty!
I'd like to see somebody
paint like that these days!
It's all scribbling, now.
Goodbye.
Isn't Pavla going out with Mara?
She used to...
Hello.
- Hello.
So say something.
- Like what?
Well, something.
- Nothing comes to mind right now...
What were you looking at? Let me see.
- It's just a poster.
Let me see it.
- It isn't a poster really.
What it was?
- It's more like a painting.
So let me see it.
- I can't.
Just let me see.
- I really can't. Where shall we go?
Okay so keep it.
- Where shall we go?
Nowhere.
So, here it is.
You've got it upside down.
Where did you get it?
In our shop.
Why is it so crumpled? Shame.
Because I had it in my pocket.
How old do you think she is?
It's hard to say with women.
I mean with paintings.
She's definitely older than nine.
- That's for sure.
It's nice.
Shame it's crumpled.
I'd really love it if you could
find time again tomorrow.
But when I get home now
my Mum will be angry
of me being late,
and I won't even be able
to ask her.
- I know just what you mean.
You can't imagine the hell
I go through at home.
Why?
- Well, just a hell.
My Mum constantly
wants me to tell her everything.
She even says I don't love her.
I do, but if I tell her that,
she starts all over again.
And Dad says
I'll be the death of her...
And she is so naive.
Just imagine I say I'm going
to the beach
and she says: Please, darling,
don't drown there.
That's really horrible.
Or I come home and she has visitors
and, even before I walk in,
she's yelling at me:
Sonny, say hello to everybody!
It's like I don't know how to behave.
Or she tells me I like
other people more than her.
Like who?
- Like my friend Lada, for example.
I must leave, you can tell me
some other time, okay?
Then you'll come tomorrow.
- I don't know yet.
I'll be there anyway, just in case.
- Bye now.
Bye.
Peter!
My Mum wants to know
if they have gherkins at your shop.
Thanks. See you!
What is it?
What are you doing?
You're just standing there and...
It's embarrassing.
You're gaping like a dummy.
I'm just doing my job.
- You call this working?
I've been watching you
and it's not a pretty sight.
Doing what?
- Well, I'm here watching.
That's not work!
Just to stand and watch.
What are you watching?
- The people, obviously.
Obviously, but why?
- So they don't steal something.
That's all right, then.
Keep your eyes open.
Sadly, there are still people
with sticky fingers around here.
Boss!
- That's correct, really.
- What is it, Peter?
He's back, he's here again.
- And who?
Well, the one that I was chasing
and he got away.
Call me later, please. A bit later,
will you?
Just wait a little.
Wait.
Has anything happened?
Nothing.
Some woman stole something.
What? Awoman?
What did she steal?
Some sweets, or something.
Nothing much.
Worth about how much?
Twelve crowns maybe.
It was not more.
Did you go after her?
I did not.
So what did you do then?
Nothing.
You didn't even follow her outside?
- No.
You didn't follow her.
Listen, didn't you have
any problem?
At work? Or with your boss?
Arert you hiding anything from me?
No, not at all.
Tell me the truth.
I can still smooth it over.
No, really. Believe me.
You shouldn't have just let her go.
I ask you for the last time,
did you have any problem at work?
I swear I didn't.
So it's all right then,
isnt' it?
Everything is okay.
Just okay.
Look,
if it ever happens again,
grab the guy by the neck
and shake him
till it all drops out!
When I was watching you there,
you were looking good!
Mother, he did look good!
No, I didn't.
Well, how could you, standing there
like a scarecrow.
You couldn't.
Wait.
I've got it now.
You're bored.
I'am not.
You're bored!
I know what interests you.
I saw it the other day.
Short time ago.
Afew kids like you,
kicking up a racket!
An offense to decent people!
Yeah, up! Yeah, across!
They call it "corkscrew"!
When you were born
we were happy to have a boy.
You grew,
I bought you a violin.
It's on the top of a wardrobe.
I bought you an accordion.
It's inside a wardrobe.
You stormed in with a guitar.
It's all the rage, it's easy.
Just sing a little,
and you're happy.
But you can't make a living out of it!
You can't.
What do you want to do?
Tell me.
I don't know.
So, you don't know.
Interesting!
You know
what you don't want to do.
But you don't know
what you want to do.
I thought you liked that job much.
And now you don't.
Don't interrupt.
You don't understand.
How dare you talk
to your mother like that!
What a behaviour?!
Come in.
Come in!
So, come in!
Damn who is it?
- Good afternoon.
Who are you looking for?
Who are you? What you want?
I am Cenek Semerad.
Good afternoon.
I came to see your son.
About something.
Please, come out. Hello.
No, he isn't going anywhere!
He'll stay here. You come in!
Oh no.
I'm okay here.
Do come in!
- It's nothing really.
I'll just tell him...
Look, I wouldn't like...
Come in! Sit down and talk it over
right here.
You're very kind,
but I'd rather stay right here.
Please, sit down and tell him.
- What?
Please, sit down.
Go ahead.
Say what you want to.
What's the matter?
What is it?
Well...
Okay then.
So, I would talk it over.
You know, when you loaned
me that twenty,
so, I would give them back,
but I gave the money,
I just stuck it in my pocket.
I didn't buy anything anymore.
So somehow I forgot about it.
I just didn't want you to think...
So I am giving it back right here.
Just wait, what's going on?
With money?
It's nothing.
He gave me some money.
I am only giving it back.
It belongs to him.
Have a piece of cake.
No, thanks. I don't want anything.
- Help yourself. Don't be shy.
I am not.
I would only like to leave.
What's your name?
- My name? I am Cenek Semerad.
All right, Mr. Cenek, take a piece.
Okay, I'll have one if you insist.
Good? Tasty?
- Oh, yeah.
So what do you do?
I'm an apprentice bricklayer.
So, bricklayer.
Show him your hands.
You mean my hands to show?
- Yes!
Look!
Take a good look!
I'd rather go.
So, goodbye.
Do you see that?
He's working hard!
He'll never turn into a hooligan.
And what about you?
"I don't know",
"I don't feel like it",
"I don't want to do it",
"I don't know".
So who is supposed to know?
Mum?
Dad?
I don't hold it against you
that you don't know.
It's normal at your age.
You will understand later.
But until you know
what you want
you'll do what I want you to do.
Good afternoon. Please, could you
hurry up. Come, so come.
Wait!
It's interesting here, mate.
This is my pal.
"Interesting",
"mate".
So for you it's interesting.
Oh, no, it's not
interesting at all! On the contrary.
You don't even know
what you're talking about.
You don't know what's what.
It's all about...
THE END