1
00:00:12,220 --> 00:00:15,472
1944年8月25日
August 25,1944.

2
00:00:16,141 --> 00:00:19,143
巴黎被解放了
Paris was liberated.

3
00:00:32,073 --> 00:00:36,035
同一天,在东面,罗马尼亚改换阵营,
That same day, to the east,
Romania changed sides,

4
00:00:36,119 --> 00:00:40,164
随着她的背叛 希特勒唯一
的天然石油供给也丢失了
and with her defection went
Hitler's only natural oil supply.

5
00:00:40,248 --> 00:00:42,499
保加利亚已退出了轴心国,
Bulgaria had already quit the Axis,

6
00:00:42,584 --> 00:00:47,714
而芬兰也开始和俄国人商谈停战事宜
and Finland, too, began negotiating
with the Russians for an armistice.

7
00:00:50,800 --> 00:00:56,430
自由法国领导人戴高乐将军进入了他的首都,
General de Gaulle, the Free French
leader, enters his capital,

8
00:00:56,514 --> 00:01:02,227
一个四年前他还是一个相对
默默无闻的军人时 离开的首都
a capital four years before he had left
a comparatively unknown soldier.

9
00:01:02,312 --> 00:01:06,648
现在他被当作法国的灵魂来欢迎
Now he was being greeted
as the very soul of France.

10
00:01:11,738 --> 00:01:16,075
对巴黎人来说,德国占领的黑暗岁月结束了
For Parisians, the dark years
of German occupation were over.

11
00:01:16,159 --> 00:01:21,038
在欧洲其余地区也被解放之前
是不是还要等很长时间?
Could it be long before the
rest of Europe was freed too?

12
00:02:31,401 --> 00:02:33,800
1944年8月15日
August 15,1944.

13
00:02:33,800 --> 00:02:38,699
铁砧行动(也就是"龙骑兵"行动),
盟军对法国南部的入侵行动
Operation Anvil,the Allied
invasion of southern France.

14
00:02:48,209 --> 00:02:52,129
随着北面来自诺曼底滩头的突破正在进行中,
With the break-out from the Normandy
beachhead under way to the north,

15
00:02:52,213 --> 00:02:56,800
"铁砧"的目的是从所有方向
对希特勒德国开始进行钳形运动...
Anvil was meant to begin the pincer movement
on Hitler's Germany from all sides...

16
00:02:56,885 --> 00:03:02,097
将要把第三帝国榨干的钳形运动
the pincer movement that was
to squeeze the Third Reich dry.

17
00:03:04,800 --> 00:03:08,937
我们在圣特罗佩附近跳出(登陆艇)
我想,"就这样了 他们随时都将开火,"
We leapt out near St Tropez and I thought,
"This is it. They'll open up any minute,"

18
00:03:09,022 --> 00:03:14,026
突然从我们所在的海滩的
迷雾中走出来一个法国人
and suddenly out of the mists on our
particular beach there came a Frenchman.

19
00:03:14,110 --> 00:03:17,070
(维恩福德·沃甘-托马斯 战地记者)
他带着一盘香槟酒杯
And he carried a tray of champagne glasses.

20
00:03:17,155 --> 00:03:18,822
我们都停下了
And we all stopped.

21
00:03:18,907 --> 00:03:21,200
很明显,这场景完全出乎意料,
Quite clearly, this was utterly unexpected,

22
00:03:21,200 --> 00:03:25,204
他笑着说,"(法语)欢迎,先生们"
and he smiled and said,
"Soyez les bienvenus, Monsieur."

23
00:03:25,288 --> 00:03:30,125
"欢迎 但是如果我可以提出一些批评
的话,那就是你们多少来得晚了一点"
"Welcome. But if I may venture a little
criticism, you are somewhat late."

24
00:03:30,210 --> 00:03:33,837
从那以后这(场战役)就以"香槟战役"为部队所知
From there on it was known to the troops
as the "Champagne Campaign".

25
00:03:38,092 --> 00:03:42,221
在各到各处,在1944年8月的
那几个疯狂,欢乐的星期里,
Everywhere, during those mad,
joyful weeks of August 1944,

26
00:03:42,305 --> 00:03:47,100
德国人正被赶向他们自己国家的边境
the Germans were being driven back
towards the borders of their own country.

27
00:03:54,192 --> 00:04:00,030
那些和被憎恨的德国鬼子勾结
的法国人变得越来越绝望
Those Frenchmen who had collaborated with
the hated Boche became ever more desperate.

28
00:04:12,252 --> 00:04:19,383
那些与她们的征服者交往的法国女人
现在被找出来 进行特殊处理
Those Frenchwomen who had consorted with their
conquerors were now singled out for special treatment.

29
00:04:46,869 --> 00:04:51,331
成千上万抑郁,茫然失措的德国人被抓了俘虏,
Thousands upon thousands of sullen,
bewildered Germans were taken prisoner,

30
00:04:51,416 --> 00:04:54,710
有时候一次有几个整师(投降)
sometimes whole divisions at a time.

31
00:04:55,586 --> 00:05:01,758
大约20,000名德军被他们的指挥官
埃里克·艾尔斯特少将下令投降
Approximately 20,000 German troops are surrendered
by their commander,Major General Erich Elster.

32
00:05:01,843 --> 00:05:07,139
艾尔斯特将军交出他的手枪作为投降的标志
General Elster hands over his pistol
as a token of surrender.

33
00:05:08,308 --> 00:05:13,186
艾尔斯特将军指挥从比利牛斯山
到比斯开湾的比亚里茨地区
General Elster commanded the Biarritz area
from the Pyrenees Mountains to the Bay of Biscay.

34
00:05:26,993 --> 00:05:30,746
对许多在盟军阵营里的人来说,
这场战争似乎几乎就要结束了
To many in the Allied camp,
the war seemed as good as over.

35
00:05:30,872 --> 00:05:34,499
确实,有一些能回家过圣诞节的传言
lndeed, there was talk
of being back home for Christmas.

36
00:05:34,584 --> 00:05:39,713
但最高层并不总是对如何赢得
最后的胜利持完全相同的看法
But the top brass didn't always see eye to eye
on just how the final victory was to be won.

37
00:05:39,797 --> 00:05:47,012
蒙哥马利争辩道 德国人已在
诺曼底遭受了一次非常惨重的失败
Montgomery argued that the Germans had
had a very heavy defeat in Normandy.

38
00:05:47,138 --> 00:05:51,391
他们已经损失了差不多50万部队
They'd lost approximately 500,000 troops.

39
00:05:51,476 --> 00:05:56,605
43个师已被打垮,以及2,000辆坦克(被摧毁)
43 divisions had been smashed,
and 2,000 tanks.

40
00:05:56,689 --> 00:05:59,816
(布莱恩·霍洛克斯将军 英国第30军司令)
现在是真正痛击他们的时候了
This was the moment to really hit them.

41
00:05:59,901 --> 00:06:05,447
他主张沿着海岸平原向上猛冲,
And what he advocated was a strong
drive up the coastal plain,

42
00:06:05,531 --> 00:06:11,661
右翼为阿登(森林) 左翼很可能几乎就在海岸线上
with the right on the Ardennes and the
left probably almost on the coastline.

43
00:06:11,746 --> 00:06:16,166
日日夜夜,绝不放松,绝不给他们时间恢复
Day and night, never letting up,
never giving them time to recover.

44
00:06:16,250 --> 00:06:19,211
而且,当然,他会来指挥这次行动
And, of course, he would be
in command of this.

45
00:06:19,295 --> 00:06:22,589
而我们会直插进去,
跳过莱茵河渡口,
And we'd go right through,
bounce the crossing of the Rhine,

46
00:06:22,673 --> 00:06:24,800
绕到鲁尔(工业区)后面,切断他们,
come round behind the Ruhr,
cut them off,

47
00:06:24,800 --> 00:06:27,844
而战争就会在1944年结束
and the war would be over in 1944.

48
00:06:27,929 --> 00:06:32,099
艾森豪威尔说,"不 我不喜欢这计划
这是个象钳子一样的突进攻击"
Eisenhower said, "No. I don't
like this. lt's a pincerlike thrust."

49
00:06:32,183 --> 00:06:36,000
"你不会用到很多在法国的部队"
"You're not touching a lot of
the troops which are in France."

50
00:06:36,000 --> 00:06:40,649
"我提议沿着一个宽大的正面推进,
一直推进到莱茵河,
"l propose to advance on a broad
front,right up to the Rhine,

51
00:06:40,733 --> 00:06:45,654
然后越过莱茵河 并在那里结束战争"
and then do a crossing of the Rhine
and finish the war there."

52
00:06:45,738 --> 00:06:48,407
但是...那或许更安全,
But... That was perhaps safer,

53
00:06:48,491 --> 00:06:52,119
但那意味着不能在1944年结束战争
but it meant that the war
couldn't be finished in 1944.

54
00:06:52,300 --> 00:07:02,295
(肯尼斯·斯壮将军 艾森豪威尔的情报主管)
我觉得英国人在意识到"欧洲战事的主要
努力有赖于美国人"这一点上非常迟钝
I think the British were very slow to realise that
the main effort for war in Europe lay with the Americans.

55
00:07:02,380 --> 00:07:06,091
我觉得英国媒体很可能也一样迟钝
I think the British press
was probably slow, as well.

56
00:07:06,175 --> 00:07:16,560
我想人们忘记了极大比重的师团
和补给品等等 都是美国人的
I think people forgot that the great weight of
divisions and supplies and so on were American.

57
00:07:17,186 --> 00:07:19,980
在我们从桥头堡突破以后,
After we broke out from the bridgehead,

58
00:07:20,064 --> 00:07:25,400
(弗兰西斯·德·古因甘德将军 蒙哥马利的参谋长)
有很长一段时间 补给不得不从海滩运过来或被空运过来
supply for a very long time had to come
over the beaches or be carried by air.

59
00:07:25,400 --> 00:07:33,285
集团军群经常发现 由于缺乏补给品,特别
是汽油,他们不能做他们想要做的事情
Army groups found often that they couldn't do what
they wanted to for lack of supplies,particularly petrol.

60
00:07:47,133 --> 00:07:51,636
每辆坦克开一英里要用一加仑汽油
Each tank used a gallon of petrol a mile.

61
00:07:52,555 --> 00:07:57,392
运送补给品的卡车绵延250英里回溯到诺曼底滩头
The trucks carrying the stuff stretched
back 250 miles to the Normandy beaches.

62
00:07:59,312 --> 00:08:05,066
盟军突破的速度如此迅猛 以至于
有许多小股的德军部队被留在了后面,
Such had been the speed of the Allied break-out
that pockets of German troops had been left behind,

63
00:08:05,151 --> 00:08:10,280
所以公路补给车队经常会遭遇
沿路狙击的敌人的夹攻
and so the road convoys had often to run
a gauntlet of enemy sniping along the way.

64
00:08:13,800 --> 00:08:20,957
卡车司机给巴黎和前线之间的
这片区域起绰号为"印第安人乡村"
The lorry drivers had nicknamed the area
between Paris and the front line "lnjun country".

65
00:08:34,138 --> 00:08:37,224
最困难的战斗是沿着海岸线(的战斗)
The hardest fighting of all
was along the coast.

66
00:08:37,308 --> 00:08:42,600
每个港口都被希特勒派卫戍部队驻防
他们得到的命令是战斗到众所周知的最后一颗子弹
Every port had been garrisoned by Hitler with
orders to fight to the proverbial last round.

67
00:08:42,600 --> 00:08:52,739
勒阿弗尔,迪耶普,布伦,加莱,敦刻尔克(皆为法国港口),
都必须依次通过各自事先精心部署的战斗 来被突击
Le Havre, Dieppe, Boulogne, Calais,Dunkirk, had all
to be assaulted in turn by separate set-piece battle.

68
00:08:55,700 --> 00:08:58,995
希特勒知道补给将是盟军的主要头痛问题,
Hitler knew supply would be
the Allies' main headache,

69
00:08:59,080 --> 00:09:02,700
所以他决心坚守这些(英吉利)
海峡的港口尽可能长的时间
hence his determination to hang on
to the Channel ports as long as possible

70
00:09:02,700 --> 00:09:07,629
而且,当最终(被迫)缴出(这些港口)时,
确保它们被彻底摧毁
and, when finally yielded,
to see they were destroyed utterly.

71
00:09:16,514 --> 00:09:22,269
蒙哥马利三分之一的部队
忙于清除占据海峡港口的德国人
One third of Montgomery's forces were engaged
in clearing Germans from the Channel ports

72
00:09:22,353 --> 00:09:24,980
而其他部队继续向前挺入比利时
while the rest pushed on into Belgium.

73
00:09:31,362 --> 00:09:35,198
我真正的重要时刻是当我们
穿越(法国比利时)边境时,
(Horrocks) My really big moment
was when we crossed the frontier,

74
00:09:35,283 --> 00:09:41,955
因为,你瞧,(四年前)撤退至敦刻尔克时
我指挥了一支后卫部队
because, you see,l had commanded the
rearguard during the withdrawal to Dunkirk.

75
00:09:42,039 --> 00:09:44,624
当时我是个营长
l was then a battalion commander.

76
00:09:44,709 --> 00:09:48,962
而我负责保卫(英军)第3师的侧翼和后方,
And l'd been doing flank guard
and rear guard to the 3rd Division,

77
00:09:49,046 --> 00:09:53,633
(而第3师就)由蒙哥马利元帅指挥,当时他是个将军
commanded by a certain Field Marshal
Montgomery, who was then a general.

78
00:09:53,718 --> 00:09:56,219
而我当时非常为自己感到羞愧
And I was very ashamed of myself.

79
00:09:56,304 --> 00:09:59,848
我们在比利时人民的欢呼声中前进,
We'd advanced to the cheers
of the Belgian people,

80
00:09:59,932 --> 00:10:05,395
几天后,我们撤退回来穿过这些脸色灰白的人群,
and now a few days later, back we were
going through these ashen-faced crowds,

81
00:10:05,479 --> 00:10:06,980
极度沮丧...
terribly despondent...

82
00:10:07,064 --> 00:10:10,567
他们知道他们将再次被德国人占领
they knew they were going
to be occupied again by the Germans.

83
00:10:10,651 --> 00:10:15,280
而我不断地说,"别担心 我们会回来的"
And I kept on saying, "Don't worry.
We'll come back."

84
00:10:15,364 --> 00:10:19,451
而当我们(四年后)越过边境时 我们已经回来了
And as we crossed the frontier,
we had come back.

85
00:10:19,535 --> 00:10:25,123
一个年轻人...我想他看到了
我戴的红圆帽,你知道...
And a young man... I suppose
he saw the red round my hat, you know...

86
00:10:25,207 --> 00:10:28,752
他跑过来到我坦克这里
and he ran across to my tank.

87
00:10:28,836 --> 00:10:33,798
有眼泪从他脸上倾泻而下
他象这样伸出他的手,
There were tears pouring down his face.
And he held out his hand like this,

88
00:10:33,883 --> 00:10:37,302
他说,"我知道你们会回来的!
我知道你们会回来的!"
and he said, "l knew you'd come back!
l knew you'd come back!"

89
00:10:50,775 --> 00:10:55,111
我在布鲁塞尔的一个朋友告诉我
他听到了坦克的声音,
A friend of mine in Brussels told me
that he heard the sound of tanks,

90
00:10:55,196 --> 00:10:57,447
但他们已经很习惯于(听到)那声音
but they were quite used to that.

91
00:10:57,531 --> 00:11:00,241
他向窗外望去,而他自言自语道:
He looked out of the window,
and he said to himself:

92
00:11:00,326 --> 00:11:03,244
"那些(坦克)不一样
它们不象是德国的"
"Those are different.
They don't seem to be German."

93
00:11:03,329 --> 00:11:07,499
然后他打开窗并探出身去,而一些人挥了手
Then he opened the window and leant out,
and somebody waved.

94
00:11:07,583 --> 00:11:12,337
他说, "它们是英国人的!"
他冲下去跑上街道,
He said, "They're British!"
And he tore down into the street,

95
00:11:12,421 --> 00:11:15,632
布鲁塞尔其他所有人也都跑到街上
and so did everybody else in Brussels.

96
00:11:15,716 --> 00:11:20,512
从来没有遇到过象我们解放布鲁塞尔
时的那种场景,从来没有
There has never been such a scene
as when we liberated Brussels, never.

97
00:11:20,596 --> 00:11:28,269
一些真的很彪悍的30军老兵想到发生的那些事仍然会脸红
And some of the really tough old 30 Corps veterans
still blush to think of the things that happened.

98
00:11:49,250 --> 00:11:53,211
到目前为止,一切都好
现在我们开始犯错误了
So far, so good.
Now we come to the mistakes.

99
00:11:53,295 --> 00:11:58,800
我们被命令停下来 理由是
我们正超出我们的补给(能力)
We were ordered to halt. The reason
was that we were outrunning our supply.

100
00:11:58,884 --> 00:12:01,302
这是错误的,
Now, this was wrong,

101
00:12:01,387 --> 00:12:06,891
因为我们的坦克上带有足够开100公里的汽油,
because we had 100 kilometres' worth
of petrol with our vehicles,

102
00:12:06,976 --> 00:12:11,479
而且在大约24小时里能够得到
(足够开)另外100公里(的汽油),
and another 100 kilometres'
within about 24 hours' reach,

103
00:12:11,564 --> 00:12:14,649
而在我看来,他们应该冒一下险
and they should, in my opinion,
have taken a chance.

104
00:12:14,734 --> 00:12:17,610
因为在我们停下来的那一天,
Because that day that we were halted,

105
00:12:17,695 --> 00:12:25,869
挡在我们和莱茵河之间的唯一阻碍
就是一个由非常老的老先生们组成的师团
the only thing between us and the Rhine
was one division of very old gentlemen.

106
00:12:25,953 --> 00:12:29,831
我们称他们为"胃(病)师",
因为他们就差不多跟我(现在)的年纪,
We called them "stomach divisions",
because they were sort of my age,

107
00:12:29,915 --> 00:12:32,417
他们所有人的胃都有问题
and all had things wrong
with their tummies.

108
00:12:32,501 --> 00:12:36,755
他们一直在守卫荷兰的海岸,
从没见过真枪实弹的射击,
They'd been guarding the coast of Holland,
never seen a shot fired in anger,

109
00:12:36,839 --> 00:12:40,633
他们会很高兴能平静地走进我们的战俘营
and they'd have been delighted
to move peacefully into our POW camps

110
00:12:40,718 --> 00:12:44,971
不用再参与这场可怕的战争...
他们就是那么一种心态
without having to indulge in this horrid
war... that was the sort of mentality.

111
00:12:45,055 --> 00:12:48,224
还有一个荷兰籍的党卫队营...没了
Plus one Dutch SS battalion... nothing.

112
00:12:48,309 --> 00:12:52,854
我们本可以直接掠过他们,越过莱茵河渡口,
We could have brushed straight through
them, bounced the crossing to the Rhine,

113
00:12:52,938 --> 00:12:57,525
把所有在荷兰的德国人
与鲁尔之间的联系切断,
cut all the Germans in Holland
off from the Ruhr,

114
00:12:57,610 --> 00:12:59,611
然后绕到鲁尔后面
and then got round behind the Ruhr.

115
00:12:59,695 --> 00:13:03,198
毫无疑问,在我看来,这是一个非常糟糕的错误
Unquestionably, it was, to my mind,
a very bad mistake.

116
00:13:03,282 --> 00:13:05,074
我们应该冒这个险的
We should have taken the risk.

117
00:13:05,159 --> 00:13:09,454
当我们被允许(重新)前进,这时已是9月7日,
When we were allowed to advance,
which was September 7,

118
00:13:09,538 --> 00:13:12,791
我们在四天里(只)推进了10英里
we made ten miles in four days.

119
00:13:14,001 --> 00:13:19,005
之前我们在七天里推进了250英里
We had previously done
250 miles in seven days.

120
00:13:19,089 --> 00:13:23,885
我们不再是在追击
我们现在又重新在战斗
We were no longer pursuing.
We were now fighting again.

121
00:13:29,767 --> 00:13:33,645
然后,在9月11日,
Then, on September 11,

122
00:13:33,729 --> 00:13:36,064
我得到了去安恒的命令
l got my orders for Arnhem.

123
00:13:36,649 --> 00:13:42,570
莱茵河三角洲的三条主要水道横亘
在盟军先头部队和德国本土之间:
The three main waterways of the Rhine delta lay
between the Allied spearheads and Germany proper:

124
00:13:42,655 --> 00:13:46,491
马斯河,瓦尔河以及下莱茵河
the Maas, the Waal and the Neder Rijn.

125
00:13:47,576 --> 00:13:52,163
蒙哥马利的计划是要铺一条
空降兵地毯跨越这些水道,
Montgomery's plan was to lay an
airborne carpet across these waterways,

126
00:13:52,248 --> 00:13:53,498
占领桥梁,
capture the bridges,

127
00:13:53,582 --> 00:13:58,000
并让一支机动部队绕过齐格菲
防线的左翼以切断鲁尔区,
and rush a mobile force round the left flank
of the Siegfried line to cut off the Ruhr,

128
00:13:58,200 --> 00:14:03,299
这样就能在1944年圣诞节前结束德国的抵抗
and so end German resistance before Christmas 1944.

129
00:14:54,476 --> 00:14:56,269
可以了
l've got it.

130
00:15:25,700 --> 00:15:30,261
许多人会告诉你 这个计划是错误的...
(Strong) Many people will tell you
that the plan was wrong...

131
00:15:30,346 --> 00:15:32,700
有太多的目标(要占领),
there were too many objectives,

132
00:15:32,700 --> 00:15:37,226
或者伞兵们没有降落在合适的地方,等等
or the parachutists were not landed
in proper places and so on.

133
00:15:37,311 --> 00:15:40,500
当然,天气也不好,而且打断了空降行动
And the weather, of course,
was not good, and did interrupt it.

134
00:15:40,700 --> 00:15:47,028
但我觉得 如果当时更多的注意力被投入到
关注你可称之为"敌人的部署"上的话,
But I think that if more attention had been paid
to what you might call the enemy's dispositions,

135
00:15:47,112 --> 00:15:50,406
那么我觉得这个计划本来是可以成功的
then I think the plan
would have been alright.

136
00:16:11,845 --> 00:16:14,100
降落在安恒的空降部队
(英国第一空降师)
(De Guingand) Airborne troops
who landed at Arnhem

137
00:16:14,100 --> 00:16:24,524
突然发现他们要面对一些正在那里休整,并且当时正好
出现在那里的德国装甲部队(党卫队第9,第10装甲师)
suddenly found themselves up against some
German armoured units that were refitting there,
and just happened to be there at the time.

138
00:16:37,788 --> 00:16:43,459
在降落的伞兵的第一批军官中,
(Strong) Among the first officers
who were landed among the parachutists,

139
00:16:43,544 --> 00:16:47,672
德国人发现了我们计划的一份完整拷贝
the Germans found a complete copy of our plan.

140
00:16:48,382 --> 00:16:52,635
而这份拷贝立即被送给了德国指挥官,
And this was whisked off
to the German commander on the spot,

141
00:16:52,720 --> 00:16:58,516
当然,从那以后他就知道了
我们想要做什么的全部信息
and, of course, from then on he had all
the information of what we were trying to do.

142
00:17:23,167 --> 00:17:28,046
谁都说不准,夺下莱茵河对岸的那个桥头堡后,
(De Guingand) lt's anyone's guess whether,
having got that bridgehead over the Rhine,

143
00:17:28,130 --> 00:17:30,900
在一年的那个时节,随着坏天气的来临,
at that time of year,
with the bad weather setting in,

144
00:17:30,900 --> 00:17:36,304
我们是否能够在冬天那几个月守住那个(桥头堡)
whether we'd have been able to maintain that
for several months during the winter.

145
00:17:36,388 --> 00:17:43,895
因为你凭经验会知道 德国人在
扭转危急局势方面有多么了不起
Because one knew from experience how magnificent
the Germans were at retrieving critical situations.

146
00:17:46,982 --> 00:17:50,526
战役继续进行了三四天,
The battle went on
for three or four days,

147
00:17:50,611 --> 00:17:53,946
而我们真的不能取得任何进展
and we couldn't really
make any progress.

148
00:17:54,865 --> 00:17:59,786
最终蒙哥马利决定 他不能再继续了,
Eventually Montgomery decided
that he couldn't go on,

149
00:17:59,870 --> 00:18:04,415
这个行动("市场花园"行动)必须停止,
and that the operation
was to be called off,

150
00:18:04,500 --> 00:18:08,300
并把尽可能多的人运回莱茵河
(南岸), 他也这么做了
and get as many people back across
the Rhine as possible, which he did.

151
00:18:08,300 --> 00:18:16,094
我们损失了很多人 但我觉得你一定
得诚实地说 这次行动没有实现目标
We lost quite a lot. But I think one's got to be
quite honest,and say that it failed in its object.

152
00:18:16,178 --> 00:18:18,888
它取得了部分的成功,
lt achieved partial success,

153
00:18:18,972 --> 00:18:22,892
而我一直讨厌用那种"光荣的失败"的说法
and I always hate using that expression
of "glorious failures".

154
00:18:22,976 --> 00:18:25,269
我不会那么称呼它,但...
l wouldn't call it that, but...

155
00:18:25,354 --> 00:18:27,939
它是一次失败,从一定程度上来说
it was a failure, up to a point.

156
00:18:28,000 --> 00:18:36,239
在安恒的失败意味着 现在战争
绝对不会在1944年圣诞节结束
The failure at Arnhem meant the war would
now definitely not be over by Christmas 1944.

157
00:18:37,282 --> 00:18:44,413
那还意味着,就目前而言,
西方盟军已失去了(战争)主动权
lt meant, too, that the initiative,for the
moment,had been lost by the Western Allies.

158
00:18:44,498 --> 00:18:48,793
但在东线,这是个极其不同的故事
But on the Eastern Front,
it was a vastly different story.

159
00:18:48,919 --> 00:18:51,504
在那里,(苏联)红军到处突飞猛进
There, the Red Army
was advancing everywhere.

160
00:18:51,588 --> 00:18:55,216
在中部,10万德军在明斯克被包围
ln the centre, 100,000 Germans
had been surrounded at Minsk.

161
00:18:55,300 --> 00:18:58,594
在北面,芬兰已被迫退出战争,
ln the north, Finland had been
knocked out of the war,

162
00:18:58,679 --> 00:19:03,558
爱沙尼亚被夺回,拉脱维亚
和立陶宛被扫清了德国部队,
Estonia recaptured, Latvia and Lithuania
cleared of German troops,

163
00:19:03,642 --> 00:19:07,436
(并且苏军)已抵达东普鲁士边境
and the borders of East Prussia reached.

164
00:19:07,521 --> 00:19:10,982
在南面,乌克兰已被解放
ln the south,
the Ukraine had been freed.

165
00:19:11,066 --> 00:19:13,192
罗马尼亚已投降,
Romania had capitulated,

166
00:19:13,277 --> 00:19:15,486
保加利亚已被占领,
Bulgaria had been overrun,

167
00:19:15,571 --> 00:19:17,530
希腊被切断,
Greece cut off,

168
00:19:17,614 --> 00:19:22,000
还与南斯拉夫的铁托游击队取得了联系
and a link-up effected
with Tito's partisans in Yugoslavia.

169
00:19:22,000 --> 00:19:29,125
这是一个(取得)巨大成功的故事,
一个在东线到处(取得)压倒性胜利的故事,
lt was a story of gigantic triumph,
of overwhelming success everywhere in the east,

170
00:19:29,209 --> 00:19:31,460
储存在一个几乎被忘记的城市里,
save in one near-forgotten city,

171
00:19:31,545 --> 00:19:35,006
在那里战争在五年前首先打响:
where the war had first begun
five years before:

172
00:19:35,090 --> 00:19:37,466
波兰的首都,华沙
Poland's capital, Warsaw.

173
00:19:39,200 --> 00:19:43,700
到1944年7月,红军占领了波兰的东半部,
By July 1944, the Red Army
occupied the eastern half of Poland,

174
00:19:43,700 --> 00:19:49,500
也就是在1939年8月的希特勒-斯大林
条约中被划给他们的那一半
that half allocated to them in
the Hitler-Stalin pact of August 1939.

175
00:19:50,000 --> 00:19:56,444
伦敦的波兰流亡政府在俄国人占领他们国家
的剩余部分前就焦急地坚决表明自己的权利
The exiled Polish government in London was anxious to assert
itself before the Russians overran the rest of their country.

176
00:19:56,528 --> 00:19:58,070
否则,在他们的眼里,
Otherwise, in their eyes,

177
00:19:58,197 --> 00:20:03,576
这将仅仅是占领者的一次替换
而不是真正的解放
it would merely be an exchange of
occupiers rather than true liberation.

178
00:20:03,660 --> 00:20:09,457
当红军接近华沙,德国守备部队似乎准备撤离
As the Red Army approached Warsaw,
the German garrison seemed ready to leave.

179
00:20:23,513 --> 00:20:28,142
在7月29日,一次俄国的广播
谈到了华沙即将发生的解放,
On July 29, a Russian broadcast
talked of Warsaw's impending liberation,

180
00:20:28,227 --> 00:20:33,814
并敦促抵抗力量的战士们
起义反抗撤退的德国人
and urged the workers of the Resistance
to rise against the retreating Germans.

181
00:20:33,899 --> 00:20:38,361
8月1日,华沙城里的波兰地下军起义了,
On August 1, the Polish underground
army inside Warsaw did rise,

182
00:20:38,445 --> 00:20:41,500
尽管他们并不全都支持伦敦(流亡)政府
though they did not all support
the London government.

183
00:20:41,500 --> 00:20:47,245
然而,那些支持(伦敦政府)的人的目标是一旦他们
取得(对华沙的)控制 就让流亡政府飞回来
However, the aim of those who did was to fly in
the government-in-exile once they had control

184
00:20:47,329 --> 00:20:52,000
并在俄国人到达前 成立一个合法政权
and set up a legitimate regime
before the Russians arrived.

185
00:20:52,600 --> 00:20:57,546
但这次起义正巧碰上俄国人的攻势耗尽了势头,
But the uprising coincided with the
Russian offensive running out of steam,

186
00:20:57,631 --> 00:21:00,841
然而这却是一个正合斯大林之意的巧合
a coincidence that nevertheless
suited Stalin's book.

187
00:21:00,926 --> 00:21:05,179
斯大林对(波兰)地下抵抗组织非常怀疑,
Stalin was very suspicious
of the underground,

188
00:21:05,264 --> 00:21:09,100
但他甚至不尝试送进补给的举动是绝对残忍的
but it was utterly cruel that
he wouldn't even try to get supplies in.

189
00:21:09,184 --> 00:21:14,400
他有好几个星期都拒绝让
我们的飞机飞进去空投补给
He refused to let our aeroplanes fly and
try to drop supplies for several weeks.

190
00:21:14,400 --> 00:21:15,500
而那对我们所有人来说都是一件令人震惊的事
And that was a shock to all of us.

191
00:21:15,500 --> 00:21:21,862
(艾弗瑞尔·哈里曼 美国驻俄国大使 1943-46)
我想这件事对在我们所有人的脑海中留下
俄国人残酷无情(的印象)起了(很大的)作用
And I think it played a role in all of our minds
as to the heartlessness of the Russians.

192
00:21:25,367 --> 00:21:28,828
我们有一个非常强大的地下组织,
We had a very strong
underground organisation,

193
00:21:28,912 --> 00:21:34,625
有一个平民政府 和所有的军事指挥(机构),
with a civilian government
and all the military commands,

194
00:21:34,710 --> 00:21:40,673
而那是在德国占领的四年里被组织起来的,
and that was organised during
the four years of the German occupation,

195
00:21:40,757 --> 00:21:43,801
而它(地下组织)就这么现身了
并发挥了其作用
and it just surfaced
and took its functions.

196
00:21:44,803 --> 00:21:47,972
由"童子军"运营的邮政服务,
The postal service,
which was run by Scouts,

197
00:21:48,098 --> 00:21:55,771
是在完全被敌人炮火切断联系的
华沙各区之间 唯一的通信方式
was the only means of communications
between the various districts of Warsaw,
which were completely cut off by enemy fire.

198
00:21:55,856 --> 00:21:59,108
要从一个区去另一个区的童子军,
The Scouts, to get from one district to another,

199
00:21:59,192 --> 00:22:05,573
有时候不得不穿过下水道,
或冒着敌人的火力前进
had sometimes to go through sewers,
or under the enemy fire.

200
00:22:10,746 --> 00:22:12,788
在起义刚开始的时候
At the very beginning of the uprising

201
00:22:12,873 --> 00:22:15,833
我想 我们只有(可以维持)
10或12天的弹药
we had ammunition for only,
l think, ten or twelve days.

202
00:22:15,917 --> 00:22:21,630
然后我们就不得不依靠
从德国人那里夺取的弹药,
And then we had to rely on
the ammunition taken from the Germans,

203
00:22:21,757 --> 00:22:27,720
另外在华沙还有武器弹药工厂在继续生产,
or there were factories of ammunition
and arms in Warsaw going on,

204
00:22:27,846 --> 00:22:30,931
他们在生产他们自己的弹药
and they were producing
their own ammunition.

205
00:22:45,655 --> 00:22:49,700
在波兰人的性格中有一些乐观的因素,
There is something in the Polish national
character,you know,which is optimistic,

206
00:22:49,785 --> 00:22:51,300
我们不会那么轻易地放弃
and we do not give up so easily.

207
00:22:51,300 --> 00:22:57,083
我愿意付出我一半的生命来
换取参加华沙起义的特权
l would have given half of my life for the privilege
of participating in the Warsaw insurrection.

208
00:22:57,167 --> 00:23:05,174
(华沙起义期间)道德生活,智力生活,
感情生活都有极大的强化
There was a tremendous intensification of moral
life,intellectual life,emotional life,you know,

209
00:23:05,258 --> 00:23:09,428
人们最好的一面凸显了出来
the best sides of people
coming to the foreground.

210
00:23:23,300 --> 00:23:28,823
在整个华沙起义期间
我们有许多值得列举的感人事迹
We had lots of recitals
through all the Warsaw insurrection.

211
00:23:36,164 --> 00:23:43,003
有人单枪匹马就去攻击坦克,
There were people who took single-handed
actions against the tanks,

212
00:23:43,088 --> 00:23:48,551
有人用他们的血肉之躯
去堵敌人的机枪,诸如此类
people who threw themselves
at enemy machine guns, things like that.

213
00:23:48,635 --> 00:23:51,387
有足够多的个人英雄主义(事迹)
There was plenty of individual heroism.

214
00:23:51,471 --> 00:23:54,223
伦敦的波兰人几乎就要成功了
The London Poles
almost pulled it off.

215
00:23:54,349 --> 00:23:57,768
到了(起义)第一周结束,
他们控制了华沙城的绝大部分,
By the end of the first week,
they controlled most of the city,

216
00:23:57,853 --> 00:24:02,398
而(英国)皇家空军已准备
把波兰流亡政府空运回去
and the RAF was set to fly in
the Polish government-in-exile.

217
00:24:02,524 --> 00:24:06,700
但是接下来 意识到斯大林
将什么也不会做的希特勒
But then Hitler, realising
Stalin was going to do nothing,

218
00:24:06,700 --> 00:24:08,800
命令党卫队镇压起义,
ordered the SS to crush the uprising,

219
00:24:08,800 --> 00:24:13,242
而他们(党卫队)以极大的乐趣
和残忍无情进行了镇压
which they proceeded to do
with great relish and ruthlessness.

220
00:24:33,889 --> 00:24:37,725
轰炸非常糟糕...事实上,没有中断过
The bombing was very bad...
without interruption, practically.

221
00:24:37,809 --> 00:24:40,978
不仅有轰炸,我们还遭受了炮击
Not only bombing, we had artillery also.

222
00:24:41,062 --> 00:24:43,606
我们会用报纸来遮盖我们的战死者
We would cover our dead with newspapers.

223
00:24:43,690 --> 00:24:48,277
这总是葬礼前的第一件事,你瞧,
This was the first thing always,
you see, before the funeral,

224
00:24:48,403 --> 00:24:51,197
为了不毁掉士气
in order not to spoil the morale.

225
00:24:56,286 --> 00:24:59,914
在起义的最后几天里,
During the last days of the uprising,

226
00:24:59,998 --> 00:25:03,125
只剩下一个区没有被德国人占领
only one district was left
unoccupied by the Germans.

227
00:25:03,210 --> 00:25:06,295
(里面)有三千到四千,或许五千人
There were three to four,
perhaps 5,000 people.

228
00:25:06,379 --> 00:25:10,299
有时候有30或40个人睡在一个房间里
There were sometimes 30 or 40 people
sleeping in one room.

229
00:25:10,383 --> 00:25:15,679
现在,德国人用他们的俯冲轰炸机轰炸我们
Now, the Germans were bombarding us
with their dive bombers.

230
00:25:27,359 --> 00:25:30,236
我们的食物越来越少,你知道
We had less and less food,you know.

231
00:25:30,320 --> 00:25:32,738
我们有一些淀粉,我们没有面包,
We had some starches,
we didn't have bread,

232
00:25:32,822 --> 00:25:34,990
我们有意大利面条,那种东西
we had spaghetti, things of that sort.

233
00:25:35,075 --> 00:25:41,455
而到最后,你知道,我们会杀马,并吃马肉
And at the end, you know, we would
kill horses, and eat horse meat.

234
00:25:41,540 --> 00:25:44,625
狗也被吃了
And dogs were eaten also.

235
00:25:49,422 --> 00:25:53,592
在伦敦的波兰人在绝望中变得更加狂乱,
The London Poles became ever more
frantic in their hopelessness,

236
00:25:53,677 --> 00:25:56,303
并为他们的困境而责备英国人
and blamed the British for their plight.

237
00:25:56,388 --> 00:26:04,812
但是只要斯大林拒绝让皇家空军在苏联控制
的领土上加油 他们就不能运进去很多补给
But the RAF couldn't fly in much supplies
as long as Stalin refused to let them
refuel in Soviet-held territory.

238
00:26:04,896 --> 00:26:09,108
到他(斯大林)被劝服 愿意发慈悲的时候,
华沙还剩下如此小的地方(还在起义军手中)
By the time he'd been persuaded
to relent, so little was left of Warsaw

239
00:26:09,192 --> 00:26:14,321
以至于(空投的)补给多半落入德国人的手中
that the supplies dropped fell
more often than not into German hands.

240
00:26:14,406 --> 00:26:20,202
我们感到极度失望 整个世界都忘记了我们
We were terribly disappointed.
The whole world forgot about us.

241
00:26:20,287 --> 00:26:24,790
我感觉波兰被同盟国出卖了,你明白?
I feel that Poland was
betrayed by Allies, you see?

242
00:26:24,874 --> 00:26:28,502
这就是(起义的)终结 我们感觉
我们绝对没有希望了,
It was the end. We felt there
was absolutely no hope for us,

243
00:26:28,587 --> 00:26:31,338
我们不会从俄国人那里得到任何帮助
that we wouldn't get any help
from the Russians.

244
00:26:31,423 --> 00:26:35,384
德国人被派来彻底地消灭我们,
The Germans were set on
absolutely annihilating us,

245
00:26:35,468 --> 00:26:44,810
所以当我在战火下行走时 我也不费心
去低下头,弯下身了,多少有点那样
and therefore I didn't bother to duck when
I was going under the fire,anything like that.

246
00:26:44,894 --> 00:26:51,066
我只是有种(反正)我迟早会死...
(不如死得)越快越好的感觉
l just had the feeling that I should die
sooner or later... sooner, better.

247
00:26:54,237 --> 00:26:57,200
德国人甚至带来了他们最大的攻城炮,
The Germans even brought
their biggest siege guns,

248
00:26:57,200 --> 00:27:00,326
绰号"雷神托尔"的令人畏惧的
巨大臼炮(又称"卡尔"臼炮),
the dreaded giant mortar nicknamed "Thor",

249
00:27:00,410 --> 00:27:04,580
它的每发炮弹重量超过两吨(口径600mm)
each of whose shells
weighed more than two tons.

250
00:27:06,708 --> 00:27:12,129
现在这是一场持续了漫长
的十个星期 毫无希望的战斗,
lt was a hopeless battle now that
had been going on for ten long weeks,

251
00:27:12,213 --> 00:27:16,759
并已经付出了超过20万个波兰人的生命
and had already cost the lives
of more than 200,000 Poles.

252
00:27:16,843 --> 00:27:19,595
已经到了停止(起义)的时间了
The time had come to call a halt.

253
00:27:37,614 --> 00:27:41,900
出乎意料的是,德国人允许波兰人体面地投降,
Surprisingly, the Germans allowed
the Poles to surrender honourably,

254
00:27:41,900 --> 00:27:45,400
并且不把他们当作可以立即处决的游击队员来对待,
and treated them not as partisans
fit for immediate execution,

255
00:27:45,400 --> 00:27:51,293
而是当作 应得到日内瓦公约下战俘的权利
的应募入伍的战斗人员(来对待)
but as enlisted combatants,due the rights
of POWs under the Geneva Convention.

256
00:27:51,378 --> 00:27:59,009
很明显,一些德国将军已经把他们的目光
投在战后可能进行的战争罪行审判上
Clearly, some of the German generals already had their
eyes on possible war-crimes trials after the war.

257
00:28:21,700 --> 00:28:25,285
一旦剩下的市民被从该城驱离,
Once the remaining citizens
had been driven from the city,

258
00:28:25,370 --> 00:28:28,914
华沙就被系统地夷为平地
Warsaw was systematically
razed to the ground.

259
00:28:56,234 --> 00:29:00,112
希特勒决心 它再也不会发生起义
Hitler was determined
it should never rise again.

260
00:29:17,130 --> 00:29:21,508
就这样 这场战争中
最悲惨的事件之一落幕了
Thus ended one of the war's
most tragic episodes.

261
00:29:44,324 --> 00:29:46,825
尽管遭受轰炸和物资匮乏,
Despite the bombing and despite the privations,

262
00:29:46,910 --> 00:29:51,914
1944年那个秋天 德国人民的士气出人意外地高昂
the morale of the German people that
autumn of 1944 was surprisingly high.

263
00:29:51,998 --> 00:29:55,667
他们对希特勒做出的每一个宣传号召都反应热烈
They responded well to every
propaganda call Hitler made.

264
00:29:55,794 --> 00:30:00,881
这是为东线(士兵)收集冬装
This one was for collecting
winter clothing for the Eastern Front.

265
00:30:06,888 --> 00:30:10,766
那个秋天 希特勒把征召
入伍的年龄降低到16岁半,
Hitler reduced the call-up age
that autumn to 16½,

266
00:30:10,850 --> 00:30:15,729
并大量征集那些迄今为止
以重要工作为借口逃避服役的人
and raked in those who so far had
escaped it on grounds of essential work.

267
00:30:15,814 --> 00:30:19,233
大约70万新兵被征募,
Some 700,000 new recruits were raised,

268
00:30:19,317 --> 00:30:22,361
部分是为了人民冲锋队,
一种国土防卫军,
partly for the Volkssturm,
a sort of Home Guard,

269
00:30:22,445 --> 00:30:27,324
部分是为了替换他在东线和西线的可怕损失
and partly to replace his terrible
losses in both east and west.

270
00:30:27,408 --> 00:30:32,371
但在他心中 他对他的新兵
还有一个更大胆的用途
But he also had in mind a more
daring use for his new recruits.

271
00:30:33,000 --> 00:30:37,700
自从他在诺曼底战败以来,希特勒
就一直在计划发动一次主要的反攻,
Ever since his defeat in Normandy, Hitler
had been planning a major counterattack,

272
00:30:37,700 --> 00:30:41,000
希望不只是在盟军到达莱茵河前止住他们,
hoping not just to halt the Allies
before they reached the Rhine,

273
00:30:41,000 --> 00:30:45,717
而是要如此决定性地把他们赶回去
以至于他们会想要乞求和平...
but rather to turn them back so decisively
that they would want to sue for peace...

274
00:30:45,802 --> 00:30:52,599
一个会给他喘息空间的和平 以赶在
俄国人太过靠近柏林前 阻止他们的推进
a peace that would give him a breathing space to stem
the Russian advance before it got too close to Berlin.

275
00:30:54,644 --> 00:30:56,728
这就是他的幻想
Such was his fantasy.

276
00:30:57,800 --> 00:31:04,987
也是为了那个目的,在诺曼底(坦克)被大量摧毁
之后,他一直在保存他的坦克,重新装备它们
To that end, too,he'd been conserving his panzers,
re-equipping them after their mauling in Normandy.

277
00:31:05,071 --> 00:31:06,864
但在哪里发动攻击?
But where to strike?

278
00:31:09,993 --> 00:31:11,869
1944年的那个秋天,
That autumn of 1944,

279
00:31:11,953 --> 00:31:16,300
西线的盟军已沿着一条1,000
英里的战线靠近了德国边境,
the Allies in the west had closed up to
the German border along a 1,000-mile front,

280
00:31:16,300 --> 00:31:20,502
并甚至已在一两个地方穿过了齐格菲防线
and had even penetrated
the Siegfried line in one or two places.

281
00:31:20,587 --> 00:31:25,591
但补给仍是一个问题,
因为安特卫普(港)仍没有开放
But supply still remained a problem,
for Antwerp was not yet open.

282
00:31:25,675 --> 00:31:29,094
但在安特卫普的北面
有一大支英国部队
To the north of Antwerp lay
the bulk of the British forces.

283
00:31:29,178 --> 00:31:33,515
如果,通过一次大胆的打击,希特勒
能占领安特卫普 并到达大海,
lf, by a daring blow, Hitler could
capture Antwerp and reach the sea,

284
00:31:33,600 --> 00:31:36,852
他就不仅能除掉盟军的主要补给港口,
he would not only eliminate
the Allies' main supply port,

285
00:31:36,936 --> 00:31:39,396
他还能把盟军一切为二,
he would also have split
the Allies in two,

286
00:31:39,480 --> 00:31:43,859
而英国人可能不得不再次
考虑接受一次敦刻尔克(撤退)
and the British might once again
have to contemplate a Dunkirk.

287
00:31:43,943 --> 00:31:47,154
艾森豪威尔,在派兵守卫
他那1,000英里长的战线时,
Eisenhower,in manning his 1,000-mile front,

288
00:31:47,238 --> 00:31:49,600
在一些地方 不得不把
他的部队分散得(相对)薄弱
had had to spread his forces
thinly in places.

289
00:31:49,600 --> 00:31:55,412
其中这样一个地方离安特卫普
只有125英里远...阿登(森林),
One such place was just 125 miles
from Antwerp... the Ardennes,

290
00:31:55,496 --> 00:31:59,666
对希特勒来说,(这地方)是
1940年不可思议的,神秘的回忆
of 1940 magical, mystical
memory for Hitler.

291
00:31:59,751 --> 00:32:03,587
要是历史能够为了他而重复(那有多好啊)
lf only history could repeat itself for him.

292
00:32:08,200 --> 00:32:13,805
在战争中,你必须记得 你不可能在哪儿都很强大
(De Guingand) In war, one must remember
that you can't be strong everywhere.

293
00:32:13,890 --> 00:32:19,436
第12集团军群,布莱德利的集团军群,
被赋予了某些任务
12th Army Group, Bradley's army group,
were given certain tasks.

294
00:32:19,520 --> 00:32:25,275
所以他必须决定 在哪里他将会
强一点,在哪里他将会弱一点
And therefore he had to decide where he was
going to be strong,and where he would be weak.

295
00:32:25,360 --> 00:32:32,324
而他评估了局势 并决定在阿登地区摊薄兵力
And he assessed the situation and decided
he'd thin out on the Ardennes sector.

296
00:32:42,961 --> 00:32:50,175
我们被一些在我们接管的
房子里住过的老兵告知...
We were told by some of the men
who were in the houses that we took over

297
00:32:50,259 --> 00:32:54,596
这是一个非常安静的地区,没什么事情发生
that it was a very quiet sector,
nothing happened.

298
00:32:54,681 --> 00:32:57,265
偶尔会有一支巡逻队会被派出去(巡逻)
Once in a while a patrol was sent out.

299
00:32:57,350 --> 00:33:02,020
他们有时候会听到很远地方的一声枪响,
They would hear sometimes
the crackling of a gun in the distance,

300
00:33:02,105 --> 00:33:05,315
然后...什么事都没有
and... well, there was nothing to it.

301
00:33:17,537 --> 00:33:22,958
我...不算很菜,
l was... not exactly green,

302
00:33:23,042 --> 00:33:30,590
但我们这支部队中 没有
多少人有过什么战斗经验
but there weren't too many in our particular unit
that had had much in the way of any combat experience.

303
00:33:42,400 --> 00:33:51,300
(齐格弗里德·韦斯特法尔将军 西线德军总参谋长)
10月24日,我授命到希特勒在东普鲁士的总部来见他,
On October 24,l was ordered to come to Hitler,
to his headquarters in East Prussia.

304
00:33:51,300 --> 00:34:01,700
他向我和陪同我一起前来的中央集团军群总参谋长
(汉斯·)克莱勃斯将军详尽阐述(了他的计划),
And he developed me and General Krebs,the chief
of the army group in the centre, who accompanied me,

305
00:34:01,700 --> 00:34:10,005
我们会在11月底或12月初得到强力增援
that we would get,end of November or beginning
of December, strong reinforcements.

306
00:34:10,089 --> 00:34:19,848
他定下了...20个步兵师,10个装甲师,
和许多其他特别的部队,
He named... twenty infantry divisions,ten armoured
divisions,and a lot of other special troops,

307
00:34:19,932 --> 00:34:27,647
而且他保证我们会得到空军的支援,大约有3,000架飞机
and he promised that we would be supported
by the air force,with about 3,000 planes.

308
00:34:29,901 --> 00:34:33,000
但我们完全大吃一惊
But we were totally surprised.

309
00:34:33,100 --> 00:34:41,700
(哈索·冯·曼陀菲尔上将 德国第5装甲集团军司令)
他解释说(战役的)目标,安特卫普和布鲁塞尔,是有几分风险,
He explained that the objectives,Antwerp
and Brussels,were something of a risk,

310
00:34:41,700 --> 00:34:49,294
并可能似乎超出了可动用部队的能力和他们的状况
and might seem beyond the capacity of
the forces available,and their condition.

311
00:34:49,378 --> 00:34:54,716
然而,他已决定要孤注一掷,
Nevertheless, he had decided
to stake everything on one card,

312
00:34:54,801 --> 00:34:58,887
因为德国需要一个喘息空间
because Germany needed a breathing space.

313
00:34:58,971 --> 00:35:03,433
一次防御战役,他说,只能推迟这个决定,
A defence struggle, he said,
could only postpone the decision,

314
00:35:03,518 --> 00:35:07,062
而不会改变德国的整体局势
and not change the general situation for Germany.

315
00:35:14,028 --> 00:35:20,000
为了他在阿登的进攻,希特勒,在未被盟军
知晓的情况下,已聚集了超过50万的部队
For his attack in the Ardennes, Hitler, unknown to the
Allies, had assembled more than half a million troops.

316
00:35:20,000 --> 00:35:25,372
面对他们的只是8万装备很差,没有经验的美国人
Opposing them were just 80,000
ill-equipped, inexperienced Americans.

317
00:35:25,456 --> 00:35:29,167
这似乎就象是1940年5月的重演
lt seemed like May 1940 all over again.

318
00:35:34,340 --> 00:35:39,800
德国攻击部队的士气很高,
(Manteuffel) The morale of the German
attacking forces was high,

319
00:35:39,800 --> 00:35:47,602
而在我看来,这弥补了我们
在武器和人力上的相对弱势
and this compensated, in my opinion,for our
comparative weakness in weapon and in manpower.

320
00:35:48,354 --> 00:35:53,942
我们看到了这次部队的集结...大量的坦克,
We saw this build-up of forces...
tanks in great number,

321
00:35:54,026 --> 00:35:58,738
比我们在过去两年中见到的坦克更多
more tanks than we had seen
in the last two years.

322
00:35:58,823 --> 00:36:01,491
我们甚至看到飞机,
We even saw aircraft,

323
00:36:01,576 --> 00:36:07,914
然后我们看到 准备工作被很好地保密着
and then we saw that the preparations
were well kept in secrecy.

324
00:36:08,833 --> 00:36:11,168
"零日"...零日...
"Null Day"... Zero Day...

325
00:36:11,252 --> 00:36:13,378
12月16日,来临了
December 16, arrived.

326
00:36:26,642 --> 00:36:28,393
(德语)开火!
Feuer!

327
00:36:39,100 --> 00:36:46,000
弹幕攻击持续了一个小时,并给盟军尝到了
几个月前他们在卡西诺(修道院),
The barrage lasted an hour,and gave the Allies a taste of
what they had themselves meted out at Cassino some months,

328
00:36:46,000 --> 00:36:49,831
以及几年前在阿尔阿拉曼给予
(德国人狂轰滥炸)的滋味
and at El Alamein some years, before.

329
00:36:53,878 --> 00:36:57,088
德国人在西线的最后一次大规模进攻开始了
The last great attack of the
Germans in the west had begun.

330
00:36:57,215 --> 00:37:00,800
希特勒最孤注一掷的赌博开场了
Hitler's most desperate gamble was on.

331
00:37:06,807 --> 00:37:09,000
作为一个普通的士兵,
一切都在路上,
As a simple soldier,
everything is on the road,

332
00:37:09,000 --> 00:37:13,100
而你以为这些是比他们
(的实际数量)更多的师团
and you think these are
more divisions than they are.

333
00:37:13,100 --> 00:37:18,318
所以我们有种感觉 那就是这支部队的集结
Therefore we had the feeling
that this build-up of force

334
00:37:18,402 --> 00:37:24,199
可能会使我们到达最终
的目标,也就是安特卫普
might enable us to reach the final goal,
which was Antwerp.

335
00:37:24,909 --> 00:37:27,410
天气多雾
The weather was foggy.

336
00:37:27,495 --> 00:37:35,377
美国和英国的空中优势在那种天气里不起作用,
The American and British air superiority
didn't matter in that type of weather,

337
00:37:35,461 --> 00:37:40,423
所以我们相信我们能够成功
and therefore we believed
that we would be successful.

338
00:37:49,517 --> 00:37:51,393
(进攻)完全出乎意料
Surprise was total.

339
00:37:51,477 --> 00:37:54,562
它是盟军方面极其混乱的一天的开始,
It was the beginning of a day of
monumental confusion for the Allies,

340
00:37:54,647 --> 00:37:58,200
在整场欧洲战争中他们经历的最糟糕一天
the worst they experienced
in the whole European war.

341
00:38:06,300 --> 00:38:12,000
甚至当德国国防军的第一攻击波
正沿着阿登地区蹂躏美军阵地时,
Even as the first Wehrmacht waves were overrunning
the American positions along the Ardennes,

342
00:38:12,000 --> 00:38:18,400
在位于(法国)凡尔赛的盟军总部里 谈论的话题
还更多地集中在(爵士)乐队领袖格伦·米勒之死上
talk at Allied headquarters back at Versailles was focused
more on the news of band leader Glenn Miller's death

343
00:38:18,400 --> 00:38:24,384
而不在(这是)自1940年以来
德军最大的攻势的可能性上
than of the possibility of the biggest
German offensive in the west since 1940.

344
00:38:24,468 --> 00:38:28,500
这一天艾森豪威尔被提升为五星将军,
lt was the day Eisenhower
was promoted five-star general,

345
00:38:28,500 --> 00:38:34,769
而蒙哥马利元帅碰巧在这天申请休假回英国过圣诞节
and the day Field Marshal Montgomery happened to
apply for leave to go home to England for Christmas.

346
00:38:34,854 --> 00:38:38,440
事实上 那天上午 艾克正在参加他的司机的婚礼,
Ike was,in fact,attending his
chauffeur's wedding that morning,

347
00:38:38,524 --> 00:38:41,401
而蒙蒂在打高尔夫球
while Monty was playing golf.

348
00:38:41,485 --> 00:38:46,531
随着这天慢慢过去,(局势)
变得和1940年5月越来越象
As the day wore on,
the resemblances to May 1940 grew.

349
00:38:46,615 --> 00:38:49,868
压倒性的德国武力,他们毫不减弱的速度,
The overwhelming German might,
their relentless speed,

350
00:38:49,952 --> 00:38:52,370
尤其是在盟军后方一片混乱,
above all the chaos in the Allied rear,

351
00:38:52,455 --> 00:38:55,749
因为茫然失措,没有经验的部队
冲向安全的地方,
as bewildered, untried troops
dashed for safety,

352
00:38:55,833 --> 00:39:00,420
堵住了公路 并妨碍增援部队抵达前线
clogging the roads and preventing
reinforcements reaching the front.

353
00:39:00,504 --> 00:39:07,635
一个流言四处传播 那就是美国人
将把一部分战俘交给俄国人,
A rumour was spread that the Americans would hand
over part of the prisoners of war to the Russians,

354
00:39:07,720 --> 00:39:13,433
而那帮助鼓舞了士气和战斗的意志
and that helped to build up morale
and the will to fight.

355
00:39:18,272 --> 00:39:21,107
7,000个美国兵一口气一起投降了
(美军第106步兵师第422,423团),
7,000 Americans surrendered in one go,

356
00:39:21,192 --> 00:39:26,000
欧洲战役中美军最大的一次大规模投降
the biggest mass surrender of
American arms in the European campaign.

357
00:39:32,995 --> 00:39:36,581
德国新闻片的摄影师在战场上忙了一天
German newsreel cameramen had a field day.

358
00:39:54,892 --> 00:40:00,105
在我们所在的地区 雾散开了一些,
The fog was lifting a little bit
in the area where we were,

359
00:40:00,189 --> 00:40:06,569
但到了大约12点钟,我们发现
我们再也不能走得更远了,
but by about 12 o'clock, we found
that we couldn't go any further,

360
00:40:06,654 --> 00:40:10,407
这只是一个投降的问题了
that it was just a question
of surrendering.

361
00:40:13,869 --> 00:40:19,833
中尉下去和负责的德国军官安排投降事宜,
The lieutenant went down and made arrangements
with the German officer in charge,

362
00:40:19,917 --> 00:40:29,717
回上来并告诉我们 我们有一个
小时来拆卸和摧毁我们的武器
and came back up and told us that we had one
hour to dismantle and destroy our weapons,

363
00:40:29,802 --> 00:40:33,972
或挖洞并埋藏我们想要埋藏的东西,
or dig holes and bury
whatever we wanted to bury,

364
00:40:34,056 --> 00:40:38,268
并准备在一小时里走下那座山
and be ready to come off that hill
within one hour.

365
00:40:43,065 --> 00:40:47,861
第一批美国战俘不知道发生了什么
The first American prisoners
didn't know what was going on.

366
00:40:47,945 --> 00:40:51,072
他们走向我们,问我们要面包,
而我们有足够多的面包,
They came to us, asked for bread,
and we had bread enough,

367
00:40:51,157 --> 00:40:55,285
所以我们给他们面包
而他们给我们巧克力
so we gave them bread
and they gave us chocolate.

368
00:41:39,622 --> 00:41:43,100
两三天后,
After two or three days,

369
00:41:43,100 --> 00:41:51,633
我们已经看到 美国部队的抵抗比我们以为的要更顽强
we already saw that the resistance of the American
troops was stronger than we had believed.

370
00:41:56,800 --> 00:42:03,000
他们起初能突破的原因 是因为
我们得不到战斗轰炸机的支援
The reason they had been able to break through in the
first place was that we could get no fighter-bomber support.

371
00:42:03,000 --> 00:42:05,400
天气(多云,云)就压在树梢上,
The weather was sitting
right on the treetops,

372
00:42:05,400 --> 00:42:11,486
我们从空中看不到他们任何移动的部队
and we couldn't pick up any of
their moving troops from the air.

373
00:42:11,570 --> 00:42:15,990
但在圣诞夜(那天),云散了,
But on Christmas Eve, the clouds lifted,

374
00:42:17,952 --> 00:42:20,700
之后战斗轰炸机飞了过来,
and thereafter the fighter-bombers came in,

375
00:42:20,700 --> 00:42:25,083
而他们就那么摧毁了德国坦克
and they simply destroyed the German armour.

376
00:42:40,307 --> 00:42:43,100
曼陀菲尔的装甲部队耗尽了汽油,
Manteuffel's panzers had run out of petrol,

377
00:42:43,100 --> 00:42:46,500
离安特卫普仍有大约70英里远
still some 70 miles short of Antwerp.

378
00:42:46,500 --> 00:42:51,985
(由于)不能开动,它们成了盟军飞机的活靶子
Motionless, they were sitting ducks
for the Allied planes.

379
00:42:57,741 --> 00:42:59,100
"这是场大屠杀",
"lt was a great slaughter",

380
00:42:59,100 --> 00:43:02,745
一位美国师长在他的报告中写道
the American divisional commander
wrote in his report.

381
00:43:02,830 --> 00:43:07,417
对希特勒来说,这不只是结束的开始
For Hitler, it was more
than the beginning of the end.

382
00:43:10,400 --> 00:43:13,300
这次攻势的失败影响了士气,
(Manteuffel) The failure of
this offensive affected morale,

383
00:43:13,300 --> 00:43:19,262
所以,士兵们和平民都表现得相同
and, therefore, the behaviour of
the soldiers and the civilians alike.

384
00:43:19,346 --> 00:43:24,726
这样 我们促成了战争的加速结束
Thus we have contributed
to speeding the end of the war.

385
00:43:26,228 --> 00:43:28,855
随着德国攻势确切地被止住,
With the German offensive definitely halted,

386
00:43:28,939 --> 00:43:31,400
美国人从南面 英国人从北面
Americans from the south
and British from the north

387
00:43:31,400 --> 00:43:35,000
对在阿登前线内形成的突出部进行挤压...
pressed on the bulge that had been
formed within the Ardennes front...

388
00:43:35,000 --> 00:43:40,033
这个突出部也给了这场战役它的俗称
("突出部战役",也称"阿登反击战"或"守望莱茵"行动)
the bulge that gave this particular
battle its popular name.

389
00:43:40,993 --> 00:43:44,100
他们在1945年1月中旬会师,
They met in mid-January 1945,

390
00:43:44,100 --> 00:43:48,200
到此时德军已处于完全的混乱之中,
by which time the German army
was in total disarray,

391
00:43:48,200 --> 00:43:51,700
因为俄国的冬季攻势已在四天前开始
for the Russian winter offensive
had begun four days before.

392
00:43:51,700 --> 00:43:57,300
现在 希特勒在西线的赌博
被看作是极度的愚蠢,
Now Hitler's gamble in the west
was seen to be supreme folly,

393
00:43:57,300 --> 00:44:01,971
因为,为了进行这场赌博,
他剥光了他在东线的防御
for, to do it, he had denuded
his defences in the east.

394
00:44:09,938 --> 00:44:16,694
随着其精心囤积的燃料和装备,
当然还有人员的储备(全都)报销
With its carefully hoarded reserves of fuel
and equipment and, of course, of men too, gone,

395
00:44:16,779 --> 00:44:20,573
德国战争机器开始瓦解
the German war machine
began to disintegrate.

396
00:45:01,200 --> 00:45:11,200
我要说希特勒在突出部的进攻
使战争提早了大概六个月结束
l would say that Hitler's attack in the Bulge
brought the war to an end perhaps six months
earlier than it would otherwise have ended.

397
00:45:11,200 --> 00:45:16,879
(约瑟夫·劳顿·柯林斯将军 美国第七军军长)
因为德国人本可以撤退过莱茵河的,而这是一个真正的障碍
because the Germans could have fallen back
to the Rhine,which was a real obstacle.

398
00:45:17,005 --> 00:45:20,400
(约瑟夫·劳顿·柯林斯将军 美国第七军军长)
但他们没有什么力量来守莱茵河了,因为基本上来说,
But they had nothing with which
to hold the Rhine, because essentially,

399
00:45:20,400 --> 00:45:25,805
德国陆军的后备队,机动部队和预备队,
the German army,the reserves of the German army,
the mobile troops and the reserves of the Germany army,

400
00:45:25,889 --> 00:45:28,307
都在突出部战役中被摧毁了
were destroyed in the battle of the Bulge.

401
00:45:28,392 --> 00:45:31,602
德国士兵筋疲力尽,
The German soldier was exhausted,

402
00:45:31,687 --> 00:45:36,983
他只有一个愿望:结束战争
and he had only one desire:
to end the war.

403
00:45:37,067 --> 00:45:42,488
但他还是愿意继续战斗,
But he was willing to fight on,

404
00:45:42,573 --> 00:45:46,993
来掩护东线的后方
to cover the rear of the Eastern Front.

405
00:45:48,954 --> 00:45:51,600
1945年1月20日,
On January 20, 1945,

406
00:45:51,600 --> 00:45:55,418
朱可夫的坦克第一次进入了德国本土,
Zhukov's tanks entered Germany proper
for the first time,

407
00:45:55,502 --> 00:45:58,000
离柏林仅有100公里远,
a mere 100 miles from Berlin,

408
00:45:58,000 --> 00:46:05,094
为了庆祝这一特殊时刻,(俄国人)对看得到
的每个村庄都进行了一次特别野蛮的洗劫
the occasion being celebrated by a particularly
savage sacking of every village in sight.

409
00:46:17,800 --> 00:46:24,864
很快,成千上万的德国平民涌上向西
的道路,远离令人畏惧的俄国人,
Soon, thousands upon thousands of German civilians took
to the roads westwards,away from the dreaded Russians,

410
00:46:24,948 --> 00:46:31,621
这场景令人回想起五年前法国和
比利时难民组成的那些长长的行列
producing scenes reminiscent of those long lines
of French and Belgian refugees five years before.

411
00:46:49,765 --> 00:46:51,500
随着盟军的轰炸加剧,
As the Allied bombing intensified,

412
00:46:51,500 --> 00:46:54,600
越来越多的德国城市被炸成一片瓦砾
more and more German cities
were reduced to rubble.

413
00:46:54,600 --> 00:46:59,565
在《我的奋斗》中,希特勒写道,
"即使我们不能征服,
ln Mein Kampf, Hitler had written,
"Even if we cannot conquer,

414
00:46:59,650 --> 00:47:03,444
我们也应该把世界拖入毁灭"
we shall drag the world
into destruction with us."

415
00:47:16,625 --> 00:47:21,879
在整个三月,在柏林都能听到俄国人的炮声
All during March, the Russian guns
could be heard in Berlin.

416
00:47:49,600 --> 00:47:53,995
然后他们来找我 并说,"你想要把
克莱沃城(德国西北城市)干掉吗?"
(Horrocks) Then they came to me and said,
"Do you want the town Cleves taking out?"

417
00:47:54,079 --> 00:47:58,300
这里的"干掉"他们是指
派重型轰炸机去炸掉克莱沃
By "taking out" they meant all
the heavy bombers putting on to Cleves.

418
00:47:58,600 --> 00:48:04,255
我知道克莱沃是一个古老的德国历史名城
Now, I knew that Cleves was a fine
old historical German town.

419
00:48:05,215 --> 00:48:09,594
克莱沃的安妮,(英国)亨利八世
的妻子之一,就来自那里
Anne of Cleves, one of Henry
VIII's wives, came from there.

420
00:48:09,678 --> 00:48:15,000
我知道在克莱沃有许多平民,男人,女人和孩子
l knew that there were a lot of civilians
in Cleves,men, women and children.

421
00:48:15,100 --> 00:48:19,103
如果我说不,他们就会活
如果我说行,他们就会死
lf I said no, they would live.
lf I said yes, they would die.

422
00:48:19,229 --> 00:48:21,000
一个你必须作出的可怕决定
A terrible decision you've got to take.

423
00:48:21,000 --> 00:48:28,404
但一切都有赖于在马特伯恩(位于
克莱沃西南的小镇)得到一片高地
But everything depended on getting
a high piece of ground at Materborn.

424
00:48:28,488 --> 00:48:31,741
德国预备队必须穿过克莱沃,
The German reserves would
have to come through Cleves,

425
00:48:31,825 --> 00:48:35,286
而我们必须突破齐格菲防线 并到达那里
and we would have to breach
the Siegfried line and get there.

426
00:48:35,370 --> 00:48:38,100
你自己的生命,你自己的部队,必须放在首位,
And your own lives, your own troops,
must come first,

427
00:48:38,100 --> 00:48:41,700
所以我说行,我想要干掉它
so I said yes, I did want it taking out.

428
00:48:42,100 --> 00:48:49,508
但当那晚 就在零时前 所有那些
轰炸机飞过去...去干掉克莱沃时,
But when all those bombers went over the night...
just before zero hour,to take out Cleves,

429
00:48:49,593 --> 00:48:52,011
我感觉就象个谋杀犯
l felt a murderer.

430
00:48:52,095 --> 00:48:57,475
在战后 我做过非常多的噩梦
一直是(梦到)克莱沃
And after the war I had an awful lot
of nightmares. lt was always Cleves.

431
00:49:24,836 --> 00:49:28,400
莱茵河以西的城市一个接
一个地被扫清了德国部队...
One after another, the cities west of
the Rhine were cleared of German troops...

432
00:49:28,400 --> 00:49:33,761
波恩,科布伦茨,美因茨,当然,还有科隆
Bonn, Koblenz, Mainz
and, of course, Cologne.

433
00:50:37,200 --> 00:50:43,600
到3月22日,不再有德国士兵
在莱茵河以西战斗
By March 22, no German soldier
fought west of the Rhine.

434
00:50:58,200 --> 00:51:04,977
现在只有莱茵河横亘于西线盟军
和希特勒德国的心脏地带之间
Only the Rhine now lay between the Western
Allies and the heartland of Hitler's Germany.

435
00:51:05,062 --> 00:51:08,564
跨越它的准备工作立即开始
Preparations began straightaway to cross it.

436
00:51:26,300 --> 00:51:28,000
安恒复仇者

437
00:53:07,350 --> 00:53:15,524
那晚9点,我记得我坐在一个指挥所里在等待,
(Horrocks) At nine o'clock in the evening,
I remember waiting,sitting in a command post.

438
00:53:15,609 --> 00:53:20,400
然后传来了苏格兰高地
警卫团越过莱菌河的消息
Then the news came through that
the Black Watch were over the Rhine.

439
00:53:20,500 --> 00:53:24,503
在某种程度上,相当历史性(的时刻),你知道
他们越过了莱茵河
Rather historic, you know, in a way.
They were over the Rhine.

