1
00:00:11,344 --> 00:00:16,015
我希望美国将置身于这场战争之外
I hope the United States
will keep out of this war.

2
00:00:16,099 --> 00:00:19,101
我相信会这样的
I believe that it will.

3
00:00:19,185 --> 00:00:22,521
而我给你们保证和再保证
And I give you assurance and reassurance

4
00:00:22,605 --> 00:00:28,736
你们政府的每项努力都将被引向那个目标
that every effort of your government
will be directed toward that end.

5
00:00:28,820 --> 00:00:34,825
只要防范(被卷入战争)
仍是我职权范围里的事,
As long as it remains
within my power to prevent,

6
00:00:34,909 --> 00:00:40,706
和平就不会在美国消失
there will be no blackout of peace
in the United States.

7
00:01:37,500 --> 00:01:42,518
在第一次世界大战后
有一股孤立主义的浪潮,
After World War I there was
a surge of isolationism,

8
00:01:42,602 --> 00:01:47,106
一种我们没理由被卷入一战的感觉
a feeling we had no reason
to become involved in World War I

9
00:01:47,190 --> 00:01:49,066
而我们(参加一战是)犯了一个错
and we'd made a mistake

10
00:01:49,150 --> 00:01:53,862
而且欧洲国家欠了许多债,
and there were a lot of debts owed
by European countries,

11
00:01:53,947 --> 00:01:56,198
整个国家变得孤立主义盛行
and the country went isolationist.

12
00:01:56,282 --> 00:02:00,077
我对欧洲事务没有丝毫概念
I haven't the slightest idea
of European affairs.

13
00:02:00,161 --> 00:02:02,700
- 让欧洲打他们自己的仗去吧
- 另一场战争? 我可不要
- Let Europe fight their own battles.
- Another war? Not for me.

14
00:02:02,700 --> 00:02:05,916
这次美国应该置身事外...
我知道我会的
This time America should keep out...
and I know I will.

15
00:02:06,000 --> 00:02:07,500
如果战争在欧洲爆发,
lf war breaks out in Europe,

16
00:02:07,500 --> 00:02:11,421
我说这个国家应该听从其第一位总统的建议
I say that this country should heed
the advice of its first president

17
00:02:11,506 --> 00:02:13,966
避免所有和外国的牵连
and avoid all foreign entanglement.

18
00:02:15,176 --> 00:02:19,930
1940年初,英国驻华盛顿大使报告称
In early 1940, Britain's
ambassador in Washington reported

19
00:02:20,014 --> 00:02:24,768
十个美国人中的九个都决心
不让美国参与这场战争
that nine out of ten Americans were
determined to keep America out of the war.

20
00:02:24,853 --> 00:02:27,000
一些人,像美国纳粹党,
A few, like the American Nazi Party,

21
00:02:27,000 --> 00:02:30,149
甚至决定美国应该帮助英国的敌人
would even determined that America
should aid Britain's enemies.

22
00:02:47,959 --> 00:02:50,836
这个国家处于极大地分裂之中
The country was enormously divided.

23
00:02:50,920 --> 00:02:55,000
有一个鼓吹孤立主义的"美国第一"运动
There was the America First movement,
which was advocating isolationism;

24
00:02:55,000 --> 00:03:02,347
在另一方面,有"威廉·艾伦·瓦特委员会"
即"通过援助同盟国来保卫美国委员会"
on the other hand there was the William Allen White Committe,
the Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies.

25
00:03:02,432 --> 00:03:07,686
我们有这些稀奇古怪的的声音,比如
查尔斯·林德伯格的,孤立主义的声音
We had these curious voices such as Charles Lindbergh's,
and so on,which was the voices of isolationism.

26
00:03:07,770 --> 00:03:13,442
在过去,我们与一个被英国和法国
所主导的欧洲打交道
In the past, we have dealt with a Europe
dominated by England and France.

27
00:03:13,526 --> 00:03:18,614
在未来,我们可能不得不与
一个被德国主导的欧洲打交道
In the future, we may have to deal
with a Europe dominated by Germany.

28
00:03:18,698 --> 00:03:22,576
查尔斯·林德伯格,由于他的非凡成就,
(首位单人不着陆飞越大西洋的飞行员)
Charles Lindbergh, thanks to
his extraordinary exploit,

29
00:03:22,660 --> 00:03:26,163
他是个非常受欢迎的人物...
他几乎就是一个民族英雄
was a very popular figure...
he was almost a folk hero.

30
00:03:26,247 --> 00:03:28,207
所以他会有影响力
So he would have influence.

31
00:03:28,333 --> 00:03:32,252
我想所有的名人都有影响力,
l suppose that celebrities of
all characters do have influence,

32
00:03:32,337 --> 00:03:35,756
否则他们不会一直为产品代言
otherwise they wouldn't be
endorsing products all the time.

33
00:03:35,840 --> 00:03:40,093
...但是不该卷入欧洲的内部事务
(Lindbergh) ..but it should not involve
the internal affairs of Europe.

34
00:03:40,178 --> 00:03:46,475
它们过去不曾,将来也永远不会,
按照我们的愿望来继续下去
They never were, and never will be,
carried on according to our desires.

35
00:03:50,021 --> 00:03:54,691
在这国家的一些地方有一种
很强的反英的厌恶情绪
There was a strong anti-British antipathy
in certain parts of the country.

36
00:03:54,776 --> 00:04:00,197
(这些人)感觉英国正想方设法
把我们拖入它的战争
It was felt that Britain was trying
very hard to drag us into its war.

37
00:04:08,373 --> 00:04:12,251
1940年在美国是总统大选年
1940 was presidential
election year in the United States

38
00:04:12,335 --> 00:04:16,546
罗斯福那个夏天主要关心的
就是使他自己获选连任
and Roosevelt's main concern that summer
was to get himself re-elected.

39
00:04:20,426 --> 00:04:22,469
女士们先生们,
Ladies and gentlemen,

40
00:04:22,553 --> 00:04:29,559
第22次共和党全国大会现在就要开始了
the 22nd convention of the
Republican Party will now come to order.

41
00:04:29,644 --> 00:04:35,524
正当我们相会的时候,
灯火正在欧洲熄灭
Even as we meet,
lights are going out in Europe.

42
00:04:35,650 --> 00:04:41,905
独裁者们的灯火管制取代了
自由的人们的灯塔
Blackouts of dictators take the place
of lighthouses of free men.

43
00:04:41,990 --> 00:04:49,371
我们的(任务)是保护自由
的灯塔这个严峻的责任
Ours is the grave responsibility
to preserve the lighthouses of liberty.

44
00:04:49,455 --> 00:04:54,042
以人民的名义...
In the name of the people...

45
00:04:54,127 --> 00:04:57,462
以整个美国的名义...
of the whole United States...

46
00:04:57,547 --> 00:05:01,091
我提名...
l place in nomination...

47
00:05:01,175 --> 00:05:04,720
那位勇敢的美国人...
that valiant American...

48
00:05:04,804 --> 00:05:08,765
富兰克林·德拉诺·罗斯福!
Franklin Delano Roosevelt!

49
00:05:10,143 --> 00:05:11,977
法国沦陷后,
After France's fall,

50
00:05:12,061 --> 00:05:15,188
大多数美国人都倾向于
以某种方式帮助英国人,
most Americans were disposed
to aid Britain in some way,

51
00:05:15,273 --> 00:05:19,609
但更多的人强烈反对
加入到英国这边参加战争
but still more were strongly opposed
to entering the war on Britain's side.

52
00:05:19,694 --> 00:05:22,237
...第三任期的候选人
(Willkie) ..third-term candidate

53
00:05:22,322 --> 00:05:25,490
没有对美国人民守信
has not kept faith
with the American people.

54
00:05:25,575 --> 00:05:29,119
那个秋天罗斯福在总统竞选中的对手
Roosevelt's opponent in the
presidential election that autumn

55
00:05:29,203 --> 00:05:33,582
是个彻底反战的候选人温德尔·威尔基
was an out-and-out anti-war candidate,
Wendell Willkie.

56
00:05:34,500 --> 00:05:43,842
如果他保证不让我们的孩子们去打外国战争的承诺
并不比他保证要平衡预算的承诺好多少的话,
If his promise to keep our boys out of foreign wars
is no better than his promise to balance the budget,

57
00:05:43,926 --> 00:05:48,263
他们几乎已经在运输船上了
they're already
almost on the transports.

58
00:05:51,100 --> 00:05:54,100
但随着纳粹到处取得胜利,
But with the Nazis
triumphant everywhere,

59
00:05:54,100 --> 00:06:01,068
罗斯福负担不起等到竞选连任后
才让美国转入某种形式的战争状态
Roosevelt couldn't afford to wait to be re-elected
before putting America on some sort of war footing.

60
00:06:01,152 --> 00:06:08,200
国会已经不分党派地讨论过
并于现在通过一个法案
The Congress has debated without
partisanship and has now enacted a law

61
00:06:08,284 --> 00:06:13,997
建立一种扩充我们的武装部队的选取办法
establishing a selective method
of augmenting our armed forces.

62
00:06:14,082 --> 00:06:20,295
我们必须,而且我们将会,
集结我们的伟大潜在力量
We must, and we will,
marshal our great potential strength

63
00:06:20,380 --> 00:06:24,508
来把战争挡在我们的海岸外
to fend off war from our shores.

64
00:06:26,803 --> 00:06:30,055
超过1600万年轻美国人
More than 16 million young Americans

65
00:06:30,139 --> 00:06:35,894
正在恢复有300年历史的美国集结(征兵)传统,
are reviving the 300-year-old
American custom of the muster,

66
00:06:35,978 --> 00:06:39,481
在这种传统下,从最早的殖民时代起,
by which,from the earliest colonial times,

67
00:06:39,565 --> 00:06:46,613
每一个身体合格的公民都要服从
在国防军中服役的号召
every able-bodied citizen was subject to
the call for service in the national defence.

68
00:06:57,917 --> 00:07:04,089
战争部长抽取的第一个号码
The first number
drawn by the secretary of war

69
00:07:04,173 --> 00:07:09,553
是序号158
is serial number 158.

70
00:07:12,056 --> 00:07:14,975
我很荣幸成为那些被第一批召唤的一员
I am honoured to be one
of those first called

71
00:07:15,059 --> 00:07:18,770
我将竭尽全力成为一个真正的好士兵
and l'll try very hard
to make a real good soldier.

72
00:07:18,855 --> 00:07:20,897
我为你感到骄傲
And l'm proud of you.

73
00:07:20,982 --> 00:07:24,568
如果你们选我当美国总统,
(Willkie) lf you elect me
president of the United States,

74
00:07:24,652 --> 00:07:31,867
我将永远不会派一个美国男孩
去打任何欧洲战争
I shall never send an American boy
to fight in any European war.

75
00:07:33,661 --> 00:07:40,375
我认为用事实来回答歪曲(事实)
是一个公共职责
I consider it a public duty
to answer falsifications with facts.

76
00:07:40,460 --> 00:07:46,756
我不会装作 我发现这是个令人不快的职责
I will not pretend
that I find this an unpleasant duty.

77
00:07:52,096 --> 00:07:57,392
我是个竞选老手 我喜欢激烈的竞争
I am an old campaigner
and I love a good fight.

78
00:07:59,979 --> 00:08:02,939
罗斯福得到了他(想要)的激烈竞争,
Roosevelt got his good fight,

79
00:08:03,024 --> 00:08:11,198
尽管为了要留在比赛中(不被淘汰),他也和他的
对手一样,保证不把美国男孩送去打外国战争
though to stay in the race he had promised,
like his opponent,not to send American boys
to fight in foreign wars.

80
00:08:12,200 --> 00:08:14,743
- 请报名字?
- 富兰克林·D·罗斯福
- Name, please?
- Franklin D Roosevelt.

81
00:08:15,870 --> 00:08:19,039
1940年11月5日是选举日,
November 5, 1940, was election day,

82
00:08:19,123 --> 00:08:23,877
到了午夜,美国选择谁当
接下来四年的总统的结果揭晓了
and by midnight America's choice of president
for another four years was clear.

83
00:08:23,961 --> 00:08:28,006
结果现在确定了...罗斯福获胜
The results are now conclusive...
Roosevelt wins.

84
00:08:44,148 --> 00:08:50,987
现在已成功连任,罗斯福感觉他有了(选民的)授权
来给予英国除了战争以外所有的援助
Now re-elected,Roosevelt felt he had a mandate
to give Britain all aid short of war.

85
00:08:51,072 --> 00:08:54,700
但他只能慢慢来,因为美国仍处于严重分裂中
But he could only move slowly,
for America was still deeply divided.

86
00:08:54,700 --> 00:09:03,500
许多的战争措施,比如在英国仍孤身抵抗
并被围攻的时候 给予英国援助的举措
Many of the war measures,such as steps to give aid to Britain
at the time when England was standing alone and was beleaguered,

87
00:09:03,584 --> 00:09:06,127
在国会只是被勉强通过
just squeaked by in Congress.

88
00:09:06,212 --> 00:09:12,300
甚至一个进行军事准备的军备项目,
Even a programme of armament,
of military preparedness,

89
00:09:12,385 --> 00:09:16,221
在国会也是以非常非常接近的票数通过,
got through Congress
on very, very close votes,

90
00:09:16,305 --> 00:09:21,560
在总共400票里仅以一票的优势(通过)
one-vote margins
in a total of 400 votes.

91
00:09:21,686 --> 00:09:25,021
然后那个非凡的法案,租借法案,
(Harriman) Then the extraordinary
legislation, which is Lend-Lease,

92
00:09:25,106 --> 00:09:31,236
在1940年12月被提出,
并在1941年3月成为法律,
was proposed in December of 1940
and that became law in March of '41,

93
00:09:31,320 --> 00:09:36,199
在那(租借法案)之下 总统尽其所能给英国援助
and under that the president did everything
he possibly could to give aid to Britain.

94
00:09:36,284 --> 00:09:41,600
当我过来(英国)做他的代表时 接到的指示
My instructions when I went
over to represent him

95
00:09:42,000 --> 00:09:44,374
非常简单,非常简短
were very simple, very brief.

96
00:09:44,458 --> 00:09:47,836
那就是与英国政府进行接触
They were to contact
the British government

97
00:09:47,920 --> 00:09:54,217
以发现我们能做什么来帮助英国...除了战争
to find out what we could do
to help Britain... short of war.

98
00:09:54,302 --> 00:10:01,308
我们立刻开始做各种在严格意义上并不算中立的事情...
And we began at once doing all sorts of things which
were not really neutral under the literal interpretation...

99
00:10:01,392 --> 00:10:05,854
比如,我们在美国港口制造英国海军船只
for instance, we were preparing
British naval vessels in American ports

100
00:10:05,938 --> 00:10:10,984
我们为(英国)船队穿越大西洋
提供护航 一直远至冰岛,
and we escorted all the convoys
across the Atlantic as far as lceland,

101
00:10:11,068 --> 00:10:14,529
我们(向英国)转移了两百万吨的船
and we transferred
two million tons of ships.

102
00:10:16,741 --> 00:10:20,000
当下的问题是要让人们明白这是在干什么
The immediate problem was to get people
to understand what it was.

103
00:10:20,100 --> 00:10:29,544
在这个问题上,我想罗斯福先生那个非常简单的
"在你邻居家着火时借给他一个消防水管"的类比
In this, I think Mr Roosevelt's very simple analogy of
lending your neighbour a fire hose when there's a fire

104
00:10:29,629 --> 00:10:34,174
是一个最有说服力的那种简单例证
was a most persuasive kind
of simple illustration.

105
00:10:34,258 --> 00:10:38,011
正在保卫他们自己的欧洲人民
(Roosevelt) The people of Europe
who are defending themselves

106
00:10:38,095 --> 00:10:41,973
没有要求我们帮他们战斗
do not ask us to do their fighting.

107
00:10:42,099 --> 00:10:45,518
他们向我们要的是战争工具...
They ask us for the implements of war...

108
00:10:45,603 --> 00:10:49,856
飞机,坦克,枪炮,货船...
the planes, the tanks,
the guns, the freighters...

109
00:10:49,940 --> 00:10:55,945
这些(战争工具)将能使他们为了
他们的自由和我们的安全而战斗
which will enable them to fight
for their liberty and our security.

110
00:10:56,030 --> 00:11:00,784
我们必须成为伟大的民主兵工厂
We must be the great arsenal of democracy.

111
00:11:00,868 --> 00:11:07,123
对我们来说,这是一件和战争
本身一样严重的紧急事件
For us, this is an emergency
as serious as war itself.

112
00:11:07,208 --> 00:11:19,761
在那个时候,商界将罗斯福视为,
至少,也是魔鬼的一个主要副手,
In those days, the business community regarded Roosevelt
as, at a minimum, a major deputy of the devil,

113
00:11:19,845 --> 00:11:24,265
而罗斯福也深深地怀疑商人,
and Roosevelt was deeply suspicious
of the businessmen,

114
00:11:24,350 --> 00:11:30,730
所以与战争动员有关联的人
so the people who were associated
with the mobilising of the war

115
00:11:30,815 --> 00:11:33,191
有着不同的利益
had a divided interest.

116
00:11:33,275 --> 00:11:36,945
他们中的一些人感觉呆在华盛顿的主要目的
Some of them felt that their
main purpose in being in Washington

117
00:11:37,029 --> 00:11:41,741
是为了抑制(罗斯福)新政
过度偏向社会主义
was to put a curb on the socialist
excesses of the New Deal.

118
00:11:41,826 --> 00:11:44,202
还有一些人对呆在那儿感到不自在...
Some of them were uneasy about being there...

119
00:11:44,286 --> 00:11:51,209
他们有种在妓院里演奏交响乐的人的感觉
they had something of the feeling of people
who were playing in an orchestra in a brothel.

120
00:11:51,293 --> 00:11:58,258
还有一种很大的不情愿...
And there was also
a great unwillingness...

121
00:11:58,342 --> 00:12:02,387
我们听说军事-工业综合企业...
We hear now about the
military-industrial complex...

122
00:12:02,471 --> 00:12:05,640
那时候非常不情愿...
in those days
there was a great unwillingness

123
00:12:05,725 --> 00:12:08,226
从民用工业转换(到军用工业)
to convert from civilian industry.

124
00:12:08,310 --> 00:12:13,606
有一种感觉就是生产战争物资
会是一种非常不赚钱的生意,
There was a feeling that war production
would be a very unprofitable business,

125
00:12:13,733 --> 00:12:18,695
这会失去汽车,轮胎,化学品
和诸如此类产品的市场
it would lose markets for automobiles,
for tyres, for chemicals, and so forth.

126
00:12:21,490 --> 00:12:28,204
和一些工会还有问题 直到1941年6月,
There was a problem with some of
the unions up until June of 1941.

127
00:12:28,289 --> 00:12:30,832
直到俄国加入战争,
Until Russia was in the war,

128
00:12:30,916 --> 00:12:34,127
而在莫洛托夫-里宾特洛甫
(1938年互不侵犯)条约时期,
and in the days of the
Molotov-Ribbentrop pact,

129
00:12:34,211 --> 00:12:38,089
一些工会领袖还有拖后腿的行为
there was foot-dragging on the part
of some of the union leaders.

130
00:12:38,174 --> 00:12:40,258
当时有罢工
And there were strikes.

131
00:12:40,342 --> 00:12:44,929
1941年参加罢工的工人是前一年的四倍
Four times as many workers were on strike
in 1941 as in the year before.

132
00:12:45,014 --> 00:12:49,934
那个春天,差不多50万煤矿工人罢工了几乎一个月,
That spring, nearly half a million
coal miners struck for almost a month,

133
00:12:50,019 --> 00:12:53,855
而那年夏天在西海岸 北美航空公司
(P-51,B-25的制造商,后并入波音)的一次罢工
while on the west coast a walk-out
that summer at North American Aviation

134
00:12:53,939 --> 00:12:58,318
把向英国交付飞机(的时间)延迟了几个星期
delayed deliveries of planes to Britain
for several weeks.

135
00:12:58,402 --> 00:13:02,405
要靠动用军队才使生产再次继续
lt took troops
to get production moving again.

136
00:13:13,292 --> 00:13:17,545
但尽管罗斯福仍对带领美国参战感到勉强,
But although Roosevelt was still
reluctant to lead America into war,

137
00:13:17,630 --> 00:13:20,757
战争现在还是追上了美国
the war was now
catching up with America.

138
00:13:20,841 --> 00:13:28,056
1941年6月11日:一艘美国货船,
"罗宾·摩尔"号,被一艘(德国)U型潜艇击沉
June 11th, 1941: an American freighter,
the Robin Moor, was sunk by a U-boat.

139
00:13:28,140 --> 00:13:31,351
罗斯福利用这起事件为借口占领冰岛
Roosevelt used this as a pretext
for occupying lceland

140
00:13:31,435 --> 00:13:34,562
并换了那里的英国守备部队的岗
and relieving the British garrisons there.

141
00:13:34,647 --> 00:13:40,151
9月4日:一艘美国驱逐舰,"格里尔"号,
在冰岛附近被一艘U型潜艇攻击
September 4th: a US destroyer, Greer,
was attacked by a U-boat near lceland.

142
00:13:40,236 --> 00:13:44,280
罗斯福现在告诉他的海军
看到(U型潜艇)格杀无论
Roosevelt now told his navy
to shoot on sight.

143
00:13:44,365 --> 00:13:52,000
10月16日:美国驱逐舰"科尔尼"号在大西洋中部
为一个船队护航时被一枚德国鱼雷击中,
October 16th: the US destroyer Kearney was struck by
a German torpedo while escorting a convoy in mid-Atlantic

144
00:13:52,000 --> 00:13:53,915
船上11名船员被杀
and 11 of her crew were killed.

145
00:13:53,999 --> 00:13:58,878
罗斯福利用这起事件推动国会废除中立法案
Roosevelt used this incident to push through
Congress the repeal of the Neutrality Act.

146
00:13:58,963 --> 00:14:03,132
我们已希望避免射击
We have wished to avoid shooting.

147
00:14:03,217 --> 00:14:07,178
但射击已经开始了
But the shooting has started.

148
00:14:07,263 --> 00:14:14,894
而历史已记录下谁开了第一枪
And history has recorded
who fired the first shot.

149
00:14:14,979 --> 00:14:17,856
然而从长期来讲,
ln the long run, however,

150
00:14:17,940 --> 00:14:24,445
最关键的还是谁开了最后一枪
all that will matter
is who fired the last shot.

151
00:14:26,282 --> 00:14:33,496
废除我们的中立法案将是
通向战争之路的最后一步
The repeal of our Neutrality Act will be
the last step on the road to war.

152
00:14:33,581 --> 00:14:38,126
如果我们把我们的船
装满违禁的战争物资
lf we load our ships
with contraband of war

153
00:14:38,210 --> 00:14:41,588
并把它们送入战区,
and send them into combat zones,

154
00:14:41,672 --> 00:14:44,674
他们肯定会被击沉
they will most certainly be sunk.

155
00:14:44,758 --> 00:14:50,638
而那意味着战争...
一场在我们许多人看来,
And that means war... a war
which in the opinion of many of us,

156
00:14:50,723 --> 00:14:54,434
尽管意图是为了拯救国外的民主,
although designed
to save democracy abroad,

157
00:14:54,518 --> 00:14:59,898
却将肯定摧毁美国国内的民主的战争
will surely destroy it at home
right here in America.

158
00:15:00,608 --> 00:15:05,111
10月30日 美国驱逐舰"鲁宾·詹姆斯"号被击沉
On October 30
the US destroyer Reuben James was sunk

159
00:15:05,195 --> 00:15:07,405
船上115人死亡
with the loss of 115 lives.

160
00:15:07,489 --> 00:15:11,034
军官和前面的所有人都死了
Officers and all hands forward perished.

161
00:15:11,118 --> 00:15:15,038
只有我本人和(另外)45个人活下来
Myself and 45 men
are all that are alive.

162
00:15:15,164 --> 00:15:21,294
尽管受到非常想让美国参战的丘吉尔
的压力,罗斯福现在还是什么都没做
Despite pressure from Churchill,who dearly wanted
America in the war,Roosevelt now did nothing.

163
00:15:21,378 --> 00:15:27,592
事情变得很明显,要让美国参战,所需要的(原因)
要远比100个左右的水手被淹死多得多
It was becoming clear it would take much more than the drowning
of 100 or so US seamen to bring America into the war.

164
00:15:27,676 --> 00:15:31,804
甚至有这样一种看法...
我记得这是这么表达的...
There was even a sentiment...
I remember this being expressed...

165
00:15:31,889 --> 00:15:36,517
大意是英国将战至最后一个美国人
to the effect that England
would fight to the last American.

166
00:15:36,602 --> 00:15:41,397
事态正在发展...当然是逐步的...
There were steps that were developing...
gradual steps, to be sure...

167
00:15:41,482 --> 00:15:45,300
多少可以和发生在第一次世界大战
时的事态(发展)相比较
somewhat comparable to the steps
that took place in World War l.

168
00:15:45,400 --> 00:15:49,989
一起事件接着一起事件...记得用鱼雷击沉"萨塞克斯"号
(法国渡轮,1916年3月被击沉)让我们激动,
You know,one incident after another... remember
the torpedoing of the Sussex got us excited,

169
00:15:50,074 --> 00:15:52,617
然后有"卢西塔尼亚"号事件...
(英国跨大西洋渡轮,1915年5月被击沉)
then there was the Lusitania episode...

170
00:15:52,701 --> 00:15:57,330
以同样的方式,我想以罗斯福先生所作的举动,
ln the same way, I think that with the
moves that Mr Roosevelt was making,

171
00:15:57,414 --> 00:16:01,334
他推行的"现购自运"项目,
the cash-and-carry programme
that he had,

172
00:16:01,418 --> 00:16:06,255
保护(英国)船队,那笔驱逐舰交易...
the protection of the convoys,
the destroyer deal...

173
00:16:06,340 --> 00:16:10,927
一件又一件事情在发生,
而那容易制造出,我想,
One thing and another was occurring
that would be apt to produce, I think,

174
00:16:11,011 --> 00:16:13,888
一起引发战争的事件
an incident that would set the war off.

175
00:16:14,473 --> 00:16:16,474
那起事件,到来时,很巨大
That incident,when it came, was massive

176
00:16:16,558 --> 00:16:19,894
而它在一个意想不到的地方到来:珍珠港
and it came in an unexpected
place: Pearl Harbour.

177
00:16:19,979 --> 00:16:26,109
夏威夷瓦胡岛上的所有陆军和
海军基地现在都正处于空袭之中
All army and navy bases on the island
of Oahu in Hawaii are now under air attack.

178
00:16:26,193 --> 00:16:29,821
想了解最新新闻,请不要换台
For the latest news,
keep tuned to this station.

179
00:16:29,905 --> 00:16:35,910
我的上级,他是负责战争中所有
民用(公司)事务的,正好出去了,
My superior, who was in charge of all
civilian operations of the war, was away,

180
00:16:35,995 --> 00:16:44,919
所以我于是被派去参加珍珠港遇袭当晚
在华盛顿召开的战时领导人大会
so I was then sent on to the great meeting of
the wartime leaders that convened in Washington
on the night of Pearl Harbour.

181
00:16:45,004 --> 00:16:50,425
我记得我去参加那个会议时的使命感
l remember my sense of mission
in going to that meeting.

182
00:16:50,509 --> 00:16:52,844
我们都已看到战争来临
We had all seen the war coming.

183
00:16:52,928 --> 00:16:55,013
就是这天,就是此时,
Here was the day and here was the hour,

184
00:16:55,097 --> 00:16:59,642
我来了,和其他伟人们一起参加会议
and here was l, attending the meeting
with the other great men.

185
00:16:59,727 --> 00:17:04,856
我们到了会议现场,其他
"伟人们"...包括我自己...
We got to the meeting and the other
"great men"... myself included...

186
00:17:04,940 --> 00:17:06,858
都失望之极,
were one hell of a disappointment,

187
00:17:06,942 --> 00:17:09,777
因为没人能想到可以说或做些什么
because nobody could think
of anything to say or do.

188
00:17:09,862 --> 00:17:15,700
看看什么物资会被日本人的推进
所威胁 似乎是一个好主意
It seemed a good idea to see what materials
were threatened by the Japanese advance.

189
00:17:15,784 --> 00:17:18,828
每个人都在讨论这事的过程中进来,
Everybody was coming in
during the course of this,

190
00:17:18,912 --> 00:17:23,458
有些穿着运动衫,有些穿着网球鞋,
some in sport jackets,
some in tennis shoes,

191
00:17:23,542 --> 00:17:32,967
有一点变得极其明显 那就是没人拥有关于
这些战略产品来自何处的任何确实的信息
and it became terribly evident that nobody had any real
information as to where these strategic commodities came from.

192
00:17:33,052 --> 00:17:39,932
我记得最终整个讨论在
木棉的问题上陷入困境
And eventually the whole discussion bogged
down, I remember,on the question of kapok.

193
00:17:40,017 --> 00:17:46,689
木棉,每个人都想...
很明显它被列为一种战略物资,
Kapok, everybody thought... lt was
clearly listed as a strategic material,

194
00:17:46,815 --> 00:17:49,692
很显然它也来自那个地区,
it evidently came
from that part of the world,

195
00:17:49,818 --> 00:17:53,863
但没人能想得出,看在上帝的份上,
那东西是派什么用的
and nobody could think, for God's sake,
what the stuff was used for.

196
00:18:02,581 --> 00:18:07,585
我请求国会宣布
l ask that the Congress declare

197
00:18:07,669 --> 00:18:21,766
由于1941年12月7日周日
日本发动的这场无缘无故的和卑鄙的攻击,
that since the unprovoked and dastardly
attack by Japan on Sunday December 7, 1941,

198
00:18:21,850 --> 00:18:32,527
美利坚合众国和日本帝国已经处于战争状态
a state of war has existed between
the United States and the Japanese empire.

199
00:18:35,447 --> 00:18:41,077
甚至到现在罗斯福都不能强使
他自己要求美国向德国宣战...
Even now Roosevelt couldn't bring himself
to ask that the US declare war on Germany...

200
00:18:41,161 --> 00:18:45,414
尽管英国已和美国联合起来对付日本
although Britain had already allied
herself with the US against Japan.

201
00:18:45,499 --> 00:18:48,501
但是希特勒替他做了决定
But Hitler decided for him.

202
00:18:49,586 --> 00:18:54,423
由于一些未作解释的原因,
希特勒向美国宣战,
For some unexplained reason, Hitler
declared war on the United States,

203
00:18:54,508 --> 00:18:57,700
这解除了罗斯福所有的困难
which relieved Roosevelt
of all of his difficulties.

204
00:18:57,700 --> 00:19:02,515
当时我正在芝加哥当律师...
那是,在珍珠港事件发生的时候...
I was practising law in Chicago...
that is, at the time of Pearl Harbour...

205
00:19:02,599 --> 00:19:06,561
我可以告诉你如果希特勒
没有作出这个决定,
and I can tell you that if Hitler
had not made this decision,

206
00:19:06,645 --> 00:19:09,564
如果他只是什么都不做,
if he had simply done nothing,

207
00:19:09,648 --> 00:19:16,000
那在美国的许多地方就会
有极多的人拥有这种看法
that there would have been enormous sentiment
in many parts of the United States

208
00:19:16,000 --> 00:19:19,283
那就是太平洋战争现在是我们的战争,
that the Pacific war now was our war,

209
00:19:19,283 --> 00:19:23,000
而欧洲战争是欧洲人的事情
that the European war
was for the Europeans

210
00:19:23,000 --> 00:19:26,414
我们应该集中我们所有的精力来对付日本人
and we should concentrate
all our efforts against the Japanese.

211
00:19:36,550 --> 00:19:39,468
♪ 欧,给我土地,许多土地
♪ Oh, give me land, lots of land

212
00:19:39,553 --> 00:19:42,513
♪ 在布满星星的天空下
♪ Under starry skies above

213
00:19:42,598 --> 00:19:45,266
♪ 别把我圈进(栅栏)去
♪ Don't fence me in

214
00:19:45,350 --> 00:19:50,229
♪ 让我骑马穿越我爱的广阔空旷的乡村
♪ Let me ride through
the wide open country that I love

215
00:19:50,314 --> 00:19:52,231
♪ 别把我圈进去
♪ Don't fence me in

216
00:19:52,316 --> 00:19:55,610
人们把他们的家以它们价值的一个零头卖掉,
(Corwin) People were selling their homes
at a fraction of their value,

217
00:19:55,694 --> 00:19:59,739
他们肯定西海岸会被攻击,我们会在这里被轰炸
they were certain the west coast would
be under attack, that we'd be bombed here.

218
00:19:59,823 --> 00:20:02,575
沿着西海岸甚至有灯火管制,
There were even blackouts
along the west coast,

219
00:20:02,659 --> 00:20:04,702
沿着东海岸也有
as there were along the east coast.

220
00:20:04,786 --> 00:20:07,997
这里甚至有过一些假警报
And there were even
some false alerts here.

221
00:20:29,144 --> 00:20:32,300
不是每个人都把这些预防措施当回事
Not everybody took these precautions seriously.

222
00:20:47,621 --> 00:20:54,794
在欧洲人眼里,美国的进入战争
有一些既荒谬又熟悉的瞬间
To European eyes, America's going to war
had moments both ludicrous and familiar.

223
00:21:07,808 --> 00:21:11,936
(♪ "当强尼行军回家时")
(♪ "When Johnny Comes Marching Home")

224
00:21:32,332 --> 00:21:34,750
♪ 男人们将欢呼 男孩们将喊叫
♪ The men will cheer
and the boys will shout

225
00:21:34,876 --> 00:21:36,836
♪ 女士们她们都将出现
♪ The ladies they will all turn out

226
00:21:36,920 --> 00:21:39,046
♪ 我们都感觉很愉快
♪ And we'll all feel gay

227
00:21:39,131 --> 00:21:43,009
♪ 当强尼行军回家时
♪ When Johnny comes marching home

228
00:21:43,093 --> 00:21:46,762
生活在我们中的是那些
我们称之为外国人的人
Living among us
are those we call aliens.

229
00:21:47,514 --> 00:21:53,185
我们必须记住我们的父母或者祖父母
We must remember
that our parents or our grandparents

230
00:21:53,270 --> 00:21:55,813
或者曾祖父母
or our great-grandparents

231
00:21:55,897 --> 00:21:59,900
在他们那时候都曾是外国人
all were aliens in their day.

232
00:21:59,985 --> 00:22:06,532
如果你相信你了解任何
外国人的任何不正当行为
lf you believe you have knowledge
of any improper activity of any alien

233
00:22:06,616 --> 00:22:11,203
你应该向最近的联邦调查局分局报告情况
you should report the fact
to the nearest FBl office.

234
00:22:11,288 --> 00:22:14,915
不要试图自行执法
Don't try to be the law yourself.

235
00:22:18,420 --> 00:22:20,129
有一个巨大的变化...
There was a tremendous change...

236
00:22:20,213 --> 00:22:24,884
这变化就是 我们仍是和12月7日前一样的人;
the change being that we were the same
individuals as prior to December 7;

237
00:22:24,968 --> 00:22:29,597
但在12月8日,当我们去学校,
我们的许多同学和朋友
on December 8, when we went to school,
many of our classmates and friends

238
00:22:29,681 --> 00:22:33,893
叫我们"肮脏的日本鬼子",
捉弄我们,骚扰我们,
called us "dirty Japs",
teased us, harassed us,

239
00:22:33,977 --> 00:22:37,480
而我们所谓的朋友也不再是朋友了
and our so-called friends
were no longer friends.

240
00:22:37,564 --> 00:22:40,700
在第一次世界大战中,正如你知道的,
德国人被极其痛恨
ln the First World War, as you know,
the Germans were hated thoroughly

241
00:22:40,700 --> 00:22:45,863
有大量针对德国人的歧视和骚扰
and there was no...there was a great deal of
discrimination and harassment of the Germans.

242
00:22:45,947 --> 00:22:50,034
在第二次世界大战中,我们
同三个不同国籍的人交战,
ln the Second World War, we were at war
with three different nationalities,

243
00:22:50,118 --> 00:22:52,578
意大利人,德国人和日本人
the Italians, the Germans
and the Japanese.

244
00:22:52,662 --> 00:22:58,376
我记得汤玛斯·曼和布鲁诺·沃尔特
为德裔(美国人)辩护
And I remember that Thomas Mann and
Bruno Walter spoke up for the Germans

245
00:22:58,460 --> 00:23:02,713
说他们不能被迁移走,因为那会是最后的绝望,
and said they couldn't be removed
because that would be the last despair,

246
00:23:02,798 --> 00:23:07,009
在逃离纳粹德国后,又再次被关进集中营
having fled Nazi Germany, to be
again put into a concentration camp.

247
00:23:07,094 --> 00:23:10,137
乔·迪麦吉奥(著名棒球手,曾与梦露结婚)
的母亲(为意裔美国人)大声说话,
And Joe DiMaggio's mother spoke up,you know,

248
00:23:10,222 --> 00:23:13,891
而那非常感人,我记得是在旧金山
and that was very moving,
in San Francisco,I remember.

249
00:23:13,975 --> 00:23:16,519
但日裔真的没什么人(为他们说话)
But the Japanese had really nobody.

250
00:23:22,109 --> 00:23:24,110
我想挑中日裔(美国人)
l think picking on the Japanese

251
00:23:24,194 --> 00:23:30,032
部分因为这是一件陆军能
应付的 逻辑上合理的事情...
was partly a logistically rational thing
that the army could handle...

252
00:23:30,117 --> 00:23:34,000
他们说,我们处理不了德裔,
但我们能应付日裔
they said, we can't handle the Germans,
but we can handle the Japanese.

253
00:23:36,581 --> 00:23:40,400
毕竟,他们不可能把这个国家所有
的德裔和意裔(美国人)给迁走...
After all, they couldn't have moved all
the Germans and Italians in this country...

254
00:23:40,400 --> 00:23:45,090
那样他们不得不把纽约市一半
的人给迁走 那就太可笑了
that they would have had to move half the people
out of New York City. It would've been ridiculous.

255
00:23:49,469 --> 00:23:51,700
这些人(日裔美国人)一直不太受欢迎
(Ball) These people had
always been rather unpopular

256
00:23:51,700 --> 00:23:57,600
因为他们在小型商品蔬菜种植以及
诸如此类的方面与美国农民竞争,
because they competed with the American farmers
in truck gardening and things like that kind,

257
00:23:57,600 --> 00:23:58,978
而且工作努力得多
and worked very much harder

258
00:23:59,062 --> 00:24:02,148
耕种起他们的土地来也远远更具效率
and cultivated their land
very much more efficiently.

259
00:24:02,232 --> 00:24:05,985
所以许多人利用他们的处境
So a lot of people
took advantage of their situation

260
00:24:06,069 --> 00:24:08,571
来制造针对他们的反感
to create antipathy toward them.

261
00:24:08,655 --> 00:24:11,532
而政府行事仓促而又颇为残忍
And the government
acted hastily and rather brutally

262
00:24:11,616 --> 00:24:13,659
...这不是一段吸引人的篇章
...it's not a very attractive chapter.

263
00:24:13,743 --> 00:24:17,955
超过十万日裔美国人被全体拘禁,
More than 100,000 Japanese
Americans were interned en masse,

264
00:24:18,039 --> 00:24:20,207
其中大多数生活在西海岸,
mostly those on the west coast,

265
00:24:20,292 --> 00:24:25,629
而六十万德裔和意裔美国人则被分别对待
whereas the 600,000 German and ltalian
Americans were treated individually.

266
00:24:25,714 --> 00:24:28,841
尽管我们已听到要疏散的传闻,
(Uno) Although we had heard rumours
of an evacuation,

267
00:24:28,925 --> 00:24:33,637
我们都没意识到这真的会发生
we didn't realise that it was
going to indeed take place.

268
00:24:33,722 --> 00:24:37,000
我们被告知我们只能带走
我们能随身携带的东西
We were told that we could
only take what we could carry.

269
00:24:40,103 --> 00:24:44,231
被疏散者有三种选择:
他们要么不得不卖了他们的财产,
Evacuees had three choices:
they either had to sell their property,

270
00:24:44,316 --> 00:24:46,567
要么放弃它或贮藏它
abandon it or store it.

271
00:24:46,651 --> 00:24:50,321
在许多情况下,因为对局势的不确定,
And in many cases, because
of the uncertainty of the situation,

272
00:24:50,405 --> 00:24:54,492
许多人只是尽他们最大的努力
处理掉他们的财产
many people just disposed of their
property as best they could.

273
00:24:54,576 --> 00:24:59,413
然后我们被送上公共汽车
并被带到了集结中心
We were then put on buses
and taken to assembly centres.

274
00:25:02,417 --> 00:25:04,251
在集结中心
From the assembly centres

275
00:25:04,336 --> 00:25:08,672
我们住在马棚或速成的沥青油纸兵营里
we lived in horse stalls
or in quickly made tarpaper barracks.

276
00:25:08,757 --> 00:25:11,592
我母亲经历的精神痛苦(包括),
The mental anguish
that my mother went through,

277
00:25:11,676 --> 00:25:15,804
她的四个儿子在为美国政府服役
having four of her sons in the service
of the United States government

278
00:25:15,931 --> 00:25:20,351
而她的丈夫被贴上了危险敌国外侨的标签...
and having her husband
labelled a dangerous enemy alien...

279
00:25:30,904 --> 00:25:34,281
我们有看守,警卫塔,机关枪...
We had guards, watch towers,
machine guns...

280
00:25:34,366 --> 00:25:37,910
这是一幅监禁的画面
It was a picture of incarceration.

281
00:25:37,994 --> 00:25:41,539
我们感觉我们是囚犯...
我们自己国家的囚犯
We felt that we were prisoners...
prisoners in our own country.

282
00:26:22,414 --> 00:26:25,374
可以肯定的一件事是
有段时间里不会再有橡胶了
The one thing was certain was there's
going to be no more rubber for a while

283
00:26:25,458 --> 00:26:29,003
我们不得不将就着使用
我们现有的橡胶轮胎库存
and we'd have to make do with the stock
of rubber tyres that we had.

284
00:26:29,129 --> 00:26:33,215
停止销售橡胶轮胎不归我们机构管,
And it wasn't in the authority of our
agency to stop the sale of rubber tyres,

285
00:26:33,300 --> 00:26:35,217
可不管怎样我们还是起草了一道命令
so we drew up an order anyway

286
00:26:35,302 --> 00:26:41,200
我们让一个无名的年轻人在
生产管理局的所有办公室散发了它
and we had an anonymous young man circulate it though
all the offices of the Office of Production Management

287
00:26:41,200 --> 00:26:45,300
他们不得不清理所有的纸
而那里已经非常非常脏乱了
that had to clear all pieces of paper,
it was already very very cruddy.

288
00:26:45,437 --> 00:26:50,149
(他)走进去,说"这里是橡胶
轮胎令,先生" 每个人都签了名
Walked in, with "Here's the rubber
tyre order,sir." Everybody signed it.

289
00:26:55,238 --> 00:26:59,617
于是我们冻结了整个国家的橡胶轮胎库存
And we froze the whole nation's
stock of rubber tyres.

290
00:27:31,733 --> 00:27:33,692
每个人都得到了工作
Everybody got work.

291
00:27:33,777 --> 00:27:38,656
(保罗·萨缪尔森 诺贝尔经济学奖得主)
在1930年代漫长的大萧条后 这深受感激
This was very much appreciated after
the long, deep depression of the 1930s.

292
00:27:38,740 --> 00:27:41,950
你可能以为通胀会成为主要问题,
You might've thought inflation
would be the major problem,

293
00:27:42,035 --> 00:27:45,621
因为在大多数国家,在大多数战争里,
这一直都是个主要问题
because in most countries, in most wars,
it's always been a major problem.

294
00:27:45,705 --> 00:27:48,415
但在我们动员的很早阶段,
But very early we mobilised,

295
00:27:48,500 --> 00:27:53,337
我们就提出定量配给制度,尽管有些许抱怨,
we put in a rationing, and, although
there was a small amount of grumbling,

296
00:27:53,421 --> 00:27:56,632
定量配给系统运行得如此之好
实在是令人惊讶
it's amazing how well
the rationing system worked.

297
00:27:56,758 --> 00:28:01,512
当时有种趋势 那就是接受短缺但有一个例外
(Galbraith) There was a tendency
to accept shortages with one exception.

298
00:28:01,596 --> 00:28:05,766
人们对汽油配给非常抵触
People were very resistant
to gasoline rationing.

299
00:28:05,850 --> 00:28:10,979
衣服短缺,食品短缺,咖啡,糖,
这些人们都能接受
Clothing shortages, food shortages,
coffee, sugar, people would accept.

300
00:28:11,064 --> 00:28:17,903
但没有哪种形式的耍流氓,欺骗,偷盗,盗窃
But there was no form of
rascality, chicanery, thievery, larceny

301
00:28:17,987 --> 00:28:21,990
是人们不会从事的
就为了得到一些额外的汽油
that people wouldn't engage in
to get extra gasoline.

302
00:28:22,075 --> 00:28:25,452
我想他们最痛恨的事
l think the thing they most resented

303
00:28:25,537 --> 00:28:29,790
就是我们许多做这件事
(汽油配给)的人都极其年轻
was the extreme youth of many
of us who were doing it.

304
00:28:29,874 --> 00:28:32,334
价格管理局,
The Office of Price Administration,

305
00:28:32,419 --> 00:28:35,754
在我今天回头看来,一定是很难熬的
as I look back on it,
must've been very hard to take.

306
00:28:35,839 --> 00:28:38,590
我当时31岁
l was then 31.

307
00:28:38,675 --> 00:28:43,846
大卫·金斯堡,我最亲近的同僚,
总顾问, 是29岁,
David Ginsberg, my immediate associate,
general counsel, was 29,

308
00:28:43,930 --> 00:28:48,225
其他大多数人都比我们还年轻...
and most everybody else
was younger than we were...

309
00:28:48,309 --> 00:28:49,810
包括理查德·尼克松,
including Richard Nixon,

310
00:28:49,894 --> 00:28:53,105
他当时是机构里众多不出名的雇员之一
who was one of the more
obscure employees of the agency.

311
00:28:53,189 --> 00:28:56,984
这是苏维·埃弗里的一张著名战时照片,
There's a famous wartime picture
of Sewell Avery,

312
00:28:57,068 --> 00:28:59,361
(他是)上一个时代的一位大亨,
a great tycoon of the last age,

313
00:28:59,446 --> 00:29:03,198
蒙哥马利·沃德公司(美国连锁百货商店
巨头)的老板 并把它带出了大萧条,
who was head of Montgomery Ward
and brought it out of the Depression,

314
00:29:03,283 --> 00:29:07,161
被两个穿制服的美国士兵
架出他的办公室
being carried out of his office
by two American soldiers in uniform

315
00:29:07,245 --> 00:29:11,665
因为他不肯遵从战时劳工委员会
(要求其承认工会的命令)
because he wouldn't comply
with the War Labor Board.

316
00:29:11,750 --> 00:29:16,044
我们为下一财政年度制定的战争项目
Our war programme
for the coming fiscal year

317
00:29:16,129 --> 00:29:21,467
将花费560亿美元
will cost 56 billion dollars.

318
00:29:21,551 --> 00:29:26,513
那意味着税收和债券...
That means taxes and bonds...

319
00:29:26,598 --> 00:29:29,475
以及债券和税收
and bonds and taxes.

320
00:29:29,559 --> 00:29:33,270
- 哦...
- 我们每抽到一支兰花就听到一声长声尖叫,女士们先生们
- Ohh...
- We have a squeal with each orchid,ladies and gentlemen.

321
00:29:35,982 --> 00:29:39,902
想要得到你的兰花吗?
请到这边来
Want to get your orchid?
Come this way, please.

322
00:29:40,779 --> 00:29:43,363
2250 这可真是件漂亮的东西
2250. This is really
a handsome thing to have.

323
00:29:43,448 --> 00:29:46,992
你购买2250美元的战争债券
就能得到这个作为奖品,
You're getting this as a premium
for a war bond for $2250,

324
00:29:47,076 --> 00:29:49,536
所以对任何人来说 这都真的是一笔划算买卖
so it's really a good purchase for anybody.

325
00:29:49,621 --> 00:29:51,914
- 让我看一眼那个
- 哦 是吗?
- Let's have a look at that.
- Oh you did?

326
00:29:51,998 --> 00:29:56,043
霍普(鲍勃·霍普 喜剧明星)正看着这双鞋
他可能把他的出价增加到2255美元
Hope is looking at the shoe.
He may increase his bid to $2255.

327
00:29:58,171 --> 00:30:01,173
你也要加点价,是吗,胖墩?
You're going to come up a little,
aren't you, flabby?

328
00:30:03,009 --> 00:30:06,011
我不该这么做,但我出2500
l shouldn't, but l'll go 25.

329
00:30:06,971 --> 00:30:12,726
我们的敌人不是容易打败的对手
他们野蛮,娴熟而又残酷无情
Our enemies aren't pushovers.
They're savage, skilful and relentless.

330
00:30:12,811 --> 00:30:16,563
他们训练经年 就为了这个奴役世界的机会,
They've trained for years for
just this chance to enslave the world,

331
00:30:16,648 --> 00:30:21,068
那就是他们想要做的
而他们会使用每一个诡计和工具
and that's just what they intend to do.
And they'll use every trick and tool.

332
00:30:21,152 --> 00:30:25,614
但在另一个方面,他们也不是超人
But on the other hand,
they aren't supermen.

333
00:30:25,698 --> 00:30:28,867
他们不是从火星上来的
They didn't come down from Mars.

334
00:30:28,952 --> 00:30:34,164
他们能被打败 他们也将被人打败
They can be licked and they
will be licked...by men.

335
00:30:36,626 --> 00:30:38,836
♪ 我们在1917年战斗
♪ We fought in 1917

336
00:30:38,920 --> 00:30:40,963
♪ 润-滴-滴 顿 顿 顿
♪ Rum-di-di dum dum dum

337
00:30:41,047 --> 00:30:43,590
♪ 从现场赶走了暴君
♪ And drove the tyrants from the scene

338
00:30:43,675 --> 00:30:45,717
♪ 润-滴-滴 顿 顿 顿
♪ Rum did-di dum dum dum

339
00:30:45,802 --> 00:30:48,136
♪ 我们在打一场更大更好的战争
♪ We're in a bigger, better war

340
00:30:48,221 --> 00:30:50,430
♪ 因为你的爱国消遣
♪ For your patriotic pastime

341
00:30:50,515 --> 00:30:54,852
♪ 我们不知道我们为何而战
但上一次我们也不知道
♪ We don't know what we're fighting for
But we didn't know the last time

342
00:30:54,936 --> 00:30:57,688
♪ 所以装填大炮,抽出军刀
♪ So load the cannon,
draw the blade

343
00:30:57,772 --> 00:30:59,648
♪ 润-滴-滴 顿 顿 顿
♪ Rum-di-di dum dum dum

344
00:30:59,732 --> 00:31:04,778
♪ 来吧 加入这场大阅兵...
♪ Come on and join the big parade...

345
00:31:08,575 --> 00:31:12,744
♪ 润-滴-滴 顿 顿 顿, 润-滴-滴 顿 顿,
润-滴-滴 顿 顿 顿
♪ Rum-di-di dum dum, rum-di-di dum dum,
rum-di-di dum dum dum

346
00:31:12,829 --> 00:31:15,289
♪ 让鼓发出宏亮的声音
♪ Let the drums roll out

347
00:31:15,373 --> 00:31:17,416
♪ 让喇叭吹响
♪ Let the trumpets call

348
00:31:17,500 --> 00:31:19,501
♪ 当人们呼喊
♪ While the people shout

349
00:31:19,586 --> 00:31:21,587
♪ 让乐队开始演奏
♪ Strike up the band

350
00:31:21,671 --> 00:31:24,047
是凶险的敌人手中的飞机
lt was the airplanes in the
hands of the treacherous foe

351
00:31:24,132 --> 00:31:26,216
导致我丈夫丧生,
that brought my husband to his death,

352
00:31:26,301 --> 00:31:29,928
如果我能在维加成为一名合格的飞机工人
and if I can qualify
as an airplane worker at Vega

353
00:31:30,013 --> 00:31:32,431
并用我的手帮助使它们飞行,
and with my hands
help to keep 'em flying,

354
00:31:32,515 --> 00:31:35,017
我会感觉我在为他继续(战斗)
I will feel that I am carrying on for him.

355
00:31:35,101 --> 00:31:37,060
♪ 听钹在鸣响
♪ Hear the cymbals ring

356
00:31:37,145 --> 00:31:39,354
♪ 呼唤每个人
♪ Calling one and all

357
00:31:39,439 --> 00:31:41,398
♪ 到习武场
♪ To the martial swing

358
00:31:41,482 --> 00:31:43,692
♪ 让乐队开始演奏
♪ Strike up the band

359
00:31:43,776 --> 00:31:46,069
♪ 有工作要完成,要完成
♪ There is work to be done, to be done

360
00:31:46,154 --> 00:31:48,238
♪ 有场战争要取胜,要取胜
♪ There's a war to be won, to be won

361
00:31:48,323 --> 00:31:50,699
♪ 来吧,你个炮娘养的
♪ Come, you son of a, son of a gun

362
00:31:50,783 --> 00:31:53,243
♪ 表明你的立场
♪ Take your stand

363
00:31:53,328 --> 00:31:55,329
♪ 排成一排,鞠个躬
♪ Fall in line, yea a bow

364
00:31:55,413 --> 00:31:58,248
♪ 来吧,我们走
♪ Come along, let's go

365
00:31:58,333 --> 00:32:01,335
♪ 嘿,指挥,让乐队开始演奏
♪ Hey, leader, strike up the band

366
00:32:01,419 --> 00:32:03,003
我们在尽我们的那份力,
We are doing our share,

367
00:32:03,129 --> 00:32:06,965
但我们要做的远比我们已做的要多得多
but we're going to do
infinitely more than we have done.

368
00:32:07,050 --> 00:32:10,969
今天我们镇上有两位母亲,
We have in our town today two mothers,

369
00:32:11,054 --> 00:32:15,390
她们每个人都已奉献两个儿子(去参军)
each of whom has given two sons already.

370
00:32:15,475 --> 00:32:20,520
就如我以前说的,我们将奉献我们
的儿子,我们将奉献我们的生命,
And, as I said before, we'll give
our sons, we'll give our lives,

371
00:32:20,605 --> 00:32:22,700
但是,在上帝的帮助和仁慈下,
but, by the help and grace of God,

372
00:32:22,700 --> 00:32:28,111
我们不会放弃我们自由的美国
或我们民主的生活方式
we will not give up our free America
or our democratic way of life.

373
00:32:28,905 --> 00:32:31,573
♪ 让乐队开始演奏
♪ Strike up the band

374
00:32:33,493 --> 00:32:35,494
♪ 扬基-嘟 嘟都-嘟 嘟都-嘟
♪ Yankee-doo doodle-doo doodle-doo

375
00:32:35,578 --> 00:32:37,996
♪ 我们会安然度过,嘟都-嘟 嘟都-嘟
♪ We'll come through,
doodle-doo doodle-doo

376
00:32:38,081 --> 00:32:40,248
♪ 为了红,白和蓝,嘟都-嘟
♪ For the red, white and blue,
doodle-doo

377
00:32:40,333 --> 00:32:43,210
♪ 借个手
♪ Lend a hand

378
00:32:43,294 --> 00:32:45,170
♪ 随着旗帜展开
♪ With the flag unfurled

379
00:32:45,254 --> 00:32:47,714
♪ 我们能打败世界
♪ We can lick the world

380
00:32:47,799 --> 00:32:55,806
♪ 嘿,指挥,让乐队开始演奏
♪ Hey, leader, strike up the band

381
00:32:59,519 --> 00:33:01,800
在珍珠港事件的那个晚上,
On the night of Pearl Harbour,

382
00:33:01,800 --> 00:33:05,399
一个人很开心...温斯顿·丘吉尔
one man had been happy...
Winston Churchill.

383
00:33:05,483 --> 00:33:08,694
因为现在他知道英国被拯救了
For now he knew Britain was saved.

384
00:33:08,778 --> 00:33:11,238
几天之后他旅行到了华盛顿
A few days later
he journeyed to Washington

385
00:33:11,322 --> 00:33:17,953
以确保战争将按照英国的"欧洲第一
太平洋第二"的计划来打,
to make sure the war was going to be fought on the
British plan of Europe first and the Pacific second,

386
00:33:18,037 --> 00:33:21,581
并巩固新的英-美联盟
and to cement the new
Anglo-American alliance.

387
00:33:21,666 --> 00:33:25,419
他们以为我们是什么样一种人?
What kind of a people
do they think we are?

388
00:33:25,503 --> 00:33:28,463
是否可能他们还没有意识到
ls it possible they do not realise

389
00:33:28,548 --> 00:33:33,135
我们将永远不会停止不屈不挠地抵抗他们
that we shall never cease
to persevere against them

390
00:33:33,219 --> 00:33:39,224
直到他们得到一个他们和
全世界都不会忘记的教训
until they have been taught a lesson
which they and the world will never forget.

391
00:33:47,608 --> 00:33:52,195
丘吉尔知道,时间在同盟国这边
Time, Churchill knew,
was on the Allies' side.

392
00:33:52,280 --> 00:33:58,035
有美国的工业实力在他们背后
(支持他们),他们不可能输
With America's industrial might
behind them, they could not lose.

393
00:34:07,879 --> 00:34:11,798
在太平洋1942年的开局对美国人很糟
1942 began badly for the
Americans in the Pacific.

394
00:34:11,883 --> 00:34:17,846
马尼拉,菲律宾的首都,
在1月1日落入日本人手中
Manila, capital of the Philippines,
fell to the Japanese on January 1.

395
00:34:20,391 --> 00:34:25,979
日本人把美国部队逼入狭隘的巴丹半岛
The Japanese pushed the American forces
back into the narrow peninsular of Bataan.

396
00:34:33,196 --> 00:34:38,909
美国人的计划是在那里坚守
6个月左右,直到援军到来
The American plan was to hold out there for
six months or so,until reinforcements came.

397
00:34:38,993 --> 00:34:41,787
但援军从未到来,
But the reinforcements never did come,

398
00:34:41,871 --> 00:34:46,625
巴丹也并未真正做好被围攻的准备
and nor had Bataan
been really prepared for a siege.

399
00:35:09,982 --> 00:35:13,860
被围困在巴丹的美国部队没有空中支援,
The American troops besieged at Bataan
had no air support,

400
00:35:13,945 --> 00:35:18,240
缺乏医疗用品 他们的士气也很低迷
were short of medical supplies
and their morale was poor.

401
00:35:18,324 --> 00:35:20,600
甚至他们的总司令,麦克阿瑟将军,
Even their commander-in-chief,
General MacArthur,

402
00:35:20,600 --> 00:35:23,579
也离开他们去了更安全的海岸(澳大利亚)
had left them for safer shores.

403
00:35:26,332 --> 00:35:30,669
他们痛苦的歌谣(是这么唱的):
"我们是巴丹的战斗中的杂种
Their bitter ballad:
"We are the battling bastards of Bataan

404
00:35:30,753 --> 00:35:33,713
没有妈妈,没有爸爸,没有山姆大叔
No mama, no papa, no Uncle Sam

405
00:35:33,798 --> 00:35:37,092
没有阿姨,没有叔叔,
没有表哥,没有侄女,
No aunts, no uncles,
no cousins, no nieces,

406
00:35:37,176 --> 00:35:40,220
没有药,没有飞机或大炮
No pills, no planes or artillery pieces

407
00:35:40,304 --> 00:35:43,348
而且根本没人在乎"
And nobody gives a goddamn."

408
00:35:45,560 --> 00:35:48,353
对他们至今取得的胜利
之轻松感到洋洋得意,
Cock-a-hoop with the ease
of their victory so far,

409
00:35:48,437 --> 00:35:52,300
日本人呼吁被围在巴丹的美国人投降
the Japanese called on the Americans
beleaguered in Bataan to surrender.

410
00:35:54,986 --> 00:36:01,533
"菲律宾之声"唤起各个地方每个人的注意
The voice of the Philippines calling
the attention of everyone everywhere.

411
00:36:02,326 --> 00:36:09,708
各个地方的每个人,全国的菲律宾人和美国人...
Everyone everywhere, Filipinos
and Americans all over the country...

412
00:36:12,211 --> 00:36:14,963
他们还尝试了传单...
They tried leaflets too...

413
00:36:17,633 --> 00:36:23,763
主要针对美国部队中的菲律宾士兵
aimed mostly at the Filipino soldiers
among the American forces.

414
00:36:24,807 --> 00:36:28,935
日本人逼近来作最后一击
The Japanese closed in for the kill.

415
00:37:07,892 --> 00:37:09,434
1942年5月上旬,
ln early May, 1942,

416
00:37:09,518 --> 00:37:13,396
驻菲律宾的美国指挥官,温赖特将军,
the American commander in the
Philippines, General Wainwright,

417
00:37:13,481 --> 00:37:18,109
接受了不可避免的(结局)
让他剩余的部队投降了
bowed to the inevitable and surrendered
the remainder of his forces.

418
00:37:18,194 --> 00:37:23,198
以人道的名义,我决定接受,
I've decided to accept,
in the name of humanity,

419
00:37:23,282 --> 00:37:33,375
菲律宾群岛上所有美国和
菲律宾陆军部队的正式投降
the formal surrender of all American and
Philippine army troops in the Philippine lslands.

420
00:37:33,459 --> 00:37:41,466
你们将...我重复,将...把你们
所有的部队向合适的日本军官投降
You will... repeat, will... surrender all
troops to the proper Japanese officer.

421
00:37:42,551 --> 00:37:45,679
八万美国人投降,
80,000 Americans surrendered,

422
00:37:45,763 --> 00:37:50,000
美国军事史上最大的一次大规模投降
the largest mass capitulation
in American military history.

423
00:37:51,269 --> 00:37:58,191
日本人让美国人在酷热的骄阳下
从巴丹向100多英里外的战俘营行军
The Japanese made the Americans march in the blazing
sun to prison camps 100 or so miles from Bataan.

424
00:37:58,276 --> 00:38:03,446
被剥夺了水和药物,
饥饿难耐并被残酷殴打,
Deprived of water and medicine,
starved and brutally beaten,

425
00:38:03,531 --> 00:38:07,117
差不多一万士兵死在了途中...
some 10,000 soldiers
died along the way...

426
00:38:07,201 --> 00:38:11,246
比在巴丹的战斗中阵亡的人还多
more than had been killed
in the actual fighting for Bataan.

427
00:38:21,340 --> 00:38:25,969
到1942年春天,日本的征服处于其顶峰
By that spring of 1942, the Japanese
conquests were at their peak.

428
00:38:26,053 --> 00:38:30,348
英国人和美国人现在当然
会要求和,东京争辩道...
Surely the British and Americans would
now want to make peace, argued Tokyo...

429
00:38:30,433 --> 00:38:34,686
一个会允许日本保留其征服地区的和平
a peace that would allow the Japanese
to retain their conquests.

430
00:38:34,770 --> 00:38:39,566
但(美国人)已经采取勇敢
的措施来回击日本人了
But already bold steps were being taken
to strike back at the Japanese

431
00:38:39,650 --> 00:38:43,486
就在他们帝国的心脏,东京
here in the heart of their empire,Tokyo.

432
00:38:43,571 --> 00:38:47,073
我在一艘叫"北汉普顿"的巡洋舰上
l was on this cruiser
called the Northampton

433
00:38:47,158 --> 00:38:52,454
当我们看见"大黄蜂"号(航空母舰)
赶上来的时候 我们已经出海几天了
and we were several days out at sea
when we saw the Hornet coming up.

434
00:38:52,580 --> 00:38:55,957
"大黄蜂"号的甲板上有些非常不寻常的飞机...
And the Hornet had very
unusual planes on deck...

435
00:38:56,042 --> 00:38:58,168
你可以从很远就看到它们
you could see them from a long way.

436
00:38:58,252 --> 00:39:02,589
他们是大型的陆基飞机...
B-25(米切尔型轰炸机)
They were large
land-based planes... B-25s.

437
00:39:04,008 --> 00:39:11,681
我们只有一个真正的担心...
那就是完全无风
We had only one real worry...
that would have been a dead calm.

438
00:39:11,766 --> 00:39:13,308
在那种条件下,
Under those conditions,

439
00:39:13,392 --> 00:39:16,978
以我们带着的重磅负荷
从航母甲板上起飞
taking off the carrier deck
with the heavy loads that we had

440
00:39:17,104 --> 00:39:19,356
在最好的情况下也是危险的
would have been at best precarious.

441
00:39:19,440 --> 00:39:21,700
我们认为可能发生的最糟糕的事情
The worst thing we thought might happen

442
00:39:21,700 --> 00:39:25,445
就是一个完全戒备的日本在等着我们
would be a completely alerted Japan
waiting for us.

443
00:39:25,529 --> 00:39:31,076
那天发生的事是在就在起飞前的那个早晨
What did happen was that
the morning just before take-off

444
00:39:31,160 --> 00:39:34,079
我们遭遇了两艘日本渔船
we encountered
two Japanese fishing boats.

445
00:39:34,163 --> 00:39:39,501
他们看到了我们的特遣舰队,
给(日本)本土发了一个消息,
They spotted our task force,
sent a message to the mainland,

446
00:39:39,585 --> 00:39:42,879
但,对日本人来说不幸的是,
but, unfortunately for the Japanese,

447
00:39:42,963 --> 00:39:47,092
(这两艘渔船)在能够重复消息前被击沉了
were sunk before they
could repeat the message.

448
00:39:50,679 --> 00:39:54,391
所以我们几乎完全出乎(日本人的)意外
So we achieved almost complete surprise.

449
00:40:16,288 --> 00:40:21,376
造成的实际伤害微不足道
The actual amount of damage done
was minimal.

450
00:40:21,460 --> 00:40:26,256
我们是16架飞机,每架携带一吨的炸弹
We were 16 aeroplanes,
each with one ton of bombs.

451
00:40:26,340 --> 00:40:31,594
在二战后期 李梅(空军上将)
指挥下的第20航空队
ln the later stages of World War ll,
the 20th Air Force under LeMay

452
00:40:31,679 --> 00:40:36,266
(詹姆斯·杜立特将军)
派出500架飞机,每架携带10吨炸弹
was sending out 500 aeroplanes,
each with 10 tons of bombs.

453
00:40:36,392 --> 00:40:40,728
(詹姆斯·杜立特将军)
所以我们扔了16吨 而后来的空袭扔了5000吨,
So we dropped 16 against
a later raid of 5,000,

454
00:40:40,813 --> 00:40:43,982
所以(造成的)伤害根本就不大
so the damage was not at all great.

455
00:40:44,066 --> 00:40:46,860
然而,这次轰炸有几个好处
However, it did have some advantages.

456
00:40:46,944 --> 00:40:50,947
第一,(当时)在国内我们只有坏消息,
One, we had had
nothing but bad news at home,

457
00:40:51,031 --> 00:40:53,575
所以这是我们的人听到的第一个好消息
so it was the first good news
our folks got

458
00:40:53,659 --> 00:40:57,162
而这也被认为是一个好消息
and it was appreciated as good news.

459
00:40:57,246 --> 00:41:00,707
这导致日本人质疑他们的军阀,
lt caused the Japanese
to question their warlords,

460
00:41:00,791 --> 00:41:04,627
(日本军阀)告知他们
日本永远也不会被攻击
who had informed them
that Japan would never be attacked.

461
00:41:07,548 --> 00:41:12,594
杜立特空袭刺痛了日本的领导人
并使他们变得草率
The Doolittle raid stung
Japan's leaders and made them careless.

462
00:41:13,179 --> 00:41:14,387
自从珍珠港事件以来,
Ever since Pearl Harbour,

463
00:41:14,472 --> 00:41:18,391
日本海军就在寻求和美国海军
打一场决定性战役,
Japan's navy had sought a decisive
battle with America's navy,

464
00:41:18,476 --> 00:41:23,272
一场永远决定太平洋统治权的战役
a battle that would decide
once and for all mastery of the Pacific.

465
00:41:31,614 --> 00:41:34,866
1942年6月初,日本航空母舰
ln early June, 1942,
the Japanese carriers

466
00:41:34,950 --> 00:41:41,956
在夏威夷西北1300英里
左右的中途岛附近集合
rendezvous'd close to Midway lsland,
some 1300 miles northwest of Hawaii.

467
00:41:59,934 --> 00:42:02,936
(源田実 第一航空舰队航空参谋)
我们不再象以前那样谨慎
We had ceased to be
as wary as before.

468
00:42:03,020 --> 00:42:06,898
(源田実 入侵中途岛策划者)
美国人事先知道了我们会进攻中途岛
The Americans knew in advance
that we would attack Midway.

469
00:42:06,982 --> 00:42:10,151
他们在等着我们 而我们走进了他们的陷阱
They were waiting for us
and we walked into their trap.

470
00:43:44,496 --> 00:43:49,167
但当日本海军的注意力集中在中途岛时,
But while the Japanese navy's attention
was focused on Midway lsland,

471
00:43:49,251 --> 00:43:53,713
美国海军正在准备反击日本航母舰队
the American navy were preparing to strike
back at the Japanese carrier fleet.

472
00:43:53,797 --> 00:43:57,175
我们有一个极大的优势...
我们破解了他们的密码
We had a wonderful advantage...
we were breaking their code

473
00:43:57,259 --> 00:43:58,400
而他们不知道这点
and they didn't know it.

474
00:43:58,400 --> 00:44:01,804
所以我们对那里将发生什么有点概念
So we had some idea
what was going to happen there.

475
00:44:01,889 --> 00:44:09,103
我们和航母编队出现在
正确的地点来迎击他们
We were on the scene with the carrier
force in the right spot to meet them.

476
00:45:14,044 --> 00:45:17,755
中途岛(战役),有史以来最伟大的海战之一,
Midway, one of the greatest
sea battles of all time,

477
00:45:17,840 --> 00:45:21,676
意味着美国重新夺得了太平洋的制海权
meant the US regained
naval control of the Pacific

478
00:45:21,760 --> 00:45:26,806
并且是日本想要进一步征服的梦想的终结
and was the end of Japan's hope
of any further conquests.

479
00:45:28,267 --> 00:45:33,396
在六个月前发动了空袭
珍珠港的四艘日本航空母舰
The same four Japanese carriers that had launched
the raid on Pearl Harbour six months before

480
00:45:33,480 --> 00:45:42,029
被从因为那天在海上而逃过一劫
的美国航空母舰上起飞的飞机摧毁
were destroyed by planes from the very American carriers
that had been at sea and escaped destruction that day.

481
00:45:46,118 --> 00:45:50,455
（渊田美津雄 飞行队长 因盲肠炎呆在"赤城"号上）
中途岛战役注定了日本的失败
The Battle of Midway doomed Japan.

482
00:45:50,539 --> 00:45:56,085
中途岛战役是,许多人说,太平洋战争的转折点...
The Midway battle was, many people say,
the turning point of the Pacific war...

483
00:45:56,170 --> 00:46:01,466
那就是,在我们这方面来说,从完全撤退
that is, the turning point
from complete retreat on our part,

484
00:46:01,550 --> 00:46:06,804
到至少企图建立一个僵持局面,
并发动反攻的转折点
to at least an attempt
to establish a stalemate, and offensive.

485
00:46:06,889 --> 00:46:12,602
转折点不仅发生在海上,也发生在陆地上
Turning point not just
at sea, but on land too.

486
00:46:14,730 --> 00:46:17,690
所罗门群岛中的瓜达尔卡纳尔岛,
The island of Guadalcanal
in the Solomons,

487
00:46:17,775 --> 00:46:22,403
位于日本征服地区的最南端
the southernmost limit
of the Japanese conquests.

488
00:46:27,159 --> 00:46:30,036
1942年8月,盟军回来了
ln August 1942, the Allies returned.

489
00:46:30,120 --> 00:46:33,956
对美国人来说,这是他们
在战争中的第一次入侵行动
For the Americans,
it was their first invasion of the war.

490
00:46:34,041 --> 00:46:38,920
我们只有美国军力和财力的
一个小小零头...
We had such a tiny fraction
of America's force and money...

491
00:46:39,004 --> 00:46:41,464
资源和人力资源
resources and manpower resources.

492
00:46:41,548 --> 00:46:44,217
90%都去了欧洲
90% went to Europe.

493
00:46:44,301 --> 00:46:48,846
我们在那里只有如此小的一丝存在
We had such a tiny little thread
of existence down there.

494
00:46:48,931 --> 00:46:51,432
这是我们在太平洋地区的第一次攻势
lt was our first offensive
in the Pacific

495
00:46:51,517 --> 00:46:55,269
而我们只派了一个师(美陆战第一师)
and we went in with only one division.

496
00:47:14,873 --> 00:47:19,460
日本人是顽强的战士
他们从不会放弃
The Japanese were tough fighters
and they never would give up.

497
00:47:19,545 --> 00:47:25,925
(劳顿·考灵斯将军 第25步兵师师长)
我们在一个被称为岐阜要塞的地方
孤立了日本人的一个团,
We had isolated a Japanese regiment in
what was known as the Gifu strongpoint,

498
00:47:26,009 --> 00:47:29,262
他们一直战斗到
事实上我们不得不消灭他们(的一刻)
and they fought until
we actually had to annihilate them.

499
00:47:29,346 --> 00:47:33,140
我们包围他们后 我们用喇叭
We used loudspeakers
after we had surrounded them

500
00:47:33,225 --> 00:47:36,727
试图劝说他们投降 但他们不肯投降
and tried to persuade them to surrender,
but they wouldn't surrender.

501
00:47:36,812 --> 00:47:43,776
日本人不应该在瓜达尔卡纳尔岛
作那么大一个努力
Japanese shouldn't have made
such a great effort in Guadalcanal.

502
00:47:43,861 --> 00:47:46,612
他们本可保存他们的实力
They could have saved their strength.

503
00:48:27,279 --> 00:48:31,616
经过很长时间后 太平洋上的优势
终于转到了盟军这一边
At long last the tide had
turned for the Allies in the Pacific.

504
00:48:31,700 --> 00:48:34,869
但这至今仍然只是一个余兴节目
But it was still as yet only a sideshow.

505
00:48:34,953 --> 00:48:38,539
主要的精力都被保留给了欧洲
The main energies
were being reserved for Europe.

506
00:48:38,624 --> 00:48:44,253
那时候对美国公众来说 这真的很奇怪
It was really a little odd to the Americans
in the general public at that time

507
00:48:44,338 --> 00:48:48,299
那就是我们在太平洋只作了如此小的努力
that we were spending
so little effort in the Pacific.

508
00:48:48,383 --> 00:48:52,470
罗斯福总统下定决心 打败希特勒
President Roosevelt made up his mind
that the defeat of Hitler

509
00:48:52,554 --> 00:48:57,683
是到目前为止首先要取得的最重要(目标)...
was by far the most important
to achieve first...

510
00:48:57,768 --> 00:49:00,686
他是最危险的敌人
he was the most dangerous
of the enemies.

511
00:49:00,771 --> 00:49:07,276
他在使美国公众舆论不断地
被引向欧洲方面 非常有技巧
And he was very skilful in keeping American
public opinion directed towards Europe,

512
00:49:07,361 --> 00:49:12,406
尽管我们在日本进行了一次非常主要的行动
和一次非常成功的行动,
although we did have a very major operation
in Japan and a very successful operation,

513
00:49:12,491 --> 00:49:18,454
在我们从珍珠港损失了海军很大一部分(舰船)
这样一个巨大打击中得到恢复以后
after we recovered from the tremendous blow of the loss
of a substantial part of our navy at Pearl Harbour.

514
00:49:18,538 --> 00:49:25,711
我想一般来说公众舆论有这种感觉,
就象我们在棒球中说的,
l think that generally public opinion
had the feeling, as we say in baseball,

515
00:49:25,796 --> 00:49:33,344
大联盟在欧洲 在英国...
我把那(英国)包括在西欧中
the big league was in Europe and in the United
Kingdom... I include that in Western Europe.

516
00:49:33,428 --> 00:49:41,560
"欧洲排在第一"这个决定很早就作出了...
而那是个聪明的决定...
The decision was made early that Europe
came first...and it was a wise decision...

517
00:49:41,645 --> 00:49:47,984
尽管(面对)在太平洋地区很长时间里
我们都被狠揍了一顿 这么个事实
in spite of the fact we got the devil knocked
out of us in the Pacific for a long time.

518
00:49:48,068 --> 00:49:52,863
那是个正确的决定
我觉得每个人都认识到了这一点
That was the right decision
and I think everybody recognised it.

519
00:49:52,948 --> 00:50:00,621
当然,海军对在太平洋被置于
动力不足的状态提出抗议
Now, of course, the navy protested at being
left way underpowered in the Pacific.

520
00:50:00,706 --> 00:50:07,878
而这的确让我们付出非常重的伤亡
以及诸如此类的代价
And it did put us up to
very heavy casualties and all of that.

521
00:50:07,963 --> 00:50:13,467
但我想国家总的来讲同意那个决定
But I think the country in general
agreed with the decision

522
00:50:13,552 --> 00:50:17,263
那就是真正的威胁在欧洲
that the real threat was in Europe.

523
00:50:17,347 --> 00:50:20,349
我们能在我们自己认为
方便时对付日本鬼子,
We could take care of the Japs
in our own good time,

524
00:50:20,434 --> 00:50:26,480
但必须面对的真正敌人在(欧洲)大陆上
but the real thing that had to be met
was on the Continent.

525
00:50:37,534 --> 00:50:41,078
♪ 这是陆军,琼斯先生
♪ This is the army, Mr Jones

526
00:50:41,163 --> 00:50:45,458
♪ 没有私人房间或电话
♪ No private rooms or telephones

527
00:50:45,542 --> 00:50:48,919
♪ 你以前在床上吃早饭
♪ You had your breakfast in bed before

528
00:50:49,004 --> 00:50:53,090
♪ 但你不会再在那里吃了
♪ But you won't have it there any more

529
00:50:53,175 --> 00:50:55,009
这里我们教你如何杀敌:
Here we teach you how to kill:

530
00:50:55,093 --> 00:50:58,345
尽快把对手打倒在地
get the opponent on the ground
as quick as possible

531
00:50:58,430 --> 00:51:01,140
用双脚踢死他,
and snuff out his life
by kicking with both feet,

532
00:51:01,224 --> 00:51:02,933
一脚,手这么放平,
one foot, the flat of the hand,

533
00:51:03,018 --> 00:51:06,103
对准后脖猛烈一击,
把眼睛抠出来,撕裂嘴巴
a rabbit punch,
gouging the eyes out, ripping the mouth.

534
00:51:06,188 --> 00:51:08,564
杀人的高尚艺术
The gentle art of killing a man

535
00:51:08,690 --> 00:51:13,027
是把他打倒在地 并用这种方式踢他 看见吗?
is to get him on the ground
and kick in this manner. See?

536
00:51:17,824 --> 00:51:20,534
来吧,你们都做一次
来吧
Come on, all of you do that.
Come on.

537
00:51:21,661 --> 00:51:25,331
♪ 按喇叭手的命令来做
♪ Do what the buglers command

538
00:51:25,415 --> 00:51:29,543
♪ 他们是在军队里而不是乐队里
♪ They're in the army and not in a band

539
00:51:29,628 --> 00:51:33,798
♪ 这是陆军,布朗先生
♪ This is the army, Mr Brown

540
00:51:33,882 --> 00:51:37,343
♪ 你和你的宝贝儿去镇上
♪ You and your baby went to town

541
00:51:37,427 --> 00:51:40,846
♪ 她担心你,但这是战争
♪ She had you worried,
but this is war

542
00:51:40,931 --> 00:51:44,767
♪ 而她不会再担心你
♪ And she won't worry you any more

543
00:51:44,851 --> 00:51:48,938
♪ 琼斯先生, 格林先生
♪ Mr Jones, Mr Green

544
00:51:49,022 --> 00:51:50,940
♪ 布朗先生...
♪ Mr Brown...

545
00:51:51,024 --> 00:52:04,620
我想丘吉尔先生对他会称之为过早地
在欧洲大陆登陆 有一种真正的反感
Mr Churchill did have a real antipathy, I think,
toward getting ashore what he would call
prematurely onto the European continent.

546
00:52:04,704 --> 00:52:11,669
他对一战中英国一代人的牺牲
有非常清晰的回忆
He had very vivid memories of the sacrifice
of a British generation in World War I.

547
00:52:11,753 --> 00:52:15,798
帕斯尚尔战役和索姆河会战...
它们对他来说一直是梦魇
Passchendaele and the Somme...
they were always nightmares to him.

548
00:52:15,924 --> 00:52:20,928
在所有这些由于珍珠港事件而被唤醒的激情
After all this passion that had been
aroused as a result of Pearl Harbour

549
00:52:21,054 --> 00:52:24,807
和我们正处于战争中,来回行军及操练 之后,
and our being in the war, marching
and counter-marching and training,

550
00:52:24,891 --> 00:52:26,976
我们只是必须在哪里登陆
we just had to get ashore someplace.

551
00:52:27,060 --> 00:52:28,811
考虑到英国的态度,
ln view of the British attitude,

552
00:52:28,895 --> 00:52:33,440
那就是感觉我们还没做好
进入主要战区的准备,
which felt we weren't prepared
to go into the main theatre,

553
00:52:33,525 --> 00:52:36,944
我们四处嗅寻另一个可以
表现我们实力的地点
we sniffed around for another spot
to express our strength

554
00:52:37,028 --> 00:52:38,863
而结果那是非洲
and it turned out it was Africa.

555
00:52:38,947 --> 00:52:43,492
♪ 去那里
♪ Over there

556
00:52:43,577 --> 00:52:45,744
♪ 传个话, 传个话
♪ Send the word, send the word

557
00:52:45,829 --> 00:52:47,955
♪ 去那里
♪ Over there

558
00:52:48,039 --> 00:52:50,499
♪ 那就是美国佬来了
♪ That the Yanks are coming

559
00:52:50,584 --> 00:52:53,002
♪ 美国佬来了
♪ The Yanks are coming

560
00:52:53,086 --> 00:52:56,463
♪ 战鼓到处敲响
♪ The drums rum-tumming everywhere

561
00:52:57,048 --> 00:52:59,133
♪ 所以准备好
♪ So prepare

562
00:52:59,217 --> 00:53:01,552
♪ 作个祈祷
♪ Say a prayer

563
00:53:01,636 --> 00:53:03,679
♪ 传个话, 传个话
♪ Send the word, send the word

564
00:53:03,763 --> 00:53:05,931
♪ 当心点
♪ To beware

565
00:53:06,016 --> 00:53:08,100
♪ 我们要来了
♪ We'll be over

566
00:53:08,185 --> 00:53:10,477
♪ 我们过来了
♪ We're coming over

567
00:53:10,562 --> 00:53:15,400
♪ 我们不会回去 直到那里一切都结束
♪ And we won't come back
till it's over over there

568
00:53:19,400 --> 00:53:24,400
♪ 我们不会回去 直到那里一切都结束
♪ And we won't come back
till it's over over there

569
00:53:26,703 --> 00:53:29,455
1942年11月
November, 1942.

570
00:53:29,539 --> 00:53:32,333
600艘船,装载着人员和物资,
600 ships, loaded with men and material,

571
00:53:32,459 --> 00:53:36,212
向北非进发...火炬行动
set sail for North Africa...
Operation Torch.

572
00:53:36,296 --> 00:53:41,342
当他听到这个消息,罗斯福说,
"我们终于上路了"
Said Roosevelt, when he heard the news,
"At last we're on our way."

