1
00:00:10,218 --> 00:00:12,302
(♪ 吹奏喇叭)
(♪ fanfare)

2
00:00:15,682 --> 00:00:18,892
1945年5月8日
May 8 1945.

3
00:00:21,563 --> 00:00:23,939
V-E日
V-E Day.

4
00:00:24,024 --> 00:00:26,108
欧洲胜利日
Victory in Europe.

5
00:00:30,989 --> 00:00:36,243
经过几年的战斗之后,(人们)
迸发出一股欢乐和解脱(的情绪)
After years of struggle,
an explosion of joy and of relief.

6
00:00:57,098 --> 00:01:01,101
(♪ "布朗妈妈之舞"
哈里斯·维斯顿和伯特·李)
(♪ "Knees Up Mother Brown"
by Harris Weston and Bert Lee)

7
00:01:51,736 --> 00:01:57,032
(英国国歌 "上帝保佑吾王")
♪ 送给他胜利
♪ Send him victorious

8
00:01:57,117 --> 00:02:01,912
♪ 欢乐和光荣
♪ Happy and glorious

9
00:02:01,996 --> 00:02:06,041
♪ 长久统治我们...
♪ Long to reign over us...

10
00:02:06,126 --> 00:02:13,215
(丘吉尔)我们可以允许自己(享受)短暂的喜悦
(Churchill) We may allow ourselves
a brief period of rejoicing.

11
00:02:19,931 --> 00:02:26,019
但让我们片刻也别忘了在前方
(等着我们)的艰苦工作和努力
But let us not forget for a moment
the toils and efforts that lie ahead.

12
00:02:27,313 --> 00:02:30,482
仍然还有日本(在负隅顽抗)
There was still Japan.

13
00:03:28,958 --> 00:03:34,087
东京,1942年12月7日正午前
Tokyo, just before midday
on 7 December 1942.

14
00:03:34,172 --> 00:03:36,715
(♪ 日本国歌)
(♪ Japanese national anthem)

15
00:03:53,524 --> 00:04:01,365
日本人民庆祝了他们的帝国海军
在珍珠港消灭美国舰队的一周年纪念日
The Japanese people observed the first
anniversary of their imperial navy's destruction
of the American fleet at Pearl Harbour.

16
00:04:01,449 --> 00:04:05,160
自从他们得知他们那8000万人口的国家
lt was one year since they learned
that their nation of 80 million

17
00:04:05,245 --> 00:04:11,083
与总人口超过2亿的美国人和
英国人开战 已经过去一年了
had engaged the combined might of over
200 million Americans and British.

18
00:04:11,167 --> 00:04:17,547
许多人曾严肃地,甚至担心地
收听了攻击珍珠港的新闻
Many had heard the news of the Pearl Harbour
attack soberly,even apprehensively.

19
00:04:20,176 --> 00:04:26,139
但是接下来 胜利一场接着一场...
香港,马来亚,新加坡
But then came victory after victory...
Hong Kong, Malaya, Singapore.

20
00:04:26,224 --> 00:04:28,558
早先的恐惧消失在狂喜之中
Earlier fears were lost in exultation.

21
00:04:47,453 --> 00:04:50,122
首相东条英机将军,
Prime Minister General Hideki Tojo,

22
00:04:50,206 --> 00:04:55,627
那些把日本变成一个侵略性的
集权国家的军国主义分子的代表,
representative of the militarists who had made
Japan into an aggressive totalitarian state,

23
00:04:55,712 --> 00:04:58,046
已带领他的国人投入这场战争
had led his countrymen into the war.

24
00:04:58,172 --> 00:05:01,800
现在他向他们保证取得最终的胜利
Now he promised them final victory.

25
00:05:03,636 --> 00:05:07,472
国家将打完这次战争的最后一轮(战斗)
The nation will complete
the final round of this conflict.

26
00:05:07,557 --> 00:05:13,061
为了打倒美国和英国
我们将战斗到最后一天
To overthrow America and Britain
we will fight until the last day.

27
00:05:16,482 --> 00:05:21,945
到那时我们将在大东亚地区消灭我们的敌人
Then in the Greater Asian area we shall
accomplish the destruction of our enemies.

28
00:05:22,030 --> 00:05:24,000
现在,在(战争)第二年的开始,
Now, at the start of the second year,

29
00:05:24,000 --> 00:05:27,993
我本人和国家都想起了前线的战士们,
both myself and the nation
think about the men in the front line,

30
00:05:28,077 --> 00:05:33,040
我要再次表达取得最终胜利的决心
and once again I express
determination for final victory.

31
00:05:33,124 --> 00:05:37,669
战争工作必须被推进下去
而斗争也要继续进行
War work must be pushed on
and the struggle carried forward.

32
00:05:41,924 --> 00:05:46,000
在这时,日本不是一个工业巨人
At this time,Japan was
not an industrial giant.

33
00:05:46,000 --> 00:05:47,500
但在战争的这第一年里,
But in this first year of war,

34
00:05:47,500 --> 00:05:51,600
他们已看到了日本士兵的精神力量和纪律
they had seen the Japanese soldiers'
spiritual strength and discipline

35
00:05:51,600 --> 00:05:58,148
战胜了在物质上更强大
但士气较差的美国人和英国人
prevail over the materially stronger
but morally inferior Americans and British.

36
00:06:03,600 --> 00:06:09,785
在国土防线上 同样的献身精神
会令日本新赢取的帝国(领土)坚不可摧
The same dedication on the home front would
make Japan's newly won empire unassailable.

37
00:06:10,870 --> 00:06:12,746
(♪ 吹奏喇叭)
(♪ fanfare)

38
00:06:18,419 --> 00:06:20,200
对一些见多识广的日本人来说,
For some well-informed Japanese,

39
00:06:20,200 --> 00:06:24,049
偷袭珍珠港是一次令人震惊的赌博
the Pearl Harbour attack
had been an astonishing gamble.

40
00:06:24,133 --> 00:06:31,640
如同往常我在大约九点上班
每个人都在那里
l came to work as usual about nine
o'clock and everybody was there.

41
00:06:31,724 --> 00:06:34,434
有武道的音乐在播放
There was martial music playing

42
00:06:34,519 --> 00:06:38,939
而当我看到报纸的号外 我几乎要跌倒了
and I almost fell over
when I saw the newspaper extra

43
00:06:39,023 --> 00:06:44,111
上面说天皇已经向美国和英国宣战
saying that the emperor had declared war
on United States and Great Britain.

44
00:06:44,195 --> 00:06:49,616
我觉得马路上的人也同样会有
这种被完全大吃一惊的感觉
l think the man on the street had the same
feeling of being taken by complete surprise.

45
00:06:52,600 --> 00:07:01,000
但现在,宣传影片能够描写 兴高采烈的
日本飞行员猛轰位于珍珠港的美国舰队
But now, propaganda film could portray jubilant Japanese
aviators smashing the American fleet at Pearl Harbour.

46
00:07:29,115 --> 00:07:32,325
怀疑者信服了
Doubters were persuaded.

47
00:07:35,997 --> 00:07:40,542
新闻片强调(曾经)傲慢的白人的恭顺
Newsreels emphasised the humbling
of the arrogant whites.

48
00:07:50,678 --> 00:07:55,765
日本人相信 他们自己的士兵总是战斗到死
The Japanese believed that their own
soldiers always fought to the death.

49
00:07:55,850 --> 00:08:01,300
白人俘虏被比他们矮许多的日本人
压往不名誉的战俘营的场景
The sight of white prisoners dwarfing the Japanese
who herded them into dishonourable captivity

50
00:08:01,300 --> 00:08:05,442
更帮助他们对自己的无敌确信无疑
helped convince them
of their own invincibility.

51
00:08:20,291 --> 00:08:27,172
日本在取胜 每天我们都从电台上
听到所有那些胜利(的消息)
Japan was winning and every day we
heard over the radio all the victories.

52
00:08:27,256 --> 00:08:31,885
整个国家都非常兴奋
And the whole nation was very excited.

53
00:08:31,969 --> 00:08:39,935
当我听到关于战争爆发的新闻时
我当时的想法是,"将会发生什么呢?"
And the thought I had at the time when I heard
the news about the war was,"What's going to happen?"

54
00:08:40,061 --> 00:08:48,527
但紧接着 电台上就整天播放 所有那些胜利
(的消息)和狂热的战争歌曲和进行曲...
But immediately all the victories and big war
songs and marches over the radio all day long...

55
00:08:48,611 --> 00:08:55,951
所以我们...十分兴奋
而这几乎就象是一个节日
So we are... quite excited
and it was almost like a festival.

56
00:09:10,758 --> 00:09:13,600
战争已经伴随日本人长达十年
War had been with the Japanese
people for ten years.

57
00:09:13,600 --> 00:09:19,766
自从1931年以来,他们的军队就一直
在中国打一场无尽的,令人沮丧的战争
Since 1931, their armies had been fighting
an endless, frustrating war in China.

58
00:09:20,476 --> 00:09:23,353
太平洋的胜利来得又快又彻底
Victory in the Pacific
had been quick and complete.

59
00:09:23,437 --> 00:09:26,439
这里终于有些什么东西可以庆祝了
Here at last was something to celebrate.

60
00:09:48,379 --> 00:09:50,200
在偷袭珍珠港的数年前,
For years before Pearl Harbour,

61
00:09:50,200 --> 00:09:54,968
在每个日本城市都举行过模拟空袭演习
there had been mock air-raid drills
in every Japanese city.

62
00:09:57,597 --> 00:10:01,224
这倒不是针对中国那几乎就
不存在的空军的预防措施,
Not a precaution against China's
almost nonexistent air force,

63
00:10:01,309 --> 00:10:06,146
而是把尚武的激情保持在高点的方法的一部分
but part of the process of keeping
war-like emotion at a high pitch.

64
00:10:23,414 --> 00:10:25,498
所有人都参加
All took part.

65
00:10:27,084 --> 00:10:30,670
街坊协会..."隣組"...
Neighbourhood Associations...
the Tonarigumi...

66
00:10:30,755 --> 00:10:36,384
确保天皇在国内的每个臣民都参与遥远的战争
ensured that every one of the emperor's subjects
at home was involved in the distant war.

67
00:10:37,470 --> 00:10:42,724
当时街坊协会控制了我们的全部生活
The Neighbourhood Associations
controlled all our life at that time.

68
00:10:42,808 --> 00:10:47,103
来自政府的所有指示都通过"隣組"传达,
All the instructions from the government
were through the Tonarigumi,

69
00:10:47,188 --> 00:10:50,357
所以我们必须服从它
so we had to obey it.

70
00:10:50,441 --> 00:10:54,569
我们也依赖"隣組"
And we relied upon the Tonarigumi.

71
00:11:00,743 --> 00:11:05,872
在每个街坊里,在学校里,在运动场和街道上,
ln every neighbourhood,in schools,
in playing fields and on the streets,

72
00:11:05,956 --> 00:11:11,711
普通公民都爱国地让他们自己甘心
服从于 思想和行为的严密管控
ordinary citizens patriotically submitted
themselves to regimentation of thought and act.

73
00:11:24,684 --> 00:11:29,270
爱国的美德从婴儿时期就开始灌输
The inculcation of patriotic
virtues began in infancy.

74
00:11:46,539 --> 00:11:53,670
从他们记事起,孩子们就全身心准备为
一个比他们自身更重要的理由而献身...
From their earliest days,children prepared mind
and body to serve a cause greater than themselves...

75
00:11:53,754 --> 00:11:56,464
家族,国家,
the family, the nation,

76
00:11:56,549 --> 00:11:58,258
天皇
the emperor.

77
00:12:05,766 --> 00:12:10,645
如果国家处于战争中,孩子们也不得不为此作好准备
And if the nation was at war,
children had to be ready for that, too.

78
00:12:35,254 --> 00:12:36,500
当(他们)从学校毕业,
When school was over,

79
00:12:36,500 --> 00:12:46,222
在帝国陆军,海军,空军中为他们的国家服役
就将是他们的职责和他们的特权
it would be their duty and their privilege to serve their
country in the imperial forces on land, on sea,in the air.

80
00:12:53,647 --> 00:12:57,275
高中学生做一天空军(飞行员)
High-school pupils
joined the air force for a day.

81
00:12:57,359 --> 00:12:58,526
如果他们幸运的话,
lf they were lucky,

82
00:12:58,611 --> 00:13:02,405
他们不用等太久就会有机会
作为成年人参加(空军)
they would have the chance
to join as adults before too long.

83
00:13:06,660 --> 00:13:13,583
当然,日本人从摇篮到坟墓就一直
被教育(这么)三四个最重要的事实...
Of course,the Japanese were brought up in three
or four cardinal truths from cradle to grave...

84
00:13:13,667 --> 00:13:17,462
(那就是)天皇是神圣的,国家是不可战胜的,
that the emperor was divine,
the country was invincible,

85
00:13:17,546 --> 00:13:22,550
它是由...一个神选的种族组成的
and it consisted of...a chosen race.

86
00:13:22,635 --> 00:13:24,000
就像这些东西,
Things like these,

87
00:13:24,000 --> 00:13:27,806
从幼儿园起就被喋喋不休地灌入日本人的脑中
which were drummed into the Japanese
mind from kindergarten up.

88
00:13:31,352 --> 00:13:35,855
日本的男孩子被教育要仿效武士道...
Japanese boys were taught to imitate
the martial code of the samurai...

89
00:13:35,940 --> 00:13:40,026
古老而又凶猛,对敌人或对自己都没有怜悯
archaic and ferocious,
devoid of pity for enemy or for self.

90
00:13:45,616 --> 00:13:51,454
对武士来说,死在战斗中就是死在最完美的时刻,
For the samurai, to die in battle
was to fall at the moment of perfection,

91
00:13:51,539 --> 00:13:53,706
就象樱花那样(凋零)
as the cherry blossom does.

92
00:14:03,000 --> 00:14:14,102
对佛的崇拜在日本已和古老的对神灵,对祖先,对太阳
女神,(即)天照大神的神道教崇拜 共存了几个世纪
The worship of Buddha had coexisted in Japan for
centuries with the ancient Shinto worship of spirits,
of ancestors,of the sun goddess, Amaterasu.

93
00:14:30,000 --> 00:14:39,000
但在1920年代和30年代,民族主义者和
军国主义者坚持把神道教变成国教
But in the 1920s and '30s, the nationalists and militarists
had insisted that Shinto be made the state religion.

94
00:14:41,672 --> 00:14:45,925
神道教是纯净的
它完全是日本的
Shinto was pure.
lt was strictly Japanese.

95
00:14:46,010 --> 00:14:50,096
而神道教的太阳女神,日本人虔诚地相信,
And it was from the Shinto sun goddess,
the Japanese devoutly believed,

96
00:14:50,180 --> 00:14:54,183
该国的领袖正是她的直系后裔...
that the nation's high priest
was directly descended...

97
00:14:54,268 --> 00:14:56,352
天皇
the emperor.

98
00:14:59,648 --> 00:15:03,276
天皇是一个神和一个武士首领
The emperor was a god
and a warrior chief.

99
00:15:03,360 --> 00:15:09,908
那种通过他,日本民族注定要征服(别国)
的神秘信仰,被系统性地宣传
The mystic belief that, through him,the Japanese race
was destined for conquest was systematically propagated.

100
00:15:18,000 --> 00:15:21,000
军方以天皇的名义采取行动,
The military acted in the emperor's name,

101
00:15:21,000 --> 00:15:23,500
但是他们设法做到,尽管表面上
(天皇是国家最高领袖),
but they contrived that,
in spite of appearances,

102
00:15:23,500 --> 00:15:26,633
他(实际上)在世间没有保留什么真正的权利
he retained little real power on Earth.

103
00:15:29,386 --> 00:15:34,140
(裕仁)天皇强烈地渴望和平,
The emperor was deeply solicitous of peace,

104
00:15:34,224 --> 00:15:43,024
(加瀬俊一 内阁秘书)
这意味着他反对与美国开战
which means that he was opposed to
starting hostilities with America.

105
00:15:43,108 --> 00:15:54,300
但他的立场是 如果内阁全体一致地建议(采取)某项政策,
But his position was such that if the cabinet
recommended, unanimously,a certain line of policy,

106
00:15:54,300 --> 00:16:00,416
他就不能不赞成它,尽管他可能从心底里不喜欢它
he could not disapprove of it,
although he might dislike it at heart.

107
00:16:01,043 --> 00:16:03,200
在一个由一名将军领导的政府里,
In a government headed by a general,

108
00:16:03,200 --> 00:16:05,922
这意味着做军队想要做的事
this meant doing what the army wanted.

109
00:16:11,720 --> 00:16:17,350
日本阵亡将士的骨灰被装在盒子里运回国
The ashes of Japan's war dead
were carried home, packed in boxes.

110
00:16:18,477 --> 00:16:22,000
阵亡者的家属,寡妇和母亲,
Relatives of the fallen,
widows and mothers,

111
00:16:22,000 --> 00:16:28,695
并不比(与她们的亲人)说再见的那天
拥有更多骄傲的理由,更多流泪的权利
had no more occasion for pride,no more right
to tears than the day they had said goodbye.

112
00:16:28,779 --> 00:16:34,867
送儿子们或丈夫去为天皇而死 是最高义务
To send sons or husband to die
for the emperor was the highest duty.

113
00:16:34,952 --> 00:16:37,495
"我们将在靖国神社相会,"
"We'll meet at the Yasukuni Shrine,"

114
00:16:37,579 --> 00:16:39,700
在那里阵亡者的骨灰被供奉起来,
where the ashes of the war dead
were consecrated,

115
00:16:39,700 --> 00:16:42,800
是离别的士兵们前往战场前的传统告别语,
was the traditional farewell of the
soldiers leaving for the battle front,

116
00:16:42,800 --> 00:16:48,047
(这句话)被裹在"腹卷"...
由一千针缝起来的保护性腰带里
wrapped in haramaki...the protective
belly band of a thousand stitches.

117
00:16:51,385 --> 00:16:54,178
一个女孩站在街角,
A girl stands on the
corners of the streets,

118
00:16:54,263 --> 00:16:56,431
比如说在东京,沿着银座街,
say if in Tokyo, along the Ginza,

119
00:16:56,515 --> 00:17:00,200
请求每个经过的妇女缝一针
and asks each passer-by woman
to make a stitch.

120
00:17:00,200 --> 00:17:03,271
而她必须收集一千针
And she must collect a thousand stitches.

121
00:17:03,355 --> 00:17:08,443
这个(千人针腰带)是给一位士兵的
我就得到一根 你把这腰带裹在你的腹部
And this is given to a soldier. I got one.
You wrapped this round your belly.

122
00:17:08,527 --> 00:17:13,865
它应该能使你的胃部保暖 那样你
就不会着凉 或起诸如此类的作用,
lt's supposed to keep your stomach warm
so that you don't catch cold or this or that,

123
00:17:13,949 --> 00:17:15,300
但(应该)也能抵挡子弹
but also to ward off bullets.

124
00:17:15,300 --> 00:17:20,621
现在,我们都知道这是不可能的,
但这也象是一个吉祥物
Now, we all know this cannot be done,
but this is like a charm, also.

125
00:17:20,706 --> 00:17:25,918
我当时会想,现在我不知道我是否应该说这个,
And I used to think, now I don't know
whether I should say this,

126
00:17:26,003 --> 00:17:28,421
但我(当时)觉得这非常不公平,
but I felt this is very unfair,

127
00:17:28,505 --> 00:17:31,090
尤其当我得到去海外的命令时
especially when I got
the order to go overseas.

128
00:17:31,175 --> 00:17:35,094
日本女孩们给了我这个千人针
The Japanese girls are giving
me this thousand stitches.

129
00:17:35,179 --> 00:17:39,000
我就要死了 我还没和一个女人睡过觉
I am going to die.
I have not experienced a woman.

130
00:17:39,000 --> 00:17:48,200
为什么她们不能把她们的身体给我来(让我)享受,
无论我的生命有多短暂,让我活着来享受它的全部?
Why cannot they give me their body to enjoy,
and let me live,however short my life is,
to enjoy the fullness of it?

131
00:17:48,200 --> 00:17:52,000
因为和我睡觉不会杀死这女孩,你知道?
Because sleeping with me is not
going to kill the girl, you know?

132
00:17:52,000 --> 00:17:53,800
也许她会喜欢,我不知道
Maybe she likes it, I don't know.

133
00:17:53,800 --> 00:17:59,243
但现在我就要死了,而我得到的就只是一根千人针
But here I am about to die,
and all I get is a thousand stitches.

134
00:18:03,000 --> 00:18:08,044
战时男女的告别应该是一种精神上的经历...
Wartime farewells for man and women were
supposed to be a spiritual experience...

135
00:18:08,128 --> 00:18:10,713
仪式的,不动感情的
ceremonial, unsentimental.

136
00:18:52,840 --> 00:18:58,386
伤势痊愈的士兵离开医院 唱起了"海军进行曲"
Men recovered from wounds left hospital
to the singing of the Umi Yukaba.

137
00:18:58,470 --> 00:19:02,557
"我去远隔重洋的一个孤坟," 他们唱道,
"I go to a lonely grave
far across the sea," they sang,

138
00:19:02,641 --> 00:19:05,309
并再次投入战争
and went off to the war again.

139
00:19:10,941 --> 00:19:15,695
但是突然,在偷袭珍珠港后不到五个月...
But suddenly, less than five months
after Pearl Harbour...

140
00:19:17,948 --> 00:19:20,950
...战争不再那么遥远了
...the war was not so far away.

141
00:19:29,209 --> 00:19:32,000
1942年4月18日
18 April 1942.

142
00:19:32,000 --> 00:19:36,674
16架(B-25)"米切尔"式中型轰炸机,
在詹姆斯·杜立特中校的指挥下,
16 Mitchell medium bombers, commanded
by Lieutenant Colonel James Doolittle,

143
00:19:36,758 --> 00:19:39,302
从美国航空母舰"大黄蜂"号上起飞,
set out from the US aircraft carrier,Hornet,

144
00:19:39,386 --> 00:19:42,972
对日本进行首次空袭
for the first-ever air raid on Japan.

145
00:19:53,200 --> 00:19:59,864
美国人的目标是对日本容易遭受空袭(的特点)
作一次象征性的,但却是早期的证明
The American aim was to make a token, but early,
demonstration of Japan's vulnerability to air attack.

146
00:19:59,948 --> 00:20:02,658
在这点上,他们完全成功了
ln this, they entirely succeeded.

147
00:20:03,700 --> 00:20:12,752
(加瀬俊一 内阁秘书)
当杜立特的空袭在东京上空进行的时候,
When Doolittle's raid was
conducted over the sky of Tokyo,

148
00:20:12,836 --> 00:20:18,000
那产生了一种...产生了一种惊慌失措(的情绪)
that produced a...produced a sort of consternation

149
00:20:18,000 --> 00:20:31,312
因为军方向公众反复保证 日本的领空是不可穿越的
because the military repeatedly assured the
public that the Japanese sky was impenetrable.

150
00:20:32,064 --> 00:20:39,153
杜立特的轰炸机渗入了日本的天空
在其城市里投下仅仅16吨炸弹
Doolittle's bombers did penetrate Japan's skies
to drop a mere 16 tons of bombs on her cities.

151
00:20:39,238 --> 00:20:41,948
实际的损害并不大
The actual damage was not great.

152
00:20:42,074 --> 00:20:43,741
冲击却很大
The shock was.

153
00:20:43,825 --> 00:20:47,870
日本报纸被告知如何排印新闻
The Japanese press were told
how to display the news.

154
00:20:47,955 --> 00:20:52,291
(此次轰炸的)性质被夸大为一次残忍的行动...
The complexion was put on as a cruel act...

155
00:20:52,376 --> 00:20:56,545
对平民,妇女和儿童不加区别的轰炸
indiscriminate bombing of
civilians and women and children.

156
00:20:59,883 --> 00:21:03,427
8名杜立特轰炸的机组成员被俘
Eight Doolittle flyers were captured.

157
00:21:10,269 --> 00:21:14,000
对日本人来说,轰炸是发生在别人身上的事情
For the Japanese, bombing was something
that happened to other people.

158
00:21:15,000 --> 00:21:19,944
他们对这种野蛮行为发生在他们身上感到愤怒
They were angry that this barbarity
had happened to them.

159
00:21:24,032 --> 00:21:27,535
俘虏们被一个军事法庭审判
The prisoners were tried
by a military court.

160
00:21:27,619 --> 00:21:30,246
三个人被处决了
Three were executed.

161
00:21:38,797 --> 00:21:43,467
日本妇女的主要作用是生儿子
The main function of Japanese
women was to bear sons.

162
00:21:43,552 --> 00:21:46,929
只擅长诸如茶道这样的女性艺术,
Skilled only in such feminine arts
as the tea ceremony,

163
00:21:47,014 --> 00:21:49,000
她们(一直)待在幕后
they stayed in the background.

164
00:21:49,000 --> 00:21:51,000
现在随着各条战线把男人们都带走,
Now with the battle fronts
taking the men away,

165
00:21:51,000 --> 00:21:53,686
她们被安排去从事更严峻的事情
they were directed to sterner things.

166
00:22:18,086 --> 00:22:23,000
乡村妇女习惯了与她们的男人一起在田里干活
Country women were used to taking their
place in the fields alongside their men.

167
00:22:23,000 --> 00:22:26,802
但对来自于城市的妇女来说,
这场战争意味着一次彻底的变化
But for the women from the cities,
the war meant a complete change.

168
00:22:26,928 --> 00:22:28,800
为了给这个国家被耗尽的食品储藏库供应(粮食),
To stock the nation's depleted larder,

169
00:22:28,800 --> 00:22:32,558
她们也被征募来进行长时间劳作
they too were conscripted
to labour long hours.

170
00:22:40,400 --> 00:22:46,947
她们开采煤炭 以最大程度地利用日本
贫乏的资源 并使战争机器保持运转
They mined coal to make the utmost use of Japan's
scanty resources and keep the war machine moving.

171
00:23:04,841 --> 00:23:07,760
城市里的女孩被培养成为妻子和母亲,
City girls were brought up
to be wives and mothers,

172
00:23:07,844 --> 00:23:11,400
被认为是"可敬的幕后人"
to be known as the "honourable hidden one".

173
00:23:11,400 --> 00:23:15,476
现在她们从隐居中走出来 并学习新技能
Now they came out of their seclusion
and learned new skills.

174
00:23:20,600 --> 00:23:28,114
日本的妇女被告知,为了确保胜利,她们必须
接管男人的工作,就象她们的敌人所做的那样
The women of Japan must take over men's work, they
were told,as their enemies had done,to ensure victory.

175
00:24:08,613 --> 00:24:10,865
当我们在工厂工作,
When we worked at the factory,

176
00:24:10,949 --> 00:24:16,454
每隔一个星期 我们必须从下午3点工作到11点
every other week we had to work from three
o'clock in the afternoon until 11 o'clock.

177
00:24:16,538 --> 00:24:20,800
当我们在11点钟结束我们的工作,
And at 11 o'clock
when we finish our work,

178
00:24:20,800 --> 00:24:27,590
他们会把我们带到一个食堂
他们会给我们一碗汤
they would take us to a dining room
and they would give us one bowl of soup.

179
00:24:27,674 --> 00:24:35,055
事实上,那只是(一碗)热盐水
里面也许有两三粒黄豆
Actually, it was hot salt water
with maybe two or three soy beans.

180
00:24:35,140 --> 00:24:37,725
我们非常饿
And we are very hungry.

181
00:24:37,809 --> 00:24:42,938
或者在碗底也许只有一根面条
Or maybe just one noodle at the bottom.

182
00:24:43,023 --> 00:24:46,442
我们得到的一切东西都要通过配给
Everything we got through rations.

183
00:24:46,526 --> 00:24:51,489
除非我们有一张配给卡,
我们得不到任何东西
Unless we have a card for rations,
we couldn't get anything.

184
00:24:51,573 --> 00:24:58,204
我们不得不做一些自给自足(的工作),
我们在我们的花园里种土豆
We have to do some self-supply,
and we grew potatoes in our gardens.

185
00:24:58,288 --> 00:25:03,167
我们非常努力地工作 来种我们自己的蔬菜
We worked very hard
to grow our own vegetables.

186
00:25:03,251 --> 00:25:09,256
我们每天的生活,那种生活非常,非常艰难
Our everyday life,that life was very, very hard.

187
00:25:10,258 --> 00:25:12,300
皇后本人承担了一个新角色,
The empress herself
took on a new role,

188
00:25:12,300 --> 00:25:15,763
敦促国家作出更多努力,更多牺牲
urging the nation to more
effort, more sacrifice.

189
00:25:15,847 --> 00:25:18,724
为了胜利,牺牲是必要的,
Sacrifice was necessary for victory,

190
00:25:18,808 --> 00:25:21,769
而他们对取得最终胜利的信心仍未动摇
and in final victory
their belief was still unshaken.

191
00:25:22,812 --> 00:25:26,300
没人知道,到了1942年6月
None knew that by June 1942,

192
00:25:26,300 --> 00:25:30,027
战争已经到了仅仅为了生存而战的地步
the battle had already become
one simply for survival.

193
00:25:43,917 --> 00:25:45,600
1942年6月
June 1942.

194
00:25:45,600 --> 00:25:52,174
美国战机起飞拦截一支进攻中途岛的日本舰队
United States war planes take off to intercept
a Japanese armada attacking the island of Midway.

195
00:26:08,817 --> 00:26:13,779
为了这场战役,日本海军(联合舰队)总司令
山本(五十六)海军大将,
To this battle, Admiral Yamamoto,
the Japanese naval commander-in-chief,

196
00:26:13,863 --> 00:26:18,701
派出了日本(联合)舰队中四艘最大的航空母舰
had committed the four largest
aircraft carriers in the Japanese fleet.

197
00:26:18,785 --> 00:26:21,579
当(中途岛)战役在1942年6月5日结束时,
When the battle ended on 5 June 1942,

198
00:26:21,663 --> 00:26:26,750
山本的四艘航母 要么成了
燃烧着的残骸 要么被击沉
Yamamoto's four carriers
were blazing wrecks or sunk.

199
00:26:26,835 --> 00:26:31,380
中途岛(战役)是一场日本海军
再也未能从中恢复过来的战败
Midway was a defeat from which
Japan's navy never recovered.

200
00:26:31,464 --> 00:26:36,427
但日本人民被告知 中途岛是一场胜利
But the Japanese people were told
that Midway was a victory.

201
00:26:36,511 --> 00:26:40,347
真相甚至对政府成员也隐瞒起来
The truth was concealed even
from members of the government.

202
00:26:44,561 --> 00:26:50,600
(星野直樹 内阁官房长官 战后被判决为甲级战犯)
我们被告知 一艘航空母舰被击沉 一艘被严重损坏
We were told that one aircraft carrier
was sunk and one was severely damaged.

203
00:26:50,600 --> 00:26:53,700
由于有四艘航母参加了这场战役,
Since there were four carriers
involved in the battle,

204
00:26:53,700 --> 00:26:56,500
(那么)根据我们听到的说法,
(应该)有三艘已经回来了,
the way we heard it,
three had come back,

205
00:26:56,500 --> 00:26:59,992
尽管有一艘被严重损坏
although one was severely damaged.

206
00:27:00,076 --> 00:27:04,913
但英美这边说全部四艘都被击沉了
But the Anglo-American side was
saying that all four had been sunk.

207
00:27:04,998 --> 00:27:07,833
这在我们的心中留下了一些怀疑
This left some doubts in our minds.

208
00:27:07,959 --> 00:27:11,170
我们强烈要求海军给我们更多的细节,
We pressed the navy
to give us more details,

209
00:27:11,254 --> 00:27:14,548
但他们坚持他们原来的说法
but they stuck to their original announcement.

210
00:27:19,304 --> 00:27:22,848
在中途岛战役中我是个新闻摄影师
I was a news cameraman
in the Midway battle.

211
00:27:22,932 --> 00:27:26,310
当我们回到我们位于日本海的基地时,
When we got back to our base
in the Japan Sea,

212
00:27:26,394 --> 00:27:29,480
我们甚至未被允许写任何信
we were not even allowed
to write any letters.

213
00:27:29,564 --> 00:27:33,275
伤员被安置在隔离病房内
The wounded were kept
in the isolation wards.

214
00:27:33,401 --> 00:27:38,489
一个绝密命令规定 决不许谈论中途岛战役,
A top-secret order said that nothing
could be talked of the Midway battle,

215
00:27:38,573 --> 00:27:41,659
甚至在海军内部也不可以
not even within the navy itself.

216
00:27:41,743 --> 00:27:48,082
在回到日本后 我事实上被关押了一个半月
l was virtually kept prisoner for about
a month and a half after returning to Japan.

217
00:27:48,166 --> 00:27:52,711
作为一个记者,我受到了特别严格的监视
As a journalist, I was kept under
particularly strict surveillance

218
00:27:52,796 --> 00:27:57,716
因为我们据说是喜欢夸夸其谈的家伙
而且口风很不紧的大嘴巴
because we were reputedly great talkers
and loose with our tongues.

219
00:27:57,842 --> 00:28:02,346
在战争剩下的时间里 我被禁止回到东京
And I was kept from going back to Tokyo
while the rest of the war lasted.

220
00:28:03,139 --> 00:28:09,853
真实的情况当然从未被"日本放送協会"播出
The true situation was never broadcast
from the NHK, of course.

221
00:28:09,979 --> 00:28:19,279
那时候播出的...每条新闻都被严格审查
Every news... broadcast was
strictly censored in those days.

222
00:28:22,826 --> 00:28:31,917
公众只知道 日本陆军和海军在
不断取得他们打的每场战役的胜利
The general public only knew that the Japanese
army and navy kept winning every battle they fought.

223
00:28:38,717 --> 00:28:41,385
没有新闻,只有宣传
No news, just propaganda.

224
00:28:46,725 --> 00:28:52,521
在宣传影片里那被不断描绘的战斗中
只有一个结果是可以想象的
Only one outcome was imaginable in the conflict
ceaselessly portrayed in the propaganda films.

225
00:28:52,605 --> 00:28:57,526
东方人民的白人压迫者 被勇敢的日本士兵战胜
The white oppressors of Oriental people
overcome by the brave Japanese soldier.

226
00:29:21,050 --> 00:29:23,500
斯巴达式的日本士兵,反过来,
The spartan Japanese soldier, in turn,

227
00:29:23,500 --> 00:29:27,848
被对他的白种敌人安逸的生活
的蔑视和暴怒弄得感觉受不了
overcome by contempt and rage
at his white enemy's soft living.

228
00:29:41,696 --> 00:29:46,617
东京,1943年6月5日
Tokyo, 5 June 1943.

229
00:29:46,743 --> 00:29:56,418
策划了(偷袭)珍珠港胜利的伟大指挥官
山本五十六海军大将的国葬
The state funeral for Admiral lsoroku Yamamoto,the great
commander who had masterminded the victory at Pearl Harbour.

230
00:29:56,503 --> 00:30:04,927
日本人民被告知,山本象英雄那样
在前线的一架战机里英勇地死去,
Yamamoto died a hero,the Japanese people were told,
in the front line,meeting death gallantly in a war plane.

231
00:30:05,011 --> 00:30:08,764
失去他(的损失)比失去许多战舰(的损失)还要大
His loss was greater than many battleships.

232
00:30:17,148 --> 00:30:20,234
但这场对一次战败的首次公开承认,
But this first public admission of a defeat,

233
00:30:20,360 --> 00:30:23,403
尽管被描绘成仅仅象征英雄主义,
although represented as only symbolic of heroism,

234
00:30:23,488 --> 00:30:28,283
却隐藏了山本本人已经清楚意识到的严酷事实
hid grimmer truths of which
Yamamoto himself had been well aware.

235
00:30:28,368 --> 00:30:35,749
他知道敌人的物质优势,一旦被
全面动员起来,将会是压倒性的
He knew that the enemy's material superiority,
once fully mobilised,would be overwhelming.

236
00:30:35,834 --> 00:30:40,170
在珍珠港,他打赌战争将会是短暂的
At Pearl Harbour, he had gambled
that the war would be a short one.

237
00:30:40,255 --> 00:30:43,382
在中途岛,赌博输掉了
At Midway, the gamble was lost.

238
00:30:55,000 --> 00:31:03,235
山本在现在充斥着敌人飞机的天空中被击落,
(这片天空下的)海洋现在被敌人的海军所控制
Yamamoto had been shot down in skies now swarming with
enemy planes,over seas now dominated by the enemy's navy.

239
00:31:08,825 --> 00:31:13,662
到1944年,天平已完全偏离日本一边
By 1944, the scales had tipped
fully against Japan.

240
00:31:15,290 --> 00:31:20,919
金属已成为一种宝贵的战争商品
贵重到不能用来做装饰品或用于典礼
Metal had become a precious war commodity
too valuable for ornament or ceremony.

241
00:31:23,506 --> 00:31:30,220
这场战争是为一片原材料稀缺的土地
取得它们而打...最重要的,是为了石油
The war had been fought to secure raw materials
for a land where they were scarce...above all, for oil.

242
00:31:30,305 --> 00:31:34,516
但现在东条将军吹嘘的 将从他们
征服的地区流回(日本)的资源
But now the resources General Tojo had
boasted would flow from their conquests

243
00:31:34,601 --> 00:31:37,936
正被(潜艇)送入大洋的海底 而不是运回日本
were getting no nearer to Japan
than the bottom of the ocean.

244
00:31:38,021 --> 00:31:41,857
运回的(资源)不足以使战争机器继续运转
Not enough got through
to keep the war machine going.

245
00:31:43,067 --> 00:31:44,800
食物很稀缺
And food was scarce.

246
00:31:44,800 --> 00:31:50,616
官方的每天1500卡路里的(食物)配给量,
(相当于)维持生存的水平,经常不能被满足
The official daily ration of 1500 calories,
subsistence level,was often not met.

247
00:31:50,700 --> 00:31:54,077
大米收成是50年来最差的
The rice harvest
was the worst for 50 years.

248
00:31:54,162 --> 00:31:56,496
饥荒在附近徘徊
Starvation hovered close.

249
00:31:58,708 --> 00:32:07,007
1941年的胜利已将日本置于一个
巨大的,被誓死捍卫的保护圈之后,
The victories of 1941 had placed Japan behind
a vast protective ring,defended in death.

250
00:32:08,426 --> 00:32:10,719
到了1944年年中,
By the middle of 1944,

251
00:32:10,803 --> 00:32:17,976
麦克阿瑟将军的两栖军队已将这个(防卫圈)
缩减到一个取决于塞班岛的内部防卫圈
General MacArthur's amphibious armies had reduced
this to an inner ring hinging on the island of Saipan.

252
00:32:19,520 --> 00:32:23,190
在日本的飞行距离之内的塞班岛,
Saipan, within flying distance of Japan,

253
00:32:23,274 --> 00:32:28,403
被日本军方断言 是一面坚不可摧的盾牌
was claimed by the Japanese military
to be a shield and an impregnable one.

254
00:32:28,488 --> 00:32:31,281
它应该(是面无法攻破的盾牌,因为
对日本人来说)这是性命攸关的
lt was vital that it should be.

255
00:32:36,079 --> 00:32:39,164
(実松譲 海军情报部指挥官)
我们意识到 如果塞班岛丢了,
It was realised that if Saipan was lost,

256
00:32:39,248 --> 00:32:42,709
我们会处于一个非常困难的境地
we would be in a very difficult position.

257
00:32:42,794 --> 00:32:46,296
塞班岛的重要性在于 一旦它沦陷了,
The importance of Saipan
was that once it fell,

258
00:32:46,381 --> 00:32:50,342
战争将直接展现在日本的眼前
the war would be right
in front of Japan's eyes.

259
00:32:52,220 --> 00:32:56,807
日本将处于美国飞机的轰炸航程之内
Japan would come within
bombing range of US planes.

260
00:32:56,891 --> 00:33:01,853
对日本而言 它是一个绝对重要的防御地区
lt was an absolutely vital
defence area for Japan.

261
00:33:13,366 --> 00:33:15,325
1944年6月15日,
On 15 June 1944,

262
00:33:15,410 --> 00:33:19,579
经过五天的海空饱和轰炸之后,
after five days of saturation
bombardment by sea and air,

263
00:33:19,664 --> 00:33:23,041
美国突击部队向海岸发起冲击
American assault troops stormed ashore.

264
00:33:35,346 --> 00:33:39,016
一如往常,日本守备部队战斗至最后一人
As always, the Japanese garrison
fought to the last.

265
00:33:49,736 --> 00:33:52,487
在这里,第一次,日本平民...
Here, for the first time,
Japanese civilians...

266
00:33:52,572 --> 00:33:55,490
妇女和儿童...被困在战斗中
women and children...
were caught up in the battle.

267
00:33:55,575 --> 00:33:58,952
(他们中的)一些晕眩而又温顺的人,投降了
Some, dazed and docile, submitted.

268
00:34:08,296 --> 00:34:13,592
塞班岛有深水港,它有两个机场
Saipan had deep-water harbours,
it had two airfields.

269
00:34:13,676 --> 00:34:15,844
每一块岩石都被保卫
Every rock was defended.

270
00:34:45,792 --> 00:34:50,921
在三个星期里,为了夺取一个
面积仅有85平方英里的岛屿,
ln three weeks, to take an island
only 85 square miles in area,

271
00:34:51,005 --> 00:34:54,674
美国人付出了15,000人的伤亡
the Americans lost 15,000 dead and wounded.

272
00:35:01,599 --> 00:35:05,727
25,000名日本守卫者全部死亡
25,000 Japanese defenders
died to a man.

273
00:35:23,663 --> 00:35:29,543
一些平民,象许多士兵一样,
选择了自杀而不是投降
And some civilians, like many soldiers,
chose suicide rather than surrender.

274
00:35:40,429 --> 00:35:44,224
他们白白死去 塞班岛被占领了
They died in vain. Saipan was taken.

275
00:35:49,272 --> 00:35:51,898
甚至在最后一个日本人死去之前,
Even before the last Japanese had died,

276
00:35:51,983 --> 00:35:56,528
美国轰炸机已准备好出发去(轰炸日本)本土
American bombers were ready
to take off for the mainland.

277
00:35:56,612 --> 00:36:01,158
真相现在近到了甚至日本
最高指挥部都无法隐藏的地步
The truth was now too close even for
the Japanese high command to conceal it.

278
00:36:10,334 --> 00:36:15,130
他们告诉人民,局势很严重但不是没有希望
The situation, they told the people,
was grave but not hopeless.

279
00:36:15,214 --> 00:36:20,093
但神圣的祖国现在处于直接威胁之下
But the sacred homeland itself
was now directly threatened.

280
00:36:20,595 --> 00:36:26,266
学校的孩子们得知,敌人现在处于空中打击距离之内
The enemy, schoolchildren learned,
was within striking distance by air.

281
00:36:30,730 --> 00:36:34,566
已经到了让所有人,年轻人和老人,
The time had come for all,young and old,

282
00:36:34,650 --> 00:36:39,362
拿出和他们的战士们一样的
抵抗(精神)来面对威胁的时候
to meet the threat with the same
defiance as their fighting men.

283
00:36:41,407 --> 00:36:49,873
日本那一度骄傲的,用于进攻而不是防御
的空军 只剩下了少数受过训练的飞行员
Only a handful of trained pilots remained of Japan's
once proud air army,built for attack not defence.

284
00:36:49,957 --> 00:36:53,543
当战争开始时,他们的零式
战斗机曾经统治了天空
When war began,their Zero
fighters had ruled the skies.

285
00:36:53,628 --> 00:36:56,588
现在它们已经过时 武器也被(对手)超过
Now they were outdated and outgunned.

286
00:36:56,672 --> 00:37:03,595
这些战士用他们的飞机来对抗 现在正在攻击
他们祖国的巨大的美式(B-29)"超级堡垒"轰炸机
These men pitted their machines against giant American
Superfortresses which now attacked the homeland.

287
00:37:06,224 --> 00:37:10,393
他们年轻而又勇敢,但他们(的人数)太少了
They were young and brave,
but they were very few.

288
00:37:27,161 --> 00:37:32,791
我感觉一架零式战斗机对我来说
就象是一把剑对一个武士那样(重要),
I felt that a Zero fighter was to me
what a sword was to the samurai,

289
00:37:32,875 --> 00:37:38,880
我感觉我必须(这样)操控飞机
就似乎它是我自己的身体一样
and I felt that I must manipulate
the plane just as if it were my own body.

290
00:37:38,965 --> 00:37:45,470
我还相信 驾驶舱是一个将会
成为我的葬身之地的秘密地方
And I also believed that the cockpit was
a secret place which would be my death place.

291
00:37:50,559 --> 00:37:55,397
当我们(起飞)进行攻击的时候,
我们从来不带降落伞
When we went on an attack,
we never took parachutes.

292
00:37:55,523 --> 00:38:04,239
这是因为我们相信 当(我们)在敌人阵地
上空被击落时 我们永远不应该成为战俘
This was because we believed we should never become
prisoners when shot down over enemy positions.

293
00:38:07,827 --> 00:38:15,208
自古以来,日本武士就相信 活着被俘是有罪的
From ancient days, it was the belief of the Japanese
warrior that to be taken prisoner alive is sinful.

294
00:38:15,293 --> 00:38:24,926
我们也一直被教育 现代的日本士兵永远
也不应该成为俘虏 因为这是最大的耻辱
We, too, were always taught that the modern
Japanese soldier should never become prisoner
because it is the greatest disgrace.

295
00:38:25,511 --> 00:38:27,887
随着帝国海军被严重削弱,
With the imperial navy shattered,

296
00:38:27,972 --> 00:38:31,349
塞班岛盾牌被刺穿,菲律宾群岛被征服,
the Saipan shield pierced,
the Philippines conquered,

297
00:38:31,434 --> 00:38:38,982
只剩下硫磺岛,以及,最后的冲绳岛,
来阻挡盟军向日本本土推进
only the islands of lwo Jima and, finally, Okinawa,
were left to bar the Allied advance on Japan proper.

298
00:38:39,066 --> 00:38:43,069
到1945年4月,硫磺岛已被占领
By April 1945, lwo Jima had been taken.

299
00:38:44,113 --> 00:38:51,244
现在一支美国军队,在大量战舰的保护之下,
对日本前面的最后一个岛屿,冲绳 构成威胁
Now an American army, protected by massed warships,
threatened Okinawa,the last island before Japan.

300
00:38:53,247 --> 00:38:56,458
作为抵挡这次最终突击的孤注一掷,
ln a desperate throw
to stave off the ultimate assault,

301
00:38:56,542 --> 00:39:02,797
日本再次召集其年轻人
象他们的祖先那样战斗和死亡
Japan once more summoned its young men
to fight and die as their ancestors had done.

302
00:39:03,924 --> 00:39:06,009
特殊的(空军)中队被组建起来
Special squadrons were formed.

303
00:39:06,093 --> 00:39:09,637
"神风突击队"...神风战士...
The kamikaze... men of the divine wind...

304
00:39:09,722 --> 00:39:15,310
以几个世纪前那场摧毁了忽必烈汗
的入侵部队的台风命名
named for the typhoon which had destroyed the
invasion force of Kublai Khan centuries before.

305
00:39:15,394 --> 00:39:19,564
他们喝下最后一杯米酒 并出发去战死
They drank a last cup of rice wine
and set off to die.

306
00:39:29,658 --> 00:39:33,370
他们的飞机已被改装成飞行炸弹
Their aircraft had been converted
into flying bombs.

307
00:39:35,956 --> 00:39:41,628
他们的任务是撞击冲绳周围敌人战舰的甲板
Their mission was to crash them onto the
decks of enemy warships round Okinawa.

308
00:40:07,988 --> 00:40:14,327
作为一个指挥官,我经常被问起 派这些
飞行员出去(送死)是否要经受重重困难
As a commander, I'm often asked whether I went
through hell in sending out these pilots.

309
00:40:14,412 --> 00:40:17,205
但是,事实上,情况完全相反
But, actually, the opposite is the case.

310
00:40:17,289 --> 00:40:20,250
我们有许多志愿去的飞行员,
We had a lot of pilots who volunteered,

311
00:40:20,334 --> 00:40:24,212
但一次攻击只能有非常少的人能去
but it was only a very few
who could leave on one attack.

312
00:40:24,296 --> 00:40:27,715
因此(倒是只能)选择少数几个人去 更加困难
And so it was more difficult
to choose a selected few.

313
00:40:27,800 --> 00:40:31,553
所有其他的志愿者都说,"派我去!派我去!"
All the other volunteers said,
"Send me! Send me!"

314
00:40:31,637 --> 00:40:37,892
所以要请求这些没被选中的人
是否能等到下次再去 是很困难的
So it's difficult to ask these people not
selected if they'll wait until another day.

315
00:40:40,729 --> 00:40:46,276
另一方面,那些参加当天攻击的人情绪非常高涨,
On the other hand, those taking part in
the day's attack were in very high spirits,

316
00:40:46,360 --> 00:40:50,572
所以派这些人出去没有困难
and so there's no difficulty
in sending these men out.

317
00:40:50,698 --> 00:40:52,866
但是不像一次普通攻击,
But unlike an ordinary attack,

318
00:40:52,950 --> 00:40:58,121
这些神风飞行员,一旦他们出发,
他们就再也不会回来了
these kamikaze pilots, once they
took off, they never come back.

319
00:40:58,205 --> 00:41:05,000
所以知道你再也见不到这些你
派出去的人 是有这种悲伤的感觉
And so there was this sadness in knowing that the
people you were sending out you'd never see again.

320
00:41:18,476 --> 00:41:21,811
神风飞机在空中被击落
The kamikaze were shot out of the air.

321
00:41:22,897 --> 00:41:25,857
他们的确造成了严重伤害,但还是失败了
They did severe damage, but failed.

322
00:41:32,948 --> 00:41:35,492
美国人入侵了冲绳
The Americans invaded Okinawa.

323
00:41:46,337 --> 00:41:51,633
冲绳离作为宗主国的日本只有350英里远
Okinawa was only 350 miles
from metropolitan Japan.

324
00:41:51,759 --> 00:41:56,304
离本土越近,战斗就越狂热
The nearer to the mainland,
the more fanatical the fighting.

325
00:42:37,096 --> 00:42:41,224
在冲绳,只有7000个日本士兵幸存下来
On Okinawa,only 7,000 Japanese soldiers survived.

326
00:42:41,308 --> 00:42:45,395
超过10万人阵亡,其中许多是自杀,
Over 100,000 died,
many by their own hand,

327
00:42:45,479 --> 00:42:48,439
还有75,000个平民死亡
and 75,000 civilians.

328
00:43:08,210 --> 00:43:13,423
與那覇夫人,(当时还是)一个学生,也准备去死
Mrs Yonaha, a student,
was ready to die, too.

329
00:43:16,885 --> 00:43:23,766
在我们周围,士兵们和居民们正手忙
脚乱地跑来跑去,很明显都很慌乱
All around us,the soldiers and the inhabitants
were running helter-skelter,obviously confused.

330
00:43:23,851 --> 00:43:28,646
不知什么原因,我跟随着士兵们
我们一起进入了一个小掩体
For some reason, I followed the soldiers
and we got into a small shelter.

331
00:43:28,731 --> 00:43:31,941
(在那里)把雨舀出去比什么都重要
lt was more to get out of the rain
than anything.

332
00:43:32,026 --> 00:43:36,070
我们发现另外几个士兵已经在这个隐蔽所里
We found several other soldiers
already in the hideout.

333
00:43:36,155 --> 00:43:40,950
我们能听到美军用扩音器叫我们出来
We could hear the US army calling us
through loudspeakers to come out.

334
00:43:41,035 --> 00:43:44,329
说话的人说着一口非常动听的日语,
Whoever it was spoke a very beautiful Japanese,

335
00:43:44,413 --> 00:43:51,085
但我们在很久以前就被教育
我们永远不该投降并成为战俘
but we had been taught from a long time that we
should never surrender and become prisoners of war.

336
00:43:51,170 --> 00:43:55,173
所以我们让这些广播一天到晚地不停地继续
So we let these broadcasts continue
all day long without any let-up.

337
00:43:55,257 --> 00:43:59,427
呼喊声来自于海上 "出来 出来"
The shouts came from the sea...
"Come out. Come out."

338
00:44:03,140 --> 00:44:08,936
他们说,"我们不会对妇女 儿童和老人造成任何伤害,
They were saying, "We will not inflict any
harm on women and children and old people,

339
00:44:09,021 --> 00:44:11,105
所以请出来吧"
so please come out."

340
00:44:11,190 --> 00:44:17,070
我已经决定去死 并觉得我应该自杀
l had already decided to die
and felt that I should commit suicide.

341
00:44:17,154 --> 00:44:22,283
一个士兵有一颗手榴弹 他说,"让我们都自杀吧"
One of the soldiers had a hand grenade
and said, "Let's all commit suicide."

342
00:44:22,368 --> 00:44:24,577
我们都同意了
And we agreed.

343
00:44:24,662 --> 00:44:26,871
一旦我们作出了那个决定,
Once we had made that decision,

344
00:44:26,955 --> 00:44:31,417
我突然感到一种强烈的解脱
和一种平静的感觉
l felt a great relief
and a calmness come over me.

345
00:44:31,502 --> 00:44:35,463
起初,当然,我不想杀死我自己
At first, of course,
l did not want to kill myself.

346
00:44:35,547 --> 00:44:39,258
我曾想设法逃离 并继续活下去
l wanted to escape somehow
and keep on living.

347
00:44:40,302 --> 00:44:45,056
但扩音器开始增加强度和音量
But the loudspeakers began to increase
in intensity and in volume.

348
00:44:45,140 --> 00:44:49,102
我们感觉美国人正越来越近,
We felt that the Americans
were coming in closer and closer,

349
00:44:49,186 --> 00:44:53,314
所以我请求那个士兵把我
和他自己一起给杀了
so I asked the soldier to kill me,
together with himself.

350
00:44:53,399 --> 00:44:56,984
就等我在等那个士兵拉(手榴弹上的)保险栓时,
Just when I was waiting for
the soldier to pull the pin,

351
00:44:57,069 --> 00:45:01,739
另一个士兵抽出一把剑
并开始四处挥舞 一边说道,
one of the other soldiers took out a sword
and started waving it around saying,

352
00:45:01,824 --> 00:45:06,244
"你们女人和孩子们出去
你们不应该死在这里"
"You women and children get out.
You shouldn't die here."

353
00:45:06,328 --> 00:45:09,622
我们被这突然的叫喊声吓了一跳,
We were quite startled
by the sudden shouting,

354
00:45:09,707 --> 00:45:13,626
所以我们站起来 并往后退了一步
and so we stood up
and took a step backwards.

355
00:45:13,711 --> 00:45:17,004
我们躲藏的地方非常小,
The place in which we were
hiding was very small,

356
00:45:17,089 --> 00:45:20,717
所以向后退了一步 我们就出了掩体
so one step back and
we were outside the shelter.

357
00:45:20,801 --> 00:45:25,805
我们抬头一看 看见两个美国兵拿手枪对着我们
We looked up and saw two American
soldiers pointing pistols at us.

358
00:45:25,889 --> 00:45:30,184
他们什么也没说,但保持着
拿手枪(瞄准我们)的姿势
They didn't say anything,
but kept gesturing with their pistols.

359
00:45:30,269 --> 00:45:32,437
"出来 出来"
"Come out. Come out."

360
00:46:08,515 --> 00:46:14,979
那些留在里面的士兵请求我们
不要告诉美国兵他们躲藏(在里面)
The soldiers we had left inside asked us not
to tell the US soldiers they were hiding

361
00:46:15,063 --> 00:46:18,316
因为他们所有人都将自杀
because all of them were
going to commit suicide.

362
00:46:23,280 --> 00:46:27,825
1945年7月2日,冲绳陷落
On 2 July 1945, Okinawa fell.

363
00:46:27,910 --> 00:46:33,998
在日本本岛,日本人民为即将到来的风暴作了准备
ln the home islands, the Japanese people
braced themselves for the storm to come.

364
00:46:34,082 --> 00:46:41,881
几个月前飞到东京上空的第一批"超级堡垒"
轰炸机只是另外几百批次的先锋
The first Superfortresses over Tokyo a few months
earlier were only the harbingers of hundreds of others.

365
00:46:44,885 --> 00:46:50,181
这些(轰炸机)现在将要在一场持久的
空中突击中(不断)吐出燃烧弹和高爆炸弹,
These were now to spew out fire and high
explosive in a sustained aerial assault,

366
00:46:50,265 --> 00:46:54,602
系统性地一座接一座的彻底摧毁日本的城市
systematically razing the cities
of Japan one after the other.

367
00:47:11,620 --> 00:47:14,622
就在那里,(海岸线的)尽头
There it is, the end of the line.

368
00:47:27,928 --> 00:47:30,847
以一次多达2000架的编队飞行,
In formations of up to 2,000 at a time,

369
00:47:30,931 --> 00:47:35,977
不分昼夜,几乎未遭遇抵抗,
它们炸毁了日本的城市
round the clock, virtually unopposed,
they laid Japan's cities waste.

370
00:48:05,632 --> 00:48:12,597
在它们下面,当防空警报响起 就冲向防空洞
成了一项令人畏惧的每日例行公事
Beneath them, the rush to air-raid shelters as
the sirens blew became a dreaded daily routine.

371
00:48:13,932 --> 00:48:17,059
我先是跑进防空洞,
I first ran into the shelter,

372
00:48:17,144 --> 00:48:24,567
但我没有依赖它 因为它非常小而且不牢固
but I didn't rely upon it
because it was very small and weak.

373
00:48:24,651 --> 00:48:34,368
防空洞里的所有人都如此疲倦
而且总是面色苍白 沉默 还有...
All people in the shelter were so tired
and always pale and silent and...

374
00:48:34,453 --> 00:48:36,037
我怎么说呢?
What I say?

375
00:48:36,121 --> 00:48:40,500
孩子们...没怎么哭泣
The children... not so crying

376
00:48:40,500 --> 00:48:45,212
因为他们太累了 (身体)太糟糕了
以至于哭不出来,我想
because they were too tired
and too terrible to cry, I think.

377
00:48:45,297 --> 00:48:47,965
所以他们都很沉默
So they were all silent.

378
00:48:59,811 --> 00:49:05,000
日本的木制城市很容易就燃烧起来,
住在其中的人也一样
Japan's wooden cities burned easily,
and their citizens in them.

379
00:49:05,000 --> 00:49:15,993
东京的这个人造地狱 甚至比这个首都遭受过的最恶劣
的自然灾害,1923年(关东)大地震后的惨状 还要糟糕
This man-made inferno in Tokyo was worse even
than that following the great earthquake of
1923, the capital's worst natural disaster.

380
00:49:20,916 --> 00:49:24,418
离我家一段距离的地方,
Some distance from my house,

381
00:49:24,503 --> 00:49:28,130
有许多人死了
there was a lot of men died.

382
00:49:28,215 --> 00:49:36,722
我最好的朋友在那晚失去了
她的父亲 兄弟和姐妹
And my best friend lost her father
and brother and sister at that night.

383
00:49:36,807 --> 00:49:43,437
而她的母亲,在那之后自杀了
And her mother, suicide after that.

384
00:50:07,921 --> 00:50:10,339
第二天早上,
The next morning,

385
00:50:10,424 --> 00:50:16,387
我觉得我想看看我的房子
l thought I want to see my house.

386
00:50:16,471 --> 00:50:21,350
所以我穿过桥去我家
So I crossed the bridge
and went to my house.

387
00:50:21,435 --> 00:50:25,646
整片房子都被摧毁了
And whole houses were destroyed.

388
00:50:25,731 --> 00:50:27,982
我是如此疲倦...
l was so tired...

389
00:50:30,152 --> 00:50:34,864
...去想任何不好的事情,
但我憎恨这场战争
..to think anything bad,
but I hated the war.

390
00:50:34,948 --> 00:50:37,283
我憎恨这场战争
And I hated the war.

391
00:50:37,367 --> 00:50:44,165
当时我痛苦地 同时也沉默地站着
l was standing in pain
and in silence, too.

392
00:50:45,917 --> 00:50:48,586
东京成了一片被烧焦的废墟
Tokyo was a charred wasteland.

393
00:50:48,670 --> 00:50:51,630
只有钢铁和混凝土幸存了下来
Only steel and concrete survived.

394
00:50:51,715 --> 00:50:55,176
首都16平方英里的地区被夷平
16 square miles of the capital
were flattened.

395
00:50:55,260 --> 00:50:58,471
死人的强烈恶臭在废墟上空缭绕
The stench of death
hung heavy over the ruins.

396
00:50:58,555 --> 00:51:00,931
在一次空袭中,在一个晚上,
ln one raid, in one night,

397
00:51:01,016 --> 00:51:03,100
超过70,000人死亡
over 70,000 perished.

398
00:51:04,436 --> 00:51:09,440
在对日本的空袭中,差不多75万平民死亡
ln air raids on Japan, nearly
a quarter of a million civilians died.

399
00:51:11,443 --> 00:51:14,278
800万人无家可归
Eight million were made homeless.

400
00:51:33,173 --> 00:51:36,258
男人和女人,男孩和女孩,
Man and woman, boy and girl,

401
00:51:36,343 --> 00:51:39,512
幸存者们准备保卫他们的祖国,
the survivors prepared
to defend their homeland,

402
00:51:39,596 --> 00:51:47,686
用木制步枪,弓箭和竹枪把入侵者赶进大海
to drive the invaders back into the sea with
wooden rifles,bows and arrows, bamboo spears.

403
00:51:47,771 --> 00:51:52,900
但最后,当入侵来临时,
它将是从天空中来的...
But the end, when it came,
was to be from the sky...

404
00:51:52,984 --> 00:51:54,777
无法抵挡,
irresistible,

405
00:51:54,861 --> 00:51:57,238
不可想象,
unimaginable,

406
00:51:57,322 --> 00:51:59,406
蘑菇状的
mushroom-shaped.

