1
00:00:17,976 --> 00:00:21,478
这个(面积)不到一平方英里的极小的岛屿,
This tiny island,
less than one square mile,

2
00:00:21,563 --> 00:00:24,000
损失了超过4,000条生命
cost more than 4,000 lives.

3
00:00:24,000 --> 00:00:35,075
这是塔拉瓦,当美国人在太平洋各处把日本人逐岛
赶回去时,它是战争中一些最激烈的战斗的典型
This is Tarawa, typical of some of the most concentrated
fighting of the war as the Americans drive the Japanese
back island by island across the Pacific.

4
00:01:43,311 --> 00:01:49,691
1942年2月,日本轰炸机攻击了澳大利亚本土
ln February 1942, Japanese bombers
attacked the Australian mainland.

5
00:01:52,070 --> 00:01:55,489
空袭暂时瘫痪了达尔文
(澳大利亚西北城市)的海军基地
The raid temporarily knocked out
the naval base of Darwin.

6
00:01:55,573 --> 00:01:58,117
随着日本人正在穿越新几内亚,
With the Japanese
advancing across New Guinea,

7
00:01:58,201 --> 00:02:01,286
一些澳大利亚人以为这是入侵的前奏,
some Australians thought
this was the prelude to invasion,

8
00:02:01,371 --> 00:02:05,415
但日本陆军和海军不能取得一致意见
but the Japanese army and navy
were unable to agree.

9
00:02:05,542 --> 00:02:08,877
他们的入侵计划被束之高阁
Their invasion plans were shelved.

10
00:02:11,089 --> 00:02:14,341
事实上,日本人发现他们
(的战线)拉得过长了
In fact, the Japanese found
they were overextended.

11
00:02:14,800 --> 00:02:17,594
在新几内亚丛林那可怕的环境中,
In the appalling conditions
of the New Guinea jungle,

12
00:02:17,679 --> 00:02:20,180
澳大利亚人,在不断增长的美国援助下,
the Australians, with growing American support,

13
00:02:20,265 --> 00:02:24,852
止住了日本人向至关重要
的基地 莫尔斯比港的推进
turned back the Japanese advance
on the vital base of Port Moresby.

14
00:02:24,978 --> 00:02:28,856
沿着科科达小道 盟军发起反攻
Along the Kokoda Trail
the Allies counterattacked.

15
00:02:30,650 --> 00:02:36,000
疾病和病害是象日本人的子弹一样可怕的障碍
Sickness and disease were obstacles
as formidable as Japanese bullets.

16
00:02:48,660 --> 00:02:53,000
到1942年底,对澳大利亚的威胁已被解除
By the end of 1942, the threat
to Australia had been removed.

17
00:02:53,000 --> 00:03:00,262
到了进行长期而又痛苦的战斗
以把日本人推回他们的祖国的阶段
The stage was set for the long and bitter struggle
to push the Japanese back to their homeland.

18
00:03:00,346 --> 00:03:04,933
盟军的攻势由两个竞争对手分别指挥,
The Allied offensive came under
the separate command of two rivals,

19
00:03:05,018 --> 00:03:08,061
西南太平洋战区的道格拉斯·麦克阿瑟将军
General Douglas MacArthur
in the southwest Pacific

20
00:03:08,146 --> 00:03:12,000
和中太平洋战区的切斯特·尼米兹
海军上将(太平洋舰队总司令)
and Admiral Chester Nimitz
in the central Pacific.

21
00:03:12,000 --> 00:03:22,000
美国的战略 是要对一个征服地区绵延数千平方英里
的陆地和海洋的敌人 发动一场两个方向的攻击
American strategy was to mount a two-pronged
attack on an enemy whose conquests extended
over thousands of square miles of land and ocean.

22
00:03:22,200 --> 00:03:29,249
麦克阿瑟的任务 是要从所罗门群岛
和新几内亚向上猛推至菲律宾群岛
MacArthur's task was to thrust upwards from
the Solomons and New Guinea to the Philippines.

23
00:03:29,334 --> 00:03:35,047
在尼米兹指挥下的部队要
进行一系列巨大的逐岛跳跃
The forces under Nimitz were to make
a series of giant leaps from island to island...

24
00:03:35,173 --> 00:03:40,135
马绍尔群岛,马里亚纳群岛,硫磺岛,冲绳
the Marshall lslands,the Marianas,
Iwo Jima, Okinawa.

25
00:03:40,220 --> 00:03:45,474
他们将会于1943年11月
在吉尔伯特群岛的塔拉瓦开始进攻
They would start in the Gilberts
in November 1943 at Tarawa.

26
00:03:47,977 --> 00:03:53,732
你们每个人都比日本佬优秀得多
Each one of you is much better than the Jap.

27
00:03:53,816 --> 00:03:58,300
体格上你们更强壮 智力上你们更聪明
你们有更好的武器
You're better physically. You're better
mentally. You have better weapons.

28
00:03:58,300 --> 00:04:06,245
当要进行个人战斗时 你们会有更好的
支援(火力) 那样你们将能轻松打败他
You'll have better support so that you'll be able to
lick him hands down when it comes to individual fighting.

29
00:04:06,329 --> 00:04:08,914
让我再重复一次将军说的话
Let me repeat again
what the general said.

30
00:04:08,998 --> 00:04:13,126
如果你们要抓一个俘虏时
不得不冒什么风险的话,
lf you have to run any chances
whatsoever to get a prisoner,

31
00:04:13,211 --> 00:04:14,503
那就别抓他了
then don't get him.

32
00:04:24,847 --> 00:04:30,477
尼米兹海军上将的跳岛大舰群
的第一个目标 塔拉瓦环礁
The first objective of Admiral Nimitz's
island-hopping armada's Tarawa atoll

33
00:04:30,561 --> 00:04:36,566
已经成为一个日本人的要塞 从那里
的机场起飞的飞机能攻击美国舰队
had become a Japanese fortress from whose
airstrip planes could strike at the US fleets.

34
00:04:36,651 --> 00:04:38,819
塔拉瓦必须被拿下
Tarawa had to be taken.

35
00:04:39,200 --> 00:04:48,453
这是第一次 对一个被珊瑚礁保护
起来的守卫森严的环礁发起海上进攻
This was the first time a seaborne attack had been launched
against a heavily defended atoll protected by a coral reef.

36
00:05:05,000 --> 00:05:13,020
在由5,000名海军陆战队员组成的第一批突击
部队中 没有人意识到塔拉瓦的防守有多么强
No one in the initial assault force of 5,000 marines
realised just how strong the defences of Tarawa were.

37
00:05:13,104 --> 00:05:16,898
他们以为他们会夷平这座岛 并彻底摧毁一切东西,
They thought they would level the island
and completely demolish everything,

38
00:05:17,025 --> 00:05:20,236
岛上不会有一个活人
that there wouldn't be
a living soul on the island.

39
00:05:22,905 --> 00:05:25,100
我记得他告诉我们,
I remember him telling us,

40
00:05:25,100 --> 00:05:29,202
"这会是我们经历过的最容易的入侵行动"
"This is gonna be the easiest
invasion we ever had."

41
00:05:31,331 --> 00:05:37,002
他说, "我们将只需要两个人...
一个拿着步枪 一个拿着记事板"
He says, "We'll only need two men...
one with a rifle and one with a slate."

42
00:05:37,086 --> 00:05:40,005
"一个人向他们开枪,还有一个用粉笔记下成绩"
"One to shoot 'em, one to chalk 'em up."

43
00:05:42,258 --> 00:05:44,760
"这将真的很容易"
"lt's gonna be real easy."

44
00:05:46,596 --> 00:05:50,223
我转过身 对甲板上站在我旁边的那个少校说,
I turned to the major standing
next to me on the deck and said,

45
00:05:50,308 --> 00:05:53,852
"我们的一些人今天炮瞄得不是很准"
"Some of our people
aren't aiming very well today."

46
00:05:53,936 --> 00:05:57,064
他说, "你不会以为那些是我们的炮弹吧?"
He said, "You don't think
those are our shells, do you?"

47
00:05:57,148 --> 00:06:02,069
我这才第一次意识到我们正在
被轰击 而塔拉瓦上还有日本人
l realised then for the first time that we're
being shot at and there were Japanese on Tarawa.

48
00:06:06,741 --> 00:06:11,495
每个人都自信 你能揍得日本人哭爹喊娘
Everyone was confident that
you could kick hell out of the Japanese.

49
00:06:11,579 --> 00:06:16,876
如果海军陆战队员们能踏上海滩
我们对付他们毫无问题
The marines would have no problem with them
if we could get our feet on the beach.

50
00:06:22,256 --> 00:06:24,257
我们走! 我们走!
Let's go! Let's go!

51
00:06:31,891 --> 00:06:35,500
你必须记得那个岛只有800或900码宽
You must remember that the island
was only 800 or 900 yards wide

52
00:06:35,500 --> 00:06:41,067
而当你把20,000个人放到那样
一个岛上时,那就十分拥挤了
and when you put 20,000 men on
an island like that, it's quite crowded.

53
00:06:48,449 --> 00:06:53,120
战线前面,战线后面,到处都有日本佬
There were Japs in front of the lines,
behind the lines, all over.

54
00:07:04,966 --> 00:07:10,637
我们被告知 也许我们能在
非常短的时间内就夺取该岛
We were told that perhaps we could take
this island within a very short time

55
00:07:10,721 --> 00:07:16,226
在登陆的几小时后 十分明显
事情不会这样(简单)
and it was quite evident within hours
of landing that this would not be so.

56
00:07:28,448 --> 00:07:32,159
那些散兵坑已经被海军的炮火
(扬起的沙子)遮盖起来,
The foxholes that had been
covered up with the naval gunfire,

57
00:07:32,243 --> 00:07:35,745
第二天早晨,在我所在位置的大约20码远,
the next morning,within about
20 yards of where I was,

58
00:07:35,830 --> 00:07:38,790
我看到日本人在挖掘
l watched the Japanese digging out.

59
00:07:38,875 --> 00:07:43,587
他们在把沙子挖出那地方 那样他们能朝外看
They were digging the sand out of
the place so that they could see out.

60
00:07:51,100 --> 00:07:59,000
战斗激烈地进行了三天 日本守卫者们
被逐渐逼进了这座极小的岛屿的一端
The battle raged for three days with the Japanese defenders
gradually pinned back into one end of this tiny island.

61
00:08:45,900 --> 00:08:51,446
日本指挥官(柴崎惠次少将)曾吹嘘说
塔拉瓦100年都攻不下来
The Japanese commander had boasted that
Tarawa could not be taken in 100 years.

62
00:08:52,323 --> 00:09:00,789
如果你能想象在这么小一个岛上
有差不多6,000个死人的感受,
If you can imagine the effect of nearly
6,000 dead men on an island this small,

63
00:09:01,415 --> 00:09:07,546
并考虑到它离赤道只有一纬度,
你在那儿得承受的这种热度,
and considering it's one degree from the
equator,the amount of heat you have there,

64
00:09:07,630 --> 00:09:13,510
你可以想象 在一两天后
你闻到的从腐烂的肉体上散发的味道
you can imagine the smell you get
within a day or two from all this rotting flesh.

65
00:09:13,594 --> 00:09:21,726
这是一种甜甜的味道...
令人作呕的甜味,我这么形容它...
lt was a sort of sweet smell...
sickly sweet, I described it...

66
00:09:21,811 --> 00:09:28,066
我不知道第二次世界大战中
还有什么地方有这么集中的死人
and I don't know anywhere in World War II
where there was such a concentration of death.

67
00:09:33,447 --> 00:09:40,078
当一切都结束时,在3,000个
日本守军中,只有17个投降
When it was all over,of 3,000
Japanese, only 17 surrendered.

68
00:09:40,162 --> 00:09:44,833
美国人的伤亡是1,000人阵亡 2,000人受伤
The Americans lost over 1,000 dead
and 2,000 wounded.

69
00:09:47,200 --> 00:09:56,344
美国的公众舆论被在如此短暂的一次
战斗中造成如此惨重的损失所震惊
Public opinion in the United States was shocked that such
heavy losses had been incurred in so short a period of fighting.

70
00:09:58,806 --> 00:10:06,521
在塔拉瓦战役后,美国入侵部队前往
马里亚纳群岛的塞班岛,提尼安岛和关岛
After Tarawa, American invasion forces headed for
the Mariana lslands of Saipan, Tinian and Guam.

71
00:10:06,606 --> 00:10:12,986
保护登陆的海军特遣舰队被部署在塞班岛的西面
The naval task force protecting the landings
was positioned to the west of Saipan.

72
00:10:13,070 --> 00:10:17,365
1944年6月 日本机动舰队从冲绳开来,
Approaching from Okinawa in June 1944
was Japan's mobile fleet,

73
00:10:17,450 --> 00:10:22,037
寻找一场能扭转战局的海上胜利
looking for a naval success that
would yet turn the war in their favour.

74
00:10:27,000 --> 00:10:33,214
突然,从他们的雷达上,美国人意识到他们已被日本人发现,
Suddenly, from their radar,the Americans realised
that they had been spotted by the Japanese.

75
00:10:44,400 --> 00:10:52,400
每一架可起飞的美国战斗机都升空
迎击一波接一波的日本舰载飞机
Every available American fighter was put into the air
to meet wave after wave of Japanese carrier-borne planes.

76
00:11:26,686 --> 00:11:32,524
许多日本飞行员相比而言 都是没有战斗经验的新手
Many Japanese pilots were comparative
novices with no battle experience.

77
00:11:34,819 --> 00:11:38,154
他们的飞机装甲很薄
Their aircraft were poorly armoured.

78
00:11:40,491 --> 00:11:43,660
对向他们的对手猛扑下去的美国飞行员来说,
For the American flyers
swooping down on their opponents,

79
00:11:43,744 --> 00:11:46,746
这就跟射杀火鸡一样容易
it was as easy as shooting turkeys.

80
00:12:07,184 --> 00:12:11,855
在第一次遭遇战后,除了一架以外
所有的美国飞机都返回了
After the first encounter, all but one
of the American planes returned.

81
00:12:38,299 --> 00:12:43,011
加满弹药和燃料后,美国人对
日本人的下一波攻击作好了准备
Rearmed and refuelled, the Americans
were ready for the next Japanese move.

82
00:12:43,095 --> 00:12:45,847
还有两次猛攻要面对
There were two more onslaughts to be faced.

83
00:12:45,931 --> 00:12:49,768
然而,美国人有差不多900架舰载机,
However, the Americans had
nearly 900 carrier planes,

84
00:12:49,852 --> 00:12:52,771
是日本舰载机数量的两倍
twice the number of the Japanese.

85
00:12:56,901 --> 00:13:01,321
"马里亚纳射火鸡大赛"只持续了8个小时
The Marianas turkey shoot
lasted just eight hours.

86
00:13:02,698 --> 00:13:08,119
在一天时间里,日本的海军航空兵力量实际上就被摧毁了
ln one day, Japanese naval air power
was virtually destroyed.

87
00:13:08,204 --> 00:13:13,208
原先的430架飞机被减少到(只剩)大约100架
The original force of 430 planes
was reduced to about 100.

88
00:13:24,720 --> 00:13:27,347
美国的损失相对轻微
American losses
were comparatively light.

89
00:13:27,431 --> 00:13:30,683
飞行员比飞机更重要
Pilots mattered more than machines.

90
00:14:04,300 --> 00:14:07,000
当天结束时,美国人已赢得了空战,
At the end of the day,
the Americans had won the air battle,

91
00:14:07,000 --> 00:14:12,392
但还没有找到现在正在撤退的日本舰队的位置
but had yet to locate
the Japanese fleet, now retiring.

92
00:14:16,063 --> 00:14:20,318
第二天,美国人继续寻找敌人
The following day, the Americans
continued their search for the enemy.

93
00:14:43,400 --> 00:14:53,057
直到下午较晚的时候(15:40) 他们的飞机才在超过200英里以外,
位于美国轰炸机的航程极限的地方 发现了(日本)机动舰队
lt was not until late afternoon that their aircraft
sighted the mobile fleet over 200 miles away,at the
extreme limit of the range of the American bombers.

94
00:14:53,142 --> 00:14:56,227
但命令下达了...进攻
But the order was given... attack.

95
00:15:18,834 --> 00:15:22,400
在逐渐变暗的天色下,美军攻击的主要目标...
In the fading light,the principle
objective of the American strike...

96
00:15:22,400 --> 00:15:26,000
日本航母编队...受到了严重的伤害
the Japanese carrier force...
was badly mauled.

97
00:15:39,500 --> 00:15:43,200
一艘航母(飞鹰号)被击沉
另外两艘(瑞鹤号和隼鹰号)被损坏
One carrier was sunk
and two others damaged.

98
00:15:43,200 --> 00:15:47,700
这场任何一支舰队都没(直接)
向另一支舰队开火的伟大海战,
This great naval battle, in which
neither fleet fired on the other,

99
00:15:47,700 --> 00:15:54,327
以日本人被打得只剩35架飞机
向他们在日本的基地撤退而告终
ended with the Japanese reduced to only 35
aircraft retreating to their bases in Japan.

100
00:16:00,600 --> 00:16:07,048
美国飞机现在面临回到航母的问题
The American planes now faced the
problem of getting back to the carriers.

101
00:16:07,800 --> 00:16:14,681
发动进攻的决定意味着它们可能
很容易在返航的途中耗尽燃料
The decision to attack had meant that they might
easily run out of fuel on the journey home.

102
00:16:17,017 --> 00:16:22,855
首先返航的是保护特遣舰队的战斗机
First to return were the fighters which
had been protecting the task force.

103
00:16:53,554 --> 00:16:56,097
在暮色中降落已经足够困难,
Landing in the dusk
was difficult enough,

104
00:16:56,181 --> 00:17:02,395
但是过了些时候 鱼雷轰炸机和(俯冲)轰炸机
不得不在一片漆黑中寻找他们的航母
but later on the torpedo planes and bombers
would have to find their carriers in pitch darkness.

105
00:17:02,521 --> 00:17:04,772
一些永远都没成功
Some would never make it.

106
00:17:55,199 --> 00:17:59,410
然后它变成我一生中见过的最黑暗的夜晚
Then it turned into probably the
blackest night l've seen in my life.

107
00:17:59,536 --> 00:18:04,332
(巴彻·沃瑞斯 美国海军上尉)
在海洋上空...我想我们是在大约7,000英尺高度往回飞,
And over the ocean... I guess we were
at about 7,000 feet flying home,

108
00:18:04,416 --> 00:18:09,420
差不多是最省油的高度,
而天黑得就象黑桃爱司
kind of our best altitude for fuel,
and it was black as the ace of spades.

109
00:18:09,505 --> 00:18:14,217
我们什么都听不见,只有我们自己,
除了(他们的)叫喊声...
And we could hear nothing,
just ourselves, except the cries of...

110
00:18:14,301 --> 00:18:18,262
我不该说"叫喊声",
而该说一种非常例行公事的呼喊,
l won't say "cry",
but a very perfunctory call,

111
00:18:18,347 --> 00:18:21,182
"我将不得不降落在水里 我没有油了"
"I'll have to land in the water.
l'm out of fuel."

112
00:18:21,266 --> 00:18:27,814
而这种呼叫一直继续下去 直到所有从这次
攻击中幸存下来的鱼雷轰炸机全都落入水中
And this continued just constantly until all the torpedo
planes that had survived the strike went into the water.

113
00:18:27,898 --> 00:18:32,693
然后在离特遣舰队还有大约100英里
的地方,俯冲轰炸机开始耗尽燃油
Then about 100 miles from the force, the
dive bombers began to run out of fuel

114
00:18:32,778 --> 00:18:35,196
他们呼叫道, "这是..."
and they called out, "This is..."

115
00:18:35,280 --> 00:18:38,616
到底呼叫了些什么 我真的不记得了
whatever the call was.
l don't really remember.

116
00:18:38,700 --> 00:18:41,369
"我要迫降了 没油了"
"I'm going in. Out of fuel."

117
00:18:41,453 --> 00:18:46,207
然后变得十分安静 直到我们
飞入特遣舰队的范围之内
And then it became quite quiet
until we got within range of the force

118
00:18:46,333 --> 00:18:52,672
然后你能够开始分辨出 在特遣舰队正在发生什么
and then you could start to make out
what was happening at the task force

119
00:18:52,756 --> 00:18:55,000
回收程序将会如何...
and what the recovery course would be...

120
00:18:55,000 --> 00:18:57,500
我们还没有看到特遣舰队
因为舰船的灯都被熄灭了,
we'd not yet seen it because the
ships were running blacked out,

121
00:18:57,500 --> 00:19:02,200
而灯火管制是一个正常的操作程序,
所以在空中(我们)发现不了它
which was a normal operating procedure,
so it couldn't be detected from the air.

122
00:19:02,200 --> 00:19:06,060
(米切尔)海军中将知道我们
(在航母上)着陆会有极大的问题
The admiral knew that we'd have
an awful problem getting aboard.

123
00:19:06,145 --> 00:19:10,189
我们真的没有时间来寻找舰队
他作出了一个决定
We didn't have time to really look
for the force. A decision was made.

124
00:19:10,274 --> 00:19:13,860
命令下达给航空母舰 让他们把灯打开
The command was given to the carriers
to turn their lights on.

125
00:19:18,200 --> 00:19:25,830
第二天 (第58)特遣舰队成功拯救了
绝大多数迫降在海中的机组成员
Next day, the task force succeeded in rescuing the vast
majority of the air crews who had been forced down in the ocean.

126
00:19:25,914 --> 00:19:28,700
这场"菲律宾海海战"的胜利,
Victory in this,
the Battle of the Philippine Sea,

127
00:19:28,700 --> 00:19:35,339
意味着在马里亚纳群岛的登陆能够
在不受日本海军干扰的情况下进行
meant the Mariana landings could go ahead
without interference from the Japanese navy.

128
00:19:46,900 --> 00:19:51,522
在付出3,000个美国人阵亡的代价后,塞班岛陷落了
At a cost of 3,000 American dead,Saipan fell.

129
00:19:58,071 --> 00:20:00,823
提尼安岛的守备没有那么森严
Tinian was less heavily defended.

130
00:20:00,908 --> 00:20:03,868
关岛抵抗了三个星期
Guam held out for three weeks.

131
00:20:12,461 --> 00:20:14,500
离开那里! 快去那儿!
Get out of there! Move there quick!

132
00:20:16,600 --> 00:20:26,474
随着两个竞争的进攻箭头开始交汇,一支从马里亚纳群岛出发
向西进发的美国两栖部队的指挥权从尼米兹转到了麦克阿瑟那里
Moving west from the Marianas,a US amphibious force
was switched by Nimitz to MacArthur's command
as the two rival prongs began to come together.

133
00:20:26,558 --> 00:20:29,352
目标是帕劳群岛
The objective was the Palau group of islands.

134
00:20:29,436 --> 00:20:33,314
在对菲律宾群岛发动入侵前
这些岛屿必须被占领
These had to be taken before
the invasion of the Philippines.

135
00:20:44,200 --> 00:20:53,084
在其中一个岛屿,贝里琉岛上,美国人再次遭遇
一支10,000人的日本一流部队的狂热抵抗
On one island, Peleliu, the Americans again ran into fanatical
resistance from a crack force of 10,000 Japanese troops.

136
00:21:05,347 --> 00:21:08,099
他们没有在海滩上迎击美国人,
lnstead of meeting the Americans
on the beaches,

137
00:21:08,183 --> 00:21:12,353
这些日本人撤退进了一个
由洞穴和隧道构成的迷宫
the Japanese had withdrawn into
a labyrinth of caves and tunnels.

138
00:22:08,827 --> 00:22:14,665
美国人不得不与一支决心
战斗到死的敌人争夺每一码
The Americans had to contest every yard against
an enemy determined to fight to the death.

139
00:22:20,380 --> 00:22:22,214
在这场争夺贝里琉的血战中,
ln the bloody battle for Peleliu,

140
00:22:22,299 --> 00:22:27,219
参战的每十个美国人中有四个阵亡或受伤
four out of every ten Americans
taking part were killed or wounded.

141
00:22:40,650 --> 00:22:45,696
把所有这些日本人赶出来 用了几个月
lt was months before all the Japanese
had been winkled out.

142
00:22:54,706 --> 00:22:59,335
在这些太平洋岛屿上 没有轻松的胜利
There were no easy victories
on these Pacific islands.

143
00:22:59,419 --> 00:23:05,674
一些死去的海军陆战队员只能
通过他们的指纹来辨认身份
Some of the dead marines could only
be identified by their fingerprints.

144
00:23:10,263 --> 00:23:15,393
1944年10月20日,麦克阿瑟兑现了他的承诺
On October 20, 1944,
MacArthur fulfilled his promise.

145
00:23:15,477 --> 00:23:18,521
他回到了菲律宾群岛
He returned to the Philippines.

146
00:23:19,022 --> 00:23:22,066
登陆几乎没有遭遇抵抗
The landings were virtually unopposed.

147
00:23:22,150 --> 00:23:25,945
日本人已撤退到他们在内陆的主要防线
The Japanese had retired inland
to their main defences.

148
00:23:26,029 --> 00:23:30,908
但这次入侵触发了历史上最大和最复杂的海战
But the invasion touched off the largest
and most complex naval battle in history.

149
00:23:30,992 --> 00:23:34,537
莱特湾海战将持续四天
The Battle for Leyte Gulf
was to last for four days.

150
00:23:35,080 --> 00:23:42,294
四支来自于婆罗洲,福尔摩萨(台湾)和
日本本土的日本舰队在菲律宾群岛会合
Four Japanese forces converged on the Philippines
from Borneo, Formosa and mainland Japan.

151
00:23:42,379 --> 00:23:46,340
美国人有两支舰队...第七和第三舰队
The Americans had two fleets...
the Seventh and the Third.

152
00:23:46,425 --> 00:23:51,637
日本人的目标是在莱特湾摧毁美国入侵舰船
The Japanese aim was to destroy the
American invasion shipping in Leyte Gulf.

153
00:23:51,763 --> 00:23:55,349
在相隔数百英里远的一系列混战之后,
After a series of confused engagements
hundreds of miles apart,

154
00:23:55,434 --> 00:23:59,311
日本帝国海军遭受了惨重损失
the lmperial Japanese Navy
suffered heavy losses.

155
00:23:59,396 --> 00:24:03,232
它不再是一支有效的战斗力量
lt ceased to be an effective
fighting force.

156
00:24:10,000 --> 00:24:19,915
在陆上,倾盆大雨延缓了麦克阿瑟的士兵
与一支人数接近40万的日本军队的战斗进程
On land, torrential rain had delayed the
progress of MacArthur's men fighting against
a Japanese army numbering nearly 400,000.

157
00:24:20,917 --> 00:24:25,296
到1945年2月,在莱特湾登陆的三个月后,
By February 1945, three months
after the Leyte landings,

158
00:24:25,422 --> 00:24:30,000
美国人正逼近菲律宾首都马尼拉
the Americans were closing in
on the Philippines capital Manila.

159
00:24:41,688 --> 00:24:44,148
在太平洋战争中第一次,
For the first time in the Pacific war,

160
00:24:44,232 --> 00:24:48,402
美国人正攻入一座大城市
the Americans were fighting
their way into a big city.

161
00:25:07,339 --> 00:25:12,176
战斗逐街逐屋地激烈进行
The battle raged from street to street,
house to house.

162
00:25:24,272 --> 00:25:26,815
许多平民丧生,
Many civilians lost their lives,

163
00:25:26,900 --> 00:25:30,653
一些人被撤退的日本人处决
some executed by the retreating Japanese.

164
00:25:53,510 --> 00:25:59,765
麦克阿瑟的第二次胜利时刻...
他回到了菲律宾的首都
MacArthur's second hour of triumph...
his return to the Philippines' capital.

165
00:26:01,600 --> 00:26:09,358
在日本入侵期间被俘虏的美国人
在囚禁了三年后终于被释放
Americans were being taken prisoner during the Japanese
invasion,were released after three years in captivity.

166
00:26:33,842 --> 00:26:35,400
随着美国人攻占菲律宾群岛,
With the American capture of the Philippines,

167
00:26:35,400 --> 00:26:40,180
为日本工业运送必不可少的战争物资的补给线被切断了
the supply routes carrying essential war
materials for Japanese industry would be cut.

168
00:26:40,265 --> 00:26:44,018
日本(最高)指挥部知道
当他们丢掉菲律宾,
The Japanese command knew that
when they had lost the Philippines,

169
00:26:44,400 --> 00:26:46,854
他们就输掉了这场战争
they had lost the war.

170
00:26:53,903 --> 00:26:56,200
在解放之后,是复仇
After liberation, revenge.

171
00:26:56,300 --> 00:27:03,370
对被指控在日本占领的岁月里与日本人
合作的菲律宾人进行的个人恩怨的了断,
The settling of personal scores against Filipinos accused
of collaborating during the years of Japanese occupation,

172
00:27:03,455 --> 00:27:05,748
现在终于结束了
now at last at an end.

173
00:27:36,600 --> 00:27:38,900
1945年2月
February, 1945.

174
00:27:38,900 --> 00:27:45,329
硫磺岛,距离日本海岸仅仅600英里的
一座面积8平方英里的火山岩石(岛屿),
Iwo Jima,eight square miles of volcanic rock
only 600 miles from the coast of Japan,

175
00:27:45,413 --> 00:27:50,125
是下一个跳越中太平洋(登陆行动)的目标
was the target for the next leap
across the central Pacific.

176
00:27:50,210 --> 00:27:51,543
从硫磺岛(起飞),
From Iwo Jima,

177
00:27:51,628 --> 00:27:56,715
美国轰炸机几乎可以随心所欲地轰炸日本城市
American bombers could raid
Japanese cities almost at will.

178
00:27:56,800 --> 00:27:59,718
从折钵山那居高临下的高处,
From the dominating heights
of Mount Suribachi,

179
00:27:59,803 --> 00:28:03,972
日本人实际上能看到向硫磺岛开来的一切东西
the Japanese could see practically
everything that moved on Iwo Jima.

180
00:28:04,057 --> 00:28:10,000
又一次,日军主力(躲藏)在内陆,远离海滩
Once again, the main Japanese forces
were inland, away from the beaches.

181
00:28:11,000 --> 00:28:16,944
在登陆前的76天里,美国人一直
在从海上和空中轰炸硫磺岛
For 76 days before the landing,the Americans
had bombarded Iwo Jima from the sea and the air.

182
00:28:23,493 --> 00:28:28,747
这个不毛之地 这地方的荒芜...
The waste,the barrenness of the place...

183
00:28:28,832 --> 00:28:32,600
真的就象是一个噩梦 这是
你能看到的最接近地狱的地方
It was actually like a nightmare. It was
the closest thing you could see to hell.

184
00:28:32,600 --> 00:28:36,600
如果地狱看起来象什么地方,
它一定看起来就像硫磺岛
lf ever hell looked like anything,
it must look like Iwo Jima.

185
00:28:43,138 --> 00:28:47,474
在你登上那些登陆艇的那一刻 你很害怕
The minute you got in
those boats you were scared.

186
00:28:47,559 --> 00:28:50,500
你会一直感到害怕 直到你登上海滩
You were scared until you hit the beach.

187
00:28:53,106 --> 00:28:56,000
你意识到你上岛是去杀人的
You realise that
you're going in to kill

188
00:28:56,000 --> 00:28:58,861
我们被一直告诫 我们必须杀人 要么被杀
and we were always taught
that we had to kill or be killed.

189
00:28:58,945 --> 00:29:02,656
要么是我们 要么是日本人,
不是你死 就是我亡
lt was either us or the Japanese,
one or the other.

190
00:29:02,741 --> 00:29:07,494
当你作为一个年轻人 面对这种局面时...
And when you're faced with
this situation as a young man...

191
00:29:07,579 --> 00:29:09,663
我只有19岁...
l was only 19...

192
00:29:09,748 --> 00:29:11,800
这真的很令人困惑
it's confusing.

193
00:29:11,800 --> 00:29:17,254
在海军陆战队里,你被打造成
接受命令和服从命令(的士兵),
You're built, in the Marine Corps,
to take orders and obey orders,

194
00:29:17,338 --> 00:29:22,009
但同样你仍然是一个人 而你只有19或20岁
but at the same token you're still
a human being and you're only 19 or 20.

195
00:29:22,093 --> 00:29:25,721
那时候 我们大多数人都只有18,19,20岁
Most of us were only 18, 19, 20,
during those days.

196
00:29:33,855 --> 00:29:37,000
我想公众都有陆战队员是超人的印象,
l think the public has the idea
that marines are supermen,

197
00:29:37,000 --> 00:29:45,157
但我觉得 在两栖登陆艇里的陆战队员
没有一个是不害怕的 包括军官们
but I don't think there was a marine in the amphibious
landing craft that wasn't afraid,including the officers.

198
00:29:56,377 --> 00:30:00,506
在海军陆战队 我总是被教育
去憎恨他们,去痛恨他们,
l was always taught to hate them
in the Marine Corps, to detest them,

199
00:30:00,590 --> 00:30:05,302
他们是野兽 我们是人,他们是畜生
and that they were animals.
We were the men, they were the animals.

200
00:30:05,386 --> 00:30:10,891
与此同时,我们被告知 他们会为了天皇而死
By the same token, we were taught
that they would die for the emperor.

201
00:30:10,975 --> 00:30:13,519
我们没被要求为我们的总统而死
We weren't taught to die
for our president.

202
00:30:13,645 --> 00:30:23,100
而要和一个想要死,或不在乎去死的人战斗
或遭遇(这么个人) 你心里会觉得这是很难打的
And to fight or to come up against an individual
who wants to die,or who doesn't care about dying,
is a tough thing to combat in your mind.

203
00:30:23,100 --> 00:30:28,408
我们想要活 我们想要杀死他 我们想要幸存下来
We wanted to live. We wanted to kill him
and we wanted to survive.

204
00:30:34,000 --> 00:30:38,877
你不得不把你的头压低
因为在你上方有太多炮火飞过
You had to keep your head down
because there's too much fire above you

205
00:30:38,962 --> 00:30:45,217
你会不断地问自己,会不会有人
把一发幸运的炮弹打进登陆艇
and it's that constant wondering, is
somebody gonna drop a lucky one in there

206
00:30:45,301 --> 00:30:50,097
而你离岸太远 带着这一身装备游不到岸边?
and you're too far out to swim
with all that gear on?

207
00:30:50,223 --> 00:30:53,308
当你到了那儿 你会遭遇什么?
And what are you gonna get into
when you get there?

208
00:30:53,393 --> 00:30:55,936
那真是个要命的地方
That's a hell of a place to be.

209
00:31:15,957 --> 00:31:22,379
而当你登上了岛 你看到了火山灰
没有任何活着的东西,
And as you hit the island and
you saw the ash and nothing living,

210
00:31:22,463 --> 00:31:26,633
那真是...如果真要有地狱的话,就是这地方
it was... if there's ever been hell,
this was it.

211
00:31:34,309 --> 00:31:37,144
我们登上了海滩
Well, we hit the beach itself.

212
00:31:37,228 --> 00:31:44,943
事实上,(海滩上)有一个小斜坡 每个人
都靠住这斜坡 因为炮火是那么密集
Actually, there was a little incline and everybody
clung to the incline because the fire was that heavy.

213
00:31:45,028 --> 00:31:49,865
而登上滩头的一切东西
刚登上滩头 就被炸得飞离水面
And everything that hit the beach was
blasted out of the water as fast as it hit.

214
00:31:58,625 --> 00:32:02,586
那时我很年轻 这是我的第四次行动 我当时18岁
I was young then. This was
my fourth operation. I was 18.

215
00:32:02,670 --> 00:32:05,172
我的第一次行动,我16岁
My first operation, I was 16.

216
00:32:11,200 --> 00:32:19,269
他们就埋伏在那里 并等我们(登陆)
然后有节奏地不断给沿着海岸线的每个人纹身
They just laid there and waited for us and rhythmically
just kept on tattooing every man along the line.

217
00:32:19,354 --> 00:32:24,691
而你根本逃避不了
这场屠杀真是令人难以置信
And you just couldn't avoid it.
The slaughter was fantastic.

218
00:32:24,776 --> 00:32:29,404
我们走进了一张网 没有出来的路
We just walked into a web
and there was no way out.

219
00:32:29,489 --> 00:32:31,657
你无法离开海滩
You couldn't get off the beach.

220
00:32:31,741 --> 00:32:38,956
登上滩头后(看到的)是一个令人沮丧的场景
And getting in to the beach
was a depressing scene.

221
00:32:39,082 --> 00:32:45,337
当你开始看到你自己组里的人
死掉时 会打击你的士气
lt knocked your morale when you started to
see your own people from your own team dead.

222
00:32:45,421 --> 00:32:50,926
从水边到一个斜坡上面,
From the water's edge
to a sort of a rise,

223
00:32:51,010 --> 00:32:56,431
有数量极多的尸体躺在那里
there was a tremendous amount
of bodies just lying there.

224
00:33:13,574 --> 00:33:20,372
我们向里面移动了大约...可能300码,
We moved about...possibly 300 yards in,

225
00:33:20,456 --> 00:33:25,585
就只有他们,他们是指日本人,
决定让我们移动的那么远
just as far as they, they meaning
the Japanese, decided for us to go.

226
00:33:28,840 --> 00:33:34,553
没有办法离开那岛,第一天晚上不行
There was no way of getting
off the island, not that first night.

227
00:33:34,637 --> 00:33:37,264
实在是太拥挤了
lt was just too congested.

228
00:33:37,348 --> 00:33:43,020
第一晚 没什么东西能离开那个岛
There was nothing that could
move off that island the first night.

229
00:33:48,860 --> 00:33:50,700
在折钵山的表面上掘壕据守,
Dug in on the surface of Mount Suribachi,

230
00:33:50,700 --> 00:33:56,033
日本指挥官(栗林忠道中将)集中了他的火炮
the Japanese commander
had concentrated his artillery.

231
00:33:59,454 --> 00:34:05,542
(美军的)炮火准备再次未能打掉日本人的据点
The preliminary bombardment again failed
to knock out the Japanese strong points.

232
00:34:05,668 --> 00:34:10,600
它们只能由在现场的士兵
一次一个地消灭
They could only be taken one at a time
by the men on the ground.

233
00:34:10,600 --> 00:34:17,929
夺取硫磺岛要比美国指挥部允许的五天时间要长得多
lt would take a lot longer to capture Iwo Jima than
the five days allowed for by the American command.

234
00:34:26,272 --> 00:34:30,942
整个植被都被完全打掉了
The entire vegetation
was gone completely.

235
00:34:31,027 --> 00:34:32,402
你在早晨醒来
You woke in the morning

236
00:34:32,487 --> 00:34:36,448
你向外朝这片广阔的无人之地望去
and you'd look out across this
particular expanse of no-man's-land

237
00:34:36,532 --> 00:34:40,660
它正在冒泡和翻腾 有蒸汽从地里冒出来
and it was bubbling and seething
with steam coming out of the ground.

238
00:34:40,745 --> 00:34:49,000
事实上,我们不得不用C口粮包装上的硬纸板
铺在散兵坑里 那样你的屁股才不会烧起来
ln fact, we had to use cardboard from C ration packs to
put down in the foxhole so that your ass wouldn't burn up.

239
00:34:52,298 --> 00:34:56,100
如果有地狱的话,那现在我正在亲身经历它,
lf there is a hell,
l'm living through it now,

240
00:34:56,100 --> 00:35:01,848
所以我不必担心将来下地狱了
我已经去过那里了
so I don't have to worry about going to hell
anytime in the future. l've been there.

241
00:35:15,113 --> 00:35:18,198
一个家伙上来找我 他是个成了家的人
One of the guys came up to me.
He was a man with a family.

242
00:35:18,282 --> 00:35:22,911
我以前甚至都不认识他,只是在那一天才遇见他
l never did even know him, just
meeting him at that particular day.

243
00:35:22,995 --> 00:35:25,372
我说, "我们在这里的迫击炮阵地里"
l said, "We're in the mortar outfit back here."

244
00:35:25,456 --> 00:35:27,582
"相当安全,没有问题"
"Fairly well safe, no problems."

245
00:35:27,667 --> 00:35:32,879
在那天结束前,他和我另一个班的一半人都死了
Before the day was over,
he and half of my other squad was dead.

246
00:35:36,551 --> 00:35:40,762
我认为最糟糕的部分 是你对死人
和肿胀的尸体变得麻木不仁,
I think the worst part was you
get callous to dead and bloated bodies,

247
00:35:40,847 --> 00:35:44,766
但你不会以那种方式对你自己
的朋友们(的尸体)感到麻木,
but you never get callous
to your own friends in that way,

248
00:35:44,851 --> 00:35:48,728
而我觉得那或许是硫磺岛(战役)最可怕的事情
and I think that perhaps was
the most terrible thing of Iwo Jima.

249
00:35:48,813 --> 00:35:52,357
我觉得如果每个人都记得所有发生了的悲惨事情,
I think if everybody remembered
all the tragic things that happened,

250
00:35:52,441 --> 00:35:55,110
你会发疯的 你不会挺下来
you'd go crazy.
You wouldn't survive it.

251
00:35:55,194 --> 00:35:58,405
欧,你总觉得你会活下来
Oh, you always think
you're gonna make it.

252
00:35:58,489 --> 00:36:03,285
你很害怕,但你仍觉得你会活下来
You're scared, but you still think
you're gonna make it.

253
00:36:42,742 --> 00:36:46,661
这是我见过的最大的混乱场面之一
It was just one of the biggest messes
I have...I myself had ever seen.

254
00:36:46,746 --> 00:36:48,800
我不知道滩头主官是谁,
l don't know who the beach master was,

255
00:36:48,800 --> 00:36:54,000
但他很可能干得是我所听说过的
任何人做过的最艰巨的工作
but he probably had the roughest job
of any man l've ever heard of.

256
00:37:01,093 --> 00:37:03,428
当时 这可能看起来很混乱无序,
It may have looked confusing at the time,

257
00:37:03,512 --> 00:37:06,000
但支持这支突击部队的后勤组织...
but the supply organisation backing the assault force...

258
00:37:06,000 --> 00:37:15,106
正是使美国在珍珠港被偷袭那天起就注定必然将
战胜日本的因素...她那压倒性的工业实力 的证明
was proof of the factor that made America's victory
over Japan inevitable from the day of Pearl Harbour...
her overwhelming industrial strength.

259
00:37:22,198 --> 00:37:25,617
似乎只有一件事在士兵中间传播...
Only one thing seemed
to permeate the men...

260
00:37:25,701 --> 00:37:29,496
(最好)受那种价值百万美元的伤(丧失战斗力
但不伤及要害的伤) 并离开这个该死的地方
get that million-dollar wound
and get off this damn place.

261
00:38:06,409 --> 00:38:08,000
在远离海滩的内陆,
lnland from the beaches,

262
00:38:08,000 --> 00:38:11,746
硫磺岛变成了另一场消耗战
Iwo Jima became another battle of attrition.

263
00:38:30,700 --> 00:38:37,500
日复一日,美国人面对情愿死也
不肯投降的日本人 缓慢地前进
Day after day,the Americans inched forward
against Japanese who preferred death to surrender.

264
00:38:37,500 --> 00:38:43,445
他们的领导人仍然希望美国人可能
会对他们的损失和这场战争感到厌倦
Their leader still hoped the Americans
might tire of their losses and the war.

265
00:38:43,529 --> 00:38:46,800
欧,我的上帝
在硫磺岛上,那是场白刃战
Oh, my Lord. On Iwo, it was
hand-to-hand fighting.

266
00:38:46,800 --> 00:38:51,077
有一半时间 你甚至都不知道
谁和你一起在那个洞里
You didn't know who was even
in the hole with you half of the time.

267
00:38:51,162 --> 00:38:52,800
你钻进那些山洞里
You went into the caves.

268
00:38:52,800 --> 00:38:57,334
我们的大多数伤亡都是以这种方式损失掉的
We lost most of our people
in this particular fashion.

269
00:38:57,418 --> 00:39:00,337
你走进山洞 并与那家伙战斗
You went into the caves
and fought it out with the guy.

270
00:39:00,421 --> 00:39:03,673
你们之中(只有)一个能走出(山洞)
One of you came out.

271
00:39:05,885 --> 00:39:10,680
我想没有人意识到他们在这么深的地下
I don't think anybody realised
they were underground so deeply.

272
00:39:10,765 --> 00:39:14,726
你知道,这地方真的是防守如此森严
You know, it was so heavily defended,really.

273
00:39:32,161 --> 00:39:35,372
在折钵山上战斗了三天后,
After three days' fighting
on Mount Suribachi,

274
00:39:35,456 --> 00:39:38,249
星条旗在山顶上飘扬
the Stars and Stripes
flew on the summit.

275
00:39:38,334 --> 00:39:42,087
一个男孩开始叫喊,"国旗在那里升起来了,"
One of the boys started
to holler, "There goes the flag,"

276
00:39:42,171 --> 00:39:44,714
不管你在那个岛的什么地方,
and I don't care where you were
on that island,

277
00:39:44,799 --> 00:39:50,011
你往折钵山看 都能看到旗帜被升起来了
you could see right up to Suribachi
that the flag was raised.

278
00:39:50,096 --> 00:39:52,764
每个人都开始高声叫喊,
And everybody started to howl,

279
00:39:52,890 --> 00:39:56,476
因为我们以为,这座岛安全了
because we figured,
well, the island was secure.

280
00:39:56,560 --> 00:39:59,020
(其实)离安全还远着呢
lt was far from secure.

281
00:39:59,105 --> 00:40:01,189
我们还有很长的路要走
We had a long way to go yet.

282
00:40:01,273 --> 00:40:05,318
但不管怎样 看到国旗升起来还是很不错
But it was nice to see
the flag up there anyway.

283
00:40:11,158 --> 00:40:14,869
他们总是叫你要抓俘虏,
They always told you
to take prisoners,

284
00:40:14,954 --> 00:40:18,206
但我们在塞班岛上抓俘虏时
有过一些很糟糕的经历
but we had some bad experiences
on Saipan taking prisoners.

285
00:40:18,332 --> 00:40:22,961
你抓住了他们 而他们一到了
战线后方就扔手榴弹
You'd take 'em and as soon as they'd get
behind the lines they'd drop grenades

286
00:40:23,045 --> 00:40:25,130
你又会损失几个人
and you'd lose a few more people.

287
00:40:25,214 --> 00:40:30,000
当他们会战斗到死 而你也是这样时
你对抓俘虏会很留神
You're a bit leery about taking prisoners
when they're fighting to the death and so are you.

288
00:40:34,765 --> 00:40:36,599
好吧,现在你可以开始了!
OK, you can kick off right now!

289
00:40:37,935 --> 00:40:39,800
他们中非常少的人会自己出来
Very few of 'em came out on their own.

290
00:40:39,800 --> 00:40:44,482
当他们出来时,在前面的
一个人会举起双手出来
When they did, one in the front
would come out with his hands up

291
00:40:44,567 --> 00:40:48,736
而他身后的那个人
他会拿着个手榴弹出来
and one behind him,
he'd come out with a grenade.

292
00:40:54,452 --> 00:40:59,700
一个西弗吉尼亚的男孩,他正靠着一堵石墙坐着
One of the West Virginia boys,
he was sitting against a stone wall

293
00:40:59,700 --> 00:41:05,879
戴着头盔把他的头靠在他的膝盖上,
就象我们那时经常那么坐的那样,
with his knees up under his helmet,
as we used to sit quite often,

294
00:41:05,963 --> 00:41:10,675
这时一个敌人跑出来 冲到石墙顶部
when one of the enemy ran out
onto the top of the stone wall

295
00:41:10,759 --> 00:41:15,763
他的肚皮上绑着一个小炸药包
and held a small explosive charge
to his abdomen.

296
00:41:16,974 --> 00:41:22,145
(爆炸过后)他躯干的一大块,下半身,
And a chunk of his torso,the lower torso,

297
00:41:22,229 --> 00:41:27,317
被急剧地炸飞到空中
并掉落在约翰的膝盖上
went spiralling into the air
and came down on John's knees

298
00:41:27,401 --> 00:41:34,365
那个没有任何衣服包裹的臀部
正对着他的脸
with the absolute posterior devoid of
any clothes staring him right in the face.

299
00:41:34,450 --> 00:41:38,161
他看着那屁股 说道,
"老天,我的伤有那么重?"
And he looked at that and he says,
"God, am I hit that bad?"

300
00:41:40,956 --> 00:41:47,629
而那事是释放了前一晚紧张的触发器
And that was the trigger that released
the tensions of the previous night.

301
00:41:47,713 --> 00:41:54,093
我们几个人有整整一个小时都完全没做什么事
And there were several of us that were
perfectly useless for as much as an hour.

302
00:41:54,178 --> 00:41:58,389
我们就躺在地上捧腹狂笑
We were just laying on the ground
in convulsions.

303
00:42:07,107 --> 00:42:12,445
当进攻开始时 在硫磺岛上的21,000名日军中,
Of 21,000 Japanese troops
on Iwo Jima when the attack began,

304
00:42:12,530 --> 00:42:14,989
只有200人被生擒
only 200 were taken alive.

305
00:42:21,330 --> 00:42:24,791
我在岛上待了总共六天
I was on the island
a total of six days

306
00:42:24,875 --> 00:42:27,627
它似乎有6,000年那么长
and it seemed like 6,000 years.

307
00:42:30,000 --> 00:42:38,972
由于美国修建营(CB)的不懈努力,甚至
在硫磺岛被占领前 这座岛的机场就启用了
Iwo Jima's airfields were functioning even
before the island was taken thanks to the
American construction battalions, the CBs.

308
00:42:40,224 --> 00:42:46,354
他们在这里和整场太平洋战争中
都扮演了一个关键角色
They played a key role here
and indeed in the whole Pacific war.

309
00:42:46,600 --> 00:42:52,026
现在到了穿透日本内部防御圈的时候了
Now the time had come to penetrate
the inner ring of Japan's defences.

310
00:42:53,400 --> 00:43:00,535
离日本本土350英里 是隔在盟军和计划好了的
对日本帝国的入侵之间的最后一个大障碍...
350 miles from the mainland was the last great barrier
between the Allies and the planned invasion of lmperial Japan...

311
00:43:00,619 --> 00:43:03,413
日本冲绳岛
the Japanese island of Okinawa.

312
00:43:03,497 --> 00:43:07,208
1945年4月1日,美国人进攻了
On April 1, 1945,
the Americans attacked.

313
00:43:48,751 --> 00:43:55,000
日本的年轻自杀飞行员,神风特攻队,
蜂拥飞来防守冲绳岛
Japan's young suicide pilots,the kamikazes,
swarmed to the defence of Okinawa.

314
00:43:58,886 --> 00:44:03,932
许多人驾驶过时的飞机,甚至是训练机
执行他们那致命的任务
Many flew their fatal missions
in obsolete aircraft, even trainers.

315
00:44:23,285 --> 00:44:26,371
有那么多事情正在发生 而且如此之快,
So many things were happening
and so quickly,

316
00:44:26,455 --> 00:44:33,670
这很象一个站在拳击台上的大个子拳击手
他的下巴,脸,身体和其他地方都正被击打
that it was a little bit like a big boxer
in a ring when he's being hit to the chin,
face,body and everywhere else,

317
00:44:33,754 --> 00:44:38,257
因为我们正从那么多不同的角度遭受攻击
cos we were catching it
from so many different angles.

318
00:44:45,099 --> 00:44:47,300
在一次常规的攻击中,
你有相当大的机会(成功抵挡住)
ln a regular attack,
it's a sporting chance you've got.

319
00:44:47,300 --> 00:44:52,000
你知道 我是说 (如果日本人是)用常规炸弹和常规
子弹进攻,你会觉得你有非常大的机会(战胜他们),
You know,I mean, with regular bombs and regular
bullets,you think you've got a very good chance,

320
00:44:52,000 --> 00:44:57,944
但当你在和人体炸弹战斗时
战争就不再是那么象一种消遣了
but war is not so much of a sport
when you're fighting human bombs.

321
00:45:03,701 --> 00:45:07,078
超过2,000名神风飞行员丧生
Over 2,000 kamikaze pilots
met their deaths.

322
00:45:07,162 --> 00:45:12,291
但他们摧毁了30艘美国战舰 损坏了200多艘
But they destroyed 30 US warships
and damaged 200 more.

323
00:45:24,096 --> 00:45:29,434
你在祈祷你能在即将发生的不管何种爆炸中幸存下来
You were praying that you could survive
whatever kind of explosion would come about.

324
00:45:29,518 --> 00:45:31,900
你的整个生命(过程)非常快地在你的眼前闪回,
Your whole life flashed in
front of you very quickly,

325
00:45:31,900 --> 00:45:36,858
因为你不知道 离你的生命被
突然终结 有几秒钟还是几分钟
because you didn't know whether it would be seconds
or minutes until your life would be snuffed out.

326
00:45:36,984 --> 00:45:38,800
美国的伤亡是如此惨重,
American casualties were so severe,

327
00:45:38,800 --> 00:45:45,324
以至于入侵冲绳的行动一度似乎可能会被中止
that at one point it seemed the invasion of
Okinawa might be stopped in its tracks.

328
00:45:46,702 --> 00:45:48,000
炮手们停不下来
The gunners can't turn it off.

329
00:45:48,000 --> 00:45:52,915
一旦他们作好了用人对抗
人体炸弹的战斗的准备,
Once they gear themselves up
to fight man against man bomb,

330
00:45:53,000 --> 00:45:58,463
即使飞机被击落了,也很难让炮手停止射击
even though the plane is down,
it's hard for the gunner to stop.

331
00:46:24,031 --> 00:46:27,909
有一个人,他在一个40mm高射炮的炮位上,
One man,he was in a 40 millimetre mount,

332
00:46:27,993 --> 00:46:32,163
(法兰克·曼森 美国海军上尉)
他已经对抗了许多架冲过来的飞机,
and he had been fighting against quite
a number of planes that had come in,

333
00:46:32,247 --> 00:46:35,208
但在他的区域 我们也被击中了两三次,
but we had been hit in his area
also two or three times,

334
00:46:35,292 --> 00:46:38,961
突然,没人理解为什么(他会这样),
and all of a sudden,
with nobody understanding why,

335
00:46:39,046 --> 00:46:41,800
他只是大叫道,"今天真热,"
然后从船舷一边跳进海里
he just yelled, "It's hot today,"
and jumped over the side

336
00:46:41,800 --> 00:46:43,925
那是我们最后一次看到他
and that's the last we ever saw of him.

337
00:46:44,009 --> 00:46:46,928
但要是他待在船上,他可能就活下来了
But had he stayed aboard,
he might have survived.

338
00:46:47,012 --> 00:46:50,598
但是当然,在那之后我们找不到他的尸体或任何东西
But of course, we couldn't find
his body or anything after that.

339
00:46:50,682 --> 00:46:53,434
但那是一种不寻常的反应
But it was an unusual type of reaction.

340
00:46:53,519 --> 00:46:58,481
他坚持了尽可能长时间,直到他崩溃
He stayed with it just as long
as he could, until he broke.

341
00:46:58,565 --> 00:47:01,150
而那就是他的战斗的结束
And then that was the end
of his fighting.

342
00:47:01,235 --> 00:47:04,779
但每个人,我相信,都有一个(崩溃的)极点
But every man, I believe,
has a breaking point.

343
00:47:04,863 --> 00:47:08,449
我估计,神风特攻队,
And the kamikaze, I would estimate,

344
00:47:08,575 --> 00:47:14,247
很可能比其他任何形式的战斗都更考验那个极点
probably tests that breaking point
more than any other form of combat.

345
00:47:19,002 --> 00:47:22,338
在冲绳的登陆一开始未遇到抵抗,
lnitial landings on Okinawa
were unopposed,

346
00:47:22,422 --> 00:47:24,173
但随着他们向内陆推进,
but as the Americans pushed inland,

347
00:47:24,258 --> 00:47:27,343
他们遭遇了一支10万人的日军部队,
they came up against
a Japanese army of 100,000 troops,

348
00:47:27,427 --> 00:47:31,806
(他们)已撤退到戒备森严的中部地区
withdrawn into a heavily fortified
central area.

349
00:47:50,300 --> 00:47:57,164
冲绳那陡峭的小山和狭窄的峡谷
为日本守卫者们形成了一个天然的堡垒
The steep hills and narrow ravines of Okinawa
formed a natural citadel for Japanese defenders.

350
00:47:58,792 --> 00:48:00,793
人数上(被美国人)以2:1超过,
Outnumbered two to one,

351
00:48:00,878 --> 00:48:05,214
他们让美国人为占领每英尺
日本土地都付出了血的代价
they made the Americans pay in blood
for every foot of Japanese soil.

352
00:48:43,128 --> 00:48:46,547
随着日本接近于投降,
With Japan herself close to surrender,

353
00:48:46,632 --> 00:48:51,510
不是每个日本士兵都想要继续战斗到死
not every Japanese soldier
wanted to fight on to the end.

354
00:50:34,114 --> 00:50:37,700
冲绳的平民遭受了非常严重的伤亡
The civilians of Okinawa
suffered appalling losses.

355
00:50:37,784 --> 00:50:42,621
24,000人被杀 好几千人受伤
24,000 were killed.
Many thousands more injured.

356
00:50:42,706 --> 00:50:48,335
一旦他们发现 我们不会做
他们一直听说(我们会做)的事情,
Once they found out we weren't going to
do the things that they had always heard,

357
00:50:48,420 --> 00:50:52,131
他们会明白,"嘿,这只是另一个人而已"
they could understand,
"Hey, this is just another human being."

358
00:50:52,215 --> 00:50:54,717
可能他们的感觉跟我们的一样,
Possibly they felt the same as we did,

359
00:50:54,801 --> 00:50:58,554
(那就是)我们不是因为
想去那里 才去那里的,
that we weren't there
because we wanted to be there,

360
00:50:58,638 --> 00:51:02,892
我们是被告知 这是我们必须做的事情
we were told that this is what we had to do.

361
00:51:02,976 --> 00:51:04,500
对许多美国人来说,
To many Americans,

362
00:51:04,500 --> 00:51:07,688
在他们横跨太平洋的伟大征程的尽头,
at the end of their great advance
across the Pacific,

363
00:51:07,814 --> 00:51:14,528
现在似乎那些野兽,那些渴望为他们
的天皇而死的没有脸的狂热分子,
it now seemed that the animals,the faceless
fanatics eager to die for their emperor,

364
00:51:14,613 --> 00:51:18,157
是象他们自己一样的人类
were human beings like themselves.

365
00:51:18,241 --> 00:51:22,620
他们对他们的自己人显示了仁慈,
这点我们倒真的没想到
They showed kindness to their own people,
to which we didn't really think,you know.

366
00:51:22,704 --> 00:51:27,208
我们以为生命对他们来说
很不值钱,但那不是事实
We thought life was cheap to them,
but that's not true.

367
00:51:27,292 --> 00:51:33,589
他们对他们自己的伤员显示出很大
的仁慈 并会把他们背在他们的身上,
They showed a lot of kindness to their own
wounded and would tote 'em on their back,

368
00:51:33,673 --> 00:51:40,513
两三个人会背着他们,
尽管他们自己也很虚弱
and two or three would carry 'em,
although they were weak themselves.

369
00:51:40,597 --> 00:51:43,349
所以他们正如我们一样 也是人
So they were people just like us.

