1
00:00:19,769 --> 00:00:22,271
1940年5月26日
May 26, 1940.

2
00:00:31,114 --> 00:00:34,450
沿路到处散落着他们
被捣毁和遗弃的装备,
Along roads lined with their
smashed and abandoned equipment,

3
00:00:34,534 --> 00:00:38,912
英国和法国部队撤退到对他们
还开放的唯一(英吉利)海峡港口:
British and French armies retreat to the
only Channel port still open to them:

4
00:00:38,997 --> 00:00:41,248
敦刻尔克
Dunkirk.

5
00:00:41,332 --> 00:00:43,959
十英里外,沿着海峡的海岸,
Ten miles away, along the Channel coast,

6
00:00:44,044 --> 00:00:48,047
德国装甲部队等待着
希特勒的进攻命令
German armour awaits
Hitler's orders to attack.

7
00:00:49,090 --> 00:00:50,841
在敦刻尔克的海滩上,
On the Dunkirk beaches,

8
00:00:50,925 --> 00:00:53,761
近五十万人...
英国人和法国人...
nearly half a million men...
British and French...

9
00:00:53,845 --> 00:01:00,017
面临着投降,或被从英国
开来的船救回的微弱机会
face surrender, or the slim chance
of rescue by ships from England.

10
00:01:57,575 --> 00:01:58,900
有大批的部队
There were masses of troops

11
00:01:58,900 --> 00:02:06,708
当他们走近水的边缘的时候 他们从一种V字形
的队伍换到一种两人一排,半单人的纵列
and they came down in a sort of a V-shape to a crocodile,
semi-single file, as they got near the water's edge.

12
00:02:06,793 --> 00:02:11,964
当然 许多士兵正走向齐脖深的水
Of course, many of these soldiers were
going out up to their necks in water

13
00:02:12,048 --> 00:02:16,301
然后爬进,比如说,能开到
离岸边就那么近的扫雷舰
and climbing into, say, minesweepers
that could get in nearly as close as that.

14
00:02:16,386 --> 00:02:19,596
当然海滩上其他人在登上小船
Others,of course, on the beach were
embarking in the small boats.

15
00:02:19,681 --> 00:02:22,891
但似乎根本没有任何恐慌或烦恼
But there didn't seem to be
any panic or worry at all.

16
00:02:22,976 --> 00:02:25,644
你会遇到许多这种小船,
One came across
lots of these small boats,

17
00:02:25,728 --> 00:02:29,940
其中许多在船上装着
或许一打(12个)或差不多的士兵,
many of them with perhaps
a dozen or so soldiers on board,

18
00:02:30,066 --> 00:02:32,526
正坚定地开回英国
heading back for England resolutely.

19
00:02:32,610 --> 00:02:37,072
你经常会向这种小船提出
把船上的士兵转移下来
One quite often offered to
take their crews of soldiers off them

20
00:02:37,198 --> 00:02:39,408
那样他们可以回去再拉一批,
而他们说道:
so they could go back for
another load,and they said:

21
00:02:39,492 --> 00:02:43,495
"不怕 我们已经装了我们的12只猩猩,
我们要带着他们回英格兰"
"No fear. We've got our 12 pongos, and
we're going back to England with them."

22
00:02:43,580 --> 00:02:45,164
"你去拉你自己的人"
"You go and get your own."

23
00:02:46,624 --> 00:02:49,251
海滩...有数以千计的人,
The beach was...
There were thousands of men,

24
00:02:49,377 --> 00:02:52,421
就象一个公共假期里的马盖特海滩
like Margate beach on a bank holiday.

25
00:02:53,715 --> 00:02:57,342
部队处于挺糟糕的状态
他们的情况很差
The troops was in a pretty bad state.
They were in a bad way.

26
00:02:58,094 --> 00:03:01,013
特别是有一个人,我总是记得
There was one man especially,
l shall always remember.

27
00:03:01,097 --> 00:03:04,516
他上了船...
他的牙被轰掉了...
He came on board...
he'd had his teeth blown out...

28
00:03:04,642 --> 00:03:07,936
他拿着一把上了刺刀的步枪
and he was holding a rifle
with a fixed bayonet.

29
00:03:08,021 --> 00:03:09,938
我们必须把每个人的武器收起来,
We had to take the arms
off everyone,

30
00:03:10,023 --> 00:03:13,025
但我们不能把那把枪从他手中拿走
but we couldn't shift
the gun out of his hands.

31
00:03:13,109 --> 00:03:17,571
他的手紧握着它,
他们是...固定在一起的
His hands was actually...gripped this,
and they was... fixture.

32
00:03:18,740 --> 00:03:22,743
一个小伙子在海滩上,然后
他上了条船 就认为他安全了
A chap was on the beach, and then he
gets aboard a ship and thinks he's safe.

33
00:03:22,827 --> 00:03:25,120
但他们真的这么想 他们说:
But they really did think this.
They said:

34
00:03:25,205 --> 00:03:29,041
"英格兰, 故乡和美人...
让我们回到那里,小伙子"
"England, home and beauty...
let us get there, boyo."

35
00:03:29,167 --> 00:03:31,668
我们留下了极深刻的印象
他们非常累
We were most impressed.
They were very tired.

36
00:03:31,753 --> 00:03:34,630
他们大多数人倒下就睡着了
Most of them just slump
down and went to sleep then.

37
00:03:37,634 --> 00:03:41,094
我们的任务是阻止敌人飞机
攻击那些部队
Our job was to stop enemy aircraft
getting at those troops,

38
00:03:41,179 --> 00:03:46,225
因为,相信我,如果敌人的飞机
在敦刻尔克有制空权的话,
because, believe me, if enemy aircraft
had got superiority of the air at Dunkirk,

39
00:03:46,351 --> 00:03:49,686
他们就会把那些在海滩上的伙计都
给屠杀了 (他们)什么都做不了
they would have massacred those fellows on
the beach. Nothing could have been done.

40
00:03:49,771 --> 00:03:52,439
他们没有炮,他们没有防空武器
They had no guns,
they had no anti-aircraft.

41
00:03:52,523 --> 00:03:57,486
德国轰炸机和德国俯冲轰炸机..斯图卡...
And German bombers
and German dive bombers... the Stukas...

42
00:03:57,612 --> 00:04:02,157
就会杀了他们 而我们就
不可能把那些部队救出来
would have just murdered them. And
we couldn't have got those troops off.

43
00:04:02,242 --> 00:04:05,535
德国人试图做的另一件事
当然就是把船炸沉
Another thing the Germans tried to do,
of course, was to sink the ships.

44
00:04:05,620 --> 00:04:09,539
他们知道伙计们不能游回英国
They knew that the fellows would
not be able to swim out to England,

45
00:04:09,624 --> 00:04:11,708
所以他们必须试图把船干掉
therefore they had to try
and get on the ships.

46
00:04:11,834 --> 00:04:16,838
如果他们能把这些船炸沉,
英国军队就会被困住了
And if they could sink these ships, the
British army would have been trapped.

47
00:04:21,427 --> 00:04:25,389
皇家空军试图使德国空军远离海滩,
The RAF tried to keep the
German air force away from the beaches,

48
00:04:25,473 --> 00:04:29,685
但还是有六艘驱逐舰
和超过200条船被炸沉
but six destroyers
and over 200 craft were sunk.

49
00:04:33,022 --> 00:04:37,693
战斗机司令部在法国战役中
损失了近一半的力量...
Fighter Command lost nearly half
its strength in the French campaign...

50
00:04:37,777 --> 00:04:40,445
仅在敦刻尔克行动中就损失了100架飞机
100 planes in the Dunkirk operations alone.

51
00:04:50,290 --> 00:04:52,833
敦刻尔克是场大败仗,
Dunkirk was a major defeat,

52
00:04:52,917 --> 00:04:56,253
但皇家海军和小船
受神灵启示的努力
but the inspired efforts
of the Royal Navy and the little ships

53
00:04:56,337 --> 00:05:00,799
拯救了三十三万英国和法国部队
saved 330,000 British and French troops.

54
00:05:02,010 --> 00:05:04,303
有一星期,天气都很好,
For a week, the weather was fine,

55
00:05:04,387 --> 00:05:07,100
德国军队被抵挡住了
and the German army was held off.

56
00:05:07,100 --> 00:05:12,227
我真的不觉得他们(皇家海军)会以为他们
能把他们(远征军)救走 那是我的观点
I really,truely don't think that they thought
they would get them off. That's my opinion.

57
00:05:12,312 --> 00:05:14,646
但他们所做的是一个上帝的行动
But it was an act of God that they did.

58
00:05:14,731 --> 00:05:18,358
天气很好,海面(平静得)象磨坊贮水池,
The weather was good,
the sea was like a millpond,

59
00:05:18,443 --> 00:05:21,028
这对每个人的帮助都很大
and this was a great help to everybody.

60
00:05:21,112 --> 00:05:24,781
如果海水浪头很大的话,你就永远
不能把他们从敦刻尔克救出来,
lf it had been rough water, you'd
have never got them off of Dunkirk,

61
00:05:24,866 --> 00:05:28,952
因为当那些船开到海滩旁,
他们就会(被浪)推走
because when those rollers
go up that beach, they go.

62
00:05:29,078 --> 00:05:32,456
在任何一刻,德国陆军的一个突破
(McBeath) Any moment,
a breakthrough by the German army

63
00:05:32,540 --> 00:05:34,750
就能把整个行动给终止了
could have stopped the whole operation.

64
00:05:34,834 --> 00:05:42,632
我认为,尽管阻挡德军的英国
和法国部队表现得非常英勇
I don't think, despite the valiant endeavours of the British
and French troops who were keeping the Germans back,

65
00:05:42,717 --> 00:05:46,845
他们还是挡不住
德国装甲力量的突破
that they could have stopped the might
of the German armour getting through

66
00:05:46,929 --> 00:05:49,389
如果希特勒想要这么做的话
if Hitler had so wanted to do it.

67
00:05:50,933 --> 00:05:55,270
留在敦刻尔克的人于6月4日投降
What was left of Dunkirk
surrendered on June 4.

68
00:05:55,355 --> 00:05:58,273
数以千计的部队没能被救出
Thousands of troops
could not be rescued.

69
00:06:01,235 --> 00:06:03,653
两个星期后,法国停止了战斗,
A fortnight later,
France stopped fighting,

70
00:06:03,780 --> 00:06:07,491
而英国首相,丘吉尔,
向全世界发表广播讲话:
and the British prime minister,
Churchill, broadcast to the world:

71
00:06:07,575 --> 00:06:12,996
被魏刚将军称为法兰西之战
(的战役)结束了
(Churchill) What General Weygand had
called the Battle of France is over.

72
00:06:13,081 --> 00:06:17,167
不列颠之战即将开始
The Battle of Britain
is about to begin.

73
00:06:17,251 --> 00:06:23,173
希特勒知道他将不得不在这个
岛屿上击败我们,或输掉战争
Hitler knows that he will have to break
us in this island, or lose the war.

74
00:06:23,674 --> 00:06:28,220
如果我们能勇敢地面对他,
全欧洲都有可能获得自由,
If we can stand up to him,
all Europe may be free,

75
00:06:28,304 --> 00:06:34,476
世界的生命可以向前进入
广阔的,充满阳光的高地
and the life of the world may move
forward into broad, sunlit uplands.

76
00:06:35,269 --> 00:06:37,145
但如果我们失败,
But if we fail,

77
00:06:37,230 --> 00:06:43,235
那么全世界将坠入一个新黑暗时代的深渊
then the whole world will
sink into the abyss of a new dark age.

78
00:06:44,362 --> 00:06:48,240
所以让我们准备面对我们的使命...
Let us therefore
brace ourselves to our duty...

79
00:06:49,200 --> 00:06:51,827
并让我们配得上这样的评价
and so bear ourselves

80
00:06:51,911 --> 00:06:58,792
那就是如果大英帝国及其联邦
能再持续一千年,
that if the British Empire and its
Commonwealth last for a thousand years,

81
00:06:58,876 --> 00:07:01,211
(到那时)人们还能说:
men will still say:

82
00:07:02,213 --> 00:07:05,257
"这是他们最光辉的时刻"
"This was their finest hour."

83
00:07:21,315 --> 00:07:24,000
英国准备面对迫在眉睫的入侵
Britain prepared
to face immediate invasion.

84
00:07:24,100 --> 00:07:31,408
把孩子从预计德国人可能登陆的南部和东部
海岸地区撤离的新一轮疏散开始了
A new evacuation of children began from the south and
east-coast areas where a German landing might be expected.

85
00:07:33,734 --> 00:07:37,112
一些父母把他们的孩子
送到海外的安全地
Some parents sent their children
overseas to safety.

86
00:07:37,196 --> 00:07:43,243
但当一艘德国U型潜艇在九月击沉了一条装有
90个孩子的英国邮轮时 这种做法被停下来
But this was stopped in September when a U-boat
sank a British liner with 90 children on board.

87
00:07:50,209 --> 00:07:57,900
为了防御入侵,超过一百万没被正规军
征召的男子自愿组成了国民自卫军
To guard against invasion, over a million men not required
by the regular forces volunteered to form the Home Guard.

88
00:08:09,700 --> 00:08:13,203
由于没有多余的步枪,
他们用扫帚进行操练,
They drilled with broomsticks
because there were no rifles to spare,

89
00:08:13,287 --> 00:08:17,666
并排练了抵抗德国进攻的嗜血防御
and rehearsed bloodthirsty defences
against a German attack.

90
00:08:39,438 --> 00:08:43,650
正规军的训练似乎给
新闻片留下了深刻印象
The regular army's training
seems to have impressed the newsreels.

91
00:08:43,734 --> 00:08:46,945
这些曾经的步行者已经
踩动了脚踏起动推进器
The one-time footsloggers have
turned kick-starter pushers.

92
00:08:47,029 --> 00:08:50,073
他们的小马已经让位于飞快的摩托
Shanks's pony has given way
to a spanking motorbike.

93
00:08:50,158 --> 00:08:54,286
这些左右,左右(并排)的小子们
把双脚同时都脱离地面
The left-right, left-right blokes have both
feet off the ground at the same time.

94
00:08:54,370 --> 00:08:57,000
他们是英国强大的机动骑兵的成员,
They're part of Britain's
mighty mobile mounties,

95
00:08:57,000 --> 00:09:02,000
他们全都很热衷于欢迎阿道夫,当他为了
喝杯茶和吃个奶油包而前来拜访
all keen to welcome Adolf when he drops
in for a cup of tea and a cream bun.

96
00:09:02,000 --> 00:09:04,588
一个轮上步兵营正在演习...
A battalion of infantry on wheels
is on exercise...

97
00:09:04,672 --> 00:09:08,925
这支快速移动的打击力量
将对敌人做许多不好的事
a swift-moving striking force that
will do the enemy a bit of no good.

98
00:09:09,010 --> 00:09:13,763
他们已经学会轻松面对困难 就象他们
有可能在实战中(遇到的环境)一样
And they learnt to take the rough with smooth, under
conditions they might meet with on active service.

99
00:09:13,848 --> 00:09:19,644
他们开上开下,但不象匈奴人(德国人)
他们从来就不耍花招
Up and down they go, but unlike the Hun
they're always on the level.

100
00:09:20,855 --> 00:09:24,024
军队把他们的步枪
从敦刻尔克带了回来,
The army had brought back
their rifles from Dunkirk,

101
00:09:24,108 --> 00:09:27,861
但其他几乎所有装备
都被丢弃在了法国
but almost everything else
had been abandoned in France.

102
00:09:27,945 --> 00:09:33,241
六月,在英国唯一装备齐全的师
是加拿大人的
ln June, the only fully-equipped
division in Britain was Canadian.

103
00:09:33,326 --> 00:09:37,746
我记得在六月我去了英国的东南角,
l remember in June going down
to the Southeast corner of Britain,

104
00:09:37,830 --> 00:09:40,207
那里由索恩将军指挥...
where General Thorne was in command...

105
00:09:40,291 --> 00:09:44,000
也就是肯特郡,萨里郡,苏塞克斯郡,
就是那一片地区,
Kent, Surrey, Sussex,
that sort of area,

106
00:09:44,000 --> 00:09:48,340
如果德国人要尝试登陆,
那里肯定是一个可能的登陆区...
certainly a possible landing area for the Germans,
if they were going to attempt it...

107
00:09:48,424 --> 00:09:52,886
我记得给温斯顿(丘吉尔)送了一份备忘录
这份备忘录一定还在他的档案里
and I remember sending a memorandum to
Winston which must be somewhere in his papers.

108
00:09:52,970 --> 00:09:55,388
如果我没记错,我是这么说的:
If I remember right,
I said something like this:

109
00:09:55,473 --> 00:09:59,600
部队的士气非常高涨,
训练也非常好, 等等
the troops were in very good heart
and very well trained,and so forth

110
00:09:59,600 --> 00:10:05,774
但是当然,没有任何种类的反坦克武器,
but of course, there is
no antitank weapon of any kind,

111
00:10:05,858 --> 00:10:09,361
没有反坦克炮,没有坦克
no antitank guns, and no tanks.

112
00:10:09,445 --> 00:10:14,300
那是在一个如果德国人要登陆,
预计他们很可能在那里登陆的地区
That was in the area where, if the Germans were going
to land, they might be very well expected to land.

113
00:10:14,300 --> 00:10:16,500
那种状态就象碗橱里是空的一样
That was the state of the cupboard was bare.

114
00:10:16,786 --> 00:10:23,000
国王(乔治六世)练了枪法,并很高兴
英国孤立无援,不再有盟国要宠着
The king practiced marksmanship and rejoiced that
Britain stood alone,with no more allies to pamper.

115
00:10:23,400 --> 00:10:26,444
战斗机司令部的首脑,
休·道丁爵士,表示同意
The head of Fighter Command,
Sir Hugh Dowding, agreed.

116
00:10:26,528 --> 00:10:30,323
他为帮助法国人已经损失了太多飞机
He had lost too many planes
helping the French.

117
00:10:31,659 --> 00:10:36,245
站名和路标被移走来迷惑入侵的德军
Station names and signposts were
removed to baffle invading Germans.

118
00:10:36,372 --> 00:10:39,082
效果是迷惑了英国的旅游者
The effect was to baffle
British travellers.

119
00:10:39,750 --> 00:10:45,254
反坦克障碍确保当德国人
沿铁路推进时不会轻松通过
Antitank barriers make sure the Germans wouldn't have
an easy passage as they advance along the railways.

120
00:10:50,761 --> 00:10:55,682
在(可能的)入侵地区,
乡间消失在一圈圈铁丝网下
And in the invasion areas, the countryside
disappeared under coils of barbed wire.

121
00:10:55,808 --> 00:11:00,144
海滩也在低潮线下被布满铁丝
The beaches, too,
were wired to below low-water mark.

122
00:11:00,229 --> 00:11:03,773
JB·普莱斯利记得对海边的一次访问
JB Priestley remembers
a visit to the seaside.

123
00:11:03,857 --> 00:11:09,000
我在一个炎热的夏天...晚夏...
I went down one hot summer day...
late summer...

124
00:11:09,738 --> 00:11:13,866
去了在肯特郡的一个海边度假地
to one of the seaside resorts
on the Kent coast.

125
00:11:14,910 --> 00:11:17,495
我上次去那里的时候,
那里挤满了人...
The last time I visited,
it was packed out...

126
00:11:17,579 --> 00:11:22,125
海滩绝对塞满了人,
游乐场充满了欢乐
the beaches absolutely crammed,
and all the fun of the fair going on.

127
00:11:22,209 --> 00:11:28,381
然后在这个奇怪,明亮,
空闲的日子看到它,
Then to see it on this
strange, bright, empty day,

128
00:11:28,465 --> 00:11:33,302
海滩被遗弃,到处是许多铁丝网,
the beaches deserted,
a lot of barbed wire all over the place,

129
00:11:33,429 --> 00:11:39,767
我那时感觉,从某种程度上来说,
这是人们感受的一种象征,
I felt then that, in a way, this was
a kind of symbol of what people felt,

130
00:11:39,852 --> 00:11:45,606
而他们准备暂时放弃这个(指海边度假)
and that they were ready
to abandon this for the time being

131
00:11:45,691 --> 00:11:48,192
为的是继续进行战争
in order to get on with the war.

132
00:11:50,779 --> 00:11:54,532
丘吉尔到处出现,不再是一个受怀疑的政客,
Churchill was everywhere,
no longer a suspect politician,

133
00:11:54,616 --> 00:11:58,161
而是英国抵抗意愿
活生生的化身
but the living embodiment
of the British will to resist.

134
00:11:58,245 --> 00:12:07,253
为同事描述一副他自己在被摧毁的白厅领导一场战至最后一人
的防御战的生动画面,似乎是他最着迷于的一种情况
It was a situation he seemed to revel in, describing
for colleagues a vivid picture of himself leading
a last-man defence of a devastated Whitehall.

135
00:12:07,337 --> 00:12:12,175
丘吉尔一成为首相,白厅的步伐就变了
Immediately Churchill became prime minister,
the pace in Whitehall changed.

136
00:12:12,259 --> 00:12:16,637
人们开始不仅想得快,而且行动得也快
People started not merely to think fast,
but to act fast.

137
00:12:16,722 --> 00:12:20,767
著名的公务员会被看到在通道里快跑
Distinguished civil servants could be
seen running down the passages.

138
00:12:20,851 --> 00:12:23,644
丘吉尔自己就非常有活力
Churchill himself
was physically very energetic.

139
00:12:23,729 --> 00:12:27,440
他会突然作出最不同寻常
和充满活力的出击
He would suddenly make the most
extraordinary and energetic sorties.

140
00:12:27,524 --> 00:12:30,985
他会视察部队,以惊人速度检阅士兵,
He would inspect troops,
marching at great speed down the ranks,

141
00:12:31,069 --> 00:12:34,238
走得比所有跟随他的年轻人更快
and outpacing all the younger men
who are following him.

142
00:12:34,323 --> 00:12:38,950
我记得一天晚上他说他要去视察一些新工厂,
l remember one evening he said he was
going to inspect some new works,

143
00:12:38,952 --> 00:12:44,624
尽管他已经65岁了,他还是翻过一堵砖墙
and although he was 65 years old,
he vaulted over a brick wall

144
00:12:44,708 --> 00:12:48,336
并一脚落在一堆湿的水泥上面,
and landed feet first
in a pool of liquid cement.

145
00:12:48,420 --> 00:12:52,006
而用一种现在回想还令我惊讶的鲁莽无礼,
And with an impertinence
which in retrospect l'm surprised at,

146
00:12:52,090 --> 00:12:56,552
我说道,"我想您遭遇了您的滑铁卢(战役),"
因为他陷在水泥里无法动弹
I said, "I think you've met your Waterloo,"
because he was stuck in the cement.

147
00:12:56,637 --> 00:13:01,100
他转过身对我说,"你怎么敢这么说?
不管怎么说,(这也是)我的布伦海姆(战役)"
He turned to me and said,
"How dare you? Anyhow, my Blenheim."

148
00:13:05,103 --> 00:13:08,064
在军工厂里 男女工人加班加点
In the arms factories
men and women worked long hours

149
00:13:08,148 --> 00:13:10,300
来填补英国防御上的缺口
to fill the gaps in British defences.

150
00:13:10,300 --> 00:13:13,903
产量在六月达到顶峰, 然后
随着工人们的疲倦而有所下降
Production reached a peak in June,
then fell as workers tired.

151
00:13:13,987 --> 00:13:16,697
但这种(突然)奋发在这段
关键的时间里一直得以维续
But the spurt lasted
through the critical time.

152
00:13:19,076 --> 00:13:21,202
战斗机的产量翻番
Production of fighter planes doubled.

153
00:13:21,286 --> 00:13:25,873
每周 一百架新"喷火"式和"飓风"式
战斗机补充道丁的部队
A hundred new Spitfires and Hurricanes
a week replenished Dowding's forces.

154
00:13:25,958 --> 00:13:28,960
新的飞机制造部长 比弗布鲁克爵士,
The minister of aircraft production,
Lord Beaverbrook,

155
00:13:29,044 --> 00:13:33,714
负责处理使普通人也觉得
是生产战役一部分(的运动)
took care to make ordinary people
feel part of the production battle.

156
00:13:33,799 --> 00:13:37,301
我父亲是一个宣传的大师
My father was a master of propaganda.

157
00:13:37,386 --> 00:13:43,349
当时有个"罐子和平底锅"(运动),每个人
都被要求交出罐子,平底锅和栏杆
There were "the pots and pans",where everyone
was asked to give up pots and pans and railings.

158
00:13:43,433 --> 00:13:45,726
斯坦利·鲍德温(英国前首相)
没有交出他的门,
Stanley Baldwin didn't give up his gates,

159
00:13:45,811 --> 00:13:49,313
但大多数人交出了所有他们
能捐出的金属物件
but most people gave up everything
they could in the way of metal.

160
00:13:49,398 --> 00:13:53,818
飞行员和我们都知道你不可能
用罐子和平底锅造出飞机,
The pilots and we all knew that you couldn't
make aircraft out of pots and pans,

161
00:13:53,944 --> 00:13:58,739
但这是件好事 它让人们
意识到局势令人绝望
but it's a good stuff it brought the people
to realise that it was a desperate situation.

162
00:13:58,824 --> 00:14:03,369
"罐子和平底锅"的反响极其热烈
他们收到了成堆的罐子和平底锅...
The response of "the pots and pans" was tremendous.
They had piles and piles of pots and pans...

163
00:14:03,453 --> 00:14:08,791
都不知道该把它们怎么办
但这足以说明他是个了不起的宣传家
not knowing what to do with them.
But he was a great propagandist.

164
00:14:08,876 --> 00:14:11,335
但德国的入侵又在哪里?
But where was
the German invasion?

165
00:14:11,920 --> 00:14:13,713
(♪ fanfare)

166
00:14:18,385 --> 00:14:22,388
1940年6月,希特勒还没有开始考虑入侵英国
In June 1940, Hitler had not begun
to think about invading Britain.

167
00:14:22,472 --> 00:14:27,727
他正忙于庆祝他在法国的胜利,
并期望英国能象法国一样讲和
He was busy celebrating his French victory,
and expected Britain like France to make peace.

168
00:14:27,811 --> 00:14:29,600
柏林给予他英雄般的欢迎
Berlin gave him a hero's welcome

169
00:14:29,600 --> 00:14:34,609
当他在7月6日和雷德尔海军上将(海军总司令)
和他的其他总司令回到那里
when he returned there on July 6 with Admiral
Raeder and his other commanders in chief.

170
00:14:34,693 --> 00:14:38,863
似乎只有德国海军有入侵(英国)的计划
Only the German navy
seemed to have plans for an invasion.

171
00:14:38,947 --> 00:14:41,324
到希特勒开始对这些计划感兴趣的时候,
By the time Hitler began to
take an interest in them,

172
00:14:41,408 --> 00:14:45,286
陆军有了它自己的计划
并对海军的计划作出批评
the army had its own plans
and was critical of the navy's.

173
00:14:48,040 --> 00:14:51,459
两者(陆军和海军)都指望戈林,
德国空军司令,来赢得制空权...
Both looked to Göring, the Luftwaffe
chief, to win control of the air...

174
00:14:51,543 --> 00:14:53,586
入侵的关键
vital for an invasion.

175
00:14:53,670 --> 00:14:58,299
而戈林相信德国空军光靠自己
就能击倒英国
And Göring believed the Luftwaffe
on its own could knock out Britain.

176
00:14:58,383 --> 00:15:02,845
军种之间的争论持续了几个月
Arguments between the services
went on for months.

177
00:15:03,430 --> 00:15:08,601
陆军一开始想在拉姆斯盖特和
莱姆湾之间的宽阔正面登陆40个师
The army at first wanted to land 40 divisions
on a wide front between Ramsgate and Lyme Bay,

178
00:15:08,685 --> 00:15:12,021
并推进至一条从埃塞克斯郡的马尔登
到塞文河口的战线,
and press on to a line from Maldon
in Essex to the Severn Estuary,

179
00:15:12,147 --> 00:15:14,190
把伦敦封锁起来
sealing off London.

180
00:15:14,274 --> 00:15:19,443
这个计划后来缩减到由9个陆军师
在福克斯通和布赖顿之间登陆,
This was later scaled down to a landing by
nine divisions between Folkestone and Brighton,

181
00:15:19,527 --> 00:15:21,697
并由两个空降师支援...
supported by two airborne divisions...

182
00:15:21,782 --> 00:15:24,325
总共约20万人
about 200,000 men in all.

183
00:15:24,451 --> 00:15:27,536
到了9月,英国已经克服先前的虚弱
By September, Britain had overcome
her earlier weakness

184
00:15:27,621 --> 00:15:31,999
并在东南方向准备了16个师
and had 16 divisions available
in the Southeast.

185
00:15:35,879 --> 00:15:40,841
从德国各地抽调来的一支
入侵舰队在北方港口集合
An invasion fleet drawn from all parts
of Germany assembled in northern ports.

186
00:15:43,300 --> 00:15:49,500
登陆舰被建造出来,船只被改装为
可以运输部队和(水陆)两栖坦克
Landing craft were built,and boats converted
to carry troops and amphibious tanks.

187
00:15:51,311 --> 00:15:54,021
陆军认为舰队规模太小
The army thought the fleet too small.

188
00:15:54,106 --> 00:15:57,400
海军认为甚至这种规模
的舰队都难以保护
The navy thought even that size fleet
difficult to protect.

189
00:15:57,484 --> 00:16:00,400
两者都同意拥有绝对制空权是至关重要的
Both agreed
that air supremacy was vital.

190
00:16:00,400 --> 00:16:04,949
这个代号为"海狮计划"的入侵行动,
被定在九月中旬开始
The invasion, codenamed Operation
Sea Lion, was set for mid-September.

191
00:16:05,033 --> 00:16:10,329
该计划没能给德国空军留下深刻印象,
而一切都得依靠他们
The plans did not impress the Luftwaffe,
on whom everything depended.

192
00:16:10,414 --> 00:16:13,666
在我看来,这个计划不太严肃
In my opinion,
the plan was not serious.

193
00:16:13,750 --> 00:16:21,048
(阿道夫·加兰德 空战英雄 后任德军战斗机总监)
尤其是海军不想承担责任,
Especially the navy didn't want
to have the responsibility,

194
00:16:21,133 --> 00:16:25,428
(阿道夫·加兰德 空战英雄 后任德军战斗机总监)
而海军已要求空军首先
and the navy has asked
the air force first of all

195
00:16:25,512 --> 00:16:33,477
在入侵地区上空建立起
绝对...绝对空中优势
to establish the absolute...the absolute
air superiority over the invasion area.

196
00:16:34,730 --> 00:16:39,066
海军所做的准备不是很令人信服
The preparation the navy did
was not very convincing.

197
00:16:39,151 --> 00:16:44,613
还有,我们的准备...
尤其是我所在的航空队被指派为
Also, our preparation...
My wing,especially,was designated to be

198
00:16:44,740 --> 00:16:48,868
要转移到英国的两个航空队之一,
one of the two wings
to be transferred to England,

199
00:16:48,952 --> 00:16:53,122
而我们的准备...是可笑的
and our preparations were... ridiculous.

200
00:16:53,665 --> 00:17:01,922
(德国)空军没有为在英国上空进行
一场独立的空战受训和做好准备
The air force was not trained and prepared to
conduct an independent air war over England.

201
00:17:08,700 --> 00:17:10,400
(加兰德的最终战果为击落104架)

202
00:17:14,186 --> 00:17:19,482
随着入侵舰队被集合,德国空军
的首批目标是商船队和港口,
As the invasion fleet assambled, the Luftwaffe's
first targets were merchant convoys and harbours,

203
00:17:19,566 --> 00:17:23,000
尤其是在(英吉利)海峡
的狭隘海域上的
particularly in the narrow
seas of the Channel.

204
00:17:24,112 --> 00:17:26,614
多佛开始被称为"地狱火之角"
Dover became known as Hellfire Corner.

205
00:17:26,698 --> 00:17:30,659
总有些什么可供新闻片镜头
或新闻记者报道...
There was always something for the
newsreel camera or the news reporter...

206
00:17:30,744 --> 00:17:34,330
比如,英国广播公司的查尔斯·加德纳:
for instance, Charles Gardner
of the BBC:

207
00:17:35,457 --> 00:17:39,794
现在德国人正在俯冲轰炸
海上的一支商船队
Now the Germans are
dive-bombing a convoy out at sea.

208
00:17:39,878 --> 00:17:42,797
有一,二,三,四,五,六,七(架飞机)
There are one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven.

209
00:17:42,881 --> 00:17:46,258
现在有一架正对着其目标俯冲
There's one going down
on its target now.

210
00:17:46,343 --> 00:17:48,886
嘭! 不,他错过了该船
他一艘船也没击中
Boom. No, he missed the ship,
he hasn't hit a single ship.

211
00:17:48,970 --> 00:17:53,800
这个船队中大约有10艘船,
但他还没击中过一艘
There are about ten ships in the convoy,
but he hasn't hit a single one.

212
00:17:53,900 --> 00:17:59,522
他们以极其陡峭的角度俯冲
你可以看到炸弹离开飞机 向我们飞来
Here they come in an extreme steep dive. You can see
the bombs actually leave the machines,and coming toward us.

213
00:17:59,606 --> 00:18:02,399
你可以听到我们自己的炮
正在拼命地开火
You can hear our own guns
going like anything now.

214
00:18:03,235 --> 00:18:07,029
有场战斗正在进行
你能听到机关枪子弹发射的声音
There's quite a fight going on. You can hear
the rattling of machine-gun bullets.

215
00:18:07,114 --> 00:18:09,400
那是枚炸弹,正如你所想象的
That was a bomb, as you may imagine.

216
00:18:10,158 --> 00:18:12,952
有另一颗炸弹掉下来了
There's another bomb dropping.

217
00:18:13,912 --> 00:18:16,205
它被投下了...它错过了船队
It's dropped... It missed the convoy.

218
00:18:16,289 --> 00:18:18,707
他们所投的炸弹无一命中船队
They haven't hit the convoy
in all this.

219
00:18:20,043 --> 00:18:23,003
我们刚击中了一架梅塞施密特战斗机!
真是太美妙了
We've just hit a Messerschmitt!
That was beautiful.

220
00:18:23,088 --> 00:18:28,467
现在他正在下坠 我想
那绝对是第一次搏斗
He's coming right down now. I think
definitely that was that first contest.

221
00:18:28,593 --> 00:18:32,221
绝对垂直的俯冲 我将四处
移动那样我能看清楚他
Absolute steep dive. I'll just move
round so I can watch him a bit more.

222
00:18:32,305 --> 00:18:35,266
他过来了 他要扎入海中了
Here he comes.
He's going slap into the sea.

223
00:18:35,350 --> 00:18:37,184
他就这么完了...嘭!
And there he goes... bam!

224
00:18:37,269 --> 00:18:40,396
哦,天!我从没见过这么好的事
Oh, boy! I've never seen
anything so good as this.

225
00:18:40,480 --> 00:18:44,000
皇家空军的战斗机真的捆住了这些小子们
The RAF fighters
have really got these boys taped.

226
00:18:46,987 --> 00:18:50,948
船队系统被中断了,象多佛
这样的港口被猛烈轰炸
The convoy system was disrupted,
and harbours like Dover were badly hit.

227
00:18:51,032 --> 00:18:53,450
但当城镇遭受(空袭)伤亡,
But while the town suffered casualties,

228
00:18:53,535 --> 00:18:57,746
道丁仍未被迫使用他全部的战斗机力量
Dowding had not yet been forced
to commit his full fighter strength.

229
00:18:57,831 --> 00:19:00,207
战斗机司令部的独特性
The unique thing about Fighter Command

230
00:19:00,292 --> 00:19:03,752
在于当战争在1939年9月爆发时...
was that when war broke out
in September 1939...

231
00:19:04,504 --> 00:19:10,676
我们就有一套覆盖全国的空防系统
we had there a system covering
the entire country for air defence.

232
00:19:10,760 --> 00:19:16,432
而那套系统基于雷达,
或者,就象我们在那些日子里称它的,RDF
And that system was based on radar,
or, as we called it in those days, RDF.

233
00:19:16,892 --> 00:19:20,102
我们沿着海岸有一条
由一长串雷达站组成的链条,
We had this chain of radar stations
around the coast,

234
00:19:20,187 --> 00:19:23,022
它们可以监测到最远100英里(的敌情)
and they were looking out
up to 100 miles.

235
00:19:23,106 --> 00:19:29,000
而且它们可以通过地面线路把
所有信息反馈到战斗机司令部
And they were feeding, on land lines,all the information
to the headquarters of Fighter Command.

236
00:19:30,280 --> 00:19:33,240
雷达真正赢得了不列颠战役
(Aitken) Radar really won
the Battle of Britain,

237
00:19:33,325 --> 00:19:37,578
因为没有它我们就得进行永久性巡逻...
because without it we would have been
doing standing patrols...

238
00:19:37,704 --> 00:19:42,917
而以有限数量的飞机和飞行员,
你是不可能做到那点的
and with the limited number of aircraft and the
limited number of pilots, you couldn't have done it.

239
00:19:43,001 --> 00:19:45,920
事实上,我们能等在地面,
As it was, we could wait on the ground,

240
00:19:46,004 --> 00:19:48,380
然后雷达会来观测
and then radar would watch.

241
00:19:48,465 --> 00:19:53,344
通过不同的控制(手段),
我们会被告知起飞
And through the various controls,
we would be told to take off

242
00:19:53,428 --> 00:19:58,474
当德国人在加莱或阿比尔上空集结时
at a time when the Germans were
massing over Calais or over Abbeville.

243
00:19:58,558 --> 00:20:04,146
所以这样我们就不用把时间和精力浪费在巡逻上...
And so, therefore, we wasted no petrol,
no time, no energy...

244
00:20:04,272 --> 00:20:08,317
事实上,我们还能在巡逻之间睡觉
in fact, we could sleep
in between patrols.

245
00:20:08,401 --> 00:20:13,239
然后我们起飞,我们会
被直接引向德国飞机编队,
And then we'd take off, and we would be
directed towards the German formation,

246
00:20:13,365 --> 00:20:18,035
根据高度,距离和他们的数量...
这是非常重要的
given height, distance and their
numbers... which was very important.

247
00:20:19,913 --> 00:20:23,415
8月13日,戈林改变了他的战术
On August 13,Göring changed his tactics.

248
00:20:23,541 --> 00:20:26,919
他下令攻击雷达站和战斗机机场,
He ordered an attack against radar
stations and fighter airfields,

249
00:20:27,003 --> 00:20:30,631
这些(目标)是战斗机司令部势必要防守的
which Fighter Command
was bound to defend.

250
00:20:33,093 --> 00:20:37,554
当德国轰炸机闪击守卫伦敦和东南部的机场,
While German bombers blitzed airfields
that defended London and the Southeast,

251
00:20:37,639 --> 00:20:43,936
(德国)护航战斗机会对付前来
攻击轰炸机的英国战斗机
escorting fighters dealt with British fighters
that came up to attack the bombers.

252
00:21:04,749 --> 00:21:08,711
在英国上空战斗把德国空军
置于一个不利地位
Fighting over England
put the Luftwaffe at a disadvantage.

253
00:21:08,795 --> 00:21:13,173
它被期望,却没被装备好,
独自赢得一场决定性战役
lt was expected, but not equipped,
to win a decisive battle alone.

254
00:21:16,261 --> 00:21:20,180
德国轰炸机没被设计成
可以携带足够重量的炸弹
The German bombers were not designed
to carry a heavy enough bomb load.

255
00:21:20,265 --> 00:21:24,893
德国战斗机带的燃料只够
在英国上空停留半小时,
German fighters had only enough fuel
to stay over England for half an hour,

256
00:21:24,978 --> 00:21:27,938
而英国战斗机,由于靠近他们的基地,
whereas the British fighters,
close to their bases,

257
00:21:28,023 --> 00:21:33,110
能够以足够快的速度降落并加油
来重新加入战斗
could land and refuel quickly enough
to rejoin the battle.

258
00:21:34,362 --> 00:21:36,447
我们的航程非常有限,
(Galland) Our range
was very very limited,

259
00:21:36,531 --> 00:21:40,576
我们只够覆盖英伦三岛
的一小片地区,
and we could only cover
a small part of the British islands,

260
00:21:40,660 --> 00:21:43,495
包括伦敦
including London.

261
00:21:43,580 --> 00:21:47,666
但在伦敦上空,比如说,
我们只能停留10分钟,
But over London, as an example,
we could only stay for ten minutes,

262
00:21:47,751 --> 00:21:49,918
就得返回我们的基地
to come back to our bases.

263
00:21:52,047 --> 00:21:58,177
所以我们战斗机和护航机
的这种有限航程
So this limited range
of our fighters and the escort

264
00:21:58,261 --> 00:22:11,231
或许是...没能对英国发动一场
有效的空中攻势的...主要原因
has been perhaps the... main point...which
avoided an effective air offensive against Britain.

265
00:22:12,692 --> 00:22:18,155
德国空军的情报把在第一轮攻击中对英国
机场造成的损害对其飞行员进行了误导
The Luftwaffe intelligence misled its pilots about the
damage done to British airfields in the first assault.

266
00:22:18,239 --> 00:22:21,075
他们宣称有8个(机场)实际上已被摧毁
They claimed eight
had been virtually destroyed.

267
00:22:21,159 --> 00:22:23,410
事实上,没有一个(机场)被毁坏,
ln fact, none had been knocked out,

268
00:22:23,495 --> 00:22:26,955
那些被损坏的机场很快就被修好
and those damaged
were quickly patched up again.

269
00:22:27,040 --> 00:22:30,918
德国飞行员,面对他们未曾预料到的抵抗,
The German pilots, faced
by resistance they hadn't expected,

270
00:22:31,002 --> 00:22:33,087
开始对取胜变得悲观起来
became pessimistic about
winning the battle.

271
00:22:33,171 --> 00:22:39,009
我们战斗机飞行员确信
我们不能赢得战斗
We fighting crews were convinced
that we couldn't win the battle

272
00:22:39,094 --> 00:22:52,064
我们不可能在陆军或海军不参加任何行动
的情况下独自攻击而迫使英国投降
and we couldn't force England to surrender by attacking
without any operation from the part of the army or the navy.

273
00:22:52,148 --> 00:22:56,235
所以,我们请求最高指挥部
Therefore, we were asking
that the High Command

274
00:22:56,319 --> 00:23:00,155
应该下令发动入侵(行动)...海狮
should order the invasion...
the Sea Lion.

275
00:23:02,033 --> 00:23:05,994
仅有1400名英国战斗机
飞行员和他们的地勤人员
A mere 1,400 British
fighter pilots and their ground crews

276
00:23:06,079 --> 00:23:08,580
保护英国不受入侵
stood between Britain and invasion.

277
00:23:08,665 --> 00:23:13,627
他们的责任很大...或许太大到不敢去想
Their responsibility was great... too
great, perhaps, to bear thinking about.

278
00:23:13,711 --> 00:23:16,839
他们展示给世界的面貌
是精神抖擞和无忧无虑的
The face they showed the world
was dashing and carefree.

279
00:23:16,923 --> 00:23:21,593
我想他们没把局势太当回事,
I think they took the situation
not the least bit seriously,

280
00:23:21,678 --> 00:23:24,096
基本上从他们的生活的角度来看
from the point of view
of their lives generally.

281
00:23:24,180 --> 00:23:27,599
一些家伙会踢会儿球或无所事事,
Some fellows would just
kick a ball around or lie around,

282
00:23:27,725 --> 00:23:34,022
一些则会睡觉,读读平装书,
听听电台...
some would sleep, read paperbacks,
listen to the radio...

283
00:23:34,107 --> 00:23:36,191
那就是我们的生活
and that was our life.

284
00:23:42,115 --> 00:23:46,118
我想打下一架飞机,
但我不想打下一个德国人
I wanted to shoot an plane down, but
I didn't want to shoot a German down.

285
00:23:46,202 --> 00:23:48,078
我真的不想
I really did not.

286
00:23:48,163 --> 00:23:53,625
我们听到了德国人向我们
跳了伞的伙计射击的故事,
We did hear stories of Germans
shooting our fellows in parachutes,

287
00:23:53,710 --> 00:23:56,462
我们当时觉得那挺可怕的,
and we used to think
that was pretty horrible,

288
00:23:56,546 --> 00:23:59,840
但我们不能肯定那是否是真实的
but we weren't sure
whether it was true or not.

289
00:23:59,924 --> 00:24:06,388
我知道我有过一次一个德国机组人员
挂在我自己的(飞机)机翼上的经历
I know I had an experience of a German
aircrew getting draped over my own wing.

290
00:24:06,473 --> 00:24:11,810
他跳出一架轰炸机 结果
把他的降落伞挂到了我的机翼上
He'd baled out of a bomber and got
caught on my wing with his parachute.

291
00:24:11,895 --> 00:24:17,149
我高兴地,尽可能容易和快速地把他弄下去,
I was jolly careful to get him off
as easily and as quickly as I could,

292
00:24:17,233 --> 00:24:20,110
通过(头尾)摆动飞机并把他抖下去
by yawing the aeroplane
and shaking him off.

293
00:24:20,195 --> 00:24:23,614
我要说在德国空军和英国空军之间
根本没有骑士精神
I say there was no chivalry at all between
the German air force and the British.

294
00:24:23,740 --> 00:24:27,493
绝对没有 就我而言没有 我恨他们
Absolutely none. Not as far as
l was concerned. I hated them.

295
00:24:27,577 --> 00:24:30,954
他们试图对我们做些什么...
他们试图把我们变成奴隶
They were trying to do something to us...
they were trying to enslave us.

296
00:24:55,146 --> 00:24:59,733
战役的高潮在八月底
和九月的第一周到来
The climax of the battle came at the end
of August,and the first week of September.

297
00:24:59,817 --> 00:25:04,404
希特勒发动入侵的决定将取决于(空战的)结果
Upon the result depended Hitler's
decision to launch his invasion.

298
00:25:04,489 --> 00:25:10,453
但空战本身是在双方的一群
相对少数的人之间进行的
But the air battle itself was between a comparative
handful of individuals on either side.

299
00:25:20,755 --> 00:25:23,715
空战比较不同寻常,
(Aitken) The fights
were rather extraordinary,

300
00:25:23,800 --> 00:25:26,552
因为尽管有很多飞机,
because although there were
a lot of aircraft about,

301
00:25:26,678 --> 00:25:31,682
突然,当你在跟一个特定的人交战,
天空就变空了
suddenly, when you were fighting
a particular man, the sky became empty.

302
00:25:38,982 --> 00:25:42,109
我想没人会去考虑
他可能会被杀
I don't think anyone ever considered
that he would be killed.

303
00:25:42,193 --> 00:25:46,405
死亡是被置于脑后的事
Death was something which was
just put at the back of your mind.

304
00:25:46,489 --> 00:25:51,326
如果不是这样,你会对此
焦躁不安,并非常担心
If it was not, you'd have just got the
jitters about it and been very worried.

305
00:25:51,869 --> 00:25:56,873
如果一个伙计失踪了,这只是,
"可怜的老某某,他报销了,"
If a fellow did go missing, it was just,
"Poor old so-and-so, he's had it,"

306
00:25:56,958 --> 00:25:59,001
就是那样
and that was that.

307
00:26:01,921 --> 00:26:06,800
在内心,当然,如果你失去了一个弟兄
你为感到非常难过
Inwardly, of course, you'd feel it
tremendously if you lost a pal.

308
00:26:06,884 --> 00:26:11,305
但你不会...你根本不会
老是想着死亡的问题
But you didn't... you didn't
dwell on the subject of death at all.

309
00:26:11,389 --> 00:26:16,435
有时候你能看出来是否一个伙计将会被杀
是的 你能 他会有点控制不住情绪
Sometimes you could tell if a fellow was going to get
killed, yes,you could. He sort of lost it,you know.

310
00:26:16,600 --> 00:26:18,500
(飞行员飞行日志)

311
00:26:18,771 --> 00:26:22,858
(查尔斯·李·斯蒂尔阵亡)
我最好的朋友被杀了
他正在向一架梅塞施密特战斗机开火,
My greatest friend was killed.
He was shooting at a Messerschmitt,

312
00:26:22,942 --> 00:26:25,652
而另一架梅塞施密特从后面击中了他
and another Messerschmitt
hit him from behind.

313
00:26:25,778 --> 00:26:30,157
当时我正向他大喊,但你什么也做不了...
你只能看着他坠落
l was shouting at him, and you couldn't
do anything... and you saw him go in.

314
00:26:30,241 --> 00:26:33,410
那会影响你,但你不得不继续
That affected you,
but you had to get on with it.

315
00:26:33,494 --> 00:26:37,831
你的朋友会深深地影响你
很可怕 但你对此无能为力
Your friends affected you deeply.
Terrible. But you couldn't help it.

316
00:26:38,000 --> 00:26:39,700
(吉拉德·克斯伯特阵亡)

317
00:26:39,700 --> 00:26:41,252
(迈克尔·多尔顿阵亡)

318
00:26:41,252 --> 00:26:44,713
(比利·费斯克阵亡)
在八月的最后一周和九月的第一周,
In the last week of August
and the first week of September,

319
00:26:44,797 --> 00:26:48,258
103名战斗机司令部的飞行员阵亡
103 of Fighter Command's pilots died.

320
00:26:48,343 --> 00:26:51,720
128人严重受伤
128 were seriously wounded.

321
00:26:53,723 --> 00:26:58,435
东南部六个关键机场一度被瘫痪几天
Six key airfields in the Southeast were
put out of action for days at a time.

322
00:26:58,519 --> 00:27:00,812
为了对付德国战斗机和轰炸机,
Against German fighters and bombers,

323
00:27:00,897 --> 00:27:04,066
英国现在损失战斗机的速度
甚至比德国还快...
Britain was now losing fighters
even faster than Germany...

324
00:27:04,150 --> 00:27:06,234
两周里(损失)差不多500架
nearly 500 in two weeks.

325
00:27:07,862 --> 00:27:11,114
八月的最后一周和九月的第一周...
The last week in August,
the first week in September...

326
00:27:11,199 --> 00:27:14,660
那两周对我们来说是最糟糕的,
those two weeks were the worst for us,

327
00:27:14,744 --> 00:27:18,080
因为到了八月的最后一周,
because by that last week in August,

328
00:27:18,164 --> 00:27:22,292
德国人已经在无情地轰击机场,
the Germans had been pounding
the airfields mercilessly,

329
00:27:22,377 --> 00:27:28,006
8月31日可能是我们最糟的一天
and 31 August was probably our worst day.

330
00:27:28,091 --> 00:27:31,259
战斗机司令部几乎要跪地认输了
Fighter Command
was very nearly on its knees.

331
00:27:31,344 --> 00:27:33,845
道丁非常清楚地意识到那一点
Dowding was very conscious of that.

332
00:27:33,971 --> 00:27:37,391
令他担心的是对机场的不断轰击,
And this is what was worrying him was
the constant pounding of the airfields,

333
00:27:37,475 --> 00:27:41,770
他不知道他还能坚持多久...
and he was wondering
how much longer he could hold out...

334
00:27:41,854 --> 00:27:44,314
我说的"他",是指战斗机司令部
when I say "he",
l mean Fighter Command.

335
00:27:44,399 --> 00:27:50,070
因为他仍不得不面对那个拒绝
给予德国人空中优势的大问题,
Because he was still having to face that big problem
of denying the Germans air superiority,

336
00:27:50,196 --> 00:27:52,698
但他们正在把机场炸成碎片,
and yet they were
knocking airfields to pieces,

337
00:27:52,782 --> 00:27:55,367
战斗机司令部也有因此而被击溃的危险
with the threat of
knocking out Fighter Command.

338
00:27:55,451 --> 00:27:59,913
9月6日,国王和王后访问了战斗机司令部,
On 6 September, the king and queen
visited Fighter Command,

339
00:27:59,997 --> 00:28:06,795
有许多人对道丁看起来有多累发表评论
and there were quite a few people who commented
on how tired Dowding appeared to be.

340
00:28:06,879 --> 00:28:10,632
之后那天,9月7日,
The day after, 7 September,

341
00:28:10,717 --> 00:28:16,513
一份入侵警报被发出...
"入侵迫在眉睫"...
when an invasion alert was issued...
"invasion imminent"...

342
00:28:16,639 --> 00:28:19,975
那天一整天都非常安静
and all that day
things were remarkably quiet.

343
00:28:20,059 --> 00:28:24,146
我们所有人都开始琢磨
接下来到底会发生什么
All of us were beginning to wonder
what the devil was going to happen next.

344
00:28:24,230 --> 00:28:27,774
然后,在下午晚些时候,
德国人发动了
And then, late afternoon,
the Germans launched

345
00:28:27,900 --> 00:28:32,904
许多不得不在空中面对这场袭击的飞行员
what many of the pilots who in the air
having to face this onslaught

346
00:28:32,989 --> 00:28:36,658
发现这是据他们所知的最猛烈的一次攻击
found to be just about the heaviest
attack they'd ever known.

347
00:28:36,743 --> 00:28:41,246
然后发生了道丁后来
描述为"奇迹"的事...
And then came what Dowding
later described as "the miracle"...

348
00:28:41,330 --> 00:28:45,292
攻击没有对着机场而去,
而是去了伦敦
the attack didn't go to the airfields,
it went to London,

349
00:28:45,376 --> 00:28:47,586
机场被放过了
and the airfields were spared.

350
00:28:47,670 --> 00:28:49,796
5点缺5分,
Five minutes to five,

351
00:28:49,881 --> 00:28:52,132
警报响了
the sirens went.

352
00:28:52,216 --> 00:28:57,262
我出来走到阳台上,
俯视着河流,
Walking out onto my veranda,
looking down the river,

353
00:28:57,388 --> 00:28:59,806
天空中布满飞机
the sky was full of planes.

354
00:28:59,891 --> 00:29:05,312
没过两分钟,炸弹就开始落在米尔沃码头上,
Within a couple of minutes, the bombs
started dropping in the Millwall Dock,

355
00:29:05,396 --> 00:29:07,981
而我能看到它们
and I could watch 'em.

356
00:29:08,065 --> 00:29:10,442
这持续很长一段时间
And it went on
for some considerable time.

357
00:29:10,568 --> 00:29:14,196
在那个第一个周六,
他们事实上彻底毁了
On that first Saturday,
they practically obliterated

358
00:29:14,280 --> 00:29:18,200
从银镇道到银镇(的那片地区)
from the Silvertown Way to Silvertown.

359
00:29:18,284 --> 00:29:22,078
事实上,整个潮水坞,海关大楼,
As a matter of fact, the whole of
the Tidal Basin, Custom House,

360
00:29:22,163 --> 00:29:26,166
直到银镇(那一段)全被炸毁了...
不用有任何疑问
right up to Silvertown was obliterated...
make no mistake about it.

361
00:29:27,293 --> 00:29:30,170
要是那种轰炸继续下去,
lf it had continued,
that type of bombing,

362
00:29:30,254 --> 00:29:32,005
在白天(轰炸的话)...
in the daylight...

363
00:29:32,089 --> 00:29:35,550
它会攻击一切重要的目标...
lt was hitting everything
of consequence...

364
00:29:35,635 --> 00:29:39,638
船坞,煤气厂,
shipyards, gasworks,

365
00:29:39,722 --> 00:29:43,517
炼油厂,一切重要的目标
oil firms, everything of consequence.

366
00:29:43,601 --> 00:29:47,729
几乎所有的炸弹都落在目标区域
Nearly all the bombs were dropping
in the proper target area.

367
00:29:48,940 --> 00:29:52,192
那晚,250架轰炸机又来了...
That night,
250 bombers returned...

368
00:29:52,276 --> 00:29:55,487
燃烧的码头和仓库是不会弄错的标记
the burning docks and warehouses
an unmistakable marker.

369
00:29:55,571 --> 00:29:59,032
但戈林战术的改变缓解了压力
But Göring's change of tactics
relieved the pressure.

370
00:30:04,330 --> 00:30:07,958
战斗机司令部重整了
伦敦着火了
Fighter Command regrouped.
London burned.

371
00:30:33,484 --> 00:30:36,820
在9月7日的空袭后,
许多救援工作者和消防员
After the raid on September 7,
many rescue workers and firemen

372
00:30:36,904 --> 00:30:39,489
不停地工作了40个小时
worked 40 hours nonstop.

373
00:30:39,574 --> 00:30:42,951
"我们大多数人已夜以继日地工作,"
他们中的一个说道,
"Most of us had the wind up
to start with," one of them said,

374
00:30:43,035 --> 00:30:46,496
"但你看看周围
就能看到其他人都在干他们的活"
"but you looked around
and saw the rest doing their job."

375
00:31:06,142 --> 00:31:10,395
9月15日,德国空军发动了
另一次大规模日间空袭,
On September 15, the Luftwaffe
mounted another major daylight attack,

376
00:31:10,479 --> 00:31:12,000
预期不会受到抵抗
expecting no opposition.

377
00:31:12,000 --> 00:31:16,359
但这一次"喷火"式和"飓风"式
战斗机正在等他们
But this time the Spitfires and
Hurricanes were waiting for them.

378
00:32:10,873 --> 00:32:15,794
在那天,9月15日,
56架德国飞机被击落
On that day, September 15,
56 German planes were shot down.

379
00:32:16,420 --> 00:32:19,673
英国保住了白天的制空权
Britain had retained
command of the air by day.

380
00:32:23,511 --> 00:32:27,097
皇家空军已经赢得了不列颠之战
The Royal Air Force
had won the Battle of Britain.

381
00:32:41,070 --> 00:32:43,697
1940年9月
September 1940.

382
00:32:43,781 --> 00:32:45,865
现在不再有白天的空袭,
Now there were no more daylight raids,

383
00:32:45,950 --> 00:32:48,868
而且在春天前不可能有入侵
and there could be no invasion
before the spring.

384
00:32:48,953 --> 00:32:53,206
但英国的城市成为夜间轰炸机的目标
But Britain's cities became targets
for the night bombers.

385
00:32:53,290 --> 00:32:57,335
连着76个夜晚,伦敦遭受了轰炸
For 76 nights in succession,
London was bombed.

386
00:32:57,420 --> 00:33:00,700
在黄昏排队进防空洞
成为一个整齐的仪式,
Queuing for shelter at dusk
became an orderly ritual,

387
00:33:00,700 --> 00:33:06,386
夜晚的警报,黎明的解除警报,
成为伦敦人生活的一部分
the evening alerts, the dawn all-clear,
part of Londoners' lives.

388
00:34:12,203 --> 00:34:14,579
我听到这些飞机过来,
I used to hear the planes come over,

389
00:34:14,663 --> 00:34:19,209
在我看来,他们是要炸断房子的脊梁
and they was, in my opinion,
trying to break the backs of the houses.

390
00:34:19,293 --> 00:34:21,961
我会听着并颤栗发抖
"下一颗是我的"
I'd listen and shudder.
"The next one's mine."

391
00:34:22,046 --> 00:34:27,175
它们会有,比方说,六枚炸弹
"一,二,三,四...这枚是我的"
They'd have, say, six bombs.
"One, two, three, four... This is mine."

392
00:34:27,259 --> 00:34:30,386
"不" 扔完了下一枚,他们走了,
错过了我的房子
"No." Over the next one, they'd go,
and miss my house.

393
00:34:30,471 --> 00:34:32,222
那持续了整个夜晚
And that used to go on all night.

394
00:34:32,306 --> 00:34:37,268
大约缺10分到8点,我对我妻子
和岳父母说,"我要走了"
About ten to eight, I said to my wife
and my in-laws, "Well,I'll be off now."

395
00:34:37,353 --> 00:34:42,273
我走出门...它们是可爱的三层大房屋
And I just walked out of the door...
lovely big three-floor houses they were.

396
00:34:42,358 --> 00:34:48,154
我刚走上阿泼罗奇路,离教堂大概20英尺远,
那里是他们的岗位,
And I just walked up Approach Road, about
20 yards from the church, which was their post,

397
00:34:48,239 --> 00:34:50,990
突然一声....
and suddenly there was a...

398
00:34:51,075 --> 00:34:53,201
听不到,我什么都没听到
Nothing, I heard nothing.

399
00:34:53,285 --> 00:34:56,287
后来我和人们谈论起这事...
l talked about this
to people afterwards...

400
00:34:56,372 --> 00:34:58,790
击中他们的炸弹,他们从没听到
and the bomb that hit them,
they never heard.

401
00:34:58,874 --> 00:35:02,919
我不知道现在坐在这里
的人是否有相同的经历
Now, I wonder if the people sitting
here now had that same experience.

402
00:35:03,003 --> 00:35:05,505
那枚击中你的炸弹,你是听不到的
The bomb that hit you, you never heard.

403
00:35:05,589 --> 00:35:07,465
我脸朝下卧倒在地
And I fell flat on my face.

404
00:35:07,550 --> 00:35:09,634
我自己起身,我转过身
l picked myself up, I turned round.

405
00:35:09,760 --> 00:35:14,472
我所能看到的是一团灰幕悬浮
在一条宽阔马路的中央...
All I could see was just a grey curtain
hanging down in the middle of a wide road...

406
00:35:14,557 --> 00:35:17,350
大概有这个酒吧的两倍这么宽
about twice as wide as this pub.

407
00:35:17,434 --> 00:35:20,520
只有一团棕灰色的幕悬在那儿
There was just a brownish-grey
curtain hanging there.

408
00:35:21,647 --> 00:35:23,773
♪ 来吧,来吧
♪ Come, come

409
00:35:23,858 --> 00:35:25,733
♪ 来和我眉目传情
♪ Come and make eyes at me

410
00:35:25,818 --> 00:35:28,111
♪ 就在"老牛和灌木丛"
♪ Down at the Old Bull and Bush

411
00:35:28,195 --> 00:35:29,863
♪ 啦啦啦, 啦啦
♪ La-la-la, la-la

412
00:35:29,947 --> 00:35:31,739
♪ 来吧, 来吧
♪ Come, come

413
00:35:31,824 --> 00:35:33,741
♪ 和我喝些葡萄酒
♪ Drink some port wine with me

414
00:35:33,826 --> 00:35:36,494
♪ 就在"老牛和灌木丛"
♪ Down at the Old Bull and Bush

415
00:35:37,580 --> 00:35:41,416
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦,啦啦啦啦啦啦啦
♪ La-la-la-la-la-la,
la-la-la-la-la-la-la

416
00:35:41,500 --> 00:35:45,044
♪ 就让我握住你的手,亲爱的
♪ Just let me hold your hand, dear

417
00:35:45,546 --> 00:35:47,255
♪ 嘟, 嘟
♪ Do, do

418
00:35:47,381 --> 00:35:49,174
♪ 来喝上一两杯
♪ Come and have a drink or two

419
00:35:49,258 --> 00:35:52,552
♪ 就在"老牛和灌木丛",
灌木丛,灌木丛,灌木丛!
♪ Down at the Old Bull and Bush,
Bush, Bush!

420
00:35:53,095 --> 00:35:55,180
不管你走进哪个防空洞,
No matter what shelter
you went in,

421
00:35:55,264 --> 00:36:00,602
那里总有人会提供娱乐
there was always someone there
who would provide the entertainment

422
00:36:00,728 --> 00:36:03,396
来舒缓紧张
to sort of take away the strain.

423
00:36:04,398 --> 00:36:09,319
(当局)作出决定,地铁站一定不能被用作防空洞
Underground stations, it was decided,
must not be used as shelters.

424
00:36:09,403 --> 00:36:13,990
但人们只是简单地接管了它们
当局也只好接受这个事实
But people simply took them over
and the authorities had to accept it.

425
00:36:14,658 --> 00:36:16,242
我们都在唱歌,
We was all singing,

426
00:36:16,327 --> 00:36:19,287
我们都很开心...
就好象根本没有战争一样
we was all happy...
just like there was no war at all.

427
00:36:19,371 --> 00:36:20,622
那里有一个餐厅
There was a canteen there.

428
00:36:20,706 --> 00:36:25,001
当轰炸进行时
我还为人们唱歌 让人们高兴起来
I used to sing as well for the people and
cheer people up when the bombs was going.

429
00:36:25,085 --> 00:36:29,964
直到有一晚,那晚真的很糟 我就在轰炸
现场的下面 祈祷大炮开始(开火)
Until one night, it was very bad, and l was just
under the scene and praying for the big guns to start.

430
00:36:34,803 --> 00:36:39,891
我在和一个驻扎在海德公园里
的(高射)炮兵中士交谈,
l was talking to a gunnery sergeant
who had been stationed in Hyde Park,

431
00:36:39,975 --> 00:36:44,562
他毫不犹豫地告诉我们...
而且当他告诉我们时他哭了:
and he told us without any hesitation...
and he cried when he told us:

432
00:36:44,647 --> 00:36:47,523
他说,"相信我,当我们被送进伦敦,
He said,"Believe me, when
we was sent into London,

433
00:36:47,608 --> 00:36:51,402
我们只是把我们的炮口抬到最高并开火"
we simply elevated our guns
to its maximum and fired."

434
00:36:51,528 --> 00:36:55,490
我们知道我们打出去的每发炮弹
都没有机会打中飞机,
"We knew that every shell we pumped up
had no chance of hitting a plane,

435
00:36:55,616 --> 00:36:58,826
但不要告诉我这没有给你们勇气."
but don't tell me
it didn't give you courage."

436
00:36:58,911 --> 00:37:03,373
坐在这张桌子周围的人里没一个人,
我想,能说这没有(给他勇气)...
And there's not a person sitting round
this table, I think, can say it didn't...

437
00:37:03,457 --> 00:37:07,460
一旦他们听到那些炮开火,
他们会想,"好,现在我们已经打中它们了"
once they heard those guns firing,
they thought, "Good, we've got 'em now."

438
00:37:07,544 --> 00:37:11,506
但他们知道那只是(在鼓舞)士气...
而且它对他们起的作用也仅此而已
But they only knew that it was the
morale... and that's all it did to 'em.

439
00:37:11,590 --> 00:37:15,760
但炸弹还是一定会掉下来
没有什么东西能阻止它们
But the bombs just had to come down.
There was nothing to stop them.

440
00:37:27,273 --> 00:37:28,940
连着76个早晨,
For 76 mornings,

441
00:37:29,024 --> 00:37:32,360
救援队在瓦砾里挖掘,搜寻幸存者
rescue squads dug through rubble,
searching for survivors.

442
00:37:32,444 --> 00:37:37,365
一枚炸弹掉在一幢大约
有四层高的公寓楼上,
A bomb dropped on a block
of flats, about four storeys,

443
00:37:37,449 --> 00:37:39,909
并把整个前半部炸掉了
and it took the whole front out.

444
00:37:39,994 --> 00:37:43,788
他们说,"上面还有个老家伙呢
他不肯去防空洞"
And they said, "There's an old chap
up there. He won't go in a shelter."

445
00:37:43,872 --> 00:37:47,917
所以我们跑上去,当我们到了那儿,
那老家伙正鼾声如雷,
So we go up, and when we got up there,
the old chap was snoring his head off,

446
00:37:48,002 --> 00:37:53,172
床周围大概有20个空酒瓶,
而床几乎快掉到大街上!
about 20 empty bottles round his bed,
and the bed's nearly out in the street!

447
00:37:53,257 --> 00:37:55,842
而他那时还没醒过来!
And he never woke up then!

448
00:38:00,848 --> 00:38:06,144
我们看见一位老妇人步履蹒跚,
我们说,"您一定得出来"
We saw an old lady staggering around,
and we said, "You'll have to come out."

449
00:38:06,228 --> 00:38:11,733
她出来了 身上穿得只有
半件应该是睡衣的衣服
She came out and all she had on was
half of what should've been a nightdress.

450
00:38:12,359 --> 00:38:16,195
我说,"不 您得穿上些衣服,让您看起来体面一点"
l said, "No.You'll have to put something
on, make yourself a bit decent."

451
00:38:16,280 --> 00:38:19,907
她大概有80多岁了,
完全处于一片茫然之中
She was about 80-odd,
and she was completely in a daze.

452
00:38:20,034 --> 00:38:24,200
她说,"我去穿些什么,"
她出来后头上戴了顶帽子!
She said, "l'll go and get something,"
and she came out with her hat on!

453
00:38:31,628 --> 00:38:35,590
人们去上班的时候总会
经过由被炸翻的公共汽车,
People somehow got to work
through a nightmare of upended buses,

454
00:38:35,674 --> 00:38:38,760
满是弹坑的马路,
被炸坏的铁路组成的恶梦
cratered roads, bombed railways.

455
00:38:38,844 --> 00:38:41,220
伦敦报道...
London calling...

456
00:38:41,305 --> 00:38:46,017
电台记者告诉美国和世界
伦敦能承受住轰炸
Radio reporters told America
and the world that London could take it.

457
00:38:46,101 --> 00:38:48,770
伦敦人的精神赢得了同情和帮助
The spirit of Londoners
won sympathy and help.

458
00:38:48,854 --> 00:38:51,898
但美国仍保持中立
But the United States remained neutral.

459
00:38:52,900 --> 00:38:57,737
当英国在1940年9月到1941年5月
独自抵抗(德国)期间,
While Britain stood alone,
from September 1940 to May 1941,

460
00:38:57,821 --> 00:39:02,283
四万人死于空袭...其中一半是伦敦人
40,000 people were killed in raids...
half of them Londoners.

461
00:39:03,786 --> 00:39:06,412
成千上万的人无家可归,
Hundreds of thousands of people
were homeless,

462
00:39:06,497 --> 00:39:10,083
只能在休息中心里吃,住,睡
eating, living,
sleeping in rest centres.

463
00:39:11,585 --> 00:39:15,004
衣服和其他一切都已
和他们的家一起消失
Clothing and everything else
had vanished with their home.

464
00:39:15,089 --> 00:39:16,881
但是士气没有
But not morale.

465
00:39:16,965 --> 00:39:21,552
为了要干净,你不太可能说,
"我今天要洗个澡,"
To be clean, you couldn't very well say,
"l'm going to have a bath today,"

466
00:39:21,637 --> 00:39:25,598
因为你害怕洗到一半警报会拉响
cos you was afraid the warning
would go halfway through it.

467
00:39:25,682 --> 00:39:29,977
所以你会用一碗水,洗一下
或许把你的脖子洗干净,
So you'd have a bowl of water, have
a wash and perhaps get your neck done,

468
00:39:30,062 --> 00:39:32,563
然后就跑路 并把你所有
的东西搬进防空洞...
and run and take all your things
in the shelter...

469
00:39:32,648 --> 00:39:34,732
或许在第二天洗完你的澡
finish your bath perhaps the next day.

470
00:39:34,817 --> 00:39:38,778
事实上从没洗过一个痛快的澡
只能跑进跑出
Never actually have a bath properly.
Step in and step out.

471
00:39:38,862 --> 00:39:42,281
你对此习惯了 你能习惯任何事
You get used to it.
You can get used to anything.

472
00:39:42,366 --> 00:39:49,205
看到这样的场景并非罕见:
"没有窗户 但有足够的精神"
lt was not an uncommon sight to see:
"No windows but plenty of spirit."

473
00:39:49,289 --> 00:39:53,876
或者,"抱歉我们没前门了
不必敲门了,直接进来吧"
Or, "Sorry we've got no front door.
Don't trouble to knock, just come in."

474
00:39:53,961 --> 00:39:57,200
你会看到这些好笑的小提示贴在门外
And you'd see these funny little notices
put up outside a door.

475
00:39:57,300 --> 00:40:01,968
这是让你觉得有些什么(精神)
在其中的事情
This was the sort of thing that really
made you think there was something in it.

476
00:40:02,052 --> 00:40:06,097
你见得越多,你就越感到受到鼓舞能够走出去
And the more you saw it, the more you felt
encouraged to be able to go out.

477
00:40:06,181 --> 00:40:12,000
你知道一旦你出门去上班,
把你的家人留在家里,
And you know that,once you'd gone out to go on
to a job and your family were left behind,

478
00:40:12,000 --> 00:40:14,188
你多少总觉得:
you always felt that somehow:

479
00:40:14,273 --> 00:40:16,357
"路那头的琼斯家或史密斯家,
"The Joneses or the Smiths up the road,

480
00:40:16,442 --> 00:40:20,736
如果家里出来什么事,
他们会照顾他们的"
if anything happens at home,
they'll look after 'em."

481
00:40:24,616 --> 00:40:28,453
工厂继续夜以继日地生产
Factories went on working,
by night as well as by day.

482
00:40:28,537 --> 00:40:32,081
但夜班工人的工作不断地被空袭打断
But night workers were
constantly interrupted by raids.

483
00:40:32,166 --> 00:40:36,711
没有对付德国夜间轰炸
的真正防御措施
There was no real defence
against German bombing at night.

484
00:40:36,795 --> 00:40:40,840
战斗机司令部对此的无能为力
令其指挥官道丁感到忧虑
Fighter Command's helplessness
worried its chief, Dowding.

485
00:40:40,924 --> 00:40:45,428
有一次我和他一起去红山,
正好有群(德国)轰炸机正奔赴伦敦
I once went down to Redhill with him
when the bombers were coming over London.

486
00:40:45,554 --> 00:40:50,308
那里有一个飞行中队 由一个
叫吉米·立特尔的伙计指挥
There was a squadron down there,
commanded by a fellow called Jimmy Little.

487
00:40:50,392 --> 00:40:55,897
他在车里对我说,他说,
"亲爱的麦克斯,我把手捂住我的脑袋
And he said to me in the car going down,
he said,"Dear Max, I hold my head in my hands

488
00:40:55,981 --> 00:41:01,277
一想到人民正在被炸,而我
却什么都做不了的可怕情景"
at the horrible thought of people being
bombed and I cannot do anything about it."

489
00:41:01,361 --> 00:41:03,821
令当局松了口气的是,
To the relief
of the authorities,

490
00:41:03,906 --> 00:41:07,450
白金汉宫也和东伦敦一样被炸了
Buckingham Palace was bombed
as well as East London.

491
00:41:07,534 --> 00:41:12,079
现在这似乎可被视为国王,王后
和人民在一起共赴国难
Now it could be seen that king, queen
and people were all in it together.

492
00:41:14,200 --> 00:41:19,295
通过那次巡视被轰炸地区
乔治(六世)国王和伊丽莎白王后赢得了尊重
King George and Queen Elizabeth won
respect by that tours of the blitzed areas.

493
00:41:19,379 --> 00:41:23,799
他们是在温莎公爵(不爱江山爱美人)
逊位后才登上王位的
They had come to the throne in the shuffling
circumstances of the Duke of Windsor's abdication.

494
00:41:23,884 --> 00:41:28,554
现在,他们第一次凭他们本身的头衔
成为了受欢迎的公众人物
Now, for the first time, they emerged
as popular figures in their own right.

495
00:41:31,808 --> 00:41:35,811
丘吉尔也以感情洋溢的言语
说服大多数政治对手
Churchill too, with exuberance,
persuaded most political opponents

496
00:41:35,896 --> 00:41:38,105
忘记他的过去
to forget his past.

497
00:41:38,190 --> 00:41:42,026
东伦敦的普通人压根就不在乎温斯顿·丘吉尔,
The average East Londoner didn't care
twopence for Winston Churchill,

498
00:41:42,110 --> 00:41:43,903
无论是作为一个人还是作为一个政治家,
as a man or a politician,

499
00:41:43,987 --> 00:41:48,074
但顶替张伯伦位子的那个人,
but the man who filled up
Chamberlain's place,

500
00:41:48,158 --> 00:41:50,701
他是个领袖 不用怀疑
他是个领袖
he was a leader,no doubt of that,
he was a leader.

501
00:41:50,786 --> 00:41:55,414
我想每次他开口,他都会把信心灌输给人民...
And I think every time he opened his mouth,
he inspired confidence into the people...

502
00:41:55,499 --> 00:41:58,292
无论他们是否 作为
一个保守党政客接受他...
whether they accepted him
as a Conservative...

503
00:41:58,377 --> 00:42:03,297
但他在那里,他支持他们,
而且他在对抗共同的敌人
But he was there, he was for 'em,
and he was against the common enemy.

504
00:42:05,884 --> 00:42:09,595
但有时候他得到的反响不一
But sometimes
he got a mixed reception.

505
00:42:09,680 --> 00:42:12,515
我记得,就在格林大道外,
I remember,just off Green Street,

506
00:42:12,599 --> 00:42:15,226
丘吉尔来到了这条街
an avenue where Churchill
came down.

507
00:42:15,310 --> 00:42:18,980
有一个和这个酒吧
一样大的巨大的弹坑
There was a devil of a great crater
as big as this pub.

508
00:42:19,064 --> 00:42:23,776
有成群的妇女正试图把她们
零零碎碎的东西搬出被炸坏的房子
And there were crowds of women trying to get
their bits and pieces out of the shattered houses.

509
00:42:24,653 --> 00:42:29,699
丘吉尔,在四处巡视后,
他说,"我们能承受这个"
And Churchill, after having a look
round, he said, "We can take it."

510
00:42:29,783 --> 00:42:34,787
那些妇女们用显而易见的态度
告诉他她们能承受什么,你要相信我
And the women told him what they could take,
in no unmistakable manner,you believe me.

511
00:42:34,871 --> 00:42:39,292
她们说,"我们才是承受这(一切)的人...
先生,你又没有危险的"
And they said, "We're the ones that are taking
it... Mister, you're out of the way."

512
00:42:50,429 --> 00:42:53,514
1940年12月29日
December 29, 1940.

513
00:42:53,599 --> 00:42:59,478
德国飞机撒下的燃烧弹
在伦敦城燃起熊熊大火
German planes scattering incendiary
bombs set the City of London ablaze.

514
00:42:59,563 --> 00:43:03,274
在城内和四周有1500个着火点
There were 1,500 fires
in and around the city.

515
00:43:03,358 --> 00:43:07,486
圣保罗大教堂被火包围
St Paul's Cathedral
was surrounded by fire.

516
00:43:10,907 --> 00:43:13,300
你能看到伦敦的大火
You could see the fire of London.

517
00:43:14,202 --> 00:43:17,788
你在60英里以外就能看见,
你能看见大火
You could see 60 miles away,
you could see the fire.

518
00:43:24,212 --> 00:43:28,466
大火燃烧的那个夜晚我在一个
防空洞里,火就在我头上燃烧
That night when the fire was burning,I was
in a shelter,and it was burning above me.

519
00:43:28,550 --> 00:43:32,136
我们都不得不出来,
但我们一点都不恐慌
and we all had to get out,
and we wasn't panicking a bit.

520
00:43:32,220 --> 00:43:36,682
我们不得不跑到商业街的尽头,
And we had to run...from the middle of
turn,to the top of Commercial Road,

521
00:43:36,767 --> 00:43:40,227
去一家在地下室下面有个防空洞的工厂
to a factory where had a shelter
down below in the basement.

522
00:43:40,312 --> 00:43:43,773
当我们沿路奔跑的时候,
四周都有火燃烧
And as we were running along,
there was fires all burning around.

523
00:43:43,857 --> 00:43:47,526
我能感受到地面的热度...
雨水坑都是烫的
l could feel the hot on the floor...
the puddles were hot.

524
00:43:47,653 --> 00:43:52,156
当我们进了防空洞里,我们站了一整夜,
靠在彼此的肩膀上睡觉
And when we got into the shelter, we stood
all night,sleeping on each other's shoulders.

525
00:43:52,240 --> 00:43:55,500
我站了一整夜,靠着其他人的肩膀睡觉
I stood all night sleeping
on somebody else's shoulder.

526
00:44:01,583 --> 00:44:06,337
最后,我们用了如此多的水,
以至于我们把水都用光了
Eventually, we used so much
water, we ran out of it.

527
00:44:06,421 --> 00:44:09,715
我们就站在那里,让火燃烧...
And there we stood,
letting the fires burn...

528
00:44:09,800 --> 00:44:13,302
而我们对此无能为力
and we couldn't do nothing about it.

529
00:44:20,102 --> 00:44:23,312
伦敦市中心被摧毁了,
The heart of the City
of London was destroyed,

530
00:44:23,397 --> 00:44:26,065
但圣保罗(大教堂)幸存了下来
but St Paul's survived.

531
00:44:27,600 --> 00:44:31,779
曼彻斯特,考文垂,伯明翰,
斯旺西,利物浦和更多的(城市)
Manchester, Coventry, Birmingham,
Swansea, Liverpool and many more

532
00:44:31,863 --> 00:44:33,400
分享了伦敦的苦难...
shared London's ordeal...

533
00:44:33,400 --> 00:44:38,119
所有这些城市都在以法国和低地国家(荷兰,比利时)
为基地的德国空军的打击范围之内,
all were within reach of the German air force,
with bases in France and the Low Countries.

534
00:44:38,203 --> 00:44:42,373
对英国轰炸机来说 要飞到
德国城市更加困难了
lt was more difficult for British
bombers to reach German cities.

535
00:44:42,457 --> 00:44:48,295
政府找了一些其他办法来和敌人作战
The government looked for some other way
of carrying the war to the enemy.

536
00:44:48,380 --> 00:44:52,466
我们决定我们能与敌人战斗的唯一地点
We decided the only place
where we could fight the enemy

537
00:44:52,551 --> 00:44:57,930
就是沙漠,北非沙漠,
基本上就是中东战区
was the desert, North African desert,
the Middle East theatre generally.

538
00:44:58,014 --> 00:45:04,500
没有其他地方(可选).在可以预见
的未来我们不能希望在法国登陆
There was nowhere else. We couldn't hope to make
a landing in France in any foreseeable future,

539
00:45:04,800 --> 00:45:07,148
因此不能用那种方式来使德国人受伤
and therefore couldn't injure
the Germans that way.

540
00:45:07,232 --> 00:45:11,277
所以另两种选择...两种可能...
轰炸和...它们不是选择,
So the other two alternatives...the two possibles...
well,the bombing and...they weren't alternatives.

541
00:45:11,361 --> 00:45:16,198
那两种可能是轰炸,和在中东战斗
The two possibles were bombing,
and fighting in the Middle East.

542
00:45:16,283 --> 00:45:19,160
那就是为什么从很早的时候起
And that is why
from those very early days

543
00:45:19,286 --> 00:45:25,374
我们就开始推动,鼓动,
要求在中东部署更多坦克
we began to push, agitate,
ask for more armour in the Middle East.

544
00:45:25,459 --> 00:45:30,337
我们必须把坦克从这里的战线上
拿出来,从英国的防御中拿出来,
We had to take the armour out of the line
here, out of the defence of Britain.

545
00:45:30,464 --> 00:45:32,716
要这么做没有其他办法
There was no other way of doing it.

546
00:45:34,500 --> 00:45:37,200
1940年12月10日,
On December 10, 1940,

547
00:45:37,200 --> 00:45:39,680
由韦维尔将军(中东英军司令部总司令)
指挥的两个英联邦师
two Commonwealth divisions
under General Wavell's command

548
00:45:39,765 --> 00:45:43,851
在北非攻击了庞大的意大利军队
attacked the big ltalian army
in North Africa.

549
00:45:45,645 --> 00:45:49,940
稍稍出乎他们自己的意料,
他们以很快的速度进军
Slightly to their own surprise,
they advanced with great speed.

550
00:45:50,984 --> 00:45:53,110
一座接一座堡垒被夺取
Fortress after fortress was taken.

551
00:45:53,195 --> 00:45:55,446
十万(意大利)战俘被俘虏
100,000 prisoners were captured.

552
00:45:55,530 --> 00:46:02,745
现在似乎有机会可以通过南斯拉夫
和希腊来接近主要敌人,德国
Now there seemed to be a chance to get at the main
enemy, Germany...through Yugoslavia and Greece.

553
00:46:02,829 --> 00:46:06,582
我们觉得如果有可能
We did think that if it were possible

554
00:46:06,666 --> 00:46:15,299
把几个巴尔干国家带入
与希特勒的冲突,
to bring certain Balkan countries
into conflict with Hitler,

555
00:46:15,383 --> 00:46:20,221
那样的结果可能真的是不可预见的...
the consequences of that
might be really unforeseeable...

556
00:46:20,347 --> 00:46:22,348
说不准结果会是什么
couldn't tell what
the result could be.

557
00:46:22,432 --> 00:46:26,894
战争内阁和国防委员会的看法是,
The view of the War Cabinet and
the Defence Committee was that,

558
00:46:26,978 --> 00:46:32,191
如果希腊人要自己抵抗德国人,
we should, if the Greeks were going to
defend themselves against the Germans,

559
00:46:32,275 --> 00:46:35,569
我们应该尽我们所能帮助他们
we should bring them what help we could.

560
00:46:35,695 --> 00:46:39,100
迪尔和我在韦维尔获胜后
被派出去,
And Dill and I were sent out,
after Wavell's victory,

561
00:46:39,100 --> 00:46:41,400
到开罗去过问这件事
to Cairo to look into this business.

562
00:46:41,400 --> 00:46:46,789
当我们到了那里,韦维尔说,
"我希望你们不会介意我要说的话"
When we got there, Wavell said, "l hope
you won't mind what l'm going to say."

563
00:46:46,873 --> 00:46:50,042
"我认为我不应该浪费时间...
"l didn't think I ought to waste time...

564
00:46:50,126 --> 00:46:55,422
我已经开始部队的移动和集中
以使我们能去希腊"
and I've begun the movement of troops and
the concentration to enable us to go to Greece."

565
00:46:55,507 --> 00:46:59,760
英联邦在希腊的登陆,
为的是预防德国的进攻
The Commonwealth landing in Greece
was meant to forestall a German attack.

566
00:46:59,845 --> 00:47:03,389
对许多希腊人来说,
这似乎更像是加速了它(德国进攻)
To many Greeks,
it seemed likely to hasten it.

567
00:47:03,473 --> 00:47:05,683
他们已靠他们自己抵御住了意大利,
They had held their own against ltaly,

568
00:47:05,767 --> 00:47:09,270
但当德国人在1941年4月6日进攻,
but when the Germans attacked
on April 6, 1941,

569
00:47:09,354 --> 00:47:12,022
希腊在三个星期里就被打败了
Greece was overwhelmed in three weeks.

570
00:47:12,107 --> 00:47:15,192
加入了盟军的南斯拉夫也一样
So was Yugoslavia,
which had joined the Allies.

571
00:47:15,277 --> 00:47:19,488
五万英联邦部队被撤走
50,000 Commonwealth troops
were evacuated.

572
00:47:19,573 --> 00:47:22,867
事后你不得不承认...
One has to admit that,

573
00:47:24,035 --> 00:47:27,788
我们没能得到我们希望取得的目标
we didn't obtain
the objectives we'd hoped for.

574
00:47:27,873 --> 00:47:32,126
在南斯拉夫人的帮助下,
我们没能在巴尔干发动
We weren't able to conduct,
with the help of the Yugoslavs,

575
00:47:32,210 --> 00:47:36,088
任何有效的战役
any effective campaign in the Balkans.

576
00:47:36,172 --> 00:47:39,842
土耳其,的确,仍是(我们的)一块防御垫
Turkey, it is true,
remained a defensive pad,

577
00:47:39,926 --> 00:47:44,513
但我们丢了希腊
并损失了许多人...勇敢的人...
but we lost Greece
and lost many men... brave men...

578
00:47:44,598 --> 00:47:46,765
而更多人被俘
and more were captured.

579
00:47:47,475 --> 00:47:50,811
所以从那种意思上来说,
资产负债表对我们很不利
So in that sense,
the balance sheet was much against us.

580
00:47:50,896 --> 00:47:55,399
那是段令人压抑的时间,毫无疑问
And it was a depressing time,
no question of that.

581
00:47:55,483 --> 00:47:58,235
1941年5月,德国及其同盟
By May 1941,
Germany and her allies

582
00:47:58,320 --> 00:48:02,072
控制了欧洲大陆的绝大部分地区
controlled most of Continental Europe.

583
00:48:02,157 --> 00:48:05,242
在北非,一支由隆美尔
指挥的德国小部队
And in North Africa,
a small German force under Rommel

584
00:48:05,327 --> 00:48:08,203
已经重新夺回了几乎所有英国夺取的地方
had recaptured
nearly all the British gains.

585
00:48:08,288 --> 00:48:11,999
英国人试图守住克里特岛(希腊南面),
将其用作一个海军基地
The British tried to hold Crete
as a naval base.

586
00:48:18,048 --> 00:48:19,798
掌握了完全制空权,
With complete command of the air,

587
00:48:19,883 --> 00:48:23,052
德国人用16,000名伞兵进攻克里特岛...
the Germans attacked Crete
with 16,000 parachutists...

588
00:48:23,136 --> 00:48:28,223
战争史上首次大规模空降突击
the first large-scale airborne assault
in the history of warfare.

589
00:48:29,184 --> 00:48:34,063
尽管损失惨重,他们在一个重要机场,
马拉马(机场),取得了落脚点
ln spite of heavy losses, they gained
a foothold on a vital airfield, Maleme,

590
00:48:34,147 --> 00:48:37,066
这意味着更多的部队可以空运进来
which meant that
more troops could be flown in.

591
00:48:57,128 --> 00:48:59,000
在密集轰炸的支援下,
Supported by intensive bombing,

592
00:48:59,000 --> 00:49:03,467
德国人能向一支更大的英联邦军队发动进攻
the Germans were able to advance
against a bigger Commonwealth force.

593
00:49:04,094 --> 00:49:07,596
空中力量又一次赢得了这场战役
Once again, air power won the battle.

594
00:49:07,681 --> 00:49:11,308
英联邦的损失为:
13,000人阵亡,受伤或被俘
Commonwealth losses:
13,000 killed, wounded or captured.

595
00:49:11,393 --> 00:49:16,313
又一次撤退添加到了挪威,
法国和希腊的(撤退)名单上
And another evacuation to add
to the list of Norway, France, Greece.

596
00:49:16,398 --> 00:49:20,776
英国人民不知道他们还得再承受多少
The British people wondered
how much more they would have to take.

597
00:49:20,860 --> 00:49:24,780
丘吉尔认为应该不惜一切代价
守住克里特岛 这很重要
Churchill thought it important that
Crete should be held at all costs.

598
00:49:24,864 --> 00:49:28,534
如果我们丢了克里特岛,我们就
丢失了我们在东地中海的基地...
If we lost Crete, we lost our base
in the Eastern Mediterranean...

599
00:49:28,618 --> 00:49:30,703
我们的海军基地和空军基地
our naval base and our air base.

600
00:49:31,371 --> 00:49:34,790
他不断给韦维尔发电报,说:
And he kept on
telegraphing to Wavell, saying:

601
00:49:34,874 --> 00:49:41,797
"你当然能匀出一打(12辆)坦克
去防守马拉马机场",
"Surely you can spare just a dozen tanks
for the defence of Maleme airfield",

602
00:49:41,881 --> 00:49:46,510
克里特岛的主要机场,
"去对付德国空降兵"
the chief airfield in Crete,
"against German paratroops."

603
00:49:46,594 --> 00:49:49,304
韦维尔回答说他没有坦克...
And Wavell replied
that he had no tanks...

604
00:49:49,389 --> 00:49:54,643
它们都正在修理履带或
给引擎上油 或在三角洲干什么...
they were all having their tracks mended or
their engines greased or something...in the delta.

605
00:49:54,728 --> 00:49:57,730
他连一打坦克都匀不出来
and that he couldn't spare even a dozen.

606
00:49:57,814 --> 00:50:01,275
克里特岛丢了
这是个巨大的灾难...
Well, Crete was lost.
lt was a great disaster...

607
00:50:01,359 --> 00:50:04,903
让下议院的每个人难过,
让(整个)国家难过
upset everybody in the House
of Commons, upset the country.

608
00:50:04,988 --> 00:50:10,242
1941年春天对我们来说是战争中的一个低点,
lt was a low point for us in the war,
in the spring of 1941.

609
00:50:10,326 --> 00:50:15,748
我(一般)到凌晨2:30还没睡,
l used to be up
until 2:30 in the morning,

610
00:50:15,832 --> 00:50:20,502
向美国和(英联邦)自治领等地广播
broadcasting to America
and the Dominions and so on.

611
00:50:20,587 --> 00:50:29,762
我会在广播公司的地下室
抓紧时间睡一会儿
And l'd snatch some pretty dicey sort of sleep
in the basement of Broadcasting House.

612
00:50:29,846 --> 00:50:35,434
我会在早晨出来,
然后我会四处走走,我会想:
l'd come out in the morning,
and then l'd walk around, and l'd think:

613
00:50:35,518 --> 00:50:40,647
"我觉得不可能再这么下去了,
因为所有东西都炸没了"
"l don't think there can be much more
of this, because everything's going."

614
00:50:40,774 --> 00:50:44,026
在那些早晨,你觉得,
"这(种轰炸)再来个两星期"
On those mornings, you thought,
"Another two weeks of this

615
00:50:44,110 --> 00:50:46,987
这里除了瓦砾就啥都不会有了"
and there'll be nothing around here
but rubble."

616
00:50:53,620 --> 00:50:56,080
1941年5月10日,
On May 10, 1941,

617
00:50:56,164 --> 00:50:59,500
伦敦遭受了战争中
最具毁灭性的夜间空袭
London suffered its most destructive
night raid of the war.

618
00:50:59,584 --> 00:51:03,212
超过3,000人伤亡
Over 3,000 people
were killed or injured.

619
00:51:05,673 --> 00:51:08,884
数以百计的火点不得不任其燃烧怠尽
Hundreds of fires had to be left
to burn themselves out.

620
00:51:08,968 --> 00:51:13,055
屠杀和毁灭似乎看不到头
There seemed no end in sight
to the slaughter and destruction.

621
00:51:13,139 --> 00:51:18,143
但尽管伦敦人不知道,这却是个转折点
But although Londoners didn't know,
it was the turning point.

622
00:51:18,228 --> 00:51:21,105
在41年4月,
ln April, '41,

623
00:51:21,189 --> 00:51:26,151
希特勒召见了所有在法国的指挥官
Hitler assembled
all the commanders in France.

624
00:51:27,403 --> 00:51:31,031
在两个小时里,
And... during two hours,

625
00:51:31,116 --> 00:51:38,622
他跟我们谈论了不列颠战役的第二部分
he talked to us about
the part two of the Battle of Britain.

626
00:51:40,125 --> 00:51:44,211
后来他告诉我们...
And... he told us later...

627
00:51:44,295 --> 00:51:49,758
我们两个人,具体说是我的朋友
莫德尔(元帅)和我本人...
two of us,
namely my friend Mölders and myself...

628
00:51:51,344 --> 00:51:57,933
这只是为了掩饰(即将开始的)向俄国的进攻
that it has only been in order to
camouflage the offensive against Russia.

629
00:51:58,768 --> 00:52:01,019
这已经是41年4月了
This has been in April, '41.

630
00:52:02,063 --> 00:52:05,524
而5月10日的空袭
And the raid on 10 May

631
00:52:05,608 --> 00:52:09,862
只能被看作是...
can only be considered
as a camouflage of the...

632
00:52:11,573 --> 00:52:15,951
俄国战役开始的一个伪装
beginning of the Russian campaign.

633
00:52:20,039 --> 00:52:23,000
5月10日那次袭击的牺牲品中,
Among the victims
of the raid on May 10

634
00:52:23,084 --> 00:52:24,626
有下议院
was the House of Commons.

635
00:52:24,711 --> 00:52:28,755
在整整一年,一年的失望和战败中,
For exactly a year,
a year of disappointment and defeat,

636
00:52:28,840 --> 00:52:31,592
下议院维持了丘吉尔的首相职务
the Commons had
sustained Churchill in office.

637
00:52:31,676 --> 00:52:34,469
但这场重要的战斗已经获胜
But the important battle had been won.

638
00:52:34,554 --> 00:52:37,472
英国已经幸存了下来
Britain had survived.

639
00:52:37,557 --> 00:52:39,516
现在轮到俄国了
Now it was Russia's turn.

