1
00:00:12,679 --> 00:00:17,766
我认为非常多的机组成员都不知道
战略轰炸真正意味着什么
I don't think very many of the aircrew
knew what strategic bombing really meant.

2
00:00:17,851 --> 00:00:20,686
我们还在学校读书时,就加入了空军,
We as by some school,joined the air force,

3
00:00:20,770 --> 00:00:22,646
因为有场战争正在进行
because there was a war being fought

4
00:00:22,731 --> 00:00:25,066
而有许多魅力与空军联系在一起
and there was a bit of glamour
attached to the air force.

5
00:00:26,151 --> 00:00:30,863
如果你不能在他的工厂把德国佬干掉，
If you couldn't get
the Kraut in his factory,

6
00:00:30,947 --> 00:00:34,074
这就跟在他的床上
把他干掉一样容易
it was just as easy to
knock him off in his bed.

7
00:00:34,159 --> 00:00:40,164
如果隔壁的席克尔格鲁贝老奶奶
挨了炸弹,那算她运气差
And if old Granny Shickelgruber next door
got the chop, that's hard luck.

8
00:00:40,248 --> 00:00:45,878
(阿瑟·哈里斯爵士 1942年皇家空军轰炸机司令部总司令)
有许多人说轰炸永远不能赢得一场战争
There are a lot of people who say
that bombing can never win a war.

9
00:00:46,500 --> 00:00:52,968
(阿瑟·哈里斯爵士 1942年皇家空军轰炸机司令部总司令)
我对那种说法的答案是它还从来没被尝试过,而我们应该试试看
Well, my answer to that is that it has
never been tried yet, and we shall see.

10
00:02:13,800 --> 00:02:16,385
(♪ 茶舞)
(♪ tea dance)

11
00:02:19,514 --> 00:02:24,500
在不列颠战役后,
皇家空军有理由庆祝
After the Battle of Britain,the Royal
Air Force had cause to celebrate.

12
00:02:28,064 --> 00:02:34,400
战斗机司令部已展示了 轰炸机要摧毁
一个能保卫其领空的国家有多么困难
Fighter Command had shown how difficult it was for bombers
to destroy a country which could defend its own air space.

13
00:02:37,949 --> 00:02:42,400
很明显,这是一个空军参谋部
自己疏于从中吸取经验的教训
A lesson the air staff, apparently,
neglected to teach itself.

14
00:02:46,457 --> 00:02:51,461
特伦查德爵士是将其作为一支
战略轰炸机部队来创建空军的
Lord Trenchard had founded the service
as a force of strategic bombers.

15
00:02:51,546 --> 00:02:54,200
防御用的战斗机是次要的
Fighters for defence were secondary.

16
00:02:57,468 --> 00:02:59,803
长距离轰炸机,有人在三十年代主张,
Long-range bombers,
it was argued in the 30s,

17
00:02:59,888 --> 00:03:02,806
能在不进行代价高昂的地面战役
的情况下赢得战争
could win wars without costly land battles.

18
00:03:02,891 --> 00:03:05,601
它们能炸掉敌人的工业中心
They would bomb the industrial
heart out of an enemy

19
00:03:05,685 --> 00:03:08,812
并完全摧毁其平民的士气
and totally demoralise
his civilian population.

20
00:03:11,649 --> 00:03:17,404
在1939年,皇家空军并没有真正
装备好 来将这个论点付诸试验
ln 1939, the RAF was not really equipped
to put this thesis to the test.

21
00:03:17,488 --> 00:03:22,659
但在敦刻尔克撤退之后,它是
唯一一支能攻击德国的力量
But after Dunkirk, it was the only force
capable of attacking Germany.

22
00:03:22,744 --> 00:03:25,704
而英国公众急切地需要一次进攻
And the British public
desperately needed an attack.

23
00:03:28,499 --> 00:03:36,716
大英帝国正在集结一支庞大的轰炸机部队,
它被设计成用来捣烂德国心脏的进攻性空中武器
The British Empire is building up a tremendous
bomber force designed as the offensive air
weapon to smash the heart of Germany.

24
00:03:42,472 --> 00:03:44,806
第一次日间轰炸是灾难性的
The first daylight raids
were disastrous.

25
00:03:44,891 --> 00:03:49,186
轰炸机成为德国空军轻易捕获的猎物
Bombers fell easy prey to the Luftwaffe.

26
00:03:49,270 --> 00:03:51,647
(♪ "带回我的轰炸机和我")
(♪ "Bring Back My Bomber And Me")

27
00:04:03,868 --> 00:04:07,746
尽管损失不断增长,皇家空军仍然坚持不懈
Still the RAF persevered,
though losses mounted.

28
00:04:07,830 --> 00:04:12,125
惨重伤亡迫使轰炸机司令部
开始在夜间飞行
Heavy casualties forced Bomber Command
to start flying at night.

29
00:04:20,134 --> 00:04:22,219
好吧,伙计们,我们走
OK, chaps, here we go.

30
00:04:26,724 --> 00:04:29,268
滑行并起飞
Taxi out and take off.

31
00:04:51,332 --> 00:04:54,209
你看到了我看到的东西了吗,机长?
Do you see what I see, skipper?

32
00:04:54,335 --> 00:04:56,586
你看到了什么,我的苏格兰朋友?
What do you see, my Scottish friend?

33
00:04:56,671 --> 00:05:00,090
雾 肮脏,黄色,讨厌的雾
Fog. Dirty, yellow, stinking fog.

34
00:05:01,000 --> 00:05:02,719
"今晚的目标" 1941英国影片

35
00:05:02,719 --> 00:05:05,700
对接受日间攻击训练的机组成员来说,
For aircrews
trained to attack in daylight,

36
00:05:05,700 --> 00:05:07,806
夜间飞行有其问题
night flying had its problems.

37
00:05:07,890 --> 00:05:15,772
(哈米什·马哈迪 皇家空军轰炸机司令部大队长)
要在夜深人静的夜晚,在一般的气候
条件下,找到一个德国境内的目标,
To find a target in Germany,in the dead
of night,in any average weather conditions,

38
00:05:15,857 --> 00:05:20,444
远远超出了任何轰炸机
机组成员(可能完成)的任务
was quite far beyond the task
of any bomber crews.

39
00:05:24,032 --> 00:05:27,784
我们过了荷兰海岸
云太多了看不清在哪里
We're over the Dutch coast.
Too much cloud to see where.

40
00:05:28,300 --> 00:05:38,670
爱国影片在给人留下 只要精心策划,有决心和吃一点生胡萝卜
就能克服你无法在黑暗中看见东西的规律 这种印象方面毫无困难
Patriotic films had no difficulty in giving the impression
that plot and determination and a diet of raw carrots could
overcome the law that says you cannot see in the dark.

41
00:05:38,755 --> 00:05:42,799
- 除了莱茵河看不见任何其他东西
- 我希望这不是多瑙河
- Can't see anything else but the Rhine.
- I hope it's not the Danube.

42
00:05:42,884 --> 00:05:46,511
继续前进 你可能可以看到
灯亮着的什么东西
Keep on going. You might be able
to pick up something with lights on.

43
00:05:46,596 --> 00:05:50,098
如果你在途中能看到可见的光点,
lf you could get visual
pinpoints en route,

44
00:05:50,183 --> 00:05:56,396
你可能距离目标只有五或七英里了
you could get within five or
seven miles of the targets.

45
00:06:00,234 --> 00:06:02,819
- 炸弹舱打开
- 稳住
- Bomb doors open.
- Steady.

46
00:06:02,904 --> 00:06:06,406
一旦到达目标,接下来就是小菜一碟了...
Once the target was reached,
it was a piece of cake...

47
00:06:06,491 --> 00:06:07,949
炸弹下去了
Bombs gone.

48
00:06:11,037 --> 00:06:15,374
...倘若你只是在炸一个制片场的模型的话
..provided you were just
blowing up a studio model.

49
00:06:18,503 --> 00:06:20,462
我希望我们没让你久等,长官
I hope we haven't
kept you waiting, sir.

50
00:06:20,546 --> 00:06:22,672
上帝啊,没有 过来坐下
Good Lord, no. Come and sit down.

51
00:06:25,259 --> 00:06:27,969
- 你们进行得怎么样?
- 引发了好一场大火
- How did you get on?
- Caused a hell of a great big fire.

52
00:06:28,096 --> 00:06:32,057
大量浓烟
在,哦,50英里外可以看到
Buckets of smoke.
Visible, ooh, 50 miles away.

53
00:06:33,267 --> 00:06:37,104
恩,老小子,来点火腿和鸡蛋怎么样?
Well, old boy,
how about some bacon and eggs?

54
00:06:45,196 --> 00:06:47,239
事实大相径庭
The truth was different.

55
00:06:47,323 --> 00:06:51,785
事实上,在那个时候,
而且后来也被证实了,
ln fact, in those days,
and it's been proved since,

56
00:06:51,869 --> 00:06:57,624
每一百枚炸弹里只有三枚
落在目标点的五英里范围内
three bombs in every 100 got
within five miles of the aiming point.

57
00:07:02,588 --> 00:07:08,051
在集体宿舍里,九个孩子被炸死,五个严重受伤
In diesem Schlafsaal wurden neun Kinder
getötet und fünf schwer verletzt.

58
00:07:08,136 --> 00:07:11,764
不精确的轰炸可能是令人尴尬的
Inaccurate bombing
could be embarrassing.

59
00:07:13,599 --> 00:07:19,062
德国宣传部迅速利用了这家
儿童医院被炸毁(的新闻)
The German propaganda ministry was quick to capitalise
on the destruction of this children's hospital.

60
00:07:19,147 --> 00:07:21,231
他们是英国谋杀男孩们的牺牲品,
Das sind die Opfer
der britischen Mordbuben,

61
00:07:21,315 --> 00:07:23,859
(英国人)故意犯下了这桩罪行
die dieses gemeine Verbrechen ganz
bewusst begangen haben.

62
00:07:23,943 --> 00:07:26,611
它将被无情地偿还
Es wird unerbittlich gesühnt werden.

63
00:07:28,656 --> 00:07:32,868
但战争内阁的看法是德国必须被轰炸
But the war cabinet's view
was that Germany had to be bombed.

64
00:07:32,952 --> 00:07:36,872
这是英国当时能采取的唯一战略轰炸
And this was the only strategic
bombing Britain could then undertake.

65
00:07:36,956 --> 00:07:43,211
考文垂和利物浦(被炸)显示 如果其工人
被炸得无家可归的话 德国工业会遭受损失
Coventry and Liverpool indicated the German industry
would suffer if its workers were bombed out.

66
00:07:43,963 --> 00:07:48,341
林德曼教授向丘吉尔建议
让三分之一的德国工人无家可归
Professor Lindemann was advicing Churchill
that de-housing a third of German workers

67
00:07:48,468 --> 00:07:51,094
会让(德国)工业生产停顿下来
would bring industrial production to a halt.

68
00:07:51,179 --> 00:07:55,348
还有要报复(德国)闪电轰炸的公众压力
And there was popular pressure
to avenge the Blitz.

69
00:07:56,392 --> 00:07:58,977
我们不想请敌人帮忙
We ask no favours of the enemy.

70
00:08:00,730 --> 00:08:07,861
我们不想从他们那里寻求...懊悔
We seek from them no... compunction.

71
00:08:09,489 --> 00:08:11,448
相反,
On the contrary,

72
00:08:11,532 --> 00:08:23,877
如果今夜伦敦人民被要求就 是否应该
签订一个停止轰炸所有城市的公约进行投票,
if tonight the people of London were asked to cast
their votes as to whether a convention should be
entered into to stop the bombing of all cities,

73
00:08:23,961 --> 00:08:26,630
压倒性的多数会呐喊:
an overwhelming majority would cry:

74
00:08:26,714 --> 00:08:30,342
"不, 我们要让德国人吃苦头
"No, we will mete out to the Germans

75
00:08:30,426 --> 00:08:35,931
(让他们吃苦的程度)要比得上
而且要超过他们让我们吃的苦头"
the measure and more than the measure
they have meted out to us."

76
00:08:42,855 --> 00:08:47,000
但德国人现在在让英国轰炸机吃苦头
But the Germans were now
meting it out to the British bomber.

77
00:08:57,203 --> 00:09:01,998
到1941年底,英国已损失了700架飞机
By the end of 1941,
Britain had lost 700 aircraft.

78
00:09:14,929 --> 00:09:20,000
海军和陆军为了大西洋和
北非沙漠(战场)要求轰炸机
The navy and the army were demanding
bombers for the Atlantic and the desert.

79
00:09:21,394 --> 00:09:25,200
轰炸机司令部面临被迫歇业(的可能)
Bomber Command stood to be put out of business.

80
00:09:25,700 --> 00:09:27,649
面对不断增加的损失,
ln the face of mounting losses,

81
00:09:27,733 --> 00:09:33,280
内阁命令减少轰炸行动,以保留轰炸机力量
the cabinet ordered bombing operations
to be cut down,to save the bomber force.

82
00:09:36,367 --> 00:09:39,035
在1942年2月的休整期间,
During the respite in February 1942,

83
00:09:39,120 --> 00:09:42,831
阿瑟·哈里斯爵士接任了轰炸机司令部的总司令
Sir Arthur Harris took over as
Commander-in-Chief, Bomber Command.

84
00:09:42,915 --> 00:09:48,044
他决心用新战术和新轰炸机来取得成功
He was determined to succeed
with new tactics and new bombers.

85
00:09:48,129 --> 00:09:52,841
纳粹带着一种十分孩子气的妄想加入这场战争
(Harris) The Nazis entered this war
under the rather childish delusion

86
00:09:52,925 --> 00:09:55,552
那就是他们会轰炸其他所有人
that they were going to bomb
everybody else

87
00:09:55,636 --> 00:09:58,930
而没人会轰炸他们
and nobody was going to bomb them.

88
00:09:59,473 --> 00:10:05,895
在鹿特丹,伦敦,华沙和其他50个地方,
At Rotterdam, London, Warsaw
and half a hundred other places,

89
00:10:06,022 --> 00:10:10,400
他们把那个十分天真的理论付诸行动
they put that rather naive theory
into operation.

90
00:10:11,235 --> 00:10:16,197
他们播撒下风(的种子)
而现在他们将收获旋风
They sowed the wind and now
they are going to reap the whirlwind.

91
00:10:16,282 --> 00:10:20,827
我把他们派去轰炸波罗的海
的德国北部港口,
l put them onto the north German ports
in the Baltic,

92
00:10:20,911 --> 00:10:24,956
(阿瑟·哈里斯爵士 皇家空军元帅 人称"轰炸机"哈里斯)
因为,我自己在夜晚飞过很长一段时间后,
because, having flown
quite a bit at night myself,

93
00:10:25,041 --> 00:10:29,419
我意识到最容易找到的目标,当然,
l realised that the easiest targets
to get hold of, of course,

94
00:10:29,503 --> 00:10:32,589
总是那些在海岸线上的目标
were always the ones on the coastline.

95
00:10:32,673 --> 00:10:36,217
因为如果你能看见什么东西,
你一定能看见海岸线
Because if you can see anything,
you can see a coastline.

96
00:10:36,302 --> 00:10:39,596
如果你能看见海岸线
那奇特的形状,
lf you can see a coastline
with its odd shapes,

97
00:10:39,680 --> 00:10:44,434
你就能一路找到港口并认出它们
you can find your way along to ports
and recognise them.

98
00:10:44,518 --> 00:10:48,980
吕贝克和罗斯托克是首批主要目标
Lubeck and Rostock
were the first major targets.

99
00:10:49,065 --> 00:10:51,858
作为港口,它们很容易找到
As ports, they were easy to find.

100
00:10:53,653 --> 00:10:55,779
而它们烧得很彻底
And they burnt well.

101
00:10:56,656 --> 00:11:02,494
1942年3月,230架轰炸机
摧毁了半个吕贝克
ln March 1942, 230 bombers
destroyed half Lubeck.

102
00:11:02,578 --> 00:11:06,665
4月,罗斯托克被炸成一片火海
ln April,Rostock was bombed into flames.

103
00:11:06,749 --> 00:11:10,752
(轰炸)方式被确定下来:夜间区域轰炸
The style was set: night area bombing.

104
00:11:11,671 --> 00:11:14,964
这将成为接下来三年的模式
This was to become the pattern
for the next three years.

105
00:11:15,049 --> 00:11:18,968
这(种轰炸方式)很可怕,
它(对平民目标)是不加区别的
lt was terrifying,
it was indiscriminate,

106
00:11:19,053 --> 00:11:22,931
但就轰炸机司令部而言,没有其他选择
but as far as Bomber Command
was concerned, there was no alternative.

107
00:11:24,016 --> 00:11:25,225
有多少时候,
How many occasions,

108
00:11:25,351 --> 00:11:28,770
向窗外看去,或在花园里散步,
looking out of the window,
or walking out in the garden,

109
00:11:28,854 --> 00:11:33,191
你抬头能看到18,000或20,000英尺外(的东西)?
could you see up to 18 or 20,000 feet?

110
00:11:33,275 --> 00:11:35,402
可能最多两或三天
Maybe on two or three days at most.

111
00:11:35,528 --> 00:11:39,781
如果你抬头能看到那么远,
有多少时候你能保证
On how many occasions can you
guarantee if you see up to it here,

112
00:11:39,865 --> 00:11:46,246
你在500英里以外,欧洲的另一头
向下也能看到那么远?
that you could see down to it 500 miles
away,in the other end of Europe?

113
00:11:46,330 --> 00:11:48,748
就是那么回事
That was the situation.

114
00:11:48,833 --> 00:11:55,755
没有命中单个目标,
一向很小的目标的可能性,
There's no possibility of hitting the individual
targets,consistently small targets,

115
00:11:56,757 --> 00:12:06,266
直到我们得到了能在黑暗中或穿过云层
显示那些目标的电子导航辅助设备
until we got the navigational electronic aids that would
show those targets up in the dark or through clouds.

116
00:12:07,852 --> 00:12:14,000
第一种用于导航的电子辅助设备
现在投入了使用 它被称为GEE
The first electronic aid to navigation
now came into service.lt was called GEE.

117
00:12:14,608 --> 00:12:20,488
在英国的三座无线电发射塔
向西欧发出一张不可见的信号网络
Three radio transmitters in England sent out an
invisible grid of signals across western Europe.

118
00:12:25,703 --> 00:12:29,080
通过监视这些信号
并将它们标绘在地图上,
By monitoring the signals
and plotting them on a map,

119
00:12:29,165 --> 00:12:32,876
一个领航员能分辨出他的飞机在哪里
a navigator could tell
where his aircraft was.

120
00:12:35,004 --> 00:12:37,839
GEE首先被用在科隆
GEE was first used at Cologne.

121
00:12:37,923 --> 00:12:43,000
在这里,哈里斯投入了他能搜集到的每架
轰炸机进行了一次非常有影响力的攻击
Here, Harris threw in every bomber he could
scrape up for a monumental prestige attack.

122
00:12:47,933 --> 00:12:56,691
在你们的手中有着一种 可以摧毁大部分
敌人战争努力赖以为系的资源 的工具
In your hands lie the means of destroying
a major part of the resources by which
the enemy's war effort is maintained.

123
00:12:56,776 --> 00:13:01,279
将你们的攻击坚持到底
如果你们各自取得成功,
Press home your attack.
lf you individually succeed,

124
00:13:01,363 --> 00:13:07,035
你们将对敌人的要害给予最致命的一击
you will have delivered the most devastating
blow against the very vitals of the enemy.

125
00:13:07,161 --> 00:13:10,330
让他在下巴上结结实实挨上一下
Let him have it right on the chin.

126
00:13:10,414 --> 00:13:14,083
把那信息传到所有大队和基地
Send that message
to all groups and stations.

127
00:13:15,836 --> 00:13:21,758
我试图向他们展示用一支接近足够
数量的部队可以取得什么样的战果,
I was trying to show them what could be achieved
with something approaching an adequate force,

128
00:13:21,842 --> 00:13:27,013
而且这种战果可以不用不正常的伤亡就取得
and that it would be achieved
without abnormal casualties.

129
00:13:30,017 --> 00:13:35,188
希特勒德国的黑夜即将被变得十分可怕
The dark hours over Hitler's Germany
are about to be made hideous.

130
00:13:35,272 --> 00:13:39,150
轰炸机司令部的战士知道
的很清楚他们必须做什么
The men of Bomber Command
know well what they have to do.

131
00:13:39,235 --> 00:13:45,198
一个平静,月光照耀的夜晚,
从飞机到战鸽,一切都做好了准备并等待着
A calm, moonlit night,everything ready and
waiting,from planes to carrier pigeons.

132
00:13:45,282 --> 00:13:48,827
它们似乎知道行动开始了
来吧,伙计们,开始行动
They seem to know the ops are on.
Come on, fellas, get cracking.

133
00:13:57,044 --> 00:13:59,337
皇家空军的一昼夜
Round the clock with the RAF.

134
00:13:59,421 --> 00:14:03,341
在一个又一个基地,有许多
重型轰炸机,包括"兰开斯特"式,
At station after station, there
are heavies, including Lancasters,

135
00:14:03,425 --> 00:14:06,761
当前最重要的重型轰炸机,
为今晚做好了准备
the heavy bomber of the moment,
ready for tonight.

136
00:14:06,846 --> 00:14:10,598
因为今晚将会非常,非常有趣...
For tonight is going
to be very, very interesting...

137
00:14:10,683 --> 00:14:12,350
一个千架轰炸机之夜
a thousand-bomber night.

138
00:14:27,616 --> 00:14:31,995
在1942年5月30日的那个夜晚,
On that night, May 30, 1942,

139
00:14:32,079 --> 00:14:35,623
1,046架轰炸机出发去轰炸科隆
1,046 bombers took off for Cologne.

140
00:14:39,962 --> 00:14:44,924
(德语)过了一会儿我们也同样
听到了飞近的轰炸机的嗡嗡声
Wir hörten auch gleich kurz darauf
das Brummen der anfliegenden Bomber.

141
00:14:45,009 --> 00:14:48,094
我们听到了飞近的轰炸机的嗡嗡声
We heard the drone
of the approaching bombers

142
00:14:48,178 --> 00:14:51,348
并猜测这是一个很大的编队
and guessed that
it was a heavy formation.

143
00:14:57,021 --> 00:15:00,857
(劳拉·斯冉夫人 科隆医院护士)
很快,第一批炸弹掉在我们周围
And soon after,
the first bombs fell around us.

144
00:15:00,941 --> 00:15:05,028
我们都害怕得发抖
一些人几乎晕过去了
We were all shaking with fear.
Some people nearly fainted.

145
00:15:05,112 --> 00:15:07,864
许多病人在哭泣
Many of the patients were crying.

146
00:15:07,948 --> 00:15:11,618
(炸弹)爆炸声和(房子)倒塌声变得越来越近
The roaring and crashing
came closer and closer.

147
00:15:11,702 --> 00:15:15,747
我们真的觉得是一片混乱
We really thought
all hell was breaking loose.

148
00:15:17,333 --> 00:15:19,542
城市中我们所在的这个地区成了一片火海
Our part of the city was in flames.

149
00:15:19,627 --> 00:15:22,670
人们正跑出地窖 跑出房子
People were running out of cellars
and out of houses.

150
00:15:22,755 --> 00:15:24,547
有些人被埋在废墟里
Some were buried in the rubble.

151
00:15:24,673 --> 00:15:27,258
其他人被掉落的砖石砸中
Others were caught
by the falling masonry.

152
00:15:27,343 --> 00:15:34,223
许多人实际上着了火,
象活着的火炬一样四处奔跑
Many people actually caught fire,
running around like living torches.

153
00:15:35,643 --> 00:15:41,773
我们真的没预计到,在42年,
会发生一次这么猛烈的空袭
We really didn't expect, in '42,
that such a heavy raid would take place.

154
00:15:41,857 --> 00:15:45,026
我们只习惯了小一些的攻击,
We were only used to smaller attacks,

155
00:15:45,110 --> 00:15:52,033
(阿尔伯特·斯佩尔 纳粹德国军备部长)
当我得知大约1,000架轰炸机在攻击科隆的消息时,
and when I got the news that about
1,000 bombers were attacking Cologne,

156
00:15:52,159 --> 00:15:53,743
那感觉真是难以置信
it was incredible.

157
00:15:58,999 --> 00:16:03,628
人们的士气并没有被打击太多
The morale of the people
was not shattered too much.

158
00:16:03,712 --> 00:16:08,508
这更象是一个一会儿就过去的短暂打击
lt was more like a short shock
which passed away.

159
00:16:11,720 --> 00:16:18,893
德国工业仍很富有活力 尽管工业中心
鲁尔整个1942年都处于空袭之下
German industry remained resilient, although Ruhr,
the industrial heart, was under attack throughout 1942.

160
00:16:18,978 --> 00:16:25,608
破坏很巨大,但经济中有一些闲置部分
被利用起来进行更多的战争生产
Damage was extensive,but there was some slack
in the economy to be taken up in more war production.

161
00:16:26,235 --> 00:16:30,363
纳粹战争机器在鼓舞平民士气方面很有技巧
The Nazi war machine was skilled
at orchestrating civilian morale.

162
00:16:30,447 --> 00:16:33,157
(♪ "德意志之歌")
(♪ "Deutschlandlied")

163
00:16:56,181 --> 00:16:58,474
飞机的声音
Flugzeuggeräusch.

164
00:17:03,689 --> 00:17:08,484
请给02:15时钟措施的速度计时
Bitte mal die Geschwindigkeit
von 02:15 Uhr nachmessen.

165
00:17:13,532 --> 00:17:17,201
德国人能给予也能吸取(教训)
The Germans could give as well as take.

166
00:17:17,286 --> 00:17:25,460
德国空军敏锐地意识到 由雷达支配
的皇家空军在不列颠之战中给予它的教训
The Luftwaffe was acutely aware of the lesson radar-controlled
RAF fighters had taught it during the Battle of Britain.

167
00:17:26,086 --> 00:17:31,424
防空司令(约瑟夫·)卡姆胡贝将军
发展出一套最有效的系统
Air defence chief General Kammhuber
evolved a most efficient system.

168
00:17:31,508 --> 00:17:33,051
在整个北海海岸
Across the North Sea coast

169
00:17:33,135 --> 00:17:36,804
绵延着一个早期预警雷达网,卡姆胡贝防线
stretched an early-warning radar grid,
the Kammhuber Line.

170
00:17:36,889 --> 00:17:39,640
这个雷达网被分成一个个方格
This grid was divided into boxes.

171
00:17:39,725 --> 00:17:44,479
在每一个方格里有一架夜间战斗机,
像一只蜘蛛等着苍蝇一样等待着
ln each box was a night fighter,
waiting like a spider for the fly.

172
00:17:44,563 --> 00:17:51,444
(威尔海姆·赫格特 夜间战斗机飞行员)
我们从侧翼超过轰炸机,
所以他会想,"啊,他没有看到我"
We overtook the plane on the side,
so he thought, "Ah, he hasn't seen me."

173
00:17:53,197 --> 00:17:57,658
他仍在作某些螺旋状或波浪状运动
He still did some corkscrewing
or waving.

174
00:17:57,743 --> 00:18:03,039
我只是稍微倾斜 给机枪手一个清晰的向下视野
l just banked slightly to give
the gunners a good view underneath.

175
00:18:03,123 --> 00:18:08,169
在这种机动期间 我把左舷和右舷摇动大约10度,
l moved off maybe ten degrees to port
and starboard during this manoeuvre,

176
00:18:08,253 --> 00:18:11,255
但从任何一方面来说
都根本不剧烈
but it wasn't violent
in any sense at all.

177
00:18:11,340 --> 00:18:18,012
然后我用这种方式射击并直接俯冲,
And then I was shooting this way
and diving directly,

178
00:18:18,097 --> 00:18:23,559
或用一种...按我们的说法...
"爵士乐"(安装在机背上的机炮),
or with a... what we said...
schräge Musik,

179
00:18:23,644 --> 00:18:27,605
两门20mm机炮,
two two-centimetre cannons,

180
00:18:27,689 --> 00:18:30,817
跟(普通机炮)一样,
只是飞在(轰炸机)下面,
the same, only flying underneath,

181
00:18:30,943 --> 00:18:34,612
并等着,非常轻松地移动着
and waiting, moving very easy.

182
00:18:34,696 --> 00:18:38,866
我们一边和轰炸机作着
同样的平行机动,一边射击
We did the same
parallel to the other one, shooting.

183
00:18:38,951 --> 00:18:45,164
在发动机之间 你有大约5,000升汽油,
Between the motors
you had about 5,000 litres of gasoline,

184
00:18:45,249 --> 00:18:48,084
那非常容易就烧起来
and that was burning very easily.

185
00:18:48,168 --> 00:18:52,797
卡姆胡贝防线的出现,
以及随之出现的所有(防御措施),
The advent of the Kammhuber Line,
and all that went with it,

186
00:18:52,881 --> 00:18:58,052
是(皇家空军)要面对的一种令人震惊的事物,
was a startling sort of thing
to be confronted with,

187
00:18:58,137 --> 00:19:04,058
因为德国夜间防御对英国
轰炸机造成了可怕的损失
because the German night defences
took a terrible toll of British bombers.

188
00:19:04,143 --> 00:19:07,270
(机组成员在唱 "原野上的家" )
(aircrew singing "Home on the Range" )

189
00:19:09,273 --> 00:19:11,691
但现在皇家空军不再孤身作战
But now the RAF
was no longer alone.

190
00:19:28,167 --> 00:19:32,796
你们好,伙计们 这是你们那份
给希特勒的鸟籽 过来拿吧
Hiya, fellas. There's your birdseed
for Hitler. Come and get it.

191
00:19:40,053 --> 00:19:46,309
贯穿整个1942年,美国陆军第八
航空队一直在英国集结力量
Throughout 1942,the US Eighth Army Air
Force had been building up in England.

192
00:19:49,563 --> 00:19:53,482
美国空军的领导们相信
他们能在白天取得成功
The American air chiefs
believed they could succeed in daylight

193
00:19:53,567 --> 00:19:56,652
而不会遭受象英国人曾经历的那种损失
without suffering the losses
the British had done.

194
00:19:56,737 --> 00:20:00,782
他们确信他们能在白天精确地轰炸
They were convinced
they could bomb accurately by day.

195
00:20:01,867 --> 00:20:04,035
查理又在作他的旋转了
Charlie's doing his twirl again.

196
00:20:04,119 --> 00:20:06,287
希望我也有那样的东西可以玩玩
Wish I had something
like that to play with.

197
00:20:06,371 --> 00:20:08,956
如果你有一架
你们也不知道该怎么操作它
You guys wouldn't know what to do
with it in times of you have one.

198
00:20:09,041 --> 00:20:12,336
得花六个月才教得会你如何扣扳机
Took six months to teach you
how to pull a trigger.

199
00:20:12,420 --> 00:20:17,673
好了 伙计们 收起你们的闲聊吧
你们要回家了
All right,fellas. Can the small talk.
You need to come home.

200
00:20:19,218 --> 00:20:24,096
他们的飞机武装到了牙齿
有一些装了多达12挺机关枪
Their aircraft were very heavily armed.
Some carried up to 12 machine guns.

201
00:20:24,181 --> 00:20:28,684
他们接受了以密集编队飞行的训练
And they were trained
to fly in close formation.

202
00:20:28,769 --> 00:20:35,733
就第八航空队而言
编队飞行才真正是游戏的名字
Formation flying was really the name of the game
as far as the Eighth Air Force was concerned.

203
00:20:35,817 --> 00:20:41,239
(詹姆斯·斯图尔特 轰炸机中队指挥官 后任美国空军准将）
在之前或之后 都没有像那样的事情发生过
There was never anything like it
happened before or since.

204
00:20:44,826 --> 00:20:50,665
(詹姆斯·斯图尔特(又译史都华) 好莱坞著名影星
1941年奥斯卡影帝 代表作"后窗","迷魂记","费城故事")
当他们结伴同行时 他们事实上是在制定他们自己的规则
They actually were sort of making
their own rules up as they went along,

205
00:20:50,749 --> 00:20:53,876
因为这是个全新的概念
because it was just a brand-new concept.

206
00:20:53,961 --> 00:21:03,177
你所有飞机的机枪手战位使得一种更集中的火力成为可能
You made it possible to have a more concentrated firepower
from the gunner's positions of all your aeroplanes.

207
00:21:03,262 --> 00:21:10,268
你能依靠良好队形,紧密队形的这个事实,
The fact that you could depend
on good formation, tight formation,

208
00:21:12,312 --> 00:21:17,942
不仅能在防御战斗机攻击时帮助你,
not only helped you
in defence of fighter attack,

209
00:21:20,153 --> 00:21:25,700
它也能使你取得出色轰炸结果的机会高得多
it made your chances of achieving
good bombing results much better.

210
00:21:25,784 --> 00:21:29,537
因为如果你在轰炸,一个中队的飞机在轰炸,
Because if you're bombing,
a squadron of aeroplanes was bombing,

211
00:21:29,621 --> 00:21:33,666
而(编队)模式是一个良好,紧密的模式,
and the pattern was
a good, tight pattern,

212
00:21:33,750 --> 00:21:39,213
你的结果也必定是出色的
your results were bound to be good.

213
00:21:41,174 --> 00:21:42,967
炸弹下去了
Bombs away.

214
00:21:43,051 --> 00:21:46,512
早期对法国的空袭似乎证实了美国人的乐观主义
Early raids into France seem
bore out American optimism.

215
00:21:46,596 --> 00:21:50,141
后来,在德国上空,是一个不同的故事
Later, over Germany,
it was a different story.

216
00:21:50,225 --> 00:21:55,521
(里昂·约翰逊将军 第44轰炸机大队指挥官 荣誉勋章获得者)
他们起先发现,是的,轰炸机群能很好地应付战斗机
They found at first, yes, the bombers
could cope pretty well with the fighters

217
00:21:55,647 --> 00:21:57,606
并承受可接受的损失,
and take acceptable losses,

218
00:21:57,733 --> 00:22:00,234
如果突破不太深入,
if penetrations were not too deep,

219
00:22:00,319 --> 00:22:04,905
如果轰炸机能保持良好的队形
而且他们能互相提供支援火力
and if the bombers kept good formation and
they had supporting fire, one from the other.

220
00:22:04,990 --> 00:22:07,825
但随着时间发展,德国人也在学习
But as the time went on,
the Germans were learning too.

221
00:22:07,909 --> 00:22:11,412
所以他们学会了如何发动进攻
并学会了如何穿透队形
And so they learned how to make their attacks
and learned how to penetrate the formation.

222
00:22:11,496 --> 00:22:15,416
他们开始迎面攻击,试图干掉领头的飞机
And they started the head-on attacks,
to try to get the leader

223
00:22:15,500 --> 00:22:17,209
并分散队形
and spread out the formation.

224
00:22:17,294 --> 00:22:19,200
一旦他们把队形冲散,
Once they got the formation spread out,

225
00:22:19,200 --> 00:22:24,800
然后他们就能随意干掉轰炸机了
总之,差不多就是这样
then they could pick the bombers off
at will. More or less, anyway.

226
00:22:39,316 --> 00:22:42,568
但承认失败还太早
But it was too early to admit defeat.

227
00:22:45,100 --> 00:22:50,500
在夜晚,英国轰炸机继续飞去轰炸,
一次数百架,但每一架都独自飞行
At night, the British bombers flew on,
hundreds at a time, but each on its own.

228
00:22:51,100 --> 00:22:56,083
我们会看到他们在傍晚飞过去,一架跟着一架,
We used to see them go over in the
early evening, one by one in trail,

229
00:22:57,167 --> 00:22:59,200
我可不会跟他们交换位子
l would not have changed places
for them.

230
00:22:59,200 --> 00:23:04,840
我更情愿有密集队形,火力,
l'd much rather have
the close formation, the firepower,

231
00:23:04,925 --> 00:23:07,468
而不是以他们那种方式飞过去
than go over the way they did.

232
00:23:07,552 --> 00:23:11,180
我们和皇家空军一起飞,
你就是"孤单的查理"
Well,we are flying with the RAF,
you were Single Charlie.

233
00:23:11,264 --> 00:23:14,141
就在我们越过了荷兰海岸后,
Just after we'd crossed the Dutch coast,

234
00:23:14,226 --> 00:23:16,560
我感觉面前一声极响的"嘭"
l felt a terrific bang in my face.

235
00:23:17,100 --> 00:23:24,000
挡风玻璃被射掉了 而我的
前臂,肩膀和头都受伤了,
And the windscreen was shot away and I'd been
wounded in the forearm,the shoulder and the head.

236
00:23:24,000 --> 00:23:27,321
飞机暂时失去了控制
And the plane went out of control temporarily.

237
00:23:32,327 --> 00:23:35,000
我看不到说我受伤了有任何意义,
so I didn't see any sense
in saying that l'm wounded,

238
00:23:35,000 --> 00:23:38,500
以防他们都想,"他现在随时都会突然挂掉"
in case they all thought,
"He's going to pop off any minute now."

239
00:23:40,300 --> 00:23:44,400
又一次,高射炮(弹)在飞机
前方 我们的附近爆炸了
Again, the gun exploded
in the front of the plane beside us

240
00:23:44,400 --> 00:23:49,000
炮弹击中了站在我旁边
的工程师的前臂
and the shell hit the engineer
who stood beside me in the forearm.

241
00:23:49,000 --> 00:23:54,849
我的腿里有弹片 它们也把
我手上的皮肤给撕下来了
And I had bits in my leg and they
sort of skinned the skin off my hand.

242
00:23:55,400 --> 00:23:57,200
左升降舵被打掉了...
The port elevator had been
shot off the plane...

243
00:23:57,200 --> 00:24:02,000
那升降舵让飞机笔直飞行,
它在尾翼的两侧
that elevator it keeps the plane
straight,on each side of the tail,

244
00:24:02,000 --> 00:24:03,525
而一号升降舵被打掉了
and the port one had been shot off.

245
00:24:03,609 --> 00:24:07,000
这意味着你必须把操纵杆向后拉,一直向后,
And this meant that you had
to hold the stick back, right back,

246
00:24:07,000 --> 00:24:10,600
就好像你要象这样爬升,
才能使飞机笔直和水平地飞行
as if you're going to climb like this,
to keep the plane straight and level.

247
00:24:10,600 --> 00:24:16,000
所以轰炸瞄准员不得不来帮忙把它向后拉
因为我肩膀...这只手已经很无力了,
So the bomb aimer had to help push it back
because my shoulder was...this hand was pretty weak,

248
00:24:16,000 --> 00:24:21,793
我的肩膀被击中 而它通过影响我前面的手
正使操纵杆多多少少不断地向前倒回去
my shoulder had been hit,and it somewhat was keeping
the stick back by holding my hands in front.

249
00:24:21,878 --> 00:24:24,963
而工程师也用他另一只手,
他好的那根手臂拉着
And the engineer held it
with his other hand, his good arm.

250
00:24:25,047 --> 00:24:30,426
所以我们协力拉着它向后,
以使飞机保持笔直和水平
So we held it, combined, back,
to keep the plane straight and level.

251
00:24:30,510 --> 00:24:32,846
这不是一种"无论如何坚持下去"的感觉,
lt wasn't a "press on regardless" feeling,

252
00:24:32,930 --> 00:24:38,435
这只是四个引擎仍在飞行的现实
it was just a fact that
the four engines were still flying.

253
00:24:38,561 --> 00:24:40,700
如果我们有任何一个引擎
被打坏了,我就会想,
lf we'd had any engine cut,
l'd have thought,

254
00:24:40,700 --> 00:24:43,690
"恩,我们再也飞不下去了"
"Well, we can't get any further."

255
00:24:43,774 --> 00:24:46,651
但这里还有另一个因素是,
要是我掉头回去,
But another factor here was,
had I turned back,

256
00:24:46,777 --> 00:24:50,822
我们还有另外六七百架轰炸机
多多少少也飞在同样的航道上,
we'd have another six or seven hundred planes
that are more or less on the same track,

257
00:24:50,907 --> 00:24:53,617
分散在大约八或十英里宽
and spread something like
eight or ten miles broad

258
00:24:53,701 --> 00:24:56,745
也许有四到六千英尺(上下)深
and maybe four to six thousand feet deep.

259
00:24:56,829 --> 00:25:03,043
而你要回头正对着它们飞,
穿过这一大群才能飞回去
And you're turning back right into them,
heading through this lot to get back.

260
00:25:03,127 --> 00:25:07,672
其次,要是我拐弯,比方说
转90度,以试图避开他们,
And then again, had I turned off, say
at 90 degrees, to try and avoid them,

261
00:25:07,757 --> 00:25:10,800
你仍会穿过许多的它们(轰炸机)
you're still turning across
quite a number of them.

262
00:25:10,885 --> 00:25:14,346
然后我看着目标指示弹 并打开了炸弹舱
Then I watched the target indicators
and opened the bomb doors

263
00:25:14,430 --> 00:25:19,000
并尽我可能使飞机保持平稳,
当我盯住目标指示弹,并保持水平
and kept the plane steady as I could on the target
indicators, and just kept straight level.

264
00:25:19,000 --> 00:25:21,200
我想这很可能是他们小题大做的事情之一,
And I think this is probably one of
the things they made a fuss about,

265
00:25:21,200 --> 00:25:24,221
就是我们要在扔完炸弹后
拍一张真实目标的照片
that we'd a picture of the actual
target after all this happening.

266
00:25:24,305 --> 00:25:29,518
但我们把照片一拍完,我就掉头回基地
But as soon as we'd a picture taken,
l turned off to head for base.

267
00:25:30,811 --> 00:25:34,400
在这一次旅途中我记得感觉的事情之一
One of the things I remember
feeling on this particular trip

268
00:25:34,400 --> 00:25:38,777
就是我们必须回去,因为我知道我们受伤了
was that we had to get back,
because I knew we were wounded.

269
00:25:38,861 --> 00:25:42,600
没有其他机组成员能飞它,
甚至在正常的笔直和水平状态,
None of the other members could fly it,you know,
even on normal straight and levels,

270
00:25:42,600 --> 00:25:45,742
所以要在晚上 少掉一个
升降舵的情况下飞它,
so to fly it at night
with one elevator gone,

271
00:25:45,868 --> 00:25:50,288
把操纵杆拉到你肚皮这里
还没有仪表(导航),可以这么说,
and having the stick in your belly
and no instruments, as it were,

272
00:25:50,373 --> 00:25:52,541
应该是不太可能做到的
would've been pretty well impossible.

273
00:25:52,625 --> 00:25:57,087
我们在回去的路上又被(高射炮)
射了几次,但我们没被再次击中
We were shot at a few times on the way
back, but we weren't hit again.

274
00:25:57,171 --> 00:26:01,174
终于,我们回到英国,
当我看到这些灯标在闪烁
And eventually, we came over England,
when I saw these beacons flashing.

275
00:26:08,683 --> 00:26:12,269
当它降落时,起落架的腿
折叠着(放不下来),
As it touched down, the legs
of the undercarriage collapsed.

276
00:26:12,353 --> 00:26:16,273
我们用我们的机肚滑行了或许有50码左右
We went along on our belly
for maybe 50 yards or so.

277
00:26:16,399 --> 00:26:20,485
并停了下来 关掉引擎以控制火灾
And came to a stop. Switched off
engines to keep the fire hazard down.

278
00:26:20,570 --> 00:26:24,656
只是到了那时,我才知道领航员阵亡了,
lt was then only, that I knew
the navigator was killed,

279
00:26:24,740 --> 00:26:27,742
因为他在我身边向前滑倒
because he'd slid forward beside me.

280
00:26:28,000 --> 00:26:30,000
血结成了冰 但获得维多利亚
十字勋章的轰炸机继续飞行

281
00:26:30,000 --> 00:26:32,200
铁匠之子 威廉·雷德获得维多利亚十字勋章
(英国军队最高勋章 相当于美国荣誉勋章)

282
00:26:32,200 --> 00:26:40,000
受伤后 他用被打坏的飞机轰炸了目标并赢得维多利亚十字勋章
维多利亚十字勋章被授予一位轰炸机飞行员,他两次受伤,
缺乏氧气,他的领航员阵亡,他的无线电操作员受致命伤,
他的飞机被打坏并无法自卫,继续轰炸他的目标-杜塞尔多夫
他就是22岁的现役飞行中尉威廉·雷德,皇家空军志愿后备队
第61中队,母基地为贝列斯顿,靠近格拉斯哥

283
00:26:42,400 --> 00:26:45,194
你看到大约多少架敌军战斗机？
And about how many enemy
fighters did you see?

284
00:26:45,278 --> 00:26:48,113
我没能记录,长官,但我数到大约65架
I couldn't keep track,sir,
but I counted about 65.

285
00:26:48,198 --> 00:26:51,367
当我数到50架 我就没再数下去,长官
I stopped trying to count
when I got to 50, sir.

286
00:26:51,451 --> 00:26:56,700
我想(不用说)一般都知道
战斗服役期是出25次任务,
I think it was generally understood
that the combat tour was 25 missions,

287
00:26:56,700 --> 00:26:59,200
因为到那时候结束,你已经死了,
because you'd be dead
by the end of that time,

288
00:26:59,200 --> 00:27:03,000
所以也没有任何理由
要求你再待更长时间了
so there wasn't any point
in asking you to stay around any longer.

289
00:27:03,200 --> 00:27:06,840
轰炸机机组人员经历的是一场奇怪的战争
Bomber crews lived a curious war.

290
00:27:06,925 --> 00:27:09,385
头一天还在交战,第二天就在城里了
One day in action, the next on the town.

291
00:27:09,469 --> 00:27:12,900
(约翰·罗根 领航员/投弹员)
当我们大队不飞的时候,
When our group wasn't flying,

292
00:27:12,900 --> 00:27:14,890
(约翰·罗根 领航员/投弹员)
他们一般进伦敦城
they'd usually go into London.

293
00:27:14,974 --> 00:27:17,267
一整天都呆在伦敦
Spend the day in London.

294
00:27:17,352 --> 00:27:21,200
但有时候,如果他们还剩下些钱,
And sometimes,
if they had some money left,

295
00:27:21,200 --> 00:27:25,025
他们会打个电话查询第二天是否会有任务,
they'd call up to find out if there
was a mission going the next day,

296
00:27:25,110 --> 00:27:26,944
如果没有,他们就留着过夜
and if not, they'd stay over.

297
00:27:27,028 --> 00:27:30,239
高射炮会很猛烈,很可能也很精确,
Flak will be heavy,
probably accurate,

298
00:27:30,323 --> 00:27:32,400
但你以前经历过更糟糕的
but you've been through worse before.

299
00:27:32,400 --> 00:27:38,247
记住你最大的敌人仍然是单引擎战斗机
Remember that your biggest enemy
still is single-engine fighter planes.

300
00:27:44,129 --> 00:27:47,172
我记得在军官俱乐部的一天晚上
l recall one evening
in the officers' club.

301
00:27:47,257 --> 00:27:52,177
(约翰·柯考兰 飞行员)
我们的行动军官把威士忌倒入一个吃角子老虎机,
Our operations officer was pouring
Scotch into a one-armed bandit,

302
00:27:52,262 --> 00:27:54,972
你知道,就是你投25美分
进去的这些东西,
you know, these things
that you put quarters in,

303
00:27:55,056 --> 00:27:59,226
试图说服这机器吐出一次累计赌注
trying to persuade the machine
to deliver a jackpot.

304
00:27:59,310 --> 00:28:07,151
但...我猜这是种吃喝玩乐式的生活
But... I guess it was a kind of an eat,
drink and be merry sort of life.

305
00:28:08,278 --> 00:28:11,321
(♪ 格伦·米勒 "美国巡逻兵进行曲")
(♪ "American Patrol" by Glenn Miller)

306
00:28:18,413 --> 00:28:21,457
这次任务会很艰难
The going's gonna be rough.

307
00:28:21,541 --> 00:28:26,254
你们将不得不扳扳你们的头颈,
呆在那儿并投弹,诸位
You'll have to pull your necks in there
and stay in there and pitch, every man.

308
00:28:53,865 --> 00:28:57,800
我觉得 飞行是如此的不受个人情感影响,
(Corcoran) I think that
flying is so impersonal,

309
00:28:57,800 --> 00:28:59,870
我说的是战斗飞行,
that is to say combat flying,

310
00:28:59,954 --> 00:29:05,542
以至于如果你看到一架飞机被击落
你不会有那种痛失战友的个人感觉
that you don't get that intimate sense of loss
if you see an aeroplane get shot down

311
00:29:05,627 --> 00:29:12,674
而你会有这种感觉 如果在(地面)战场上
距你咫尺之遥的伙计的头被轰掉的话
that you'd have if your buddy on a battlefield
had his head blown off right within arm's length.

312
00:29:17,305 --> 00:29:22,000
来自英国,美国,被占领的欧洲,和英联邦的年轻人
Young men came from Britain,America, Occupied
Europe,and the British Commonwealth

313
00:29:22,000 --> 00:29:26,689
参加并死于迄今为止发动
的最坚决的一次空中攻势
took fight and die in the most
determined air offensive yet waged.

314
00:29:28,816 --> 00:29:35,489
1943年1月,在卡萨布兰卡,丘吉尔和罗斯福
决定联合起英国和美国的轰炸努力
ln January 1943, at Casablanca,Churchill and Roosevelt
decided to combine the British and American bombing efforts

315
00:29:35,615 --> 00:29:38,200
为在纳粹占领下的欧洲登陆做准备
in preparing Nazi Europe for D-day.

316
00:29:40,078 --> 00:29:43,330
U型潜艇造船厂,飞机制造厂...
U-boat yards, aircraft plants...

317
00:29:45,041 --> 00:29:47,042
..军工厂,
..armament factories,

318
00:29:47,126 --> 00:29:50,003
原油设施和运输工具,
oil installations and transport,

319
00:29:50,088 --> 00:29:55,300
被认为是进行全天候
精确轰炸的优先目标
were deemed priority targets
for round-the-clock precision bombing.

320
00:30:00,390 --> 00:30:04,560
但在夜间进行精确轰炸
对于哈里斯来说仍然是不可能的
But precision bombing at night
was still impossible for Harris.

321
00:30:04,644 --> 00:30:08,063
用特殊设计的炸弹来炸掉
鲁尔大坝的一次进攻企图
An attempt to pick off the Ruhr dams
with specially designed bombs

322
00:30:08,147 --> 00:30:10,566
只取得部分成功,
was only partially successful,

323
00:30:10,650 --> 00:30:14,069
并付出了一些最好的机组成员的生命
and cost the lives
of some of the best aircrews.

324
00:30:24,455 --> 00:30:30,377
尽管这次攻击导致后来的轰炸精确度
有所提高,但不是所有的大坝都被击中
Though the raid led to improved accuracy
later on, not all the dams were hit.

325
00:30:30,461 --> 00:30:34,172
鲁尔的军工生产未受影响
Ruhr arms production was unaffected.

326
00:30:34,257 --> 00:30:38,260
哈里斯相信只有发动夜间区域轰炸的猛攻
Harris believed that only the mounting
onslaught of night area bombing

327
00:30:38,344 --> 00:30:41,346
才能摧毁德国的工业能力
would crush German industrial capacity.

328
00:30:41,431 --> 00:30:44,766
在这个时候,我们正得到更好的飞机
(Mahaddie) At this time,
we were getting better aircraft.

329
00:30:44,892 --> 00:30:47,394
"兰开斯特"轰炸机正被大量生产出来
The Lancaster was coming out in great numbers.

330
00:30:47,478 --> 00:30:52,733
我们正在减少不那么有效率的
"斯特林"和"哈利法克斯"轰炸机
We were losing the less efficient
Stirling and the Halifax.

331
00:30:52,817 --> 00:30:55,152
我们正得到更好的雷达设备
We were getting better radar devices.

332
00:30:55,236 --> 00:31:01,074
我们有极其出色的领航员,
经过挑选的领航员
And we had extremely good navigators,
selected navigators.

333
00:31:01,159 --> 00:31:03,410
而这是整件事情的实质
And this was the essence
of the whole thing.

334
00:31:03,494 --> 00:31:11,084
而这些领航员能把飞机带到离瞄准点
比我们以前(到的位置)近得多的地方
And these navigators were able to get much closer
to an aiming point than we had previously.

335
00:31:11,169 --> 00:31:16,006
(哈米什·马哈迪 皇家空军探路机中队)
然后我们撒下大量照明弹,数以百计的照明弹
Then we laid great lanes of flares,
hundreds of flares.

336
00:31:16,090 --> 00:31:18,175
即使我们错过了瞄准点,
Even if we missed the aiming point,

337
00:31:18,259 --> 00:31:24,681
我们也能认出地面上一些非常明确的特征,
we would identify some
very positive feature on the ground,

338
00:31:24,766 --> 00:31:28,185
象一座湖或河上的一个弯曲
like a lake or a bend in the river.

339
00:31:28,269 --> 00:31:31,355
而从那里,我们就能慢慢靠近目标
And from there,
we could then creep on to the target

340
00:31:31,439 --> 00:31:35,484
并放下照明弹,不同颜色的照明弹
and put flares down,
different coloured flares.

341
00:31:35,568 --> 00:31:38,654
再后来,我们有了目标指示弹
And then later on,
we got target indicators.

342
00:31:38,738 --> 00:31:45,327
而这些是...就想象一下一大串白炽的葡萄
And these were... Just imagine
a great bunch of incandescent grapes

343
00:31:45,411 --> 00:31:52,501
从2,000, 4,000(英尺) 无论
我们想引燃它们的高度落下
falling from 2,000, 4,000, wherever
we wanted them to detonate from.

344
00:31:53,336 --> 00:31:55,671
1943年7月底,
At the end of July 1943,

345
00:31:55,755 --> 00:32:01,093
哈里斯部署了他改进过的科技
结果在汉堡取得毁灭性的效果
Harris deployed his improving technology
with devastating effect on Hamburg.

346
00:32:01,177 --> 00:32:10,310
第一次汉堡空袭如此有效
是由于我们终于获得允许
(Harris) The effectiveness of the first Hamburg
raid was due to us at last getting permission

347
00:32:10,395 --> 00:32:13,814
使用我们在包里放了很长时间的一件东西,
to use something we'd had
in the bag for a long time,

348
00:32:13,898 --> 00:32:16,441
它被称为"窗户",
which was known as "window",

349
00:32:16,526 --> 00:32:21,488
也就是撒下一团团铝纸箔,
which was the dropping
of clouds of aluminium paper strips,

350
00:32:21,572 --> 00:32:27,327
它不仅完全扰乱了德国人的定位仪器,
which completely upset
not only the German location apparatus,

351
00:32:27,412 --> 00:32:30,163
而且还使它们的高炮瞄准装置无法使用
but also their gun-aiming apparatus.

352
00:32:49,350 --> 00:32:53,270
我们中没有人,无论是平民还是消防员,
None of us,neither civilians nor firemen,

353
00:32:53,354 --> 00:32:56,523
知道这个晚上发生了什么
knew what happened on this night.

354
00:32:56,607 --> 00:32:58,900
这是一次非常猛烈的空袭,
lt was a very heavy raid,

355
00:32:58,985 --> 00:33:04,614
(汉斯·布伦斯威格 汉堡消防官员)
但我们在一年前有过一次几乎一样的空袭
but we had almost the same one year before.

356
00:33:05,241 --> 00:33:12,664
我们没有为在空袭后半个小时
爆发的火风暴做好准备
We were not prepared for the fire storm
which broke out half an hour after the raid.

357
00:33:16,544 --> 00:33:20,046
轰炸的效果,和一股夏天的热浪汇合起来,
The effect of the bombing,
combined with a summer heat wave,

358
00:33:20,131 --> 00:33:23,508
将引起一场人造的火焰旋风
was to create
a man-made tornado of flame.

359
00:33:23,593 --> 00:33:25,677
一场火风暴
A fire storm.

360
00:33:28,598 --> 00:33:32,559
这整个地区都有水道穿过...
Und diese ganze Gegend
wurde von Kanälen...

361
00:33:32,643 --> 00:33:35,479
我去了靠近码头的这个地区
I went to this area near the docks.

362
00:33:35,563 --> 00:33:37,647
(本·威特 汉堡记者)
它被许多水道穿过
lt was crossed by canals.

363
00:33:37,732 --> 00:33:41,568
人们试图从火焰中跳入其中，
People tried to leap down into them
out of the flames,

364
00:33:41,652 --> 00:33:43,820
但水也着了火
but the water was on fire.

365
00:33:50,787 --> 00:33:54,873
很难解释为什么水也在燃烧
lt's difficult to explain
why the water was burning.

366
00:33:54,957 --> 00:34:00,253
有许多船,小船,停泊在水道中
There were many ships, small ships,
moored in the canals.

367
00:34:00,338 --> 00:34:06,218
它们已经爆炸了,而燃烧
的汽油已经被释放到水中
They had exploded, and burning oil
had been released onto the water.

368
00:34:08,095 --> 00:34:12,933
而人们,他们自己就已着了火,跳了进去
And the people, who were themselves
on fire, jumped into it.

369
00:34:13,017 --> 00:34:19,022
他们燃烧,游泳,燃烧,沉没
And they burnt, swam,
burnt and went under.

370
00:34:41,504 --> 00:34:46,132
大多数人被狂暴的高温杀死,
Most people were killed by the fierce heat,

371
00:34:46,259 --> 00:34:53,306
不是烧死 或窒息而死 或被一氧化碳毒死
not burnt or suffocated
or poisoned by carbon monoxide.

372
00:34:53,432 --> 00:34:56,101
我们认为在一些地方,
We think that in some places,

373
00:34:56,185 --> 00:35:02,274
温度达到了1,000摄氏度
the temperature reached 1,000 degrees centigrade.

374
00:35:05,987 --> 00:35:11,324
英国人的夜间空袭和美国人
的日间空袭持续了几乎一周
The British night attacks and American
day raids lasted nearly a week.

375
00:35:11,409 --> 00:35:13,410
30,000人死亡
30,000 died.

376
00:35:13,494 --> 00:35:19,958
在汉堡,我们真的第一次发现
ln Hamburg, we really
found out the first time

377
00:35:20,042 --> 00:35:25,463
德国人民的士气能被打击得如此厉害
that the morale of the German people
can be shattered so much

378
00:35:25,548 --> 00:35:33,263
以至于工业的生产,军工产业的生产,会崩溃
that work for industry,the work in
the armaments industry, would collapse.

379
00:35:39,478 --> 00:35:45,650
当时,斯佩尔说 再来六次
这样的空袭将会结束战争
At the time, Speer said six more raids
like that would have finished the war.

380
00:35:48,779 --> 00:35:52,115
盟军没有那种能力
The Allies did not have that capacity.

381
00:35:54,785 --> 00:35:57,078
冲击过去了
The shock passed.

382
00:36:01,208 --> 00:36:08,632
与此同时,(美国)第八航空队提高了
其针对精确目标的日间空袭的强度
At the same time, the Eighth Air Force had stepped up the
intensity of its daylight raids against precise targets.

383
00:36:08,758 --> 00:36:12,594
下一个大队将从13,000英尺高度投弹
Next group will bomb
from an altitude of 13,000 feet.

384
00:36:15,097 --> 00:36:21,895
我们感觉这种低高度(投弹的优势)
将被我们会遇到的惊骇元素所抵消
We feel that this low altitude will be equalised
by the element of surprise which is with us.

385
00:36:23,814 --> 00:36:30,570
汉堡轰炸的两个星期后,他们计划
对德国工业进行一次他们的致命打击
Two weeks after Hamburg,they planned to deal
their knockout blow against German industry.

386
00:36:30,655 --> 00:36:32,322
请打开灯
Lights, please.

387
00:36:32,406 --> 00:36:36,618
这里的这组建筑是你们的目标
This group of buildings here
is your target.

388
00:36:36,702 --> 00:36:39,788
这幢建筑将是瞄准点
This building will be the aiming point.

389
00:36:39,872 --> 00:36:43,500
如果你们的炸弹散布面
集中在这个区域,
lf your bomb pattern
is concentrated in this area,

390
00:36:43,584 --> 00:36:47,379
应该会非常有效地摧毁该工厂
it should very effectively
knock out the factory.

391
00:36:47,505 --> 00:36:51,174
目标是位于施韦因富特的滚珠轴承工厂,
The target was the
ball-bearing factories at Schweinfurt,

392
00:36:51,258 --> 00:36:54,135
其生产满足了德国的大部分需求
producing a major part
of Germany's needs.

393
00:37:40,057 --> 00:37:43,018
攻击部队被一分为二
The attacking force
was to be split into two.

394
00:37:43,102 --> 00:37:45,770
第一波将攻击一个次要目标,
The first wave would fight
to a secondary target,

395
00:37:45,855 --> 00:37:49,357
位于雷根斯堡的梅塞施米特式战斗机制造厂
the Messerschmitt aircraft plant
at Regensburg.

396
00:37:49,442 --> 00:37:52,694
然后它将不受阻碍的飞往北非
Then it would fly on unhindered
to North Africa.

397
00:37:52,778 --> 00:37:55,405
第二波(轰炸机群),
距第一波后方10分钟(航程),
The second wave,
ten minutes behind the first,

398
00:37:55,489 --> 00:37:57,449
接着会抵达施韦因富特,
would then arrive at Schweinfurt,

399
00:37:57,533 --> 00:38:00,910
正当德国战斗机在地面加油时
whilst the German fighters
were on the ground refuelling.

400
00:38:00,995 --> 00:38:04,080
他们的战斗将发生在返航途中
Their battle
would be during the trip home.

401
00:38:05,875 --> 00:38:09,169
我们...我根本没有任何战斗护航就飞进去了,
We went in...I went in without
any fighter escort at all,

402
00:38:09,253 --> 00:38:19,345
(柯蒂斯·李梅将军 第三航空师(第一波)指挥官)
和当时我所在师的125架轰炸机一起
在没有战斗机护航的情况下飞越欧洲
and flew clear across Europe without fighter escort,with
about 125 aeroplanes that I had in the division at the time.

403
00:38:21,265 --> 00:38:29,522
随着第一波轰炸机群越来越深入德国
惊讶的德国防空参谋部将其航道标绘出来
Astonished German air defence staff plotted the path of
the first wave as it flew further and further into Germany.

404
00:38:30,441 --> 00:38:33,610
他们不知道计划正在出错
They could not tell
the plan was going wrong.

405
00:38:33,694 --> 00:38:37,280
英国的天气扰乱了美国人的精心计划
British weather helped to upset
the Americans' careful plans.

406
00:38:37,406 --> 00:38:40,784
未曾预料到的低云推迟了第二波
(轰炸机群)的起飞(四个小时)
Unexpected low cloud
delayed the takeoff of the second wave.

407
00:38:40,868 --> 00:38:44,120
结果是:加满了油料和补充了弹药的德国空军,
The result: the Luftwaffe,
refuelled and re-armed,

408
00:38:44,205 --> 00:38:45,830
正在等着他们
was waiting for them.

409
00:38:45,915 --> 00:38:53,129
(沃纳·施罗尔 德国日间战斗机领导人 战绩为114架
160位双剑银橡叶骑士铁十字勋章获得者之一)
我们没有预料到 会在没有战斗机护航
的情况下 如此深入国境进行一次攻击
Well, we didn't expect an attack coming that
far into the country without fighter escort.

410
00:38:53,214 --> 00:38:56,424
我们都非常惊讶
And we were all very astonished.

411
00:39:00,387 --> 00:39:03,556
没有 请求维克多
Null. Anfrage Viktor.

412
00:39:28,249 --> 00:39:35,088
施韦因富特(的大胜)是
非常有利于德国战斗机的条件,
Schweinfurt was the result of very good
conditions in favour of German fighters,

413
00:39:35,172 --> 00:39:42,011
以及我们能把我们所有的战斗机都投入
截击轰炸机群这么一个事实的结果
and the fact we could bring all our fighters
into operation to intercept the bomber stream.

414
00:39:42,096 --> 00:39:47,016
(阿道夫·加兰德将军 德国战斗机总监)
这些因素加在一起促成了我们的(胜利)结果
This altogether has favoured our results.

415
00:39:51,856 --> 00:39:58,945
21架(B-17)飞行堡垒在首批炸弹
落在施韦因富特前就被击落了
21 Flying Fortresses were lost before
the first bomb fell on Schweinfurt.

416
00:40:05,911 --> 00:40:09,581
随后到达的第一航空师(第二波),
遭受了更惨重的损失,
(Lemay) The first division,
coming in later, had heavier losses,

417
00:40:09,665 --> 00:40:13,710
因为他们除了要飞进去 还必须飞回去
because they had to go back out
in addition to coming in.

418
00:40:13,794 --> 00:40:17,922
我想我们在那天结束后
损失了大约60架飞机,
l think we wound up the day
by losing about 60 aeroplanes,

419
00:40:18,007 --> 00:40:21,843
那让任何人都高兴不起来
which didn't make anybody very happy.

420
00:40:23,345 --> 00:40:26,347
我再次爬升 并俯冲到底...
Ich kam dann noch mal hoch und bin
von unten ins Ziel und...

421
00:40:26,473 --> 00:40:28,558
然后把它打成碎片
hat dann prima hingehauen.

422
00:40:56,212 --> 00:40:58,254
代价高昂
The cost was high.

423
00:40:58,339 --> 00:41:02,383
但滚珠轴承的生产被中断了六个星期
But ball-bearing production
was disrupted for six weeks.

424
00:41:02,468 --> 00:41:07,597
当一开始你击中了施韦因富特,
(Speer) When you hit Schweinfurt first,

425
00:41:07,681 --> 00:41:12,310
那真是噩梦成真
it was a nightmare getting true.

426
00:41:12,394 --> 00:41:16,564
但是接着,我有一个非常好的代表,凯斯勒,
But then, I had a very good
representative, Kessler,

427
00:41:16,649 --> 00:41:21,527
而他用尽了一切手段,不仅仅是维修,
and he did with all means,
not only the repair,

428
00:41:21,612 --> 00:41:27,659
还用其他设备代替了滚珠轴承
but also the replacement
of ball bearings with other devices

429
00:41:27,743 --> 00:41:30,954
而这(种代替品)也能用,
which could do the job,

430
00:41:31,038 --> 00:41:34,207
(尽管)不象滚珠轴承那么好用,但也可以用
not as good as a ball bearing,
but it could be done.

431
00:41:38,963 --> 00:41:40,800
在这次两波的攻击中,
ln the two-wave attack,

432
00:41:40,800 --> 00:41:45,468
超过120架飞机被击落或被打坏到无法维修
over 120 aircraft were lost
or damaged beyond repair.

433
00:41:45,552 --> 00:41:50,265
为了在施韦因富特证明他们的观点,
美国人将不得不再回去(继续轰炸)
To prove their point at Schweinfurt,
the Americans would have to go back.

434
00:41:50,349 --> 00:41:56,729
(艾拉·埃克 空军中将 第八航空队司令)
自然地,我感到强烈地失望,
很大程度上是因为要派我的机组回去,
Naturally, I was keenly disappointed,
largely because in sending my crews back,

435
00:41:56,814 --> 00:42:00,024
我知道他们将蒙受额外的损失
l knew they would sustain
additional losses.

436
00:42:00,109 --> 00:42:02,777
如果我们第一次就完成任务,
lf we had done the job right
in the first place,

437
00:42:02,861 --> 00:42:05,446
我们本可以避免这些损失
we could have avoided these losses.

438
00:42:05,531 --> 00:42:11,077
但没人会在开枪的时候
每次都命中他的目标
But nobody who fires a gun
hits his target every time.

439
00:42:11,161 --> 00:42:13,788
我们回去是因为我们有好天气
We went back
because we got good weather

440
00:42:13,872 --> 00:42:16,874
而这是我们的最优先目标
and it was our highest priority target.

441
00:42:16,959 --> 00:42:18,918
那就是我们为什么要回去
That's why we returned.

442
00:42:20,671 --> 00:42:25,591
(1943年)10月14日,差不多
300架轰炸机在英国上空集结
On 14th October, some 300 bombers
were marshalled over England.

443
00:42:26,302 --> 00:42:29,804
英国上空到处有飞机在爬升
(Rogan) There were aeroplanes
climbing all over England.

444
00:42:29,888 --> 00:42:31,639
英国真的就是个机场
England was just an airport,really.

445
00:42:31,724 --> 00:42:36,519
而我觉得,这真的很难
And this, I think, was real difficult.

446
00:42:38,439 --> 00:42:44,902
把大量重型轰炸机编成
一个紧密队形要花一些时间
lt took some time to group a large number
of heavy bombers into a tight formation.

447
00:42:44,987 --> 00:42:51,701
这些复杂的机动给了德国空军关于一支
攻击部队的实力和方向的足够警报
These complicated manoeuvres gave ample warning to the Luftwaffe
of the strength and direction of an attacking force.

448
00:42:51,785 --> 00:42:57,832
德国全部战斗机的三分之二
现在被集中起来对付第八航空队
Two thirds of all German fighters were now
concentrated against the Eighth Air Force.

449
00:42:57,916 --> 00:43:00,293
战斗机 他真是(吓人的)夜魔人
(Stewart) For the fighter,he was the boogie man.

450
00:43:00,377 --> 00:43:08,092
战斗机有眼线,并且在很多情况下,
The fighter had eyes
and, in a great many instances,

451
00:43:08,177 --> 00:43:14,057
战斗机都有一个非常有能力
的家伙坐在操纵装置前
the fighter had a pretty competent fella
at the controls.

452
00:43:14,141 --> 00:43:21,606
而当他缠住你时,许多时候你都会有麻烦
And when he latched on to you,
you were in trouble lots of times.

453
00:43:21,690 --> 00:43:26,319
我(离那架轰炸机)是如此之近
以至于我真的能看到后炮塔的炮手
l was that close
that I could really see the rear gunner.

454
00:43:26,403 --> 00:43:31,199
我看到他就跟我一样的害怕
l saw him as frightened as I was.

455
00:43:35,412 --> 00:43:39,624
他们在他们的内部通讯系统中
大声叫出战斗机的位置
(Rogan) They'd call the positions
of the fighters out over their intercom.

456
00:43:39,708 --> 00:43:44,754
有时候他们是如此害怕
以至于他们继续按着麦克风,
Sometimes they'd get so frightened that
they'd continue to hold the microphone down,

457
00:43:44,880 --> 00:43:48,674
并不断对着麦克风叫喊
and keep hollering into the microphone.

458
00:43:51,011 --> 00:44:00,311
他们从几乎是1,000米开外,
开始用他们的曳光弹扫射,为了吓唬我们
And they started at 1,000 metres,almost,with
their tracing ammunition, in order to frighten us.

459
00:44:00,396 --> 00:44:04,982
而我告诉我没有经验的年轻飞行员,
And I told my younger pilots,
who had no experience,

460
00:44:05,067 --> 00:44:09,278
闭上他们的眼睛,从后面攻击
to close their eyes,
attacking from behind.

461
00:44:13,700 --> 00:44:18,663
没有很多时间思考
你只是打开那机枪瞄准器
(Rogan) There wasn't much time to think.
You just put that gun sight on

462
00:44:18,747 --> 00:44:22,625
不断四处摇动你的脑袋
寻找敌人的战斗机
and kept waving your head around
looking for enemy fighters

463
00:44:22,709 --> 00:44:25,211
并把瞄准器套准它们
and kept the gun sight on 'em.

464
00:44:26,380 --> 00:44:29,507
驾驶员致领航员,怎么样了?
Pilot to navigator, what's the word?

465
00:44:29,591 --> 00:44:31,217
我们正在投弹
We're making the run.

466
00:44:31,301 --> 00:44:34,637
就在我们命中目标前是最糟糕的部分
(Rogan) Right before we hit the target
was the worst part.

467
00:44:34,763 --> 00:44:38,433
我们被战斗机发现,被带到
目标上方 它们离开了,
We got picked up by fighters, were
taken into the target and they left,

468
00:44:38,517 --> 00:44:42,854
我们扔完炸弹 他们在
我们离开目标后又盯上我们
and we dropped the bombs
and they picked us up after the target.

469
00:44:46,316 --> 00:44:52,113
在施韦因富特 超过全部滚珠
轴承生产(能力)的60%被摧毁了
More than 60% of all ball-bearing production
at Schweinfurt was destroyed.

470
00:44:52,197 --> 00:44:56,492
美国人损失了超过60架的空中堡垒
The Americans had lost
more than 60 Flying Fortresses.

471
00:44:57,744 --> 00:45:01,205
要是你们在那不久之后再重复那些空袭,
lf you would have repeated those raids
shortly afterwards,

472
00:45:01,290 --> 00:45:04,792
那就不会给我们时间来重建
it wouldn't have given us
the time to rebuild.

473
00:45:04,877 --> 00:45:08,296
那么这就将会是一个灾难性的后果
Then it would have been
a disastrous result.

474
00:45:08,422 --> 00:45:13,134
你能不能承受部队蒙受的损失
当你不知道你是否完成了任务?
Could you take the losses the forces took
when you didn't know if you'd accomplish it?

475
00:45:13,218 --> 00:45:17,430
当你以为(德国的)滚珠轴承
是从瑞典和瑞士进口的?
When you thought ball bearings were
coming in from Sweden and Switzerland?

476
00:45:17,514 --> 00:45:20,266
你不知道 你不会继续那些事情(指轰炸)
You didn't know.
You don't go on with those things.

477
00:45:20,350 --> 00:45:30,276
所以战略从精确轰炸象施韦因富特这样
的目标 摆回到又一次夜间区域空袭:柏林
So the strategy swung back from pinpoint targets like
Schweinfurt to another night area offensive: Berlin.

478
00:45:30,861 --> 00:45:35,406
在美国人的帮助下,哈里斯相信
他能在六个月里摧毁柏林
With American support, Harris believed
he could wreck Berlin in six months

479
00:45:35,491 --> 00:45:37,450
并赢得战争
and win the war.

480
00:45:37,534 --> 00:45:41,871
但元气大伤的第八航空队
现在不能加入他(的轰炸)
But the depleted Eighth Air Force
were not now able to join him.

481
00:45:41,997 --> 00:45:46,751
他发出了最令人惊讶的信号
这个信号我一直都记得...
He sent the most amazing signals.
And one that l'll always remember...

482
00:45:46,835 --> 00:45:52,340
这是你在简报会上向
你的机组成员们读的那种东西...
and this is the sort of thing
you read out to your crews at briefing...

483
00:45:52,424 --> 00:45:55,134
这篇东西是这么说的:
this one went on to say:

484
00:45:55,219 --> 00:45:58,596
"今晚你们要去这座大城市"
那是柏林
"Tonight you go to the big city."
That's Berlin.

485
00:45:58,680 --> 00:46:03,017
"你们有机会在敌人的肚皮上点一把火
"You have the opportunity to light
a fire in the belly of the enemy

486
00:46:03,101 --> 00:46:05,478
并把他的黑心烧出来"
and burn his black heart out."

487
00:46:12,694 --> 00:46:16,447
机组成员们,在他们停止那样的欢呼后,
Well, crews, after they stopped
cheering a thing like that,

488
00:46:16,532 --> 00:46:18,491
他们不想要飞机
they didn't want aircraft.

489
00:46:18,575 --> 00:46:21,202
你只能在他们的口袋里塞满炸弹
You could just fill their pockets
with bombs

490
00:46:21,286 --> 00:46:25,581
并把柏林指给他们看
他们就会自己出发
and point them towards Berlin
and they'd take off on their own.

491
00:46:29,002 --> 00:46:32,296
(皇家空军)轰炸机司令部
不得不独自继续(轰炸)
Bomber Command
had to go on on its own.

492
00:46:32,381 --> 00:46:38,010
这是条很长的路,而1943年底的天气特别糟糕
lt was a long way, and the weather
at the end of 1943 was particularly bad.

493
00:46:38,136 --> 00:46:44,809
但每晚,轰炸机群都杀开一条血路
直扑柏林和其他德国内陆城市
But each night, the bombers fought their way
to Berlin and other cities deep in Germany.

494
00:46:49,815 --> 00:46:53,943
哈里斯的机组造成了可怕的损失
Harris' crews wrought terrible damage.

495
00:46:58,574 --> 00:47:01,534
柏林正尝到全面战争的真正滋味
Berlin is getting a real taste of total war.

496
00:47:01,618 --> 00:47:06,330
皇家空军的突击对纳粹德国首都造成的
极大压力已令匈奴人(德国人)摇摇晃晃
The terrific weight of RAF assaults on the
capital of Naziland has set the Hun reeling.

497
00:47:06,415 --> 00:47:12,837
他(现在)对他在华沙,鹿特丹,贝尔格莱德,伦敦,考文垂
和其他地方进行的残忍空袭 一定该有多么后悔
How he must regret the ruthless attacks he made on
Warsaw, Rotterdam,Belgrade, London,Coventry and the rest.

498
00:47:12,921 --> 00:47:15,172
日日夜夜的报应就在这里
The day and night of reckoning is here.

499
00:47:15,257 --> 00:47:17,341
对此你作何感想,基斯?
And what do you think of it, Keith?

500
00:47:17,426 --> 00:47:21,554
德国佬这次绝对尝到了厉害
这肯定是一次杰出的轰炸
Jerry definitely had it this time.
lt certainly was a wizard prang.

501
00:47:30,689 --> 00:47:36,200
但许多柏林的办公室和工厂仍能继续运行
Yet many of Berlin's offices
and factories managed to go on working.

502
00:47:38,363 --> 00:47:44,493
以我的经验来看,人们已经相当麻木了
(Speer) In my experience,
people rather got numb.

503
00:47:44,578 --> 00:47:49,540
他们就象影子一样穿过街道
They were going through the streets
like shadows.

504
00:47:49,625 --> 00:47:53,336
但他们仍象机器人一样工作
But they were still working
like automats.

505
00:48:30,624 --> 00:48:33,334
我们到那儿基本上没什么困难,
We had very little trouble
in getting there,

506
00:48:33,418 --> 00:48:42,551
但我注意到的一件事是 每个德国城镇现在似乎
都不分青红皂白地发射高射炮的这种邪恶方式
but one thing I did notice was the vicious
way in which every German town now seems
to throw up flak indiscriminately.

507
00:48:42,636 --> 00:48:48,516
在汉堡大获全胜的科技优势不再适用
The technological advantages which
prevailed over Hamburg no longer applied.

508
00:48:48,600 --> 00:48:53,270
德国的防空已经又一次跳到了前面
The German air defence
had leapfrogged ahead once more.

509
00:49:00,070 --> 00:49:03,948
柏林看来似乎的确仍是柏林
Berlin looked as if
it would indeed remain Berlin.

510
00:49:04,032 --> 00:49:06,826
(♪ "柏林仍然是柏林")
(♪ "Berlin bleibt doch Berlin")

511
00:49:22,801 --> 00:49:28,514
到1944年早春,哈里斯
还没有完全摧毁这座城市
By early spring, 1944, Harris
had not totally destroyed the city.

512
00:50:01,047 --> 00:50:04,592
轰炸机司令部已被德国人凶狠地伤害了
Bomber Command had been
savagely mauled by the Germans.

513
00:50:04,676 --> 00:50:09,054
在那四个月里,在针对
柏林和其他目标的空袭中,
ln those four months, in raids
against Berlin and other targets,

514
00:50:09,139 --> 00:50:14,518
1,000架飞机,(轰炸机)司令部
的一线力量,被损失掉了
1,000 aircraft, the Command's
first-line strength, were lost.

515
00:50:15,353 --> 00:50:18,898
但哈里斯当时没有,
现在也没有,承认失败
But Harris did not,
and does not, concede defeat.

516
00:50:18,982 --> 00:50:21,525
(轰炸)柏林战役的伤亡
(Harris) The casualties
in the Battle of Berlin

517
00:50:21,610 --> 00:50:29,909
并不比 如果我们去德国其他地方,
深入德国会遭受的损失多(多少)
were no more than we would have suffered if we'd
gone anywhere else in Germany,deep into Germany.

518
00:50:29,993 --> 00:50:35,706
人们似乎忘记了轰炸机司令部
在战争期间进行了1,000多次战斗
People seem to forget that Bomber Command
fought 1,000 battles during the war.

519
00:50:35,791 --> 00:50:37,666
你不可能每次都成功
You can't succeed in every one.

520
00:50:37,751 --> 00:50:42,046
我不是说柏林战役是一次失败
或类似失败的什么东西
l'm not saying the Battle of Berlin
was a defeat or anything like a defeat.

521
00:50:42,130 --> 00:50:47,092
我认为它对打败德国作出了主要贡献
l think it was a major contribution
towards the defeat of Germany.

522
00:50:47,177 --> 00:50:51,597
有数以千计的重型高射炮,
There were thousands
of heavy anti-aircraft guns,

523
00:50:51,723 --> 00:50:56,310
数以百万计的用于它们的炮弹,
millions of ammunition for them,

524
00:50:56,394 --> 00:51:04,443
以及几十万从我们在东线
的战斗中被拉来的士兵,
and hundreds of thousands of soldiers,which were
torn away from our fight in the Eastern Front.

525
00:51:04,528 --> 00:51:09,240
所以我应该说,有了对德国的空袭,
So I should say,
with air attacks on Germany,

526
00:51:09,324 --> 00:51:13,160
你们有了,在一个很早的阶段,从43年起,
you had, in an early stage, from '43 on,

527
00:51:13,245 --> 00:51:15,788
真正地一个所谓的第二战场
really a so-called second front.

528
00:51:20,293 --> 00:51:24,129
尽管所有这些破坏,德国人仍继续(战争)
Despite all the devastation,
the Germans carried on.

529
00:51:24,214 --> 00:51:29,718
德国工业仍在向 在东线和
在意大利凶猛作战的军队提供补给
German industry was still supplying the armies
fighting fiercely in the east and in ltaly.

530
00:51:29,803 --> 00:51:34,723
战略轰炸理论至今仍未被证明
The strategic bombing thesis
remained as yet unproven.

531
00:51:40,063 --> 00:51:43,774
施韦因富特的教训被美国人牢牢汲取
The lessons of Schweinfurt
had been well learnt by the Americans.

532
00:51:43,859 --> 00:51:47,778
重新装备后,他们在1944年3月
与皇家空军联手轰炸柏林
Re-equipped, they joined the RAF
over Berlin in March 1944.

533
00:51:47,863 --> 00:51:50,155
但现在他们由"野马"(P-51型)战斗机护航,
But now they were escorted
by the Mustang,

534
00:51:50,240 --> 00:51:53,450
一种改变了一切的卓越战机
a remarkable aeroplane
which was to change everything.

535
00:51:53,535 --> 00:51:56,579
它有着一架轰炸机的航程
和一架战斗机的性能
lt had a bomber's range
and a fighter's performance.

536
00:51:56,663 --> 00:52:00,332
德国日间战斗机现在遇到了对手
The German day fighter
had now met its match.

537
00:52:06,047 --> 00:52:12,720
到1944年春末,德国日间战斗机已输掉了(英国)
喷火式和飓风式战斗机(在不列颠战役)中曾取得的胜利
By the end of spring 1944,the German day fighter
had lost where the Spitfire and Hurricane had won.

538
00:52:12,804 --> 00:52:18,642
美国人终于用他们的长程战斗机
在白天的欧洲上空打败了德国空军
The Americans had finally beaten the Luftwaffe over
daylight Europe with their long-range fighters.

539
00:52:19,895 --> 00:52:25,482
我们没有与之匹敌的飞机
We had nothing of the same effort.

540
00:52:25,567 --> 00:52:29,737
我想它们把我们吓得够呛
And I think they frightened us quite a bit.

541
00:52:29,821 --> 00:52:35,826
我觉得主要的担心是他们显示出的数量
l think the main concern was the quantities
in which they were showing up.

542
00:52:40,957 --> 00:52:45,127
在白天 德国人已失去他们领空的制空权
The Germans had lost control
of their air space in daylight.

543
00:52:45,211 --> 00:52:51,884
从此,盟军将能随心所欲地向德国发起日间空袭
From now on, the Allies would be able to
launch day raids over Germany at will.

544
00:53:00,977 --> 00:53:05,189
但,在1944年3月,
But, in March 1944,

545
00:53:05,273 --> 00:53:11,362
(英美)两支轰炸机部队均被置于艾森
豪威尔的统一指挥下 以准备D日登陆
both bomber forces were placed under Eisenhower's
overall command to prepare for D-day.

546
00:53:11,446 --> 00:53:19,954
在盟军轰炸机能再次出发 以粉碎德国
人民的意志前,将有六个月的休整期,
There would be six months' respite before the Allied bombers
could set out once more,to break the will of the German people.

