1
00:00:12,303 --> 00:00:17,725
1940年夏天的柏林 迎接难以置信的胜利
Berlin in the summer of 1940
welcomed victory beyond belief.

2
00:00:23,189 --> 00:00:28,318
第三帝国的士兵在仅仅一年的战争后就回了家
The soldiers of the Third Reich
came home after only a year of war.

3
00:00:28,403 --> 00:00:30,446
他们已征服了法国
They had conquered France.

4
00:00:30,530 --> 00:00:33,449
中北欧也已陷落
Central and northern Europe
had fallen, too.

5
00:00:33,533 --> 00:00:37,786
这些人群由于狂喜和解脱而极度兴奋
These crowds were delirious
with exultation and relief.

6
00:00:40,123 --> 00:00:44,710
他们变得对他们的元首极度感激
They turned to their Führer
in a frenzy of gratitude.

7
00:00:55,972 --> 00:00:59,516
他们并不喜欢战争
他们害怕战败
They had not fancied war.
They had feared defeat.

8
00:00:59,601 --> 00:01:02,600
现在他们以为战争已经结束
Now they thought the war was over

9
00:01:02,600 --> 00:01:05,272
他们深感欣喜
and they rejoiced.

10
00:02:05,458 --> 00:02:06,800
士兵们回家了
The men came home.

11
00:02:06,800 --> 00:02:10,879
他们肤色黝黑 身体健康
他们中只有一些人阵亡了
They were brown and fit
and only a few of them had died.

12
00:02:18,388 --> 00:02:23,500
我正去购物 就在这时有人对我说,
"你听到那声音了吗?"
I just went shopping when somebody
told me,"Don't you hear the noise?"

13
00:02:23,500 --> 00:02:28,313
在那儿我看到了这支凯旋归来的军队就在我们附近
And there I saw this part of the army
coming back just near us.

14
00:02:28,398 --> 00:02:33,318
所以我买了一碗樱桃 并跑到那里
So I bought a bowl of cherries
and ran there.

15
00:02:36,406 --> 00:02:38,907
我们全都如此高兴
We all were so glad.

16
00:02:38,992 --> 00:02:46,123
我们听说了如此多的关于第一次世界大战
的那些可怕战役和那么多人战死沙场
We heard so much of the First World War with
those dreadful battles and those many dead.

17
00:02:46,207 --> 00:02:52,171
(玛琳·特金)
我们如此快地结束战争让我感到一种民族自豪
l felt a sort of national pride
we ended the war so quick.

18
00:02:55,884 --> 00:02:58,093
在未受战争影响的城市里,
ln cities untouched by war,

19
00:02:58,178 --> 00:03:01,805
德国人民还没有开始放弃和平的生活方式
the German people had hardly begun
to give up the ways of peace.

20
00:03:01,890 --> 00:03:04,099
有定量配给,甚至短缺,
There was rationing, even shortages,

21
00:03:04,184 --> 00:03:08,604
但为了弥补这一点,
(纳粹)政权鼓吹欢乐,奢侈
but to make up for it,
the regime preached enjoyment, luxury.

22
00:03:08,688 --> 00:03:11,940
(♪ "罗莎蒙德")
(♪ "Rosamunde")

23
00:03:22,619 --> 00:03:25,100
当英国人已宣布(消费)
不必要的东西是不道德的,
While the British had declared
frivolous things immoral,

24
00:03:25,100 --> 00:03:28,790
纳粹试图显示奢侈品仍然盛行
the Nazis tried to show
that luxury still flourished.

25
00:03:28,875 --> 00:03:30,876
作出保证的是他们的宣传机器
Promises were their propaganda.

26
00:03:30,960 --> 00:03:34,630
那些掌管战争努力的人开始相信他们自己的承诺
Those who ran the war effort
came to believe their own promises.

27
00:03:34,714 --> 00:03:36,840
只有一些人看得更远
Only a few saw further.

28
00:03:36,925 --> 00:03:47,059
(汉斯·凯尔 经济部官员 1938-43)
差不多8月时 (上面)下令许多(产品的)生产
被停止了或被最小化了 或诸如此类的事情
Just about August it was ordered that a lot of
production was stopped or minimised or things like that.

29
00:03:47,143 --> 00:03:53,649
当时有一种极度愉快的情绪
那就是可以这么说 战争已经结束了
And there was a kind of euphoria
that the war was, so to say, over.

30
00:03:53,733 --> 00:03:55,817
我根本不相信那种说法
l didn't believe in that at all.

31
00:03:55,902 --> 00:03:59,196
不,我认为我知道英国人
No, I thought I knew the British

32
00:03:59,280 --> 00:04:04,451
而我有这种观点 那就是他们会把战争坚持到底
and I had the opinion
that they would see this thing through

33
00:04:04,535 --> 00:04:07,246
而美国会加入战争,
and that the United States
would join the war,

34
00:04:07,330 --> 00:04:14,836
所以(我们)应该尽一切努力来准备长期的封锁
and therefore every effort should be
made to prepare for a long blockade.

35
00:04:18,758 --> 00:04:21,718
希特勒没有准备进行长期斗争的计划,
Hitler had no plans ready
for a long struggle,

36
00:04:21,800 --> 00:04:26,515
没有为全部产能的动员进行准备
no preparations for the total
mobilisation of all productive capacity.

37
00:04:26,599 --> 00:04:30,060
德国工业是为一场闪电战准备的
German industry had been geared
to a blitzkrieg war.

38
00:04:30,144 --> 00:04:35,482
纳粹政权仍让工厂制造和平时期的产品
The regime still let the factories
turn out peacetime goods.

39
00:04:37,443 --> 00:04:40,862
被征服但未被完全转变的(德国)工人们,
The workers, subjugated
but not fully converted,

40
00:04:40,947 --> 00:04:45,909
毫无热情地看着纳粹巨头们来来去去
watched the comings and goings
of the Nazi princes without enthusiasm.

41
00:04:52,041 --> 00:04:55,794
想要被爱戴的纳粹们不断给予
Wanting to be loved,
the Nazis gave and gave.

42
00:04:55,878 --> 00:05:00,424
1940年,宣传部长戈培尔博士是圣诞老人
For 1940, propaganda minister
Dr Goebbels was Father Christmas.

43
00:05:02,176 --> 00:05:04,970
他给孩子们(礼物) 他给母亲们(礼物)
He gave to children. He gave to mothers.

44
00:05:05,054 --> 00:05:09,266
在柏林 新影片"母爱"首映了
In Berlin wurde der neue Film
"Mutterliebe" uraufgeführt.

45
00:05:09,350 --> 00:05:14,146
由帝国(宣传)部长戈培尔博士发起
邀请了纳粹人民福利组织的优胜者...
Auf Veranlassung von Reichsminister Dr. Goebbels
lud die NSV 1.200 Trägerinnen...

46
00:05:14,230 --> 00:05:18,600
生了一大群孩子的女士们被邀请
参加电影"母爱"的首映式,
Ladies with larger broods were invited
to the film premiere of Mother Love,

47
00:05:18,600 --> 00:05:23,281
(这部电影)是纳粹政权对家庭和民间社区的颂歌
the regime's hymn to family and folk community.

48
00:05:24,407 --> 00:05:29,036
这意味着,他甚至将从天空中帮助我们,
而他也能够(这样帮助我们)
Das heißt, er wird uns ja vom Himmel
aus helfen, so gut er kann.

49
00:05:29,120 --> 00:05:31,100
他将和上帝交谈
Er wird mit dem lieben Gott sprechen.

50
00:05:31,100 --> 00:05:34,800
而因为他是如此有趣
并能让所有的天使发笑...
Und weil er so lustig ist
und alle Engel lachen macht...

51
00:05:34,800 --> 00:05:39,379
在她们的胸口 她们戴着纳粹母亲十字勋章
On their breasts
they wore the Nazi Mother Cross.

52
00:05:42,133 --> 00:05:44,968
婴儿车是国土防线上的坦克
The pram was the tank of the home front.

53
00:05:45,053 --> 00:05:48,680
政府希望能在生育率上取得突破
The government hoped
for a breakthrough on the birth rate.

54
00:05:48,806 --> 00:05:50,891
愉快的婴儿,愉快的未来的母亲
Happy babies, happy future mothers

55
00:05:50,975 --> 00:05:54,770
以及非常特别欢乐的音乐沉浸着这个国家
and very specially happy music
soused the nation.

56
00:05:54,896 --> 00:06:01,068
(♪ 进行曲)
(♪ march)

57
00:06:01,152 --> 00:06:08,241
固定在仍然经常半信半疑和紧张的人们
脸上的灿烂笑容,被拉得更宽了
The big smile glued across the face of the people,
still often dubious and nervous,was stretched even wider.

58
00:06:25,301 --> 00:06:31,598
每个人都必须学会享受希特勒
的民间社区的快乐团队合作
Everybody must learn to enjoy the happy
teamwork of Hitler's folk community.

59
00:06:37,271 --> 00:06:41,483
下午两点零一分
德国国防军报告
Vierzehn Uhr und eine Minute.
Der Wehrmachtsbericht.

60
00:06:41,567 --> 00:06:46,905
纳粹从一开始就将电台
视作为他们自己的工具
Radio was the instrument which the Nazis
made their own from the beginning.

61
00:06:46,989 --> 00:06:49,157
他们的外语广播,
Their foreign-language broadcasts,

62
00:06:49,242 --> 00:06:52,200
在技术上极其出色
但荒唐地令人难以信服,
technically marvellous
but grotesquely unconvincing,

63
00:06:52,200 --> 00:06:56,415
贪婪地把手伸向国外的头脑
reached greedily out to minds abroad.

64
00:06:56,499 --> 00:06:59,751
今天的德国官方战争公报如下
Today's official German war communiqué
reads as follows.

65
00:07:00,878 --> 00:07:04,714
但收听外国电台是被禁止的
But listening to foreign radio was forbidden.

66
00:07:04,799 --> 00:07:08,009
许多人,就象宣传漫画人物特兰和赫勒,
Many, like the propaganda comics
Tran and Helle,

67
00:07:08,094 --> 00:07:14,300
在瞥一眼外面的世界和冒入狱的风险
之间进行无谓的争执
argued the toss between getting a glimpse of the
outside world and the risk of a jail sentence.

68
00:07:15,000 --> 00:07:17,300
这意味着进监狱!

69
00:07:18,900 --> 00:07:21,400
即使没人发现?

70
00:07:22,000 --> 00:07:26,000
那不是问题所在
好的德国人不干那个

71
00:07:26,400 --> 00:07:29,891
但我需要知道正在发生什么

72
00:07:29,891 --> 00:07:34,000
你认为外国广播是真实的...

73
00:07:34,400 --> 00:07:36,000
...别傻了!

74
00:07:36,300 --> 00:07:40,000
你不知道他们是如何运作的吗?

75
00:07:40,600 --> 00:07:45,000
他们的全部目的就是削弱我们的士气

76
00:07:45,300 --> 00:07:52,300
但我已经老到能分辨事实和谎言了

77
00:07:56,800 --> 00:08:00,700
...由于收听外国广播...

78
00:08:00,700 --> 00:08:03,691
被宣判2年半徒刑

79
00:08:03,691 --> 00:08:08,445
如果我们收听外国电台,我们也一直这样做,
If we listened to foreign radio,
which we always did,

80
00:08:08,529 --> 00:08:14,409
我们会把声音调得非常轻
而我们就坐在它旁边贴着它听
we turned it very low and we used
to sit right up close against it.

81
00:08:14,494 --> 00:08:23,168
(克里斯塔贝尔·贝伦堡 德国人的妻子)
我记得有这么一次 我的儿子,当时他还是个小学生,
And I remember one particular moment
when my son,who was a little schoolboy,

82
00:08:23,252 --> 00:08:27,547
跟我说他有个非常有趣的故事要告诉我,
told me that he had
a very funny story to tell me,

83
00:08:27,673 --> 00:08:34,346
那就是他朋友的母亲也跟我们一样
把她的耳朵贴着无线电收听
that his friend's mother also listened to the radio
with her ear right up against it the same as we did.

84
00:08:34,430 --> 00:08:37,682
我突然意识到我可以让她入狱
l suddenly realised
that I could have her imprisoned

85
00:08:37,808 --> 00:08:39,000
而她也可以让我入狱,
and she could have me imprisoned,

86
00:08:39,000 --> 00:08:42,939
因为这两个孩子已经在谈论这件事
because these two children
had been talking about it.

87
00:08:46,000 --> 00:08:47,700
除了地理和其他(科目),
As well as geography and the rest,

88
00:08:47,700 --> 00:08:51,321
纳粹的学校还必须添加一门特别的科目
Nazi schools were obliged
to add a special subject.

89
00:08:51,405 --> 00:08:58,245
孩子们被用图片和测量法来教会
(辨别)一个健康雅利安种族的特点
Children were taught with pictures and measurements
the dimensions of a healthy Aryan race.

90
00:08:58,329 --> 00:09:03,124
官方影片让德国人作好保持
种族纯净的重要性的思想准备
Official films prepared the Germans for
the consequences of keeping the race pure.

91
00:09:03,251 --> 00:09:10,215
无法治愈的低能者,被宣判为坏种子,
进了实验性的毒气室
The mentally incurable,condemned as the bad
seed, went to experimental gas chambers.

92
00:09:11,000 --> 00:09:14,300
德国人民不能想象...

93
00:09:14,300 --> 00:09:18,000
相关的痛苦

94
00:09:21,300 --> 00:09:27,300
照顾低能儿是怎么样的(痛苦)

95
00:09:29,800 --> 00:09:33,500
比动物还低等

96
00:09:37,600 --> 00:09:42,800
但他们仍在繁殖患有低能症的孩子

97
00:09:42,900 --> 00:09:45,500
很显然...

98
00:09:45,500 --> 00:09:52,500
...制止他们繁殖将是人道的

99
00:09:55,511 --> 00:09:57,345
但现在,仅此一次,
But now, for once,

100
00:09:57,430 --> 00:10:00,432
德国人知道了正在发生什么 并提出了抗议
the Germans learnt what was going on
and protested.

101
00:10:00,516 --> 00:10:04,894
明斯特(德国西北部城市)的加伦主教
在(教堂的)讲坛上攻击了安乐死
Bishop Galen of Münster
attacked euthanasia from the pulpit.

102
00:10:04,979 --> 00:10:08,356
这个节目暂时被停止了
For a time, the programme was stopped.

103
00:10:09,025 --> 00:10:12,902
被控制的媒体避免了这样的顾虑
A controlled press
avoided such misgivings.

104
00:10:12,987 --> 00:10:16,865
一些报纸仅仅是(印着)
仇恨和谎言的(纳粹)党小报
Some newspapers were
mere party sheets of hate and lies.

105
00:10:16,949 --> 00:10:20,035
一些(报纸)在字里行间插入了批评
Some slipped criticism
between the lines.

106
00:10:20,119 --> 00:10:25,373
这些报纸没有一张能满足
仍然受过高度教育的民众
None of them satisfied a people
which was still highly educated.

107
00:10:25,458 --> 00:10:32,797
永远不被允许公开说出你的观点
真是极其令人沮丧
It was terribly frustrating never to
be allowed to say your opinion openly.

108
00:10:32,923 --> 00:10:39,929
当我本人在1940年初被征召
入伍时,我感到十分高兴
l myself was quite happy when I was
called up,early 1940, to the army,

109
00:10:40,056 --> 00:10:47,771
(弗雷德里克·鲁夫特)
那突然丢下了所有那些我每天都感受到的压抑
and that suddenly left behind
all the oppression I had every day.

110
00:10:47,855 --> 00:10:51,441
作为一个士兵,你不读报纸
Being a soldier,
you don't read newspapers.

111
00:10:51,525 --> 00:10:53,943
你不听无线电
You don't listen to the radio.

112
00:10:54,028 --> 00:11:01,785
你不用每时每刻总是处于
对准着你的宣传的压力之下
You're not always under the stress of the
propaganda which was pointed at you every hour.

113
00:11:06,749 --> 00:11:10,293
欧洲战争在1941年6月变成世界大战
European war became world war in June 1941.

114
00:11:10,378 --> 00:11:14,923
纳粹领导人已秘密决定
必须进行对俄国的征服
The Nazi leaders had secretly resolved
that the conquest of Russia must come.

115
00:11:15,007 --> 00:11:18,700
帝国宣传部长戈培尔博士宣读元首的声明
Reichsminister Dr. Goebbels
verliest die Proklamation des Führers.

116
00:11:18,700 --> 00:11:21,137
德国人民
Deutsches Volk.

117
00:11:21,222 --> 00:11:26,059
此刻 一次进军正在发生,...
ln diesem Augenblick vollzieht sich
ein Aufmarsch, der...

118
00:11:26,519 --> 00:11:33,024
对许多人来说,进攻苏联带来了恐惧和困惑
For many, the attack on the Soviet Union
brought fear and bewilderment.

119
00:11:33,109 --> 00:11:39,572
当然我听说(进行)了一定的准备
Of course l'd heard
of certain preparations

120
00:11:39,657 --> 00:11:44,577
但这一切都被掩盖起来(以防张扬出去)
but it was all... well, hushed up,

121
00:11:44,662 --> 00:11:48,957
而且直到最后一刻,
and till the last moment,

122
00:11:49,041 --> 00:11:52,043
我还以为战争不会发生
l didn't think that the war
would come about.

123
00:11:54,588 --> 00:11:56,300
对一场长期战争来说,
For a long war,

124
00:11:56,300 --> 00:12:00,385
德国需要将俄国南部的油田占为己有
Germany would need to have the south
Russian oil fields for her own.

125
00:12:01,470 --> 00:12:08,601
俄国在前一年根据纳粹-苏联条约交付了100万
吨石油,现在(这种交付石油的机会)被丢掉了
Russia had delivered a million tons of oil the previous
year under the Nazi-Soviet Pact,now flung away.

126
00:12:08,686 --> 00:12:09,500
事实上
(Kehrl) As a matter of fact

127
00:12:09,500 --> 00:12:13,982
我们和他们有着我们有过的最大贸易协定
we had the greatest trade agreements
with them that we ever had

128
00:12:14,066 --> 00:12:16,192
而他们交付(货物)很准时,
and they delivered promptly,

129
00:12:16,277 --> 00:12:23,616
从经济角度来看 一切似乎都秩序井然
and from an economic point of view
everything seemed to be in order.

130
00:12:23,701 --> 00:12:29,000
我个人已经,通过我手下的人,
l personally had, through my men,

131
00:12:30,499 --> 00:12:37,422
和他们协商在俄国建立一个人造纤维工厂
negotiations with them of putting up
a synthetic fibre mill in Russia

132
00:12:37,506 --> 00:12:43,553
而协议在1941年6月15日签署
(苏德战争在6月22日爆发),
and the treaty was signed
on 15 June, 1941,

133
00:12:43,637 --> 00:12:52,020
而第一笔一千万马克的黄金
应该在1941年7月1日启运
and the first ten million marks in gold
should be shipped on July 1, 1941.

134
00:12:59,862 --> 00:13:04,407
德国人向东猛冲 碾过正在崩溃的俄国军队
The Germans drove eastwards
over disintegrating Russian armies.

135
00:13:08,412 --> 00:13:11,706
胜利看起来只是几周的事情,又一次闪电战,
Victory looked like a matter of weeks,
another blitzkrieg,

136
00:13:11,832 --> 00:13:14,959
而国内的士气恢复了
and morale at home revived.

137
00:13:25,596 --> 00:13:29,182
戈林视察了现在成为德国殖民地的乌克兰,
Göring inspected what was now
the German colony of Ukraine,

138
00:13:29,266 --> 00:13:32,644
(这里)将被规划为一个农业的农奴地区
intended to be a serf region
of agriculture.

139
00:13:32,728 --> 00:13:40,819
纳粹的斯拉夫人专家希望 这里有着淳朴风俗
的(头脑)简单的人们会喜欢这样的前景
Nazi experts on the Slavs hoped that this simple folk
with simple customs would enjoy this prospect.

140
00:13:40,903 --> 00:13:44,864
六个月后,在莫斯科前
伸手不见五指的大雪里,
Six months later,
in the blinding snow before Moscow,

141
00:13:44,949 --> 00:13:46,825
德国人被止住了
the Germans were stopped.

142
00:13:53,207 --> 00:13:54,874
他们缺乏冬衣
They lacked winter clothing

143
00:13:54,959 --> 00:13:58,336
政府呼吁(捐献)毛皮和暖和的大衣
and the government appealed
for furs and warm coats.

144
00:13:59,547 --> 00:14:01,756
在收集(冬衣)的最后几天冲刺里,
An den letzten Tagen
der Sammlung drängen

145
00:14:01,841 --> 00:14:04,801
慷慨的民众挤满了收集点,
drängen sich vor den Annahmestellen
die Gebefreudigen,

146
00:14:04,885 --> 00:14:06,344
来交付他们的捐赠物
um ihre Spenden abzuliefern.

147
00:14:06,428 --> 00:14:10,723
你不感到可惜吗? 这么漂亮的毛皮?
欧,穿着它一定很暖和
Tut Ihnen das nicht leid? So einen
schönen Pelz? Oh, ist das warm da drin.

148
00:14:10,850 --> 00:14:18,398
再多排练过的热情也无法隐藏
这是帝国的第一次军事挫败
No amount of rehearsed enthusiasm could conceal
that this was the Reich's first military reverse.

149
00:14:25,656 --> 00:14:29,450
(纳粹)军工部长和战争努力的领导 弗里茨·托特
The minister of munitions
and head of the war effort Fritz Todt

150
00:14:29,535 --> 00:14:33,872
飞去视察东线上的建筑工程
flew to inspect the construction work
on the Eastern Front.

151
00:14:33,956 --> 00:14:37,834
本该在飞机上的人之一是希特勒的宫廷建筑师,
One of the men who should have been
on the plane was Hitler's court architect,

152
00:14:37,918 --> 00:14:41,921
纽伦堡集会(会场)的设计者,阿尔伯特·施佩尔
the producer of the Nuremberg rallies,
Albert Speer.

153
00:14:42,006 --> 00:14:47,260
我在总部听说托特的飞机坠毁了
l heard in the headquarters
that Todt's plane crashed.

154
00:14:47,344 --> 00:14:53,182
他死了 半小时后我被要求去见希特勒
He was dead. And half an hour afterwards
l was asked to come to Hitler

155
00:14:53,267 --> 00:14:56,060
大大出乎我的意料 他告诉我,
and to my great surprise he told me,

156
00:14:56,145 --> 00:15:00,023
"你将成为他所有公职的继任者"
"You shall be his successor in all his offices."

157
00:15:04,320 --> 00:15:07,530
托特得到了一个国家社会主义英雄的葬礼
Todt got the funeral
of a National Socialist hero.

158
00:15:23,881 --> 00:15:27,592
到目前为止 已有近25万德国人在战场上阵亡,
By now nearly 250,000 Germans
had been killed on the battle fronts,

159
00:15:27,676 --> 00:15:32,180
但托特是希特勒在战争中死亡的第一个亲密同志
but Todt was the first of Hitler's
close comrades to meet death in the war.

160
00:15:32,306 --> 00:15:36,768
希特勒受到了震动
战争终于影响到了他个人
Hitler was shaken.
The war had reached him personally.

161
00:15:48,906 --> 00:15:54,118
施佩尔已经看到了纳粹战争工业
那混乱,分离的运作方式
Speer had already seen the chaotic,
disconnected way that Nazi war industry worked.

162
00:15:54,203 --> 00:16:00,500
运输工具,军火...这一切都必须
被划归一个单一的指挥(机构)来管理
Transport, munitions... all had to be
brought under a single control.

163
00:16:05,339 --> 00:16:09,217
他的第一批目标之一是劳工供应
One of his first targets
was the labour supply.

164
00:16:09,301 --> 00:16:13,304
纳粹德国从没有动员过其全部的劳动力
Nazi Germany had never mobilised
its full workforce.

165
00:16:13,389 --> 00:16:18,351
我试图让妇女进入战争生产机器,
(Speer) I tried to get the women
in the war production machinery,

166
00:16:18,435 --> 00:16:23,564
但这建议遭到掌管全部劳力
的沙克尔的反对
but it was opposed by Sauckel
who was in charge of all the labour.

167
00:16:23,649 --> 00:16:27,151
这事闹到戈林那里 而戈林也断然拒绝
And the thing came to Göring
and Göring flatly denied, too.

168
00:16:27,236 --> 00:16:29,487
然后此事由希特勒来做决断,
Then it came to the decision of Hitler,

169
00:16:29,571 --> 00:16:33,157
而希特勒也说,"不,妇女们必须被保护好"
and Hitler also said,
"No, the women must be preserved."

170
00:16:33,242 --> 00:16:38,121
"她们有其他任务 她们是为家庭(而存在的)
她们必须养育孩子
"They have other tasks. They are for
the family. They have to bear children

171
00:16:38,205 --> 00:16:45,920
如果她们在工厂里工作
那会损害她们的健康和她们的士气"
and it would spoil their health and their morale
if they are working in the factories."

172
00:16:48,048 --> 00:16:51,551
但乌克兰妇女正被引进来当女佣...
But Ukrainian women
were being imported as maids...

173
00:16:51,635 --> 00:16:54,929
外国壮丁被抓来奴隶劳工
foreign conscripts for slave labour.

174
00:16:55,014 --> 00:16:57,515
在施佩尔的指挥下,一件巨大的
具有讽刺意味的事情被实现了,
Under Speer,a great irony was fulfilled,

175
00:16:57,599 --> 00:17:02,395
因为德国正恰恰在变成 纳粹党人
说它不会成为(的那个国家)
for Germany was becoming exactly what
the Nazis said it would not become.

176
00:17:02,479 --> 00:17:07,066
他们保证过要归还土地,结束大资本(的支配地位)
They had promised a return to the land,
an end to great capitalism.

177
00:17:07,151 --> 00:17:12,447
相反,军备生产的压力
正在加强巨大的工业寡头
lnstead, the armaments drive was strengthening
the vast industrial monopolies

178
00:17:12,531 --> 00:17:17,535
并使各个城市充斥着德国和外国劳工
and swelling the cities
with German and foreign labour.

179
00:17:17,619 --> 00:17:19,078
在两年半里,
ln two and a half years,

180
00:17:19,163 --> 00:17:23,082
施佩尔使军工产量达到原来的近四倍
Speer multiplied armament production
nearly four times.

181
00:17:23,167 --> 00:17:26,669
80%的工业归他指挥
80% of industry came under his control.

182
00:17:26,754 --> 00:17:32,133
他不顾官僚政治 并用他自己的专家解决问题
He brushed aside bureaucracies
and worked through his own experts.

183
00:17:32,217 --> 00:17:40,266
他有想法 而他把他全部的精力
投入到(实现)这些想法中
(Kehrl) He had ideas and he put
all his energy behind these ideas

184
00:17:40,350 --> 00:17:44,228
并非常成功地实行了它们
and put them through
with very much success.

185
00:17:44,313 --> 00:17:48,941
(汉斯·凯尔 军备部计划局局长 1943-45)
他不知道在过去事情是如何被完成的
He didn't know how things
had been done in the past.

186
00:17:49,026 --> 00:17:51,277
他与之完全没有任何关系,
He hadn't anything to do with it,

187
00:17:51,361 --> 00:17:55,531
所以他不知道什么是不可能的
和什么是可能的,
so he didn't know what was impossible
and what was possible,

188
00:17:55,616 --> 00:17:59,535
有时候 他在做不可能的
事情方面也取得了成功
and he succeeded sometimes
in doing the impossible, too.

189
00:18:00,996 --> 00:18:12,882
对每一个没有在我们的专制体制中生活过的人来说
听到(在这样的体制中也)很难完成命令 是令人震惊的
(Speer) lt is astounding for everybody who didn't
live in our authoritarian system to hear that
it was difficult to get through with orders.

190
00:18:12,966 --> 00:18:20,300
但这(的确)很难 因为德国被分成许多地区,32个地区
But it was difficult because Germany was
divided into many districts, 32 districts.

191
00:18:20,300 --> 00:18:22,200
每个地区的领导是一位地方长官
At the head of every district
was a Gauleiter.

192
00:18:22,200 --> 00:18:28,564
他是个政治强人 并在他的辖区有绝对权力
He was strong political man
and had absolute power in his district.

193
00:18:28,649 --> 00:18:32,777
他只服从于希特勒本人
He was only subordinated
to Hitler himself.

194
00:18:32,861 --> 00:18:37,198
所以当我的命令让一位地方长官不快时,
So when my orders didn't please
one of the Gauleiters,

195
00:18:37,282 --> 00:18:40,409
他们可能就不执行
possibly they weren't carried out.

196
00:18:42,913 --> 00:18:47,700
坦克生产显示了 即使是施佩尔
也如何不能总是得偿所愿
Tank production showed how even
Speer failed to get all of his way.

197
00:18:48,418 --> 00:18:53,500
他不能在希特勒选择的政府样式中
切断相互竞争的领导阶层
He could not slice through the competing hierarchies
in Hitler's chosen style of government.

198
00:18:53,500 --> 00:18:56,300
有太多种类的坦克
坦克总数却太少
There were too many types of tanks.
Too few tanks in all.

199
00:18:56,300 --> 00:19:00,680
太多口径的火炮和不同尺寸的弹药
Too many calibres of gun
and different sizes of ammunition.

200
00:19:01,181 --> 00:19:04,851
希特勒认为在(解决)这些问题方面 他要远更出色
(Speer) Hitler thought he was
far superior to such problems

201
00:19:04,935 --> 00:19:08,813
对其他人来说 要反复讨论上几周的事情
and what for others would have been
discussions of weeks and weeks

202
00:19:08,897 --> 00:19:13,109
对他来说 只要一会儿工夫就能做出决定
for him was a decision
of just a fraction of a minute.

203
00:19:13,193 --> 00:19:15,027
当然,还有一个变化
Of course, there was a change, too.

204
00:19:15,112 --> 00:19:18,447
你永远不能说 一个人会一成不变,
One can never say
that a man is always the same person,

205
00:19:18,532 --> 00:19:21,951
而希特勒在从42到43年(这段时间里)变了很多
and Hitler changed a lot
from '42 to '43.

206
00:19:22,035 --> 00:19:25,204
1943年 他越来越确信
ln '43 he was more and more convinced

207
00:19:25,289 --> 00:19:27,957
他再也不需要任何人的建议
that he didn't need
any more advice of anybody

208
00:19:28,041 --> 00:19:32,253
而他在不听从(建议)的
情况下 自己做出决定
and he made the decisions
by himself without listening.

209
00:19:34,423 --> 00:19:37,967
希特勒把越来越多的时间花在狼穴,
Hitler spent more and more
time at the Wolf's Lair,

210
00:19:38,051 --> 00:19:43,556
他位于拉斯腾堡(现属波兰肯特申),
东普鲁士森林里 那阴郁,遥远的营地
his melancholy, remote encampment at
Rastenburg in the East Prussian forest.

211
00:19:43,640 --> 00:19:46,642
他周围的那些人都是奉承谄媚的(家伙)
Those around him were obsequious.

212
00:19:46,727 --> 00:19:49,520
更出色的顾问失去了联系
The better advisers lost touch.

213
00:19:52,941 --> 00:19:58,279
希特勒的私人党卫队副官
是理查德·舒尔茨-柯森斯
Hitler's personal SS adjutant
was Richard Schulze-Kossens.

214
00:19:58,363 --> 00:20:02,783
几乎所有的部长都驻扎在柏林
(Schulze-Kossens) Nearly all ministers
were stationed at Berlin

215
00:20:02,868 --> 00:20:09,165
他们中的一些人在总部有联络官
and some of them had contact officers
in the headquarters.

216
00:20:09,291 --> 00:20:14,045
只有里宾特洛甫,希姆莱 有时候
还有戈林有他们自己的总部,
Only Ribbentrop, Himmler and sometimes
Göring had their own headquarters,

217
00:20:14,129 --> 00:20:17,131
离我们的总部不是太远
not so far from our headquarters.

218
00:20:18,300 --> 00:20:21,093
施佩尔非常频繁地来到总部
Speer was very often in the headquarters

219
00:20:21,178 --> 00:20:26,182
因为他的部(军备部)对战争来说非常重要
because his ministry
was very important for the war.

220
00:20:26,266 --> 00:20:30,228
只有(马丁·)鲍曼 (纳粹党秘书长,
希特勒私人秘书)一直在总部里
Only Bormann was always in the headquarters

221
00:20:30,312 --> 00:20:35,316
在那里他有与希特勒的唯一直接联系
where there was the only
direct contact to Hitler.

222
00:20:35,400 --> 00:20:38,778
鲍曼,作为(希特勒的)秘书,
是最有权势的人...
(Speer) Bormann, as the secretary,
was the most powerful man...

223
00:20:38,904 --> 00:20:43,824
我想比希特勒权力更大
因为当权力被分开时,
more powerful, I think, than Hitler,
because when the power was divided,

224
00:20:43,951 --> 00:20:49,622
所有那些掌权的人都必须
通过他才能去见希特勒
all those men who were in power
had to go via him to Hitler.

225
00:20:49,706 --> 00:20:54,669
除了我 我可以直接见到希特勒
Except me.
l had direct access to Hitler.

226
00:20:54,753 --> 00:20:56,921
(高官之间)没有很多合作
There wasn't much cooperation.

227
00:20:57,005 --> 00:21:02,218
合作(一般)在低级别的小技术专家中进行
The cooperation was in the lower levels
of the smaller technocrats.

228
00:21:02,344 --> 00:21:05,388
我们没有象内阁那样的机构
We didn't have anything like a cabinet.

229
00:21:05,472 --> 00:21:09,517
部长们的碰面,即使有的话,也极其少有
Ministers met, if at all, very seldom

230
00:21:09,601 --> 00:21:12,895
而且不会谈论非常重要的事情...
and didn't talk about
very important matters...

231
00:21:12,980 --> 00:21:15,523
那就是我的印象
so was my impression.

232
00:21:15,607 --> 00:21:18,943
每个部都为自己工作
Every ministry worked for itself

233
00:21:19,027 --> 00:21:24,824
有时候他们从希特勒那里
得到命令,但这非常,非常少见
and sometimes they got orders
from Hitler, but very, very seldom.

234
00:21:26,900 --> 00:21:29,800
外国访客 象芬兰领导人
曼纳海姆(元帅 芬兰总统)
Foreign visitors like Mannerheim,
the Finnish leader,

235
00:21:29,800 --> 00:21:32,700
能看出希特勒生活在一个幻觉的世界里
could see that Hitler was living
in a world of illusion.

236
00:21:32,700 --> 00:21:37,253
他仍然相信德国空军司令戈林的一再保证
He still trusted the reassurances
of Göring, head of the Luftwaffe.

237
00:21:37,337 --> 00:21:39,005
戈林,几个月后,
Göring, a few months later,

238
00:21:39,089 --> 00:21:42,300
宣称他的飞机能为东线空运补给
claimed that his aircraft
could supply the Eastern Front

239
00:21:42,384 --> 00:21:45,428
甚至当一整支集团军在斯大林格勒被包围
even when a whole army
was cut off at Stalingrad.

240
00:21:46,013 --> 00:21:49,473
注意,我再次呼叫斯大林格勒
Achtung,ich rufe noch einmal Stalingrad.

241
00:21:49,558 --> 00:21:53,477
这里是斯大林格勒
这里是伏尔加河前线
Hier Stalingrad.
Hier ist die Front an der Wolga.

242
00:21:53,979 --> 00:21:57,148
注意,大西洋上的U型潜艇艇员
Achtung,die U-Bootfahrer im Atlantik.

243
00:21:57,274 --> 00:21:59,775
1942年圣诞节
Christmas 1942.

244
00:22:01,278 --> 00:22:03,779
注意,卡塔尼亚(意大利港口城市)
Achtung, Catania.

245
00:22:03,864 --> 00:22:06,574
这里是地中海和非洲前线
Hier ist die Mittelmeerfront und Afrika.

246
00:22:06,658 --> 00:22:11,287
斯大林格勒的士兵在无线电通讯中
传来清晰响亮的声音,
The man at Stalingrad had come through
on the radio link-up loud and clear,

247
00:22:11,371 --> 00:22:15,958
但这些勇敢的话语是在
一个柏林录音室里伪造的
but the brave words
were faked in a Berlin studio.

248
00:22:17,961 --> 00:22:20,046
(♪ "平安夜")
(♪ "Stille Nacht")

249
00:22:28,263 --> 00:22:34,018
柏林的大教堂最后一次未受损伤地
作为进行圣诞节庆祝的场所
For the last time the cathedral stood undamaged
as the Christmas fair took place in Berlin.

250
00:22:34,770 --> 00:22:37,813
但斯大林格勒(的第六集团军)仍被切断
But Stalingrad was still cut off

251
00:22:37,898 --> 00:22:41,484
而在内心深处 这个国家
感觉到了什么即将发生
and deep down the nation sensed
what was to happen.

252
00:22:41,568 --> 00:22:44,111
(1943年)2月3日
Dritter Februar.

253
00:22:44,196 --> 00:22:48,366
德国国防军最高指挥部宣布:
Das Oberkommando
der Wehrmacht gibt bekannt:

254
00:22:48,450 --> 00:22:51,160
斯大林格勒战役结束了
Der Kampf um Stalingrad ist zu Ende.

255
00:22:51,286 --> 00:22:55,956
"斯大林战役已经结束了"
"The Battle of Stalingrad
has come to an end."

256
00:22:56,041 --> 00:23:00,252
仅此一次 电台说出了真相,
而且带着一些尊严
For once the radio spoke the truth,
and with some dignity.

257
00:23:00,337 --> 00:23:04,298
91,000名幸存者投降了
91,000 survivors surrendered.

258
00:23:04,383 --> 00:23:08,677
(其中)只有几千人能再次看到德国
Only a few thousand
ever saw Germany again.

259
00:23:08,762 --> 00:23:11,722
我在总部的时间不长
l was not long in the headquarters

260
00:23:11,807 --> 00:23:17,269
但我感觉这一天的气氛非常的凝重
but I felt very significant
the atmosphere on this day.

261
00:23:18,563 --> 00:23:26,529
(特劳德尔·琼格 希特勒的秘书 1943-45
电影"帝国的毁灭"女主角原型)
所有人都很抑郁 而希特勒本人非常严肃
All people were depressed and
Hitler himself was very serious

262
00:23:26,613 --> 00:23:35,579
他没有说任何话就开始喝他的汤,而且...
and he started on his soup
without saying any word, and...

263
00:23:36,665 --> 00:23:40,918
他...他非常沮丧
He was... He was very depressed.

264
00:23:50,595 --> 00:23:52,300
全世界都意识到
The world realised

265
00:23:52,300 --> 00:23:56,934
而德国人也意识到这是个转折点
and the Germans realised
that this was the turning point.

266
00:23:57,018 --> 00:24:01,063
这是无法被隐藏的悲剧
This was the tragedy
which could not be hidden.

267
00:24:07,821 --> 00:24:11,824
而斯大林格勒(的失败)并非传来
的唯一坏消息 该城陷落的一周前,
And Stalingrad did not come alone.
A week before the city fell,

268
00:24:11,908 --> 00:24:18,164
德国人得知同盟国要求无条件投降
the Germans learned that the Allies
would demand unconditional surrender.

269
00:24:20,333 --> 00:24:23,502
那样,对德国人就将绝不留情了
There was, then,
to be no mercy for the Germans.

270
00:24:23,587 --> 00:24:29,508
纳粹和非纳粹都失去了一些幻想
并一起拉近了(彼此之间的关系)
Nazi and non-Nazi both lost some illusions
and drew a little closer together.

271
00:24:29,593 --> 00:24:31,969
逃生舱门已经被栓上了
The escape hatches had been bolted.

272
00:24:32,095 --> 00:24:35,931
这将是一场战斗到底的全面战争
This was to be a total war,
fought to the finish.

273
00:24:38,018 --> 00:24:41,604
普遍的感觉是,我们什么也做不了
(Bielenberg) The general feeling was,
well, we can do nothing.

274
00:24:41,688 --> 00:24:45,566
我们做什么都无济于事
我们最好坚持到底
lt doesn't matter what we do.
We'd better stick it out.

275
00:24:45,650 --> 00:24:49,987
我记得,忍耐是挂在每个人嘴边的那个词
Ausharren was the word,
l remember, on everyone's lips.

276
00:24:50,071 --> 00:24:55,075
别无其他选择 我们必须血战到底
There's no alternative.
We've got to fight to the bitter end.

277
00:24:55,160 --> 00:25:00,456
而戈培尔在他的宣传中
把这一点用到了极致
And this Goebbels used to the uttermost
in his propaganda.

278
00:25:01,100 --> 00:25:04,000
你想要全面战争吗?

279
00:25:06,963 --> 00:25:08,800
斯大林格勒(战役结束)的两周后,
Two weeks after Stalingrad,

280
00:25:08,800 --> 00:25:12,801
戈培尔使一群经过挑选的纳粹
观众达到最后一次大规模狂热
Goebbels brought a picked
Nazi audience to a last mass frenzy.

281
00:25:13,500 --> 00:25:19,000
你们是否决心跟随元首...

282
00:25:19,300 --> 00:25:25,400
并无论付出多大代价
为胜利而战?

283
00:25:31,112 --> 00:25:34,782
这是他最辉煌的一刻,宣告进行全面战争
lt was his supreme moment,
the proclaiming of total war

284
00:25:34,866 --> 00:25:38,911
并激发出这个国家潜藏的能量
and the invoking
of the nation's hidden power.

285
00:25:51,400 --> 00:25:53,800
让我们的战斗口号是...

286
00:25:54,700 --> 00:25:57,200
现在,民众们,起来...

287
00:25:57,400 --> 00:26:01,000
...暴风雨 迸发出来!

288
00:26:02,394 --> 00:26:06,605
"现在,民众们,起来
暴风雨,迸发出来!"
"Now, folk, rise up
and storm, break loose."

289
00:26:06,690 --> 00:26:13,654
它们是1812年 全国起义反对拿破仑时的号令
They were the words of 1812,of the
national uprising against Napoleon.

290
00:26:13,738 --> 00:26:15,489
它们现在(听起来)很空洞
They were empty now.

291
00:26:19,077 --> 00:26:21,328
(♪ 短曲)
(♪ fanfare)

292
00:26:29,212 --> 00:26:33,549
在1943年 听音乐比听新闻要更好一些
ln 1943 it was better
listening to music than to news.

293
00:26:46,021 --> 00:26:49,273
这是全面战争和在所有战线上撤退(的一年)
lt was total war
and retreat on all fronts.

294
00:26:49,357 --> 00:26:53,360
全面战争意味着
甚至是德国妇女也必须工作
Total war meant that even
German women must work.

295
00:26:57,991 --> 00:27:00,000
这带来了其辛酸的幽默
lt brought its own sour humour.

296
00:27:00,100 --> 00:27:05,000
有一个口号,"享受战争 和平将是可怕的"
(Tucking) There was a slogan,
"Do enjoy war. Peace will be dreadful."

297
00:27:07,917 --> 00:27:12,755
在被招募去矿井和工厂工作
的男孩中 有一种新的平等
There was a new sort of equality among the boys
drafted to the mines and factories.

298
00:27:12,839 --> 00:27:18,260
"希特勒青年团"被动员起来
参加生产 并最终参加战斗
The Hitler Youth was mobilised into
production and eventually into battle.

299
00:27:18,345 --> 00:27:23,641
处于围攻之下,人们之间的隔阂消失了
正如它们在伦敦大轰炸中消失了一样
Under siege,the barriers between people crumbled
as they had crumbled in the London Blitz.

300
00:27:25,685 --> 00:27:29,855
人们想要挤在一起,唱歌并遗忘
People wanted to huddle together,
to sing and forget.

301
00:27:29,939 --> 00:27:32,608
到了早晨,他们可能死去
By the morning, they might be dead.

302
00:27:44,162 --> 00:27:47,831
在白天美国轰炸机群在帝国上空出没
By day the American bomber fleets
ranged over the Reich.

303
00:27:47,916 --> 00:27:50,042
在晚上则来了英国人
At night came the British.

304
00:27:50,126 --> 00:27:52,461
在防空洞里人们等待黎明
ln the shelters
the people waited for dawn

305
00:27:52,545 --> 00:27:55,255
并想知道他们的城市是否仍然在那里
and wondered if their cities
would still be there.

306
00:27:56,800 --> 00:28:01,220
当我们第一次挨炸时,我们被震惊了
(Tucking) When we had the first bombs,
we were shocked.

307
00:28:01,304 --> 00:28:06,350
我们看到所有的天空被火光映亮
We saw all the sky
lighted up from the fire.

308
00:28:06,434 --> 00:28:10,396
这是一个巨大的和可怕的场景
lt was an enormous and a dreadful sight.

309
00:28:11,564 --> 00:28:19,238
当我们看到如此多的居民区
被摧毁的时候 我们非常愤怒
We were very angry when we saw that
so many residential areas were destroyed.

310
00:28:19,322 --> 00:28:27,079
只剩下如此少的人 以至于
每一个有力气的人都在灭火
There were so few men left that everybody
who had the strength was firefighting.

311
00:28:37,674 --> 00:28:42,177
一座接一座德国城市被火风暴烧成灰烬
One by one the German cities
were incinerated by firestorms.

312
00:28:42,262 --> 00:28:46,432
对汉堡十天的空袭造成40,000人死亡
Ten days' raids on Hamburg
left 40,000 dead.

313
00:28:52,480 --> 00:28:58,026
戈培尔注意到,"西部的人民正逐渐开始失去勇气"
Goebbels noted, "The people in the west
are gradually beginning to lose courage."

314
00:28:58,111 --> 00:29:01,405
"象那样的苦难是很难承受的."
"Hell like that is hard to bear."

315
00:29:05,660 --> 00:29:10,456
我认为轰炸并没有一个人会以为产生的那种效果
(Bielenberg) I think that the bombing
hadn't the effect one would have thought.

316
00:29:10,540 --> 00:29:14,293
它有使人们团结起来的作用
lt had the effect
of bringing people together.

317
00:29:14,377 --> 00:29:16,712
如果你们全都挨同样的炸弹,
lf you were all under the same bombs,

318
00:29:16,796 --> 00:29:21,633
你的邻居是不是一个纳粹
或是干什么的就不再重要
it didn't matter whether your neighbour
was a Nazi or what they were.

319
00:29:27,474 --> 00:29:29,000
为了避免看到废墟,
To avoid seeing the ruins,

320
00:29:29,000 --> 00:29:32,686
希特勒对柏林罕见的视察
被安排在夜里进行
Hitler's rare visits to Berlin
were made by night.

321
00:29:32,771 --> 00:29:36,690
但为了他的生日 旗帜仍被命令(竖立起来)
And yet banners were ordered
for his birthday.

322
00:29:36,775 --> 00:29:42,112
它们写道,"我们的墙破碎了,
但我们的心没有"
They read, "Our walls have broken,
but not our hearts."

323
00:29:42,947 --> 00:29:48,285
希特勒越来越失去他的现实感
(Junge) Hitler lost more and more
his sense of reality.

324
00:29:48,369 --> 00:29:56,502
他从来,从来没有那种决心 那就是他必须
用他自己的眼睛来看看战争是什么样子的
He never, never had the will that he must
see with his own eyes what the war was.

325
00:29:58,838 --> 00:30:02,466
我们没有来自外界的信息
We had no information from outside

326
00:30:02,550 --> 00:30:13,435
所以我有一种生活在一个修道院,
一个集中营里的感觉,
and so I had the feeling to live in
a monastery,in a concentration camp.

327
00:30:13,520 --> 00:30:18,106
一个将军有一次说,
"我感觉就象待在一个集中营里"
One of the generals once said,
"l feel like a concentration camp."

328
00:30:18,191 --> 00:30:25,697
"我们都被关在里面
而我们全都使用同样的说法"
"We are included and we
all use the same phrases."

329
00:30:25,782 --> 00:30:29,201
"我们全都想同样的事情
我们全都听到同样的东西"
"We are all thinking the same.
We are all hearing the same."

330
00:30:29,285 --> 00:30:36,708
"我们的想法和我们的感觉
全都被希特勒所控制着"
"We are all led in our thoughts
and our feelings by Hitler."

331
00:30:37,794 --> 00:30:42,339
我们全都在一出戏剧里演出,
每个人都是他的角色
We all were playing in a play,
each his role

332
00:30:42,423 --> 00:30:46,343
而他是唯一一个知道剧本的人.
and he was the only one
who knew the script.

333
00:30:46,427 --> 00:30:51,265
他让我们所有人扮演我们
的角色 并说我们的台词
He made us all do our play
and speak our text.

334
00:30:51,349 --> 00:30:55,143
没有其他人知道它会怎么收场
Nobody else knew how it would end.

335
00:30:59,691 --> 00:31:05,779
无论是希特勒还是戈林还是希姆莱
都未在公众场合露面 只有戈培尔
Neither Hitler nor Göring nor Himmler
were seen in public. Only Goebbels.

336
00:31:07,991 --> 00:31:11,201
每当有一次非常猛烈的轰炸,
Whenever there was
a very heavy bombing,

337
00:31:11,327 --> 00:31:16,164
戈培尔站在集市那里 发表他的演讲
Goebbels stood there on the marketplace
and held his speeches

338
00:31:16,249 --> 00:31:20,377
并试图说忍耐
and tried to say ausharren.

339
00:31:21,129 --> 00:31:28,260
我个人还是很尊敬(戈培尔的),
因为(他的演讲)有一种鼓舞人心的感觉
l personally had respect,because
there was a sort of inspiring.

340
00:31:28,803 --> 00:31:31,471
你有点像是处于一种恍惚之中
You were sort of in a trance.

341
00:31:33,892 --> 00:31:37,144
(♪ "纽伦堡的名歌手" - 瓦格纳)
(♪ "The Mastersingers of Nuremberg"...Wagner)

342
00:31:42,817 --> 00:31:47,863
一个紧张的,精疲力尽的国家
仍能沉湎于音乐之中
A strained, exhausted nation
could still lose itself in music.

343
00:31:52,243 --> 00:31:57,539
交响乐团仍能给予德国艺术
的传统中伟大和真实的(音乐)
The orchestras still gave what was great
and true in the tradition of German art.

344
00:31:59,792 --> 00:32:06,048
在画廊中 只有纳粹绘画,
纳粹雕塑那空洞的扭曲表情
ln the galleries there was only the empty
grimacing of Nazi painting, Nazi sculpture.

345
00:32:14,766 --> 00:32:17,017
真正雅利安人的样本 假笑着和皱着眉,
True Aryan models simpered and scowled,

346
00:32:17,101 --> 00:32:22,105
他们的面容被精心设计
以描绘胜利的北欧(日耳曼)种族
their features carefully designed
to portray the victorious Nordic race.

347
00:32:29,489 --> 00:32:32,866
种族是希姆莱和党卫队的绝对疆域
Race was the empire
of Himmler and the SS.

348
00:32:34,369 --> 00:32:36,703
但现在党卫队自己就是一个帝国
(empire同时有疆域和帝国之意)
But now the SS was itself an empire.

349
00:32:36,788 --> 00:32:42,334
希姆莱,前养鸡场农场主,
统治着死亡营和集中营
Himmler, the ex-chicken-farmer,ruled
the death camps and the concentration camps.

350
00:32:43,044 --> 00:32:47,547
党卫队有它自己的学校,工厂和法庭
The SS had its own schools
and factories and courts.

351
00:32:47,632 --> 00:32:51,343
它管理着被占领的东部地区巨大的大片土地
lt administered huge tracts
of the occupied east.

352
00:32:51,427 --> 00:32:56,056
它是德国统治欧洲的工具 它甚至是一支军队
lt was the instrument of German dominion
over Europe. lt was even an army.

353
00:32:56,182 --> 00:33:02,938
(国防军)将领们对武装党卫队师团
的几十万精英部队没有什么控制权
The generals had little control over the hundreds
of thousands of elite troops in the Waffen-SS division.

354
00:33:03,481 --> 00:33:09,111
进入党卫队培训学校的 是从被占领国家
抽选的有着雅利安(种族)样貌的志愿者,
lnto the SS training schools were drawn
Aryan-looking volunteers from the occupied countries,

355
00:33:09,195 --> 00:33:13,657
因为这个党卫队帝国将不仅
是德国的 而且是欧洲的
for the SS state was to be
not merely German but European.

356
00:33:13,741 --> 00:33:18,000
所有人都志愿在武装党卫队服现役
(Schulze-Kossens) All had volunteered
for active service in the Waffen-SS

357
00:33:18,000 --> 00:33:25,711
因为他们把与布尔什维克主义战斗
视为在欧洲的最重要任务
because they regarded the fight against Bolshevism
as the most important task in Europe.

358
00:33:25,837 --> 00:33:35,303
(理查德·舒尔茨-柯森斯 党卫队学院指挥官)
欧洲教育的观点是新的 因为我们持有这样一种观点
New was the point of European education
because we were of the opinion

359
00:33:35,388 --> 00:33:48,859
在有着相同血统或来自于相同血统
的国家之间 只存在着虚构的差别
that only an imaginary contrast existed between the nations
who had the same or were from the same origin, yes.

360
00:33:52,572 --> 00:33:56,158
对有着不同种族血统的那些人来说,
没有(他们的)容身之地
For those of different
race origin, there was no place.

361
00:33:56,284 --> 00:34:03,081
对犹太人来说 (先是)驱逐到东方的
(犹太人)聚居区 然后是党卫队的毒气室
For the Jews there was deportation to eastern
ghettos and then the gas chambers of the SS.

362
00:34:03,166 --> 00:34:05,917
官方说法是"重置"
The official word was "resettlement".

363
00:34:06,002 --> 00:34:10,672
大多数德国人宁愿相信 这意味着
(对犹太人的处置)不会超过那个
Most Germans preferred to believe
that it meant no more than that.

364
00:34:10,757 --> 00:34:15,886
希特勒经常提到他恨犹太人
(Speer) Hitler often mentioned
that he is hating the Jews

365
00:34:15,970 --> 00:34:21,725
当我和他在一起的早期,
他已经举了许多例子,
and he gave many examples already
in an early time when I was with him,

366
00:34:21,809 --> 00:34:27,314
我本该引起警觉 他对此是当真的
and I should have been warned
that he is serious about it

367
00:34:27,398 --> 00:34:32,027
因为事实证明他对其他
他曾预言的事情也很认真
because he proved to be serious
about other things he predicted too.

368
00:34:36,532 --> 00:34:41,286
(赫莎·比瑟 柏林家庭主妇)
一天晚上,一定已经是午夜时分了,门铃响了
One night, it must have been
around midnight, the doorbell rang.

369
00:34:41,370 --> 00:34:45,874
我开了门 站在我眼前的是一对犹太夫妇
I opened it and in front of me
there stood a Jewish couple.

370
00:34:45,958 --> 00:34:49,961
这就是我如何开始帮助被迫害的犹太人的
This was how I began
to help persecuted Jews.

371
00:34:50,046 --> 00:34:56,968
突然之间 我就进入了一个无形的
偷带犹太人(四处躲藏)的人组成的圈子
All of a sudden l'd entered into an invisible
circle of people who smuggled Jews about.

372
00:34:57,053 --> 00:35:00,138
只要一个藏身地一被发现,
As soon as one hiding place
had been detected,

373
00:35:00,223 --> 00:35:02,140
他们就被迅速传递(到下一家)
they were quickly passed on.

374
00:35:02,225 --> 00:35:05,143
他们总是在夜间移动
They'd always move about at night.

375
00:35:05,228 --> 00:35:11,691
那就是我如何成为一个当犹太人象这样
被传递时,留宿他们的团体的成员的
That's how I came to belong to a group who had
to put up Jews when they were passed on like this.

376
00:35:11,776 --> 00:35:16,863
我从未发现一开始是谁把他们送到我这里来的
l've never found out who it was who'd
sent them to me in the first place.

377
00:35:16,948 --> 00:35:19,491
很正派的人,我能肯定
Decent people, l'm sure.

378
00:35:19,575 --> 00:35:23,411
问题是从喂养这两个犹太人开始的
The problems started
with the feeding of the Jewish people.

379
00:35:23,496 --> 00:35:28,291
他们既没有食品配给卡 也没有任何钱,
They neither had food rationing cards
nor did they have any money,

380
00:35:28,376 --> 00:35:38,301
所以我们转而利用(我们的)朋友,(让他们)
用他们的香烟配给卡换取剩余的土豆或一些面包
so we in our turn made use of friends
who exchanged their cigarette ration
cards for the odd potato or some bread.

381
00:35:43,474 --> 00:35:49,646
有一天我们的一个 为这些
犹太人收集食品卡的朋友
One day a friend of ours who used
to collect food cards for these Jews

382
00:35:49,730 --> 00:35:58,280
来找我 她带来了另一个
把头发染成金色的妇女
came to me and she came with
another woman with dyed blonde hair.

383
00:35:58,948 --> 00:36:03,660
我现在还能回想起她坐在那里转动她的结婚戒指
l can see her sitting there now
twisting her wedding ring

384
00:36:03,744 --> 00:36:07,706
并告诉我(他们)不会待很长时间,
and telling me
that it wouldn't be for long,

385
00:36:07,790 --> 00:36:13,587
她会帮我做家务事
她丈夫永远不需要出门
that she would help me in the house
and her husband need never go out.

386
00:36:13,671 --> 00:36:16,840
他可以住在地窖里 或无论什么地方
He could live in the cellar or wherever.

387
00:36:16,924 --> 00:36:19,700
但克里斯塔贝尔·贝伦堡的丈夫不在家
But Christabel Bielenberg's
husband was away

388
00:36:19,700 --> 00:36:22,971
并卷入了一个推翻希特勒的密谋
and was involved
in a plot to overthrow Hitler.

389
00:36:23,055 --> 00:36:28,393
她找她信任的邻居和朋友,也是
另一个密谋者卡尔·兰本恩商量
She consulted her trusted neighbour and
friend Carl Langbehn,another conspirator.

390
00:36:28,477 --> 00:36:31,396
兰本恩同情但又坚定地告诉她
Langbehn told her
compassionately but firmly

391
00:36:31,480 --> 00:36:37,652
(收容犹太人的)风险对她本人和她的家庭
以及对(推翻希特勒)的密谋都太大了
that the risks to herself and her family
and to the conspiracy were too great.

392
00:36:37,737 --> 00:36:44,034
我被我从我邻居那里得到的答复
大吃一惊...受不了,真的
l was astonished... overcome, really...
at the response that I got from my neighbour

393
00:36:44,118 --> 00:36:49,706
他告诉我无论如何我绝不能收容这些人,
who told me that under no circumstances
whatsoever could I house these people,

394
00:36:49,790 --> 00:36:52,709
收容犹太人意味着要进集中营
that housing of Jews
meant concentration camp

395
00:36:52,793 --> 00:36:57,756
不仅是我本人 还有我丈夫,
可能我的孩子(也会进去)
not only for myself but for my husband,
possibly also for my children.

396
00:36:58,883 --> 00:37:02,510
我能记得我穿过并走在路上
l can remember going through
and out into the road

397
00:37:02,637 --> 00:37:08,892
从黑暗中传来一个声音...
我知道有人在那里...
and out of the darkness came a voice...
l knew there was somebody there...

398
00:37:08,976 --> 00:37:11,061
传来一个声音说:
came a voice saying:

399
00:37:11,145 --> 00:37:15,190
"博士夫人... 贝伦堡夫人,
"Frau Doktor... Frau Bielenberg,

400
00:37:15,274 --> 00:37:17,525
你做出了决定了吗?"
haben Sie einen Schluss gefasst?"

401
00:37:17,610 --> 00:37:20,528
意思是,"你决定了吗?"
which means, "Have you decided?"

402
00:37:21,572 --> 00:37:25,617
而我只是不能说不
And I simply couldn't say no.

403
00:37:25,701 --> 00:37:31,748
我只是说,"好吧,我不能
让你们待超过两天"
l just said, "Well, I can't
for longer than two days."

404
00:37:34,835 --> 00:37:40,382
我让他进了地窖
And I let him into the cellar.

405
00:37:42,009 --> 00:37:51,142
他们待了两天 在第二天
They stayed for two days
and on the second day

406
00:37:51,227 --> 00:37:53,853
更确切地说在(第二天)晚上,
他们一定已经离开了
or rather in the evening,
they must have left

407
00:37:53,938 --> 00:37:59,526
因为在(第三天)早上她已经走了,地窖空了,
because in the morning she was gone,
the cellar was empty,

408
00:37:59,610 --> 00:38:06,157
我竖起的小床全都已被理得很整齐
他们已经走了
the little bed l'd put up all
tidily arranged and they had gone.

409
00:38:07,702 --> 00:38:15,458
我后来知道他们在一个火车站买票时被抓了
l knew later that they were caught
buying a ticket at a railway station

410
00:38:15,543 --> 00:38:18,670
并被运往奥斯维辛(集中营毒死)
and were transported to Auschwitz.

411
00:38:19,714 --> 00:38:25,677
为什么我说 这是我必须说出
的最痛苦和可怕的故事
And why I say this is the most painful
and terrible story for me to have to tell

412
00:38:25,761 --> 00:38:34,644
是因为在他们离开后 我意识到
希特勒已经把我变成一个杀人犯
is because after they left l realised
that Hitler had turned me into a murderer.

413
00:38:36,856 --> 00:38:40,233
1944年的一天,
One day in '44,

414
00:38:40,318 --> 00:38:44,946
(下西里西亚)地方长官(卡尔·)汉克
走进我办公室并告诉我
Gauleiter Hanke came in my office
and told me

415
00:38:45,031 --> 00:38:50,869
他访问了一个位于上西里西亚
的集中营(即奥斯维辛集中营)
that he was visiting
a concentration camp in Upper Silesia

416
00:38:50,953 --> 00:38:55,915
并警告我永远不要走进那里的集中营
and warned me never to go
in a concentration camp there

417
00:38:56,000 --> 00:38:59,085
因为可怕的事情会发生
because horrible things would happen.

418
00:38:59,170 --> 00:39:09,095
这事以及我得到的其他暗示
本应使我下定决心
This together with other hints I got
should have made my decision

419
00:39:09,180 --> 00:39:15,185
立即去找希特勒或希姆莱
并问他们正在发生什么事
to go to Hitler immediately or to Himmler
and to ask them what is going on

420
00:39:15,269 --> 00:39:19,189
并采取我自己的措施
and to take my own steps.

421
00:39:19,273 --> 00:39:28,448
但我没有这么做,而现在我认为
没有这么做是我一生中最大的错误
But I didn't do it and not doing it was,
I think nowadays,the biggest fault in my life.

422
00:39:28,532 --> 00:39:34,704
(艾米·波诺赫弗 柏林家庭主妇)
我们感觉人们应该知道正在发生什么事,
We felt that people should
know what was going on,

423
00:39:34,789 --> 00:39:37,800
而(我的)这个小经历也许有代表性
and maybe typical is this little experience

424
00:39:37,800 --> 00:39:43,880
有一天我站在排队买菜
或买诸如此类东西的队伍中
which I had one day standing in the line
for vegetables or something like that.

425
00:39:43,964 --> 00:39:47,258
我告诉站在我周围的邻居们
l told my neighbours standing around me

426
00:39:47,343 --> 00:39:53,264
现在他们开始在集中营里杀犹太人,
that now they start to kill the Jews
in the concentration camps,

427
00:39:53,349 --> 00:40:00,438
他们被告知的那种"他们只是被带到那里 并能象
他们住在这里一样住在那里"的说法不是真的,
that it is not true that they only are brought there
and can live there as they live here,as it was told them.

428
00:40:00,523 --> 00:40:04,567
他们被杀了 而纳粹甚至用他们做肥皂
They are killed and they
even make soap out of them.

429
00:40:04,652 --> 00:40:07,737
我知道那情况
l know that.

430
00:40:07,822 --> 00:40:12,700
而他们说,"波诺赫弗夫人,如果
你不停止说这样恐怖的故事
And they said, "Frau Bonhoeffer, if you
don't stop telling such horror stories

431
00:40:12,700 --> 00:40:16,996
你也会进集中营的 而我们之中没人能帮你"
you will end in a concentration camp too
and nobody of us can help you."

432
00:40:17,081 --> 00:40:18,700
"你所说的事情不是真的"
"lt's not true what you're telling."

433
00:40:18,700 --> 00:40:23,600
"你不应该相信这些事情
你大概是从外国广播中听到它们的"
"You shouldn't believe these things.
You heard them from foreign broadcasts or so."

434
00:40:23,600 --> 00:40:27,799
"他们说这些事来树立德国的敌人"
"They tell these things
to make enemies against Germany."

435
00:40:27,883 --> 00:40:32,762
我说, "不, 那不是从广播中听来的
我是从第一手(信息来源)那里直接得知的"
l said, "No, that's not from broadcasts.
l know that directly from first hand."

436
00:40:32,847 --> 00:40:35,974
"你可以肯定事情就是那样的"
"You can be sure it is that way."

437
00:40:36,058 --> 00:40:39,978
回到家 我在晚上告诉我丈夫
And coming home
l told my husband in the evening

438
00:40:40,062 --> 00:40:45,066
而他根本没有称赞我...恰恰相反
and he was not at all applauding to me...
on the very contrary.

439
00:40:45,151 --> 00:40:48,820
他说, "亲爱的, 很抱歉地说,
He said, "My dear, sorry to say,

440
00:40:48,904 --> 00:40:52,782
但你(今天)的所作所为绝对白痴"
but you are absolutely idiotic,
what you are doing."

441
00:40:52,908 --> 00:40:55,452
"请你明白,
"Please understand,

442
00:40:55,536 --> 00:41:00,123
一个独裁政权就象一条蛇"
a dictatorship is like a snake."

443
00:41:00,207 --> 00:41:03,209
"如果你把你的脚踩在它的尾巴上,
"lf you put your foot on its tail,

444
00:41:03,294 --> 00:41:07,046
就象你做的那样,它就会咬你
as you do it, it will just bite you

445
00:41:07,131 --> 00:41:10,049
而没有人会得到帮助"
and nobody will be helped."

446
00:41:10,134 --> 00:41:12,093
"你必须攻击(蛇的)头部"
"You have to strike the head."

447
00:41:14,305 --> 00:41:19,100
只有军队的指挥官们
能有效地攻击头部
Only the commanders of the army
could strike effectively at the head.

448
00:41:19,185 --> 00:41:23,229
其他人勇敢地攻击尾巴 并(因此)丧生
Others had struck bravely
at the tail and perished.

449
00:41:23,355 --> 00:41:26,858
在慕尼黑,围绕在绍尔兄妹(汉斯和
苏菲·绍尔)周围的一些学生(白玫瑰组织)
ln Munich, a few students around
the Scholl brother and sister

450
00:41:26,942 --> 00:41:29,736
用传单表达抗议 并被屠杀了
had protested with leaflets
and been slaughtered.

451
00:41:29,820 --> 00:41:37,327
在柏林 一个由哈罗·舒尔茨-波伊森和哈耐克夫妇
领导的共产党间谍小组("红色乐队")被粉碎了
ln Berlin a communist spy team led by Harro
Schulze-Boysen and the Harnacks had been crushed.

452
00:41:37,411 --> 00:41:43,708
共产党员,社会主义者,基督徒,无名的
男男女女以极小的团体(形式)反抗着独裁者
Communists, socialists, Christians, anonymous
men and women defied the dictator in tiny groups.

453
00:41:43,834 --> 00:41:50,131
15万德国人由于政治上的抵抗
而被关进监狱或受到更糟(的惩罚)
150,000 Germans suffered prison or worse
for political resistance.

454
00:41:50,216 --> 00:41:53,134
针对蛇头的密谋是一个密谋的联盟
The plot against the snake's head
was a federation of plots.

455
00:41:53,219 --> 00:41:57,055
有象戈德勒那样的保守分子,
象毛奇那样的贵族,
There were conservatives like Goerdeler,
aristocrats like Moltke,

456
00:41:57,139 --> 00:42:01,476
波诺赫弗那样的教会人士,
特洛特那样的外交官
churchmen like Bonhoeffer,
diplomats like Trott.

457
00:42:01,560 --> 00:42:05,939
面临战败(的局面),
许多参谋军官也加入进来
Faced with defeat,
many staff officers joined in.

458
00:42:06,023 --> 00:42:12,362
所有人在接受"要想攻击蛇头 就必须要求对
希特勒进行肉体谋杀"(这个事实方面)都很犹豫
All were slow to accept that to strike at the head
demanded the physical murder of Hitler.

459
00:42:12,863 --> 00:42:16,783
但在1944年,出现了一个将之付诸行动的人...
But in 1944, there appeared
a man for action...

460
00:42:16,867 --> 00:42:20,620
陆军上校克劳斯·冯·斯陶芬伯格伯爵
Colonel Count Claus von Stauffenberg.

461
00:42:20,704 --> 00:42:25,500
当斯陶芬伯格来到柏林,
(他)当然带来了极大不同
All the difference was brought in,of course,
when Stauffenberg came to Berlin.

462
00:42:25,584 --> 00:42:32,757
(奥托·约翰博士 抵抗组织成员)
他(在战争中)失去了他的左眼,
他的左手,或者说他左手的三根手指,
He had lost his left eye,his left hand,
or three fingers of his left hand,

463
00:42:32,841 --> 00:42:35,635
以及他的全部右手
and his right hand altogether.

464
00:42:35,719 --> 00:42:39,264
起先他只是政变的策划人,
Originally he was only
the planner of the coup d'état,

465
00:42:39,348 --> 00:42:44,435
但他必须去希特勒的总部报告
并参加那里的会议
but he had to report to Hitler's headquarters
and to attend conferences there.

466
00:42:44,520 --> 00:42:48,273
这使他能真的很接近希特勒
并因此能尝试行刺(希特勒),
This enabled him to get really near
to Hitler and then to make an attempt,

467
00:42:48,357 --> 00:42:51,234
而他在1944年7月20日这么做了
which he did on July 20, '44.

468
00:42:54,363 --> 00:43:00,243
突然有一声非常令人惊恐的爆炸声
(Junge) Suddenly there was
a very alarming bang.

469
00:43:00,327 --> 00:43:03,496
我们听到呼叫医生的声音
We heard voices crying for a doctor

470
00:43:03,581 --> 00:43:08,876
我们还看到一些穿着沾满血渍制服的将军
and we saw some generals
with bloodstained uniforms.

471
00:43:09,920 --> 00:43:11,838
然后跑来一位副官
Then came one of the adjutants

472
00:43:11,922 --> 00:43:16,843
并说,"发生了一次炸弹爆炸,
但元首没有受伤"
and said, "There was a bomb explosion,
but the Führer is not hurt."

473
00:43:16,927 --> 00:43:18,886
"他仍然活着"
"He's still alive."

474
00:43:18,971 --> 00:43:24,642
我们前往希特勒的地堡
我们碰到了他
We went towards Hitler's bunker
and we met him.

475
00:43:24,727 --> 00:43:29,439
或许是这次爆炸的一小时后吧
Maybe it was an hour
after this explosion.

476
00:43:29,523 --> 00:43:39,949
他看起来很滑稽 因为他的头发
象一把刷子一样竖着
He looked funny because his
hair stood up like a brush

477
00:43:40,034 --> 00:43:46,456
而他的裤子被撕裂成一小条一小条的
and his trousers were slit in small stripes.

478
00:43:46,540 --> 00:43:52,253
他说,"你瞧,命运为了我的使命而拯救了我"
He said, "You see,
fate has saved me for my mission."

479
00:43:52,338 --> 00:43:55,632
"我要做我必须做的事"
"l am to do what I must do."

480
00:43:57,843 --> 00:44:00,345
在柏林的战争部,
At the War Ministry in Berlin,

481
00:44:00,429 --> 00:44:04,724
密谋的将军们相信希特勒已死
the plotting generals
believed that Hitler was dead.

482
00:44:05,184 --> 00:44:11,800
当我来到(战争部)总部,斯陶芬伯格
正忙着给不同的司令部打电话,
(John) When I came to the headquarters,Stauffenberg
was busy with telephoning the various army commands,

483
00:44:11,800 --> 00:44:14,984
海夫顿(斯陶芬伯格的副官)
告诉我发生了什么,
and Haeften informed me of what had happened,

484
00:44:15,069 --> 00:44:20,031
他们是如何扔炸弹的,
然后他说,"希特勒死了"
how they'd thrown the bomb,
and then he said, "Hitler's dead."

485
00:44:20,115 --> 00:44:23,159
我们真的相信了 因为接着斯陶芬伯格走了进来
We really did believe it
because Stauffenberg then came in.

486
00:44:23,243 --> 00:44:26,579
我们同他进行了简短的交谈...
他忙到没空说出细节
We had a short talk with him...
he was much too busy to give details.

487
00:44:26,664 --> 00:44:29,499
他说, "希特勒死了
一切听其自然吧"
He said, "Hitler's dead.
Leave everything alone."

488
00:44:29,583 --> 00:44:31,334
"我们看看能做些什么"
"We'll see what can be done."

489
00:44:33,087 --> 00:44:37,000
密谋者们命令来占领(柏林)城的人
是奥托·雷莫少校,
The man the plotters ordered
to occupy the city was Major Otto Remer,

490
00:44:37,000 --> 00:44:41,094
一个被训练成遵守任何上级命令的狂热军人
a fanatical soldier programmed
to obey any superior order.

491
00:44:41,178 --> 00:44:46,182
一开始他服从了密谋者们(的命令),
然后戈培尔找到了他
At first he obeyed the plotters,
then Goebbels got hold of him.

492
00:44:53,565 --> 00:44:58,152
戈培尔看到我真的非常高兴
他眉开眼笑
Goebbels was really very pleased
to see me. He was beaming.

493
00:44:58,237 --> 00:45:01,906
他说, "雷莫,对所有这一切你知道什么?"
He said, "Remer,
what do you know about all this?"

494
00:45:01,990 --> 00:45:05,827
"这里发生了什么?
你接到了什么命令?"
"What's going on here?
What orders have you got?"

495
00:45:05,911 --> 00:45:12,041
我说, "部长, 我来(逮捕)你
那样你能澄清情况"
l said, "Minister, I have come to you
so that you can clarify the situation."

496
00:45:12,126 --> 00:45:15,962
戈培尔回答道, "他们正试图
用一块毛布蒙住你的眼睛"
Goebbels replied, "They're trying
to pull the wool over your eyes."

497
00:45:16,046 --> 00:45:20,049
"希特勒还活着.
我刚同他交谈过"
"Hitler's alive.
l've just spoken to him."

498
00:45:20,134 --> 00:45:24,887
我是如此震惊 以至于说道,
"请让我和元首说话,"
l was so astonished that I said,
"Please, let me speak to the Führer,"

499
00:45:24,972 --> 00:45:27,724
电话被接通了
and this was done.

500
00:45:27,850 --> 00:45:33,146
在电话线的另一头希特勒说,
"雷莫先生,你瞧我还活着"
On the other end of the line Hitler
said, "Herr Remer, you see I am alive."

501
00:45:33,230 --> 00:45:37,817
"我是阿道夫·希特勒 你认出了我的声音"
"l am Adolf Hitler.
You recognise my voice."

502
00:45:37,901 --> 00:45:40,403
"现在你相信我还活着吗?"
"Now do you believe l'm alive?"

503
00:45:52,499 --> 00:45:54,959
现在雷莫被重新编排了程序
Now Remer was reprogrammed.

504
00:45:55,043 --> 00:45:58,796
他把部队开回战争部
并逮捕了他找到的每个人
He marched back to the War Ministry
and arrested everyone he found.

505
00:45:58,881 --> 00:46:04,427
(政变)密谋突然失败了 动摇的军队
复归到了它(效忠希特勒)的誓言
The plot collapsed.
The wavering army returned to its oath.

506
00:46:05,137 --> 00:46:07,180
被告冯·维茨莱本(元帅,曾任德军西线总司令)
Der Angeklagte von Witzleben.

507
00:46:07,264 --> 00:46:10,300
许多密谋者,在被关进监狱和经过刑讯之后,
Many of the plotters,
after prison and torture,

508
00:46:10,300 --> 00:46:18,524
将要面对一场由纳粹德国的明星法官
罗兰德·弗莱斯勒主持的可怕的虚假审判
were to face a ghastly sham trial conducted by
Roland Freisler,the star judge of Nazi Germany.

509
00:46:18,609 --> 00:46:23,446
他们的家人被逮捕
而他们的孩子被送进孤儿院
Their families were seized
and their children sent to orphanages.

510
00:46:23,530 --> 00:46:26,491
更幸运的密谋者,他们之中有斯陶芬伯格,
The luckier conspirators,
among them Stauffenberg,

511
00:46:26,575 --> 00:46:29,660
立即在战争部的庭院里被枪决
had been shot out of hand
in the War Ministry courtyard.

512
00:46:29,745 --> 00:46:32,747
一些人试图在法庭上解释他们的动机
Some attempted to explain their motives in court.

513
00:46:32,831 --> 00:46:36,709
冯·什未林伯爵是一个曾在波兰服役的军官
Count von Schwerin was an officer
who had served in Poland.

514
00:46:36,800 --> 00:46:42,200
我的想法改变了,对我来说很难...

515
00:46:42,700 --> 00:46:48,000
我在波兰为德国效过力

516
00:46:48,500 --> 00:46:54,000
我对我们的政策变得担忧,

517
00:46:57,500 --> 00:47:01,800
担忧我们的国家社会主义

518
00:47:03,000 --> 00:47:06,500
我回想起许多谋杀...

519
00:47:07,000 --> 00:47:09,000
谋杀?

520
00:47:11,800 --> 00:47:15,800
你这个...可怜...虫!

521
00:47:20,712 --> 00:47:25,299
被定罪的人被缓慢地在肉钩上吊死
The condemned were hanged
slowly on meat hooks.

522
00:47:25,384 --> 00:47:29,804
一部展示他们(受刑)的痛苦的影片被
拍摄下来 并随后被播放给希特勒观看
A film of their agony was made
and shown later to Hitler.

523
00:47:29,888 --> 00:47:33,558
但这场密谋使希特勒成为
一个担惊受怕,受到伤害的人
But the plot left Hitler
a frightened, damaged man.

524
00:47:34,393 --> 00:47:41,607
7月20日后的镇压永远打破了
贵族的权力和普鲁士传统
The repression after 20 July broke the power of the
aristocracy and of the Prussian tradition forever.

525
00:47:41,692 --> 00:47:45,945
但没有统治阶级能取代他们的位置
But there was no ruling class
to take their place.

526
00:47:47,614 --> 00:47:51,951
对希特勒来说,所有的将军们
现在似乎都是嫌疑犯
To Hitler, all generals
now seemed suspect.

527
00:47:52,035 --> 00:47:57,123
只有戈培尔,鲍曼和希姆莱能接近他
Only Goebbels, Bormann and Himmler
could get close to him.

528
00:48:03,046 --> 00:48:08,301
他缓慢但又持续地变得虚弱
(Junge) Slowly but steadily
he became weak.

529
00:48:08,385 --> 00:48:14,348
医生们进进出出
而他变得完全缺乏感情
The doctors went in and out
and he became totally apathetic.

530
00:48:14,433 --> 00:48:16,934
对任何事情都不感兴趣
Not interested in anything.

531
00:48:17,019 --> 00:48:22,106
这是西线上一个非常关键的紧要关头
lt was a very critical situation
on the West Front

532
00:48:22,190 --> 00:48:24,483
在东线上也一样
and on the East Front, too.

533
00:48:26,361 --> 00:48:31,866
在一些日子里 就好像希特勒不存在一样
And some days
it was like Hitler didn't exist.

534
00:48:32,784 --> 00:48:37,330
他的健康突然恶化,
He was deteriorating suddenly
in his health,

535
00:48:37,414 --> 00:48:40,082
但我不会过分到竟敢说
but I wouldn't go so far as to say

536
00:48:40,167 --> 00:48:44,170
他不再为他所做的事情负责
that he was no more responsible
for what he was doing.

537
00:48:45,547 --> 00:48:47,840
在某些方面他...
ln some ways he was...

538
00:48:47,925 --> 00:48:50,593
我有一个坐了20年牢的囚犯的经历
l have the experience
of a prisoner of 20 years.

539
00:48:50,677 --> 00:48:53,387
在某些方面他表现得象一个囚犯
ln some ways he was behaving
like a prisoner.

540
00:49:03,482 --> 00:49:08,486
在一片破坏痕迹之中
德国人仍设法继续(工作生活)下去
Through the devastation
the Germans somehow kept going.

541
00:49:10,280 --> 00:49:14,408
沿着(被炸成)一片废墟的街道,
工人们打开一条通向被炸毁的工厂的道路
Down ruined streets, the workers
made their way to ruined factories

542
00:49:14,493 --> 00:49:17,620
那里一些机器仍能被拿来(修好)使用
where a few machines
could still be made to turn.

543
00:49:29,508 --> 00:49:32,259
生活退却到了地窖中
Life retreated to the cellars.

544
00:49:33,762 --> 00:49:38,557
人们意识到 八颗炸弹呈一条
直线落下 然后你就安全了
People learned that eight bombs fell
in a row and then you were safe.

545
00:49:38,642 --> 00:49:41,644
他们学会了得过且过地过日子
They learned to live a day at a time.

546
00:49:55,784 --> 00:49:58,953
要忍受这(种生活)真的很可怕
(Tucking) lt was really dreadful
to endure it.

547
00:49:59,746 --> 00:50:02,164
我们是如此疲惫
We were so tired.

548
00:50:02,249 --> 00:50:04,625
你总是处于匆忙之中
You were always in a hurry.

549
00:50:05,752 --> 00:50:10,881
所有的铁路都被摧毁了
而卡车都没有汽油了
All the railways were destroyed
and the lorries had no petrol.

550
00:50:10,966 --> 00:50:14,135
我们从一开始就有配给(制度)
We had rations from the beginning

551
00:50:14,219 --> 00:50:18,431
它一步步地变得越来越糟
and step by step it was worse and worse.

552
00:50:19,933 --> 00:50:23,769
德国自身已接近其(能力)限度的极限
Germany itself was near the end of its tether.

553
00:50:23,854 --> 00:50:27,982
七百万外国强制劳工仍不够用
Seven million foreign forced labourers
were not enough.

554
00:50:28,066 --> 00:50:32,695
一切东西...石油,金属,食物...
都正在消耗殆尽
Everything... oil, metal, food...
was running out.

555
00:50:32,779 --> 00:50:38,117
从衣服到飞机的所有东西都
被打上补丁并重新投入使用
Everything from clothes to planes
was patched and made to serve again.

556
00:50:38,201 --> 00:50:40,286
军人们也一样
Men, too.

557
00:50:43,498 --> 00:50:46,751
战争伤残者被送到工厂里循环利用
The war cripples were recycled
for the factories.

558
00:50:46,835 --> 00:50:50,463
脑部受损的士兵被教会重新说话
The brain-damaged soldiers
were taught to speak again.

559
00:50:50,547 --> 00:50:54,091
现在我们甚至想要低声说话
Nun wollen wir einmal das hauchen.

560
00:50:54,176 --> 00:50:57,553
那怎么说?
Was ist das für ein Laut?

561
00:50:57,637 --> 00:50:58,846
A.
A.

562
00:50:58,930 --> 00:51:04,560
我们读A,那么这是?
Hauchen wir das A, dann heißt es?

563
00:51:04,644 --> 00:51:06,103
Ha.
Ha.

564
00:51:06,188 --> 00:51:10,357
现在我给你看这里的一本书
Nun werde ich Ihnen
dieses Buch hier zeigen.

565
00:51:10,442 --> 00:51:13,944
我们应该怎么说?
Was sollen wir hauchen?

566
00:51:14,029 --> 00:51:17,114
哈, 哈, 哈.
Ha, ha, ha.

567
00:51:17,199 --> 00:51:20,242
- 快速重复.
- 哈, 哈, 哈.
- Schnell hintereinander.
- Ha, ha, ha.

568
00:51:21,620 --> 00:51:25,915
现在敌人正在接近帝国的边界
Now the enemy was approaching
the very frontiers of the Reich.

569
00:51:25,999 --> 00:51:32,546
人民冲锋队,由老人,未成年人和不适合参军者
组成的国土防卫部队,被(带领着)宣誓就职
The Volkssturm, the home guard of the elderly,
the underaged and the unfit, was sworn in.

570
00:51:32,700 --> 00:51:36,000
柏林国土防卫军的战士们

571
00:51:36,800 --> 00:51:41,500
举起你们的右手 并跟着我宣誓...

572
00:51:43,000 --> 00:51:47,300
我对上帝发出这个神圣的誓言

573
00:51:51,800 --> 00:51:55,300
对德意志帝国的领导人

574
00:51:59,400 --> 00:52:01,300
阿道夫·希特勒

575
00:52:03,500 --> 00:52:08,000
完全效忠和服从

576
00:52:11,628 --> 00:52:17,091
柏林人民冲锋队的战士们,
你们刚刚已...
Männer des Berliner Volkssturms,
ihr habt soeben...

577
00:52:17,217 --> 00:52:24,014
他们带着僵硬的面容 听着戈培尔
(进行)关于战斗到最后一刻的慷慨演讲
They listened with closed faces to oratory
from Goebbels about fighting to the bitter end.

578
00:52:24,558 --> 00:52:31,397
做好准备的和坚决抵抗的部队,
(Goebbels) ..wehrbereiter
und wehrentschlossener Männer verfügt,

579
00:52:32,149 --> 00:52:36,777
有一种坚定和不可动摇的意志...
die den festen und unerschütterlichen
Willen haben...

580
00:52:36,777 --> 00:52:40,400
数百万人已不可动摇地下定了决心

581
00:52:43,400 --> 00:52:47,200
绝不让我们的旗帜降下

582
00:52:47,500 --> 00:52:51,400
并象懦夫一样投降

583
00:53:07,642 --> 00:53:16,025
人民冲锋队步履艰难地穿过 四年前同样
见证从巴黎凯旋的士兵们 的勃兰登堡门
The Volkssturm trudged out through that same
Brandenburg Gate which had seen the soldiers
march back from Paris four years before.

584
00:53:22,949 --> 00:53:25,534
他们朝俄国人走去,
They went towards the Russians,

585
00:53:25,619 --> 00:53:28,996
把他们的想法埋在他们的心底
keeping their thoughts to themselves.

