1
00:00:15,140 --> 00:00:17,850
温斯顿·丘吉尔曾经告诉斯大林:
Winston Churchill once told Stalin:

2
00:00:17,934 --> 00:00:21,645
"地中海是鳄鱼柔软的下腹"
"The Mediterranean is the soft
underbelly of the crocodile."

3
00:00:22,856 --> 00:00:25,300
丘吉尔和英国的参谋长们确信
Churchill and the British
Chiefs of Staff were sure

4
00:00:25,300 --> 00:00:30,821
通过意大利进攻被德国占领
的欧洲将帮助缩短战争
that attacking German-occupied Europe
through ltaly would help shorten the war.

5
00:00:31,698 --> 00:00:33,300
美国人未被说服,
The Americans were not convinced,

6
00:00:33,300 --> 00:00:37,453
他们更倾向于集中力量越过
英吉利海峡发动决定性的一击
preferring to concentrate on the decisive
blow across the English Channel.

7
00:00:38,300 --> 00:00:43,459
他们只是勉强才同意和他们的
英国盟友一起踏上去罗马的征途
Only reluctantly did they agree to join
their British allies on the road to Rome.

8
00:01:45,021 --> 00:01:46,897
1942年11月
November, 1942.

9
00:01:47,300 --> 00:01:49,691
珍珠港事件11个月后,
11 months after Pearl Harbour,

10
00:01:49,776 --> 00:01:54,071
美军准备好了与德国国防军的第一次遭遇
the American army prepared for its
first encounter with the Wehrmacht.

11
00:01:59,200 --> 00:02:07,000
火炬行动...英美在法属北非殖民地
摩洛哥和阿尔及利亚登陆行动的代号
Operation Torch... codename for the Anglo-American landings
in the French North African colonies of Morocco and Algeria.

12
00:02:10,296 --> 00:02:14,049
他们遇到了维希法国部队
的极小或没有抵抗
They met little or no resistance
from the forces of Vichy France.

13
00:02:14,134 --> 00:02:17,803
法国指挥部很快与贝当政府决裂
The French command soon broke
with the government of Pétain

14
00:02:17,887 --> 00:02:21,974
他们的部队也成为盟军的一部分
and their troops became
part of the Allied army.

15
00:02:24,394 --> 00:02:29,982
一位美国将军,德怀特·D·艾森豪威尔,
是最高指挥官
An American general,Dwight D Eisenhower,
was supreme commander.

16
00:02:30,066 --> 00:02:32,800
美国(战争)规划者们
从不热衷于(策划)行动,
The American planners
were never keen on the operation,

17
00:02:32,800 --> 00:02:40,000
但罗斯福总统决心在1942年将他的
地面部队投入与希特勒的作战中
but President Roosevelt was determined to get his
ground forces into action against Hitler in 1942.

18
00:02:41,000 --> 00:02:46,999
在突尼斯进攻德国人是仅次于
在欧洲开辟第二战场的最好事情
Attacking the Germans in Tunisia was the next
best thing to a second front in Europe.

19
00:02:56,467 --> 00:02:59,200
在卡萨布兰卡,在登陆的两个月后,
At Casablanca,within two
months of the landings,

20
00:02:59,200 --> 00:03:03,641
令人印象深刻的一大批英国
和美国最高级官员聚集到一起
an impressive array of British
and American top brass assembled.

21
00:03:13,860 --> 00:03:15,000
俄国人不在场,
The Russians were not present,

22
00:03:15,000 --> 00:03:20,324
但那儿的每个人都知道
他们必须做点什么来分担红军的压力
but everybody there knew they had to do something
to take the pressure off the Red Army.

23
00:03:20,408 --> 00:03:25,330
丘吉尔和罗斯福现在必须决定
接下来他们去哪里
Churchill and Roosevelt had now to
decide where they went from here.

24
00:03:28,625 --> 00:03:30,200
1943年初,
At the beginning of 1943,

25
00:03:30,200 --> 00:03:34,171
英国人和美国人在北非站稳了脚跟
the British and Americans
were firmly established in North Africa.

26
00:03:34,255 --> 00:03:37,600
希特勒增援了在突尼斯的隆美尔的部队,
Hitler had reinforced
Rommel's forces in Tunisia,

27
00:03:37,800 --> 00:03:40,400
但随着英国第八军从东面逼近,
but with the British Eighth Army
closing from the east,

28
00:03:40,400 --> 00:03:46,308
整个非洲海岸线落入盟军手中只是个时间问题
it could only be a matter of time before the
entire African coastline was in Allied hands.

29
00:03:46,392 --> 00:03:47,400
然后怎么办？
What then?

30
00:03:47,400 --> 00:03:57,736
我们必须面对这个现实 那就是双方在战争
应采取什么未来战略上存在很大的区别
We've got to face the fact that there was a big
difference between the two sides about what
the future strategy of the war would be.

31
00:03:57,862 --> 00:04:03,617
(肯尼斯·斯壮将军 艾森豪威尔的情报参谋)
英国人,英国参谋长们,丘吉尔,
The British, the British
Chiefs of Staff, Churchill,

32
00:04:03,701 --> 00:04:11,583
都赞同未来的战役应通过意大利进行
were all in favour of the future of the
campaign being carried out through ltaly

33
00:04:11,668 --> 00:04:17,965
并打击德国人下腹的下部,
and hitting at the underside
of the underbelly of the Germans,

34
00:04:18,049 --> 00:04:21,718
向上移动并最终与俄国人汇合
moving up and eventually joining up
with the Russians.

35
00:04:21,803 --> 00:04:26,098
美国人持有完全相反的看法
The Americans held
exactly the opposite view.

36
00:04:26,182 --> 00:04:30,560
他们感觉你能打败德国的唯一办法
They felt the only way
that you could defeat Germany

37
00:04:30,645 --> 00:04:35,440
就是取最近的路直插德国中心,穿过(英吉利)海峡,
was to take the shortest way into the
centre of Germany, across the Channel,

38
00:04:35,566 --> 00:04:43,615
并推进至鲁尔和萨尔地区,这些大工业区,
and advance into the areas of the Ruhr
and Saar,the great industrial areas,

39
00:04:43,700 --> 00:04:48,120
然后用那种方法消灭德国部队
and then destroy the German forces
by that means.

40
00:04:48,997 --> 00:04:53,200
由帝国总参谋长,艾伦·布鲁克爵士领导的英国人,
The British,led by Sir Alan Brooke,
Chief of the lmperial General Staff,

41
00:04:53,200 --> 00:04:57,300
带着一定要按他们方案行动的决心
来到卡萨布兰卡 他们如愿了
came to Casablanca determined
to have their way. They got it.

42
00:04:57,300 --> 00:05:03,427
由马歇尔领导的美国人被说服
下个目标将是入侵西西里,
The Americans, under General Marshall,were persuaded
that the next objective would be the invasion of Sicily,

43
00:05:03,511 --> 00:05:06,263
并希望这能导致意大利的投降
leading, it was hoped,
to the surrender of ltaly.

44
00:05:06,347 --> 00:05:10,600
这样主要的第二战场又被推迟了一年
Thus the main second front
was postponed for another year.

45
00:05:10,800 --> 00:05:18,608
然而当时 从卡萨布兰卡会议传出的大新闻
是美国总统作出的一个令人意外的宣言
At the time, however, the big news from
the Casablanca conference was an unexpected
pronouncement by the American president.

46
00:05:18,693 --> 00:05:23,280
罗斯福先生开头说道 当他还是个年轻人时
Mr Roosevelt began by saying
that when he was a young man

47
00:05:23,364 --> 00:05:29,119
美国军事家中最富盛名的是格兰特将军,
the great reputation in the American
military was General Grant,

48
00:05:29,203 --> 00:05:36,251
(德鲁·米德尔顿 战地记者)
他曾下过一道命令 说他除了无条件投降外不接受任何条件,
who had once sent an order saying that he would
accept no terms but unconditional surrender,

49
00:05:36,336 --> 00:05:44,468
这些事实上也是同盟国,或联合国,
想要向它们的敌人提出的条件
and that these in fact were the terms
that the Allies, or the United Nations,
wanted to present to their enemies.

50
00:05:45,678 --> 00:05:53,143
然后他继续说下去 仿佛他
不清楚他所作的声明有多重要
He then went on as though he did not understand
how important a statement he had made.

51
00:05:53,227 --> 00:05:57,272
丘吉尔先生看来对此相当惊讶
Mr Churchill looked
considerably surprised at this.

52
00:05:57,357 --> 00:06:00,275
我认为丘吉尔先生感觉
And I think that Mr Churchill felt that

53
00:06:00,360 --> 00:06:05,238
把盟国的立场呈现给敌人不是最好的办法
it was not the best way to present
the Allied position to the enemy.

54
00:06:05,323 --> 00:06:09,659
然而,就象他那时和后来说的那样,
他是罗斯福先生的热心副手
However, as he said then and later,
he was Mr Roosevelt's ardent lieutenant

55
00:06:09,744 --> 00:06:12,245
而且他会赞同这个宣言
and he would go along with it.

56
00:06:21,172 --> 00:06:25,092
会谈后,罗斯福以他另一个身份出现...
After the talking, Roosevelt
appeared in his other capacity...

57
00:06:25,176 --> 00:06:29,012
美国武装部队总司令
commander in chief
of the American armed forces.

58
00:06:36,200 --> 00:06:42,401
如果这支新到的看来自信满满的美国军队
越过大西洋 期望能所向披靡的话,
If this fresh confident-looking American army had
crossed the Atlantic expecting to carry all before it,

59
00:06:42,485 --> 00:06:46,029
那它很快就被残酷地打破了幻想
it was very soon cruelly disillusioned.

60
00:06:52,954 --> 00:06:56,665
在穿过位于突尼斯的凯塞林
隘口进行的一次突然猛攻中,
In a sudden onslaught through
the Kassarine Pass in Tunisia,

61
00:06:56,749 --> 00:07:02,000
隆美尔使美军遭受了
整场战争中最惨痛的失败之一
Rommel inflicted on the American army
one of its worst defeats of the entire war.

62
00:07:21,700 --> 00:07:30,000
对装甲很薄,火力也不足的美国坦克来说
非洲军团的装备好出太多,经验也高出太多
The Afrikakorps was far too well-equipped
and experienced for the lightly armoured
and underpowered American tanks.

63
00:07:34,036 --> 00:07:38,081
这些没有经验的年轻美国人
的士气被严重动摇了
The morale of these raw young
Americans was badly shaken.

64
00:07:38,166 --> 00:07:40,625
许多人被俘虏
Many were taken prisoner.

65
00:07:57,226 --> 00:08:03,482
这让部队面对这样一个现实
那就是这将是一场漫长的战争
(Middleton) It brought the troops face to face
with the fact that this was going to be a long war

66
00:08:03,566 --> 00:08:05,901
而且是一场艰苦的战争
而德国人非常厉害
and a tough one and
the Germans were very good.

67
00:08:05,985 --> 00:08:10,200
军队从来不从其他军队那里
吸取教训,他们不得不自己学会,
Armies never learn from other armies,
they have to learn by themselves,

68
00:08:10,200 --> 00:08:14,400
我们在凯塞林(隘口)灾难性地使用的许多战术
and a lot of the tactics that
we used disastrously at Kassarine

69
00:08:14,400 --> 00:08:21,583
就是英军两年前在西部沙漠同样
灾难性地使用,然后摈弃的那些(战术)
were those that the British army had used
equally disastrously two years before in
the western desert, then discarded.

70
00:08:21,667 --> 00:08:24,961
我想这帮助了我们的军队
这也使他们意识到,
l think it helped our army
and it also made them realise,

71
00:08:25,046 --> 00:08:28,006
由于英国人从北面下来并帮了很大忙,
because the British came down
from the north and did help,

72
00:08:28,090 --> 00:08:32,000
这将是一次合作的努力,
我们不可能独自赢得战争
that this was going to be a cooperative
effort, that we couldn't win it alone.

73
00:08:32,000 --> 00:08:38,308
还有,这使普通大兵习惯于
一场战斗后还有一场的事实
And also, it got the average GI accustomed to the fact
that there was going to be one battle after another.

74
00:08:39,268 --> 00:08:43,000
但隆美尔缺乏力量来利用他的胜利
But Rommel lacked the strength
to exploit his victory.

75
00:08:43,000 --> 00:08:48,401
在(英国元帅)亚历山大指挥下的盟军,
重整队伍并在十天后夺回(凯塞林)通道
The Allies, under Alexander, regrouped
and within ten days retook the path.

76
00:08:48,486 --> 00:08:51,400
在突尼斯的德国人现在被包围了
The Germans in Tunisia
were now hemmed in.

77
00:08:51,400 --> 00:08:57,300
盟军对海岸线的海空封锁
使大规模撤离变得不可能
The Allied sea and air blockade of the coastline
made large-scale evacuation impossible.

78
00:08:57,300 --> 00:09:03,333
在南面,(英国)第八军的一支
突前巡逻队与美国第二军会合
In the south, a forward patrol of the Eighth
Army linked up with the American Second Corps.

79
00:09:03,417 --> 00:09:05,502
牢笼合上了
The trap closed.

80
00:09:07,797 --> 00:09:12,801
两支盟军部队,一度相隔2,000英里的山川和沙漠,
Two Allied forces, once separated
by 2,000 miles of mountain and desert,

81
00:09:12,885 --> 00:09:18,014
联手对德国在非洲的阵地发起了最后的猛攻
joined hands for the final onslaught
on the German position in Africa.

82
00:09:29,100 --> 00:09:31,900
在人数上占有巨大优势的盟军,
The Allied armies, vastly superior in numbers,

83
00:09:31,900 --> 00:09:38,300
把失去因病回国疗养的隆美尔的敌人,
从突尼斯的山川赶向了大海
drove the enemy,now without Rommel who had been invalided
home,back through the mountains of Tunisia towards the sea.

84
00:09:47,878 --> 00:09:52,382
盟国空军拥有无可置疑的制空权
The Allied air forces
had undisputed control.

85
00:09:56,000 --> 00:09:59,014
七天后一切都结束了
In seven days it was all over.

86
00:10:32,298 --> 00:10:35,967
终于,非洲军团意识到战至最后一人毫无意义
Finally, the Afrikakorps saw no point
in fighting to the last man.

87
00:10:36,052 --> 00:10:39,095
他们成群投降
They surrendered in droves.

88
00:10:43,142 --> 00:10:46,394
接替隆美尔的倒霉的(汉斯·)冯·阿尼姆将军,
The unfortunate General von Arnim,
who succeeded Rommel,

89
00:10:46,479 --> 00:10:49,773
也和他所有的参谋一起投降了
also surrendered with all his staff.

90
00:10:49,857 --> 00:10:53,234
差不多二十五万人成了战俘...
Nearly a quarter of a million men
were taken prisoner...

91
00:10:53,319 --> 00:10:56,863
一个可与斯大林格勒媲美的胜利
a victory to rank alongside Stalingrad.

92
00:10:56,947 --> 00:11:02,000
这对英国人和他们的地中海
战略来说是一个重大推动
This was a major boost for the British
and their Mediterranean strategy.

93
00:11:08,500 --> 00:11:13,004
西西里,就如在卡萨布兰卡同意的那样,
是议事日程上的下一个项目
Sicily, as agreed at Casablanca,
was the next item on the agenda.

94
00:11:13,089 --> 00:11:16,132
德国在突尼斯崩溃仅仅两个月后,
Only two months after the
German collapse in Tunisia,

95
00:11:16,217 --> 00:11:21,000
英国人和美国人开始
在西西里海滩登陆部队
the British and Americans began
landing troops on Sicilian beaches.

96
00:11:29,855 --> 00:11:33,858
英国人由蒙哥马利领导,
美国人则是由巴顿将军指挥...
The British were led by Montgomery,
the Americans by General Patton...

97
00:11:33,943 --> 00:11:40,448
这两个以自我为中心的风云人物
第一次被卷入同一场战役中
the first time these egocentric personalities
had been involved in the same campaign.

98
00:11:56,757 --> 00:12:01,636
是英国第八军遭遇了德国人最凶猛的抵抗
It was the British Eighth Army which
met the fiercest German resistance.

99
00:12:01,721 --> 00:12:07,517
在他们左翼,巴顿的美军很成功地横扫西西里
On their left, Patton's Americans
swept across Sicily in style.

100
00:12:12,523 --> 00:12:19,320
他们在黑手党和平民中的家族关系中找到了有用的盟友
They found useful allies in the Mafia and family
connections among the civilian population.

101
00:12:19,405 --> 00:12:22,031
局势多少被这样一个事实所缓解
The situation was relieved
somewhat by the fact

102
00:12:22,116 --> 00:12:27,500
那就是在西西里很少有一个
家族在美国是没有亲戚的
that there was hardly a family in Sicily
that didn't have relatives in the United States.

103
00:12:28,247 --> 00:12:32,000
把战争带上他们自己土地的西西里登陆,
The Sicilian landing,bringing
the war on to their own soil,

104
00:12:32,000 --> 00:12:35,253
使绝大多数意大利人确信
他们的努力注定要失败
convinced most ltalians
that theirs was a lost cause.

105
00:12:35,337 --> 00:12:38,089
如果有可能成团地缴械投降,
Giving themselves up,
if possible by the regiment,

106
00:12:38,174 --> 00:12:42,844
成为意大利武装部队的首要目标
became the first objective
of ltaly's armed forces.

107
00:12:47,850 --> 00:12:53,146
盟军对罗马的空袭为退出
战争提供了另一个理由
Allied bombing raids on Rome provided another
argument for getting out of the war.

108
00:12:57,985 --> 00:13:00,403
当了20年"领袖"的贝尼托·墨索里尼,
Benito Mussolini, il Duce for 20 years,

109
00:13:00,529 --> 00:13:04,449
被他自己的大法西斯议会
以票数通过了(对他的不信任动议)
was outvoted in his own
Fascist Grand Council.

110
00:13:08,662 --> 00:13:12,415
7月25日,他被推翻了
On July 25th,he was toppled from power.

111
00:13:14,300 --> 00:13:19,673
国王维托里奥·埃马努埃莱三世批准年长的
(佩特罗·)巴多格里奥元帅为政府首脑
King Victor Emmanuel approved the elderly
Marshal Badoglio as head of the government.

112
00:13:20,758 --> 00:13:25,053
巴多格里奥公开宣称战争将继续,
Badoglio declared publicly
that the war would go on,

113
00:13:25,137 --> 00:13:30,058
但立即与盟军就投降事宜展开秘密谈判
but immediately began secret negotiations
with the Allies for surrender.

114
00:13:35,356 --> 00:13:41,402
到现在西西里,仅仅在几周之后,
几乎全部落入盟军手中
By now Sicily, after only a few weeks,
was almost all in Allied hands.

115
00:13:47,034 --> 00:13:50,995
这次不再有大批的德国战俘了
This time there was to be no great haul
of German prisoners.

116
00:13:52,540 --> 00:13:57,293
德国穿越狭窄的墨西拿海峡的撤退非常成功
German evacuation across the narrow
Straits of Messina was highly successful.

117
00:14:06,679 --> 00:14:11,099
德国国防军的绝大部分人员
逃到了(意大利)本土
Most of the Wehrmacht's personnel
got away to the mainland.

118
00:14:11,183 --> 00:14:14,519
甚至是最后一只看门狗
Even the last guard dog.

119
00:14:23,529 --> 00:14:27,699
巴顿将军打败蒙哥马利(抢先)进入墨西拿
General Patton beat Montgomery into Messina.

120
00:14:27,783 --> 00:14:31,494
盟军是在不知道他们接下来会去
哪儿的状况下 登陆西西里的
The Allies had landed in Sicily
not knowing where they would go next.

121
00:14:31,579 --> 00:14:35,500
在意大利不久即将崩溃的前景下,
英国人完全赞成进攻意大利本土
At the prospect of early Italian collapse, the
British were all for attacking the mainland.

122
00:14:35,500 --> 00:14:40,461
美国人同意打一场有限的战役,但坚持
"霸王"行动,即入侵诺曼底(的行动),
The Americans agreed to a limited campaign, but
insisted that Overlord, the invasion of Normandy,

123
00:14:40,546 --> 00:14:43,548
必须拥有对资源的优先调配权
must take priority for resources.

124
00:14:44,383 --> 00:14:51,973
一位密使,卡斯特拉诺将军,被巴多格里奥
派去探询以什么条件意大利能加入同盟国
A secret envoy, General Castellano,was sent by Badoglio
to find out on what terms Italy could join the Allies.

125
00:14:52,057 --> 00:14:54,200
但同盟国只是要意大利的投降
But the Allies simply wanted
ltalian surrender

126
00:14:54,200 --> 00:14:57,520
并拒绝告诉卡斯特拉诺他们的入侵计划...
and refused to tell Castellano
of their invasion plans...

127
00:14:57,605 --> 00:15:02,108
部分是因为他们不想让意大利人
知道他们的军力是多么有限
partly because they didn't want the ltalians
to know how limited their forces were.

128
00:15:02,192 --> 00:15:05,320
我们对卡斯特拉诺将军能说的只有这个:
(Strong) All we could say
to General Castellano was this:

129
00:15:05,404 --> 00:15:12,285
"我们会在事情发生前两或三个小时告诉你,
"Well, we will tell you
two or three hours before it happens,

130
00:15:12,369 --> 00:15:20,000
那样你能尽你所能向英国人...
向盟军的行动提供援助
so that you can give any assistance you can
to the British...to the Allied operations.

131
00:15:20,085 --> 00:15:25,965
最后,在9月3日,这些条款被签署了
Eventually, on the 3rd September,
these terms were signed.

132
00:15:29,845 --> 00:15:32,055
就在那天,盟军入侵了
On that day,
the Allies invaded.

133
00:15:32,400 --> 00:15:36,643
蒙哥马利穿过墨西拿海峡
进攻意大利的脚趾部位，
Montgomery went across the Straits
of Messina to attack the toe of ltaly,

134
00:15:36,727 --> 00:15:38,200
但没有遇到抵抗
but found no resistance.

135
00:15:38,200 --> 00:15:44,568
德国人已经北移 以应对一个
海岸更北面的盟军登陆的威胁
The Germans had moved north to counter the threat
of an Allied landing further up the coast.

136
00:15:48,238 --> 00:15:52,408
意大利人想要(盟军在罗马附近进行)
一次登陆以保卫罗马不受德国人的进攻,
The ltalians had wanted a landing
to safeguard Rome from German attack,

137
00:15:52,493 --> 00:15:54,000
但这是不可能的
but this was impossible.

138
00:15:55,000 --> 00:16:01,417
美国人和英国人感觉稳健的最靠北的登陆地点
离罗马还差得远,而是在萨莱诺,
The furthest north the Americans and British felt it
prudent to land was nowhere near Rome,but at Salerno,

139
00:16:01,502 --> 00:16:06,714
这是盟军从西西里岛为基地的
空中支援能到达的地方
as far as the Allied air cover
operating from Sicily could stretch.

140
00:16:08,801 --> 00:16:13,500
这次行动以极快的速度发动
以利用意大利的混乱(局面)
The operation had been mounted at great speed
to take advantage of the confusion in ltaly.

141
00:16:14,500 --> 00:16:21,396
行动指挥官,美国将军马克·克拉克的部队
刚刚足够应付他们必须完成的任务
The forces of the commander,American general Mark Clark
were barely adequate for the job they had to do.

142
00:16:26,151 --> 00:16:30,200
在路上,部队听到了由艾森
豪威尔将军发表的广播讲话
On the way,the troops heard
a broadcast by General Eisenhower.

143
00:16:30,300 --> 00:16:35,400
意大利政府已让其武装部队无条件投降
The Italian government has surrendered
its armed forces unconditionally.

144
00:16:35,500 --> 00:16:40,498
作为盟军总司令,我已批准一个军事停战协定
As Allied commander in chief,
l have granted a military armistice.

145
00:16:40,582 --> 00:16:46,045
停战协定由我的代表和
巴多格里奥元帅的代表签署
The armistice was signed by my representatives
and the representative of Marshal Badoglio.

146
00:16:46,130 --> 00:16:48,840
它在此刻生效
And it becomes effective this instant.

147
00:16:57,182 --> 00:17:01,769
他的盟友的投降没有让希特勒吃惊
The surrender of his allies
did not take Hitler by surprise.

148
00:17:01,854 --> 00:17:04,500
他已经把增援部队开进意大利北部
He'd already moved reinforcements
into northern ltaly.

149
00:17:04,500 --> 00:17:11,988
在一个嘲讽地被命名为"轴心行动"的计划下
意大利人在这里被迅速地解除了武装
Here the ltalians were quickly disarmed under
a plan ironically codenamed Operation Axis.

150
00:17:12,072 --> 00:17:16,785
在此时,希特勒还没决定
他应该在哪里守住防线
At this point, Hitler had not decided
just where he would hold the line.

151
00:17:18,829 --> 00:17:22,100
德国人进入罗马 发现它
是一个没有政府的首都
The Germans entered Rome to find it
a capital without a government.

152
00:17:22,200 --> 00:17:30,548
巴多格里奥和他的部长们已通过跳进他们的
汽车并开走 来避免因背叛而被枪毙的风险
Badoglio and his ministers had avoided
the risk of being shot for treachery by
leaping into their cars and driving away.

153
00:17:34,720 --> 00:17:39,474
在罗马的南面,克拉克的入侵部队正在靠近海滩
South of Rome, Clark's invasion force
was nearing the beaches.

154
00:17:39,558 --> 00:17:41,400
萨莱诺,如果你坐船进去,
Salerno, if you go in on a boat,

155
00:17:41,400 --> 00:17:47,231
你会看到包围着你的山和你要穿过的隘口
you look at the mountains that hem you
in and the passes through which you go.

156
00:17:47,316 --> 00:17:49,650
敌人会正俯视着你
The enemy would be
looking down your throat.

157
00:17:51,528 --> 00:17:54,989
德国人准备好了 并正等着
The Germans were ready and waiting.

158
00:19:11,650 --> 00:19:15,903
48小时后,德国人发动了一次猛烈的反攻
After 48 hours, the Germans
launched a furious counterattack.

159
00:19:32,400 --> 00:19:34,840
滩头的局势变得如此危险,
The situation at the beachhead
became so precarious,

160
00:19:34,840 --> 00:19:37,925
克拉克下令为可能的
重新登船(撤退)做计划
Clark ordered plans
for possible re-embarkation.

161
00:19:40,470 --> 00:19:42,700
但在来自空中和海上的巨大火力支援下,
But with massive support from air and sea,

162
00:19:42,700 --> 00:19:46,767
萨莱诺的入侵者设法坚持了下来
the Salerno invaders
just managed to hold on.

163
00:20:07,039 --> 00:20:11,459
经过一周的凶猛战斗后,德国人撤退了
After a week of savage fighting,
the Germans withdrew.

164
00:20:20,219 --> 00:20:26,140
需要所有空中力量的干预
才能在萨莱诺拯救我们
(Strong) It required the intervention of
all the air forces to save us at Salerno.

165
00:20:27,517 --> 00:20:30,100
在艾森豪威尔将军的所有战役中,
Of all General Eisenhower's battles,

166
00:20:30,100 --> 00:20:37,860
那是我认为我们最接近于战术失败的一次
that is the one where I think
we were nearest to a tactical defeat.

167
00:20:37,945 --> 00:20:43,783
我心中从没有任何怀疑 这是一次完全成功的行动
I've never had any doubts in my mind that
it was a completely successful operation.

168
00:20:43,867 --> 00:20:46,118
(马克·克拉克将军 美国第五军司令)
我们被命令去那里,
We were ordered to go in there,

169
00:20:46,203 --> 00:20:50,081
我们被命令去抢下一个
桥头堡 我们做到了
we were ordered to seize
a bridgehead. We did it.

170
00:20:50,165 --> 00:20:56,000
我们被命令去占领那不勒斯港...
我们在三个星期后也做到了
We were ordered to capture the port of
Naples... we did that within three weeks.

171
00:20:56,421 --> 00:20:59,131
到目前为止,一切都好
So far, so good.

172
00:20:59,216 --> 00:21:03,219
至少一大部分的意大利南部落入盟军手中
At least a large part of southern ltaly
was in Allied hands.

173
00:21:17,109 --> 00:21:19,402
那不勒斯极度短缺食物
Naples was desperately short of food.

174
00:21:20,946 --> 00:21:23,489
有面包暴动
There were bread riots.

175
00:21:27,536 --> 00:21:29,037
水很稀缺
Water was scarce.

176
00:21:42,843 --> 00:21:45,052
有一场斑疹伤寒的流行病(爆发)
There was a typhus epidemic.

177
00:21:54,980 --> 00:22:01,444
推进继续了,但就在前面
横亘着真正的德国抵抗的防线
The advance continued, but just ahead
lay the line of real German resistance.

178
00:22:01,528 --> 00:22:05,740
盟军指挥官们曾希望希特勒能撤退到更北边
The Allied commanders had hoped
Hitler would withdraw further north.

179
00:22:05,824 --> 00:22:09,118
相反,被他在萨莱诺几乎
就要取得的胜利大大鼓舞,
lnstead, greatly encouraged
by his near-victory at Salerno,

180
00:22:09,244 --> 00:22:14,457
他已决定在罗马南面的山里战斗
he had decided to fight here,
in the mountains south of Rome.

181
00:22:24,843 --> 00:22:27,720
象一张坏掉的里拉,墨索里尼又出现了
Like a bad lira,
Mussolini turned up again.

182
00:22:27,804 --> 00:22:34,393
他被一支德国救援队从他的藏身地
提了出来 并被带去见希特勒
He was hoisted from his hiding place
by a German rescue party and taken to Hitler.

183
00:22:37,314 --> 00:22:39,690
元首对他的出现大吃一惊,
The Führer was aghast
at his appearance,

184
00:22:39,775 --> 00:22:45,946
但认为他可能在鼓励由德国占领
的意大利的法西斯分子方面会有用
but thought he might come in useful to encourage
the Fascists in German-occupied ltaly.

185
00:23:01,671 --> 00:23:04,507
在意大利的德国军队由(阿尔伯特·)凯塞林指挥
The German forces in ltaly
were led by Kesselring,

186
00:23:04,591 --> 00:23:07,593
战争中最有能力的防御指挥官之一
one of the war's ablest
defensive commanders.

187
00:23:07,677 --> 00:23:09,513
凯塞林有很多的路要走
Kesselring had a lot going for him.

188
00:23:10,597 --> 00:23:14,100
绵延几乎整个意大利的山脊
The rocky spine which runs
almost the whole length of ltaly

189
00:23:14,184 --> 00:23:19,000
意味着盟军必须沿着(山脊)
两边的海岸平原推进
meant the Allies had to advance along
the coastal plains on either side.

190
00:23:19,773 --> 00:23:24,235
包抄德国人侧翼的唯一办法
就是通过两栖登陆
The only way to outflank the Germans
was by amphibious landings.

191
00:23:24,319 --> 00:23:29,156
但到现在为止 必要的登陆舰
都被指定用于诺曼底登陆
But by now the necessary landing craft
were earmarked for Normandy.

192
00:23:49,761 --> 00:23:53,180
当他们向北 去他们准备好的防御阵地时,
As they went north to their
prepared defensive positions,

193
00:23:53,265 --> 00:23:57,000
凯塞林的部队摧毁了唯一的交通路线
Kesselring's men destroyed
the only lines of communication.

194
00:24:09,656 --> 00:24:14,160
在城镇里,德国人埋下了诡雷
这是那不勒斯
ln the towns, the Germans
left booby traps. This was Naples.

195
00:24:32,345 --> 00:24:37,016
他们(德国人)是训练有素的部队
他们是顽强的部队 他们有出色的指挥官
They were well-trained troops. They were
tenacious troops, they were well led.

196
00:24:37,100 --> 00:24:42,313
我想表明的一点是他们都是同种类的...
And one point I like to make is
they were homogenous...

197
00:24:42,397 --> 00:24:45,274
他们都是一个国家的人
they were all of one nationality.

198
00:24:45,358 --> 00:24:49,028
他们都装备着同样的武器和弹药
They were all equipped with the same
weapons and ammunition.

199
00:24:49,112 --> 00:24:53,616
他们吃同样的食物 他们信仰差不多同一个神
They ate the same food. They believed
pretty much in the same god.

200
00:24:53,700 --> 00:24:58,496
我有来自16个不同国家的士兵,
I had 16 different nationalities with me,

201
00:24:58,580 --> 00:25:01,540
他们中有些人不能吃这个,不能吃那个,
some of whom couldn't eat this
and couldn't eat that,

202
00:25:01,625 --> 00:25:06,170
有些人不想在星期五或
一星期的其他什么日子战斗,
and some that didn't want to fight on
Fridays or some other day of the week,

203
00:25:06,254 --> 00:25:13,969
而英国人,他们的步兵武器
和大炮和我们的完全不同
and the British,with their infantry weapons
and your artillery completely different from ours.

204
00:25:14,054 --> 00:25:19,475
你不能象德国人那样 把他们
轻易地从一个前线调动到另一个
You couldn't move them with ease from one
front to the other like the Germans could.

205
00:25:22,145 --> 00:25:26,440
冬天 盟军地面部队指挥官
亚历山大将军和他的同事们
Winter. The Allied ground commander
General Alexander and his colleagues

206
00:25:26,525 --> 00:25:31,403
现在面对着他们的地中海战略的令人不快的现实
were now confronted with the unpleasant
realities of their Mediterranean strategy.

207
00:25:32,030 --> 00:25:36,116
习惯于迅速穿越沙漠的(英国)第八军,
The Eighth Army, accustomed to swift
advances across the desert,

208
00:25:36,201 --> 00:25:39,912
一天只能前进几百码
could only manage
a few hundred yards a day.

209
00:25:49,422 --> 00:25:55,344
在山那边,克拉克的(美国)第五军也陷入泥泞
Across the mountain,Clark's
Fifth Army was also mud-bound.

210
00:25:55,428 --> 00:25:59,890
雨停之后他们发给我们套鞋
They issued us galoshes
after the rains had stopped.

211
00:25:59,975 --> 00:26:02,300
如果有人是做套鞋生意的,
lf anybody was in the galoshes business,

212
00:26:02,300 --> 00:26:06,313
他能沿着路边发现大约几百万双,
he could have found about
millions along the roadside,

213
00:26:06,439 --> 00:26:08,000
因为你不可能穿着它们走路
because you couldn't walk with them.

214
00:26:08,000 --> 00:26:11,443
我是说 (穿套鞋)走过那片泥泞是不可能的
I mean,it was impossible
to go through that mud.

215
00:26:13,655 --> 00:26:17,741
这不是旅游海报上阳光明媚的意大利
This was not the sunny ltaly
of the travel posters.

216
00:26:21,705 --> 00:26:26,792
一个步兵走出那些山的唯一办法就是被运出来
The only way an infantryman was coming out
of those mountains was to be carried out.

217
00:26:26,876 --> 00:26:31,797
那就是为什么受伤实际上是值得向往的事
That's why it was actually desirable
to get wounded.

218
00:26:36,720 --> 00:26:41,765
可怕的天气,困难的地形,德国人坚决的抵抗
Dreadful weather, difficult terrain,
determined German resistance.

219
00:26:41,850 --> 00:26:46,562
对泥泞中的部队来说,这个组合
和丘吉尔的想象不太符合
To the men in the mud, this combination
did not match up to Churchill's vision.

220
00:26:46,646 --> 00:26:51,358
我现在还能回想起他在他的地图前
拿着指示棒 用他有说服力的方式,
(Clark) I can see him now at his map
and his persuasive way with his pointer,

221
00:26:51,443 --> 00:26:55,779
指出地中海"柔软的腹部"
pointing out the "soft belly"
of the Mediterranean.

222
00:26:55,864 --> 00:27:00,117
我们去了那儿以后,我经常想到
这是一个多么"坚硬的老肠胃",
After we got in there, I often thought
of what a tough old gut it was,

223
00:27:00,243 --> 00:27:03,412
而不是他让我们相信的"柔软的腹部"
instead of the soft belly
he had led us to believe.

224
00:27:19,137 --> 00:27:20,800
1943年年底前,
Before the end of 1943,

225
00:27:20,800 --> 00:27:24,183
盟军正在敲击凯塞林的冬季防线
the Allies were hammering
at Kesselring's Winter Line.

226
00:27:24,267 --> 00:27:30,064
亚历山大有11个师,凯塞林有9个,
还有8个师作为预备队
Alexander had 11divisions, Kesselring
nine, with eight more in reserve.

227
00:27:52,003 --> 00:27:55,464
必须为了(争夺)每一座小山村而战
Every small mountain village
had to be fought for.

228
00:27:55,548 --> 00:28:00,260
12月,美军第36(步兵)师试图夺取圣彼得罗
ln December, the American 36th Division
tried to take San Pietro.

229
00:28:34,921 --> 00:28:39,174
我们绝大多数在意大利的战斗
都是采取这么一种方式
lt was one of the things
that most of our fighting was in ltaly.

230
00:28:39,259 --> 00:28:44,430
你进入一个阵地,你掘壕据守,你就待在那里
You got into a position, you dug in
and you just stayed.

231
00:28:44,514 --> 00:28:48,642
我是说,我们向他们射击 他们也向我们射击
l mean, we'd shoot at them
and they'd shoot at us.

232
00:28:48,727 --> 00:28:54,481
只是当他们准备离开了我们才前进
And it was only when they were ready
to leave that we moved forward.

233
00:29:00,947 --> 00:29:06,994
10天后,美国人以惨重的代价拿下了圣彼得罗
After ten days,the Americans took
San Pietro...at heavy cost.

234
00:29:26,806 --> 00:29:30,309
在任何一支部队,你都会有一个坟墓登记分队,
ln any unit, you would have
a Graves Registration Unit,

235
00:29:30,393 --> 00:29:33,812
而他们的任务就是到处去抬走尸体
and their job was to go round
picking up bodies.

236
00:29:33,897 --> 00:29:38,400
(比尔·莫尔丁 漫画家 "星条旗")
他们要做的是,如果有人被仓促地埋葬,
And what they would do,
if someone had been hastily buried,

237
00:29:38,485 --> 00:29:41,195
(比尔·莫尔丁 漫画家 "星条旗")
他们会掘出他来,或者如果他就躺在那儿,
they would disinter him,
or if he was just lying there,

238
00:29:41,279 --> 00:29:46,658
他们会抬起他 并把他们倒入床罩中,
they'd pick him up and slide them
into the mattress covers,

239
00:29:46,743 --> 00:29:48,410
把他们堆放进卡车里
pile them up into the trucks

240
00:29:48,495 --> 00:29:52,706
并把他们带到某处的一个临时墓地
and take them off to
a temporary cemetery somewhere.

241
00:29:52,791 --> 00:29:57,669
我想一些人很可能以那种方式被埋葬了多达四或五次,
I suppose some people probably got buried
as many as four or five times that way,

242
00:29:57,754 --> 00:30:02,466
这真的是非常不幸
which is kind of unfortunate, really.

243
00:30:02,592 --> 00:30:07,095
我一直觉得(死去的)
人们应该被留在原地
I always thought people
should be left where they were.

244
00:30:40,046 --> 00:30:44,091
意大利人民曾被墨索里尼告知:
The ltalian people
had once been told by Mussolini:

245
00:30:44,175 --> 00:30:50,472
"战争把高贵的印记敲在那些
有勇气来面对它的人身上"
"War puts the stamp of nobility on those
who have the courage to meet it."

246
00:31:12,829 --> 00:31:15,581
1943年11月在德黑兰,
At Tehran in November 1943,

247
00:31:15,665 --> 00:31:17,958
罗斯福和斯大林驳回了丘吉尔(的意见)
Roosevelt and Stalin overruled Churchill

248
00:31:18,042 --> 00:31:21,128
并终于确定了在法国登陆的确切日期:
and at last fixed a definite date
for the landing in France:

249
00:31:21,212 --> 00:31:23,380
1944年5月
May 1944.

250
00:31:23,464 --> 00:31:26,300
意大利将变成一个次要战场
ltaly was to become a sideshow.

251
00:31:26,384 --> 00:31:30,345
但德黑兰会议后,丘吉尔拒绝接受意大利的僵局
But after Tehran, Churchill refused
to accept the deadlock in ltaly.

252
00:31:30,430 --> 00:31:36,977
他找到罗斯福并说服他借出
登陆舰来一次新的两栖登陆
He got on to Roosevelt and persuaded him to
lend landing craft for a new amphibious landing.

253
00:31:38,021 --> 00:31:40,105
该计划分为两个阶段
The plan was in two stages.

254
00:31:40,189 --> 00:31:44,443
首先,马克·克拉克的第五军
将在卡西诺进攻德国人,
First, Mark Clark's Fifth Army
would attack the Germans at Cassino,

255
00:31:44,527 --> 00:31:47,905
把他们的部队引向南面,
耗尽他们的预备队
draw their forces southward,
drain their reserves.

256
00:31:47,989 --> 00:31:54,661
然后两栖登陆的部队将在他们防线后面
进攻距罗马南面仅22英里的安齐奥
Then the amphibious troops would strike behind
their lines at Anzio,just 22 miles south of Rome.

257
00:31:55,997 --> 00:31:58,707
在卡西诺,德国人占领着高地
At Cassino, the Germans
held the high ground.

258
00:31:58,791 --> 00:32:01,835
他们能看见下面山谷里移动的一切东西
They could see everything
that moved in the valley below.

259
00:32:01,920 --> 00:32:05,088
第五军在(1944年)1月20日发动进攻
The Fifth Army attacked
on January 20th.

260
00:32:05,173 --> 00:32:10,510
其部队未被增援 他们又冷又湿,筋疲力尽
Its troops had not been reinforced.
They were cold, wet, exhausted.

261
00:32:10,595 --> 00:32:13,555
进攻灾难性地失败了
The attack failed disastrously.

262
00:32:13,640 --> 00:32:16,725
但计划的第二阶段在两天后开始了...
But the second stage of the plan
went ahead two days later...

263
00:32:16,809 --> 00:32:18,894
攻击安齐奥
the assault on Anzio.

264
00:32:18,978 --> 00:32:28,236
经历了在没有足够部队的情况下进攻萨莱诺...
指挥官没有他认为他应该有的任何东西...
Having gone into Salerno with not enough troops...
no commander ever has what he thinks he ought to have...

265
00:32:28,321 --> 00:32:32,491
我决心如果我成为进攻安齐奥的指挥官,
l was determined that if I was to be
the commander going into Anzio,

266
00:32:32,575 --> 00:32:36,536
或成为总指挥官,我们不应该以小规模部队进攻
or be the overall commander, that we
should not go in on a shoestring.

267
00:32:36,621 --> 00:32:42,834
我带着一又三分之二个师进去,
而这点部队完全不能胜任
I went in with one and two-thirds
division, which was totally inadequate.

268
00:32:43,878 --> 00:32:47,214
但那就是战争中 球反弹的方式
But that's the way
the ball bounces in war.

269
00:32:47,298 --> 00:32:49,300
你只有服从命令,
You do what you're told to do,

270
00:32:49,300 --> 00:32:51,970
否则他们会另找他人来做
or they'll get somebody else
that will do it.

271
00:32:58,393 --> 00:33:00,400
德国人预计到了会有登陆,
The Germans expected the landing,

272
00:33:00,400 --> 00:33:02,938
但不知道它会从哪儿来
but had no idea where it would come.

273
00:33:03,022 --> 00:33:06,483
他们没有足够的部队来控制所有可能的滩头
They did not have enough troops
to cover all possible beaches.

274
00:33:06,567 --> 00:33:10,070
安齐奥的登陆部队完全没有遇到抵抗
The Anzio force was completely unopposed.

275
00:33:11,364 --> 00:33:14,700
什么事也没有 很远的地方传来
一声奇怪的"嘭",但什么也没发生
Nothing. An odd bang
in the distance, but nothing.

276
00:33:14,784 --> 00:33:18,829
当黎明破晓时,我们完全大吃一惊
And when dawn broke,
we'd got complete surprise.

277
00:33:21,332 --> 00:33:25,711
几分钟之后,沿着路,开来一辆
喝得酩酊大醉的(人开的)汽车,
And a few minutes later, along the road,
there came a marvellous drunken car,

278
00:33:25,795 --> 00:33:27,000
左摇右晃,
swaying back and forth,

279
00:33:27,000 --> 00:33:31,591
(维恩福德·沃甘-托马斯 战地记者)
车上装满了在罗马度过一夜并摇摇晃晃
开车回去的一伙最开心的德国人,
it was just full of the most happy Germans who'd
had a night out in Rome and were staggering back,

280
00:33:31,676 --> 00:33:33,400
他们不能相信他们被俘虏了
and they couldn't believe they were captured.

281
00:33:33,400 --> 00:33:37,889
他们说, "同志们" 他们不断拥抱我
They said, "Kameraden"
and they kept on embracing me.

282
00:33:37,974 --> 00:33:40,017
最终他们把他们也关进了牢房
Finally they put them in the clink too.

283
00:33:40,101 --> 00:33:43,145
而那就是登陆...完全出乎意料
And that was the landing...
complete surprise.

284
00:33:46,899 --> 00:33:51,486
安齐奥滩头在一种怪异的平静中被巩固了
The Anzio beachhead was
consolidated in an eerie calm.

285
00:34:07,170 --> 00:34:12,340
(经历了)萨莱诺登陆之后,德国人
没有立即还击似乎显得难以置信
After Salerno, it seemed incredible that
there was no instant German riposte.

286
00:34:12,425 --> 00:34:15,093
或许现在是闪电般猛冲的时候了,
Perhaps now was the time
for a lightning dash,

287
00:34:15,178 --> 00:34:18,221
以巴顿将军的方式,直扑罗马的大门
in the style of General Patton,
for the gates of Rome.

288
00:34:18,306 --> 00:34:21,433
但在安齐奥的美国指挥官不是巴顿
But the American commander at Anzio
was no Patton.

289
00:34:21,517 --> 00:34:23,400
卢卡斯将军是一个谨慎的人
General Lucas was a cautious man

290
00:34:23,400 --> 00:34:27,314
他相信在攻击内陆前
滩头必须被确保安全
who believed the beachhead must
be secured before striking inland.

291
00:34:27,398 --> 00:34:30,150
亚历山大没有否决他(的意见)
Alexander did not overrule him.

292
00:34:44,207 --> 00:34:48,668
在伦敦,丘吉尔痛苦地抱怨说,"我以为我们把一只
野猫扔进阿尔本山(罗马以南20英里的一座火山),
In London,Churchill complained bitterly, "I thought
we'd flung a wildcat into the Alban Hills,

293
00:34:48,753 --> 00:34:52,047
但相反我们在海滩上有一头鲸鱼在挣扎"
but instead we got a whale
floundering on the beach."

294
00:34:54,967 --> 00:35:08,814
(齐格弗里德·韦斯特法尔将军 凯塞林的参谋长)
在海岸只有两个营和一些非常老式的岸炮用于防卫
There were only two battalions and some very old-fashioned
coast batteries at the coast for defending.

295
00:35:08,898 --> 00:35:17,781
如果美国人意识到了这种情况,
lf the Americans had realised the situation,

296
00:35:17,865 --> 00:35:23,703
他们本可以在罗马度过登陆日的夜晚的
they could stay on the evening
of the landing day in Rome.

297
00:35:23,788 --> 00:35:29,167
卢卡斯将军可以(打下罗马的),但(这样的话)
他很快就会遇到一支有压倒性优势的部队
General Lucas could, but he would have
soon been met by an overwhelming force

298
00:35:29,293 --> 00:35:32,504
而它会打败他,他会被打败,毫无疑问
which would have defeated him,
he'd been defeated,no question about it.

299
00:35:32,588 --> 00:35:38,135
所以我们不得不在我们可能
消化的最大周边挖壕据守,
So we had to dig in on the biggest
perimeter we could possibly digest,

300
00:35:38,219 --> 00:35:40,595
并等待到来的猛攻
and wait for the onslaught which came.

301
00:35:44,183 --> 00:35:47,700
被打得(措手不及)失去平衡,
就如他经常被亚历山大打成的那样,
Caught off-balance,
as he often was by Alexander,

302
00:35:47,700 --> 00:35:49,771
凯塞林迅速恢复过来
Kesselring recovered fast.

303
00:35:50,898 --> 00:35:56,027
被希特勒立即消灭"安齐奥脓肿"的要求所鞭策,
Spurred on by Hitler's demands for the
immediate liquidation of the "Anzio abscess",

304
00:35:56,112 --> 00:35:59,000
他将他所有的部队投入反击
he threw all he had
into the counterattack.

305
00:36:00,449 --> 00:36:02,000
如果安齐奥被消灭,
lf Anzio were eliminated,

306
00:36:02,000 --> 00:36:07,539
那么也许盟军会重新考虑穿越英吉利海峡
then perhaps the Allies would think again
about crossing the English Channel.

307
00:36:42,283 --> 00:36:48,414
盟军沿海滩展开的突前部队
被德国人进攻的重压完全压倒了
Allied advance units which had spread out from the beaches
were overwhelmed by the weight of the German attack.

308
00:36:51,000 --> 00:36:54,211
我知道有一支部队就那么放弃了...
(Vaughan-Thomas) There was one unit
I knew that simply packed in...

309
00:36:54,295 --> 00:36:56,800
折叠好他们的大衣 并投降了
folded their great coats
and handed themselves over.

310
00:36:56,800 --> 00:36:58,000
他们再也受不了了
They couldn't take it any more.

311
00:36:58,000 --> 00:37:01,400
他们很年轻 以前没见过这种事情
They were young and hadn't
seen this sort of thing before.

312
00:37:01,400 --> 00:37:04,221
而我一丁点也不责怪他们
And I don't blame them one little scrap.

313
00:37:13,564 --> 00:37:20,487
两个游骑兵营被俘虏 并被羞辱性地在罗马街头游街示众
Two American Ranger battalions were captured and
humiliatingly paraded through the streets of Rome.

314
00:37:51,700 --> 00:37:59,276
(安齐奥)滩头只能从南面通过突破贯穿
卡西诺修道院的德国防线 才能被解围
The beachhead could only be relieved from the south
by breaking through the German defensive line
which ran through the monastery of Monte Cassino.

315
00:37:59,360 --> 00:38:01,400
被高高置于山谷之上,
Perched high above the valley,

316
00:38:01,400 --> 00:38:06,074
这里的一个观察哨能看到
方圆几英里移动的一切东西
an observation post here could see
everything that moved for miles around.

317
00:38:08,327 --> 00:38:13,415
盟军错误地相信,修道院已被筑成堡垒
The Allies believed, wrongly,
that the monastery had been fortified.

318
00:38:14,750 --> 00:38:20,922
这是前线部队普遍的看法和普遍的信念
lt was the general view and the general
belief of the troops involved on that front

319
00:38:21,007 --> 00:38:27,137
那就是在卡西诺的修道院正被德国人用于军事用途
that the monastery at Cassino was being
used for military purposes by the Germans.

320
00:38:27,221 --> 00:38:30,056
(约翰·哈丁爵士 英国陆军元帅 亚历山大的参谋长)
如果真是那样,
That being the case,

321
00:38:30,141 --> 00:38:36,855
(约翰·哈丁爵士 英国陆军元帅 亚历山大的参谋长)
而这也是我和许多其他人的军事哲学的一部分,
and it also being part of my military philosophy,
and a great many other people's,too

322
00:38:36,939 --> 00:38:39,774
那就是你一定不能把部队投入战斗
that you must not put troops into battle

323
00:38:39,859 --> 00:38:47,949
在没有给他们一切可能的有形和物质支持
以给予他们取得成功的最好机会 的情况下
without giving them all possible physical and material support
you can to give them the best chance of getting a success.

324
00:38:54,874 --> 00:38:56,708
1944年2月15日,
On February 15th, 1944,

325
00:38:56,792 --> 00:39:01,421
超过200架盟军轰炸机
把修道院炸成一片瓦砾
over 200 Allied bombers
pounded the monastery into rubble.

326
00:39:37,416 --> 00:39:40,460
空中和地面进攻协调得很差
The air and ground attacks
were badly coordinated,

327
00:39:40,544 --> 00:39:46,132
给德国人时间涌入瓦砾堆...
防御的理想隐蔽场所
giving the Germans time to swarm into
the rubble... ideal cover for defence.

328
00:39:48,302 --> 00:39:50,845
古斯塔夫防线被守住了
The Gustav Line was held.

329
00:40:01,232 --> 00:40:06,194
在安齐奥,凯塞林投入了10个德国师
来对付盟军的4个半师
At Anzio, Kesselring flung ten German divisions
against the Allies' four and a half.

330
00:40:06,278 --> 00:40:10,490
希特勒希望安齐奥
会是德国命运的一个转折点
Hitler hoped Anzio would be a turning
point in Germany's fortunes.

331
00:40:10,574 --> 00:40:17,288
突破的那支部队,他承诺,将获得
护送盟军战俘穿过柏林街道的荣誉
The unit that broke through,he promised, would have the honour
of escorting Allied prisoners through the streets of Berlin.

332
00:40:35,099 --> 00:40:39,060
集中起来的一波波德国步兵被投入进来
Massed waves of German infantry
were flung in.

333
00:40:39,145 --> 00:40:45,483
他们穿过一个月球表面一样的地形,一路上
到处是弹坑,被打坏的坦克,被遗弃的吉普车
They came over a moon landscape, pitted,
wrecked tanks,abandoned Jeeps along the road,

334
00:40:45,568 --> 00:40:49,028
而我到今天仍不理解德国人的战术
and I still to this day
don't understand the German tactics.

335
00:40:49,113 --> 00:40:54,909
有一个时刻你能看到他们实际上就象索姆河战役
的老电影(里放的)那样离开他们的防线
There was a moment you could actually see them leaving
their lines like the old films of the Somme battle,

336
00:40:54,994 --> 00:40:57,704
并当我们的机枪打中他们的时候纷纷倒下
and falling down as our
machine guns took them.

337
00:41:06,922 --> 00:41:09,674
德国人的攻势持续了四天
The German offensive lasted four days.

338
00:41:09,758 --> 00:41:14,262
到最后,盟军在重炮方面的优势打破了平衡
ln the end, the Allied superiority
in heavy guns tipped the balance.

339
00:41:19,602 --> 00:41:22,896
它(德国人的进攻)终于被打回去了
lt was finally beaten back.

340
00:41:52,718 --> 00:41:54,302
德国人撤退了,
The Germans had pulled back,

341
00:41:54,386 --> 00:41:57,347
但盟军仍缺乏力量取得突破
but the Allies still lacked
the strength to break out.

342
00:41:58,700 --> 00:42:00,600
这是个僵局
lt was stalemate.

343
00:42:00,684 --> 00:42:03,186
然后我们不得不挖战壕,
(Vaughan-Thomas) We then had to form trenches,

344
00:42:03,312 --> 00:42:08,858
安齐奥于是就变成一场老式的
第一次世界大战的壕沟系统
and Anzio then became an old-fashioned
World War I trench system.

345
00:42:08,943 --> 00:42:11,236
他们被轰炸 他们被迫击炮炸
And they were bombed
and they were mortared

346
00:42:11,320 --> 00:42:13,321
然后他们必须进行战壕巡逻
and then they had to do
trench patrols

347
00:42:13,447 --> 00:42:20,954
偶然地,机敏的将军会派人去尝试并发现
谁在和我们对阵并来一次壕沟突袭
and occasionally, keen generals used
to send up people to try and find out
who was opposite us and do a trench raid.

348
00:42:21,038 --> 00:42:24,290
这情形就象是从"旅程的尽头"(关于
一战时的壕沟的戏剧)出来的那样
lt was right out of Journey's End.

349
00:42:27,002 --> 00:42:30,838
(敌我)两条前线只隔了几码
The two front lines
were only yards apart.

350
00:42:30,923 --> 00:42:35,426
有两个家伙在清洗这把机关枪,
把它拆成零件并...
A couple of fellows were cleaning this
machine gun, got it all to pieces and...

351
00:42:37,596 --> 00:42:41,933
一个名叫汤米·麦高夫的爱尔兰伙计
在那儿 他抬头一看并说道:
An lrish fellow named Tommy McGough
was there and he looked up and said:

352
00:42:42,017 --> 00:42:43,893
"耶稣基督啊!"
"Bloody Jesus Christ!"

353
00:42:44,019 --> 00:42:47,272
他冲向这把机枪,试图把枪管装回去,
He tried and rushed for this gun,
trying to put the barrel back on,

354
00:42:47,356 --> 00:42:49,524
他把它装倒了 诸如那样
he put it on upside down and all sorts.

355
00:42:49,608 --> 00:42:53,194
当然,我只是看了一下 我说,"没事,汤米"
Of course, I just looked and I said,
"Quite all right, Tommy."

356
00:42:53,279 --> 00:42:59,200
(比尔·柏开特 舍伍德巡林者团士兵)
我能看见这伙计是个...我走向铁丝网 他英语说得很好
l could see this fellow was... I go down
to the wire. He speaks very good English.

357
00:42:59,326 --> 00:43:02,245
他说,"佛莱德在哪儿?"
我说,"他走了"
He says, "Where's Fred?"
l said, "He's gone."

358
00:43:02,371 --> 00:43:05,248
我说,"没事儿 你有什么东西?"
l said, "lt's quite all right,
what have you got?"

359
00:43:05,374 --> 00:43:07,208
丹麦猪肉和新鲜柠檬
Danish pork and fresh lemons.

360
00:43:07,293 --> 00:43:09,544
当然,我给了他一听罐头牛肉
Of course,I gave him a tin of bully beef.

361
00:43:09,628 --> 00:43:13,673
我们和他谈起形势和战争和所有那些事
We got talking to him about
the position and the war and all that.

362
00:43:13,757 --> 00:43:19,512
- 他来自埃姆登(德国城市)附近的一个地方?
- 埃姆登,是的
- He come from a place near Emden?
- Emden, yes.

363
00:43:19,597 --> 00:43:23,558
当时,这座城市遭遇了
一次一千架轰炸机的空袭
And at the time,
this city had a thousand-bomber raid.

364
00:43:23,684 --> 00:43:26,269
我说,"欧,那你家也挨炸了"
I said,"Oh, you've had the bugger then?"

365
00:43:26,353 --> 00:43:28,104
"你家完蛋了"
"You've had it."

366
00:43:28,188 --> 00:43:31,608
"不,不"他说,"我来自埃姆登
附近的一个小村 我家没事"
"No, no," he said, "l come from
a little village near Emden. Me OK."

367
00:43:31,692 --> 00:43:38,531
他给我看他妻子的照片
她是埃姆登的一个公共汽车售票员
He showed me his photos of his wife. She
was a bus conductor in Emden and that.

368
00:43:38,616 --> 00:43:44,454
我说,"你为何不投降算了?
现在你也受够了"
And I said, "Why don't you pack in?
You've had it now."

369
00:43:44,538 --> 00:43:48,499
他说,"不,德国不会被打败"
He said, "No, Germany will not be beat."

370
00:43:48,584 --> 00:43:53,087
"我们将就象那样走下去,直到我们接近底部,
"We shall go right down like that,
till we get near to the bottom,

371
00:43:53,172 --> 00:43:59,677
然后我们将和英国和美国联手 与俄国战斗"
and then we shall join forces with
Britain and America and fight Russia."

372
00:43:59,762 --> 00:44:02,430
说完那话后他就走了
我再也没见过他
After that he just went.
l never seen him any more.

373
00:44:02,514 --> 00:44:04,682
第二天晚上他一定被换岗了
He must've got relieved the next night.

374
00:44:18,989 --> 00:44:23,159
在吃饭时间,厨子们会叫,"吃饭了"
At meal time, the cooks would shout,
"Grub up."

375
00:44:23,243 --> 00:44:26,579
(沃尔特·戴维斯 舍伍德巡林者团士兵)
你拿着你的饭盒去打你的饭
You'd go with your mess tins
down for your grub.

376
00:44:26,664 --> 00:44:29,540
在你能下到厨房前,
Before you could get down
to the cookhouse,

377
00:44:29,625 --> 00:44:32,502
"安齐奥安妮"(德国280mmK5(E)"利奥波德"
列车炮) 会送过来一发,一发大的,
Anzio Annie would send one over,
a big one,

378
00:44:32,586 --> 00:44:34,671
爆炸的烟云升腾而起,你知道,
one of these clouds raised, you know,

379
00:44:34,755 --> 00:44:40,677
而你自动地,就在那爆炸的
一瞬间,你就趴到了地上
and you automatically, as soon as
that burst, you'd drop to the floor.

380
00:44:40,761 --> 00:44:44,097
你总是习惯于那样 你走路也是蹲着走
You were always used to it.
You walked crouched.

381
00:44:44,181 --> 00:44:48,434
他们称之为,当你四处走动时,
你有了"安齐奥蹲姿"
They called it, when you were walking
about, you'd got "the Anzio crouch".

382
00:45:01,073 --> 00:45:03,241
当你躺在那儿,
And as you lay there,

383
00:45:03,325 --> 00:45:10,373
你会把频道调到...在你不应该拥有
的无线电上...调到"萨莉之声"
you used to tune in... on the radios that you
shouldn't have had...and...to the voice of Sally.

384
00:45:10,457 --> 00:45:13,751
萨莉住在罗马 她是个了不起的...
Sally lived in Rome
and she was a great...

385
00:45:13,836 --> 00:45:18,005
她听起来就是最不可思议,最性感的女性
Well, she sounded the most
wonderful, sexy female ever.

386
00:45:18,090 --> 00:45:20,174
她不断传递消息给部队
And she kept on giving messages to the troops.

387
00:45:20,259 --> 00:45:22,677
"你好, 你好..."
"Hello, hello..."

388
00:45:22,803 --> 00:45:27,515
女人总是认为她们说话声音越低沉,
她们听起来就越性感
Women always think that the lower
they speak, the more sexy they sound.

389
00:45:27,599 --> 00:45:30,393
她有任何女人里最低沉的音域
And she had the lowest register
of any woman.

390
00:45:30,477 --> 00:45:36,441
她说,"你好,这是萨莉
你为什么不过来看我呢?"
She said, "Hello, this is Sally.
Why don't you come over and see me?"

391
00:45:36,525 --> 00:45:41,696
"福克斯列兵...昨晚你记得他吗?
他踩上一颗鞋雷"
"Private Fox... you remember him last
night? He stepped on a shoe mine."

392
00:45:41,780 --> 00:45:43,448
"真是恶毒的东西,那些鞋雷"
"Nasty things, shoe mines."

393
00:45:43,532 --> 00:45:46,993
"你能听到福克斯列兵叫了大半夜"
"You could hear Private Fox yelling
for most of the night."

394
00:45:47,077 --> 00:45:50,913
"别象福克斯列兵那样,
还是过来看萨莉吧"
"Don't be like Private Fox,
come over to see Sally."

395
00:45:54,460 --> 00:45:56,502
在头顶上有聪明的俏皮话,
There would be a smart crack overhead,

396
00:45:56,587 --> 00:45:59,088
在下面则飘落着宣传小册子,
and down would flutter
propaganda pamphlets,

397
00:45:59,173 --> 00:46:02,341
上面说,"美国佬正在租借你们的女人"
saying, "The Yanks
are lease-lending your women."

398
00:46:02,426 --> 00:46:05,678
"他们正在快活的老英格兰共度美好时光"
"They're having a lovely time
in jolly old England."

399
00:46:05,763 --> 00:46:08,473
一幅一个裸体女人
拥抱一个美国人的图片,
A picture of a naked woman
embracing an American,

400
00:46:08,557 --> 00:46:14,729
或一个美国人巧妙地打着
他的领带 当她穿上她的短裤
or an American tactfully knotting
his tie while she did up her panties.

401
00:46:18,734 --> 00:46:21,903
在卡西诺,盟军保持着压力,
At Cassino,the Allies maintained the pressure,

402
00:46:21,987 --> 00:46:25,490
他们的目标是牵制
那里尽可能多的德国部队
their aim to tie up as many
German troops there as possible.

403
00:46:25,574 --> 00:46:30,800
第三次夺取已被毁坏的修道院的进攻
以一次对卡西诺镇的巨大轰炸进攻开始
A third attempt to take the ruined monastery opened
with a massive bombing attack on Cassino town.

404
00:46:30,800 --> 00:46:35,958
500架飞机在一个娱乐性的行动代号
"布莱德曼挥击明天"下 飞去轰炸
500 planes went in under the sporting
codeword "Bradman Batting Tomorrow".

405
00:46:36,084 --> 00:46:41,339
被彻底炸碎的地方中 有英国第八军的司令部
Among the places knocked for six was the
headquarters of the British Eighth Army.

406
00:47:07,491 --> 00:47:12,995
又一次,空中和地面部队的协调很差
Once again, there was poor coordination
between air and ground forces.

407
00:47:23,799 --> 00:47:26,551
轰炸过后,德国人走出地面
After the bombing,
the Germans came out of the ground

408
00:47:26,635 --> 00:47:31,000
并在新西兰人发动他们的进攻前 再次进入阵地
and were in position again before the
New Zealanders launched their attack.

409
00:47:39,481 --> 00:47:42,692
德国防守者是精锐的伞兵
The German defenders
were elite paratroops.

410
00:48:00,711 --> 00:48:06,007
战斗激烈地进行着,从房子到房子,
房间到房间,地窖到地窖
The battle raged from house to house,
room to room, cellar to cellar.

411
00:48:23,525 --> 00:48:26,527
新西兰人损失了4,000人
The New Zealanders lost 4,000 men.

412
00:48:32,868 --> 00:48:35,286
德国人仍在坚守
The Germans still held out.

413
00:48:38,373 --> 00:48:42,209
三次对卡西诺山的突击,
三次血淋淋的失败
Three assaults on Monte Cassino,
three bloody failures.

414
00:48:42,336 --> 00:48:47,006
盟军指挥官终于意识到 要占领此山
他们必须用人数的重量来压垮防御
The Allied commanders finally realised,to take the Mount
they must crush the defence by weight of numbers.

415
00:48:47,090 --> 00:48:50,468
他们大规模增援了第五军
They massively reinforced
the Fifth Army.

416
00:48:53,347 --> 00:49:02,021
他们还用了一个复杂的欺骗计划使德国人认为
他们正在准备在罗马北面进行另一次两栖登陆
They used, too,an elaborate deception plan
to make the Germans think they were preparing
another amphibious landing north of Rome.

417
00:49:02,105 --> 00:49:06,400
德国人削弱了他们的山顶防御来为之做准备
The Germans weakened their
mountain defences to prepare for it.

418
00:49:06,485 --> 00:49:12,740
5月,盟军终于在人数上达到
在卡西诺的德军人数的三倍
ln May, the Allies at last outnumbered
the Germans at Cassino by three to one.

419
00:49:12,866 --> 00:49:16,786
在一次2,000门火炮的
弹幕射击后,修道院陷落了
After an artillery barrage
by 2,000 guns, the monastery fell.

420
00:49:21,100 --> 00:49:23,400
波兰部队是第一批到达废墟的,
Polish troops were the first to reach the ruins,

421
00:49:23,400 --> 00:49:26,253
在那里他们竖起了他们的国旗
where they raised their national flag.

422
00:49:32,386 --> 00:49:37,181
被俘德国人的眼睛诉说了
他们经受严酷考验的故事
The eyes of the captured Germans
told the story of their ordeal.

423
00:49:48,902 --> 00:49:51,320
德国人现在正仓促撤退
The Germans were now
in headlong retreat.

424
00:49:51,405 --> 00:49:53,823
凯塞林宣布罗马为一个不设防城市
Kesselring declared Rome an open city

425
00:49:53,907 --> 00:49:56,826
并企图在首都北面重整旗鼓
and attempted to regroup
north of the capital.

426
00:49:56,910 --> 00:50:02,206
1944年5月25日,卡西诺前线
与安齐奥滩头联结了起来
On the 25th of May, the Cassino front
linked up with the Anzio beachhead.

427
00:50:02,290 --> 00:50:06,877
亚历山大的计划是让
克拉克切断德国人的退路
Alexander's plan was for Clark
to cut off the Germans' retreat.

428
00:50:06,962 --> 00:50:10,715
相反,克拉克投入一切力量直扑罗马
lnstead, Clark threw everything
into a drive for Rome.

429
00:50:13,844 --> 00:50:17,471
他决心赶在其他人之前到达那里,他做到了
He was determined to get there
before anyone else, and he did.

430
00:50:17,556 --> 00:50:20,766
在1944年6月4日的傍晚,
On the evening of June 4, 1944,

431
00:50:20,851 --> 00:50:23,477
第一批盟军部队进入了该城
the first Allied troops
entered the city.

432
00:50:33,321 --> 00:50:38,451
那些支持错误一方的罗马人现在付出了代价
Those Romans who had backed
the wrong side now paid the price.

433
00:51:04,561 --> 00:51:07,313
克拉克的罗马胜利很短暂
Clark's Roman triumph was short-lived.

434
00:51:07,397 --> 00:51:10,733
凯塞林将成功重整队伍
Kesselring would succeed in regrouping.

435
00:51:10,817 --> 00:51:13,486
另一个意大利冬天就在前面
Another ltalian winter lay ahead.

436
00:51:13,570 --> 00:51:15,613
在不到48个小时里,
And in less than 48 hours

437
00:51:15,697 --> 00:51:19,200
世界的注意力将转向另一个战区...
the world's attention
would turn to another theatre of war...

438
00:51:19,284 --> 00:51:21,452
诺曼底的海滩
the beaches of Normandy.

