1
00:00:11,970 --> 00:00:14,304
1940年10月
October,1940.

2
00:00:14,389 --> 00:00:18,183
温斯顿·丘吉尔致被打败的法国人民:
Winston Churchill to the
defeated French people:

3
00:00:18,268 --> 00:00:20,394
那么晚安了
Good night, then.

4
00:00:20,478 --> 00:00:24,398
好好睡觉 为黎明积聚力量
Sleep to gather strength
for the morning.

5
00:00:24,482 --> 00:00:26,775
因为黎明将会来临
For the morning will come.

6
00:00:26,860 --> 00:00:30,571
它将闪亮地照耀在勇敢的和真实的(人)身上,
Brightly will it shine
on the brave and true,

7
00:00:30,697 --> 00:00:35,075
仁慈地照在所有那些为了
这个事业而遭受痛苦的人身上
kindly on all who suffer for the cause.

8
00:00:35,160 --> 00:00:37,244
法国万岁!
Vive la France!

9
00:00:39,247 --> 00:00:41,749
(法语)好吧,晚安
Allons, bonne nuit.

10
00:00:42,667 --> 00:00:44,752
(法语)好好睡
Dormez bien.

11
00:00:44,878 --> 00:00:49,798
(法语)为黎明积聚你们的力量,
因为黎明将会来临
Rassemblez vos forces pour l'aube,
car l'aube viendra.

12
00:00:52,010 --> 00:00:55,220
现在,终于,在近四年之后,
Now, at last,
after nearly four years,

13
00:00:55,305 --> 00:00:57,848
那个黎明即将破晓而出
that dawn was about to break.

14
00:00:57,932 --> 00:01:01,685
对(欧洲)大陆的入侵即将到来
The invasion of the Continent
was at hand.

15
00:02:02,122 --> 00:02:04,164
迪耶普(法国港口),1942年.
Dieppe, 1942.

16
00:02:05,583 --> 00:02:11,713
让盟军部队在法国登陆的
第一次主要尝试是一场灾难
The first major attempt to land
Allied troops in France was a disaster.

17
00:02:13,100 --> 00:02:20,013
7,000人的攻击部队中的几乎一半
在试图冲击该港口强大的防御时被损失掉了
Almost half the assaulting force of 7,000 was lost
trying to storm the port's powerful defences.

18
00:02:23,560 --> 00:02:26,228
许多部队从没有越过海滩
Many troops never got
beyond the beaches.

19
00:02:26,312 --> 00:02:30,100
数以百计的其他(部队)直接投降了
Hundreds of others
walked straight into captivity.

20
00:02:30,100 --> 00:02:38,240
就最终的入侵而言 我们从迪耶普(登陆)中学到如此多
(的教训) 以至于我认为它(的价值)是无可估量的
We learnt so much from Dieppe that I think it was quite
invaluable as far as the final invasion was concerned.

21
00:02:38,324 --> 00:02:42,286
我认为在那次行动中 能出错的一切事情都出错了
l think everything that could go wrong
went wrong with that operation.

22
00:02:42,370 --> 00:02:45,300
它的结果就是,到了最后,
The result of it was that, by the end,

23
00:02:45,300 --> 00:02:55,966
(戈伦韦·里斯 "考萨克"主要参谋)
你会被 以那种规模进行的任何形式的
联合行动的风险和危险 留下骇人地印象
one was appallingly impressed by the dangers and the hazards
of any kind of combined operation on that kind of scale.

24
00:02:56,050 --> 00:03:00,470
我们之前从未尝试过进行
一次那种规模的联合行动
We'd never attempted to do a combined
operation on that scale before.

25
00:03:00,555 --> 00:03:02,764
而且,说真的,没人知道怎么来做
And, really, nobody knew how to do it.

26
00:03:02,849 --> 00:03:06,400
要进行一次成功的(登陆)入侵
有三个必要的条件
There are three conditions necessary
for a successful invasion.

27
00:03:06,400 --> 00:03:11,481
(路易斯·蒙巴顿勋爵 联合作战司令部司令 1942-1943)
首先,很明显,无论面对多猛烈的反抗都要上岸
First, obviously, to get ashore
against no matter what opposition.

28
00:03:11,566 --> 00:03:13,400
其次,登上岸后,
Secondly, having got ashore,

29
00:03:13,526 --> 00:03:16,862
无论天气条件如何都要待在岸上
to stay ashore no matter
what the weather conditions.

30
00:03:16,946 --> 00:03:22,201
第三,要阻止敌人以比你更快的速度
集结起他的部队来对付你,
Thirdly, to stop the enemy from building up
his forces against you quicker than you can,

31
00:03:22,285 --> 00:03:24,300
否则他将把你丢回到海里去
otherwise he'll throw you
back into the sea.

32
00:03:25,163 --> 00:03:27,200
考虑到这些基本因素,
Given these essentials,

33
00:03:27,200 --> 00:03:33,000
两个最可能的登陆区域是 在英吉利
海峡最狭窄处对面的加莱海峡(简称加莱),
the two likeliest landing areas were the Pas-de-Calais,
across the English Channel at its narrowest point,

34
00:03:33,000 --> 00:03:35,131
以及西面的诺曼底
and Normandy to the west.

35
00:03:35,800 --> 00:03:43,555
在其中作出选择是弗雷德里克·摩根中将和他的
特殊的被称为"考萨克"的盟军参谋部的首要任务
The choice between was the first task of Lieutenant General
Frederick Morgan and his special Allied staff,known
as COSSAC(Chief Of Staff to Supreme Allied Commander)

36
00:03:43,640 --> 00:03:48,727
(他们)在1943年被委派
来制定最初的入侵计划
appointed in 1943 to frame
the initial invasion plans.

37
00:03:48,811 --> 00:03:52,814
试探性的入侵计划自1941年来就已进行(规划)
Tentative invasion planning
had gone on since 1941.

38
00:03:52,899 --> 00:03:55,692
"考萨克"("盟军最高指挥官的总参谋长"的简称)
最后的选择是诺曼底,
COSSAC's choice in the end
was Normandy,

39
00:03:55,777 --> 00:04:00,989
就在瑟堡半岛东面的一段延伸50英里的海岸
a 50-mile stretch of shore
just east of the Cherbourg peninsula.

40
00:04:02,617 --> 00:04:06,453
比起加莱海峡 诺曼底有几个优势
Normandy had several advantages
over the Pas-de-Calais.

41
00:04:06,537 --> 00:04:11,541
尽管离英国更远,它没有(加莱的)
防御工事那么坚固完备
Though farther from England,
it was less strongly fortified.

42
00:04:11,626 --> 00:04:17,130
它的海滩,大多数没有悬崖
而且只有极少的黏土和洼地,
lts beaches, mostly without cliffs
and with a minimum of clay and depressions,

43
00:04:17,215 --> 00:04:22,928
更适合于部队和补给的登陆
以及将其迅速部署到内陆
were more suited to the landing of troops
and supplies and to rapid deployment inland.

44
00:04:23,012 --> 00:04:27,683
而且它靠近瑟堡(法国西部最大港口)
以及布列塔尼(半岛)的港口
And it was close to Cherbourg
and the Brittany ports.

45
00:04:32,438 --> 00:04:35,440
1943年8月,在(加拿大)魁北克,
At Quebec, in August, 1943,

46
00:04:35,525 --> 00:04:41,280
"考萨克"拟定的入侵计划被丘吉尔和罗斯福批准
COSSAC's outline plan for invasion
was approved by Churchill and Roosevelt.

47
00:04:41,364 --> 00:04:44,992
跨海峡的突击现在终于将变为事实
The cross-Channel assault
was now, at last, to become reality.

48
00:04:45,076 --> 00:04:50,497
它的行动代号...霸王(行动)
它的目标日期...1944年5月
lts codename... Overlord.
lts target date... May, 1944.

49
00:04:54,377 --> 00:04:57,671
入侵的跳板(出发点)将是英国
The springboard for invasion
would be England.

50
00:04:57,755 --> 00:05:01,758
一度被希特勒的炸弹弄得背井离乡
的英国人,再次离开家园
Britons, displaced once by Hitler's
bombs, were on the move again.

51
00:05:01,843 --> 00:05:06,179
这次,是为入侵大军让路
This time, to make way
for the great invasion armies.

52
00:05:06,639 --> 00:05:11,101
对许多人来说,这意味着剧烈的变化,
钱财的损失,个人的难题
For many, this meant upheaval,
financial loss, personal problems.

53
00:05:11,185 --> 00:05:13,562
但(导致他们再次离开家园的)
原因是极其重要的...
But the cause was momentous...

54
00:05:13,688 --> 00:05:16,523
期待已久的第二战场
the long-awaited second front.

55
00:05:16,607 --> 00:05:19,359
(♪ 棕色小壶)
(♪ Little Brown Jug)

56
00:05:34,208 --> 00:05:35,800
早已从美国开出,
Already from the United States,

57
00:05:35,800 --> 00:05:39,421
拥挤不堪的运兵船正鱼贯穿越大西洋
the packed troop ships were
streaming across the Atlantic.

58
00:06:02,153 --> 00:06:06,740
到现在,在英国的美国人
人数已达到了150万人,
By now, the number of Americans in Britain
approached one and a half million,

59
00:06:06,824 --> 00:06:10,786
而伦敦的街头展现了每一种已知的盟军制服
and London's streets displayed
every known Allied uniform.

60
00:06:12,580 --> 00:06:17,918
在这个流动的大兵营里,士气是至关重要的
ln this great floating barracks,
morale was all-important.

61
00:06:23,049 --> 00:06:24,716
(美国喜剧演员 鲍勃·霍普)
我们经历了一些美妙的旅程
We've had some grand trips.

62
00:06:25,200 --> 00:06:27,636
但这(旅程)很令人愉快
我对能到这里来感到非常激动
But it's been wonderful.
l'm very thrilled to be here.

63
00:06:27,720 --> 00:06:29,200
我真的没从美国带来
什么新消息(向你们)报告
l really have nothing new
to report from the States.

64
00:06:29,200 --> 00:06:33,183
你们知道,美国...
那是丘吉尔住的地方 我...
You know, the States...
that's where Churchill lives. l...

65
00:06:37,313 --> 00:06:40,000
但他真的(到处)旅行,不是吗?
伙计,他哪里都去过
But he really travels,doesn't he?
Boy, he's been around.

66
00:06:40,000 --> 00:06:44,277
他去卡萨布兰卡的次数比亨弗莱·鲍嘉
(电影"卡萨布兰卡"男主角的扮演者)还多
He's been to Casablanca
more than Humphrey Bogart.

67
00:06:45,029 --> 00:06:47,600
在一个不同的舞台上,另一位美国人,
On a different stage,
another American,

68
00:06:47,600 --> 00:06:49,500
德怀特·戴维·艾森豪威尔将军,
General Dwight David Eisenhower,

69
00:06:49,500 --> 00:06:54,162
被罗斯福任命为霸王行动的最高指挥官
named by Roosevelt
Overlord's supreme commander.

70
00:06:54,247 --> 00:07:00,127
艾森豪威尔在1942年指挥了盟军对北非的远征
Eisenhower had commanded the Allied
North African expedition in 1942.

71
00:07:00,211 --> 00:07:04,089
除了将才,他还需要一个外交官的手腕
As well as generalship,he would
need the finesse of a diplomat

72
00:07:04,173 --> 00:07:09,177
因为现在他要领导一支巨大的多国部队
because he was now to lead
a huge multinational force.

73
00:07:09,804 --> 00:07:14,400
(凯·萨默斯比 艾森豪威尔的司机和情人)
你总是有各种问题,但作为盟军最高统帅,艾森豪威尔将军
You always have problems,but General Eisenhower,
being the supreme Allied commander,

74
00:07:14,400 --> 00:07:20,856
他有这种能与所有不同国籍的人们
融洽相处的绝妙技巧
he had this wonderful knack of getting along
with people of all different nationalities.

75
00:07:20,982 --> 00:07:23,000
他不把他自己看作是一个美国人,
He didn't think of himself
as an American,

76
00:07:23,000 --> 00:07:29,156
他不把他自己看作是一个英国人
或法国人或波兰人或任何(某国籍的)人
he didn't think of himself as British
or French or Polish or anything.

77
00:07:29,240 --> 00:07:32,826
他只考虑什么对整个盟军的努力是最好的(选择)
He just thought what was best
for the whole Allied effort.

78
00:07:34,287 --> 00:07:39,749
艾克未来的指挥官中 最知名的是
蒙哥马利将军,阿拉曼(战役)的胜利者
Best known of lke's commanders-to-be
was General Montgomery,victor of Alamein.

79
00:07:39,834 --> 00:07:42,419
以他对他的部队坦率的讲话而闻名,
Famous for his plain speaking
to his troops,

80
00:07:42,503 --> 00:07:46,882
蒙蒂现在敦促战争工人们竭尽全力生产
Monty now urged the war workers
to maximum effort.

81
00:07:47,800 --> 00:07:53,972
为什么...为什么今天(战争的)趋势已经改变
Why is it... why is it that
today the tide has turned

82
00:07:54,056 --> 00:08:01,938
我们正在打败德国人 并向着
这场战争的最后高潮前进?
and we are beating the Germans and coming
towards the final climax of the war?

83
00:08:02,023 --> 00:08:08,236
我会告诉你为什么会这样 这是因为
我们有远比他们好的最好装备
l'll tell you why it is. lt's because
we've got far the best equipment

84
00:08:08,321 --> 00:08:13,325
我们有远比他们好的最好战士
还有女人 都是最好的
and we've got far the best men.
And women too. Far the best.

85
00:08:17,955 --> 00:08:24,252
如果战场前线和国土防线
今年真的都能认真对待的话,
lf the battle front and the home front
really get down to it this year,

86
00:08:24,337 --> 00:08:27,005
我们就能把这东西(纳粹)几乎结果掉,
we can get the thing almost finished,

87
00:08:27,131 --> 00:08:32,302
我们能把它绑得如此紧,
以至于明年我们就能把它推翻掉
we can get it so tight,
that next year we just topple it over.

88
00:08:32,386 --> 00:08:34,554
再见了你们所有人 非常感谢
Goodbye to you all.
Thank you very much.

89
00:08:34,639 --> 00:08:38,200
蒙蒂的乐观富有感染力,
但英国,像美国一样,
Monty's optimism was infectious,
but Britain, like America,

90
00:08:38,200 --> 00:08:43,021
已经在全压力下工作了 无论有没有音乐
was already working at full pressure
with or without music.

91
00:08:43,606 --> 00:08:46,024
(♪ 埃里克·寇特斯 "呼唤所有的工人")
(♪ "Calling All Workers" by Eric Coates)

92
00:08:58,329 --> 00:09:02,249
巨大的努力正尽全力达成
"霸王行动"最终的目标
The massive effort was straining
towards the final Overlord targets.

93
00:09:02,333 --> 00:09:04,584
飞机...13,000架
Aircraft... 13,000.

94
00:09:04,669 --> 00:09:07,128
坦克和装甲车辆...17,000辆
Tanks and vehicles... 17,000.

95
00:09:07,213 --> 00:09:11,925
降落伞...90,000顶.
数百万计的炸弹和炮弹
Parachutes... 90,000.
Bombs and shells in millions.

96
00:09:48,921 --> 00:09:53,300
"霸王行动"还需要4,000艘
攻击和登陆舰艇
And Overlord would also need
4,000 assault and landing craft.

97
00:09:53,384 --> 00:09:55,719
但是,首先,它们根本就没有准备好
But, at first,they simply weren't there.

98
00:09:55,803 --> 00:10:01,000
对一次(两栖)入侵来说 绝对关键的事
就是要把部队运过海去
(Mountbatten) The absolutely crucial thing for
an invasion is to get the troops across the water.

99
00:10:01,000 --> 00:10:03,300
为此 你需要登陆舰和登陆艇
For that you want landing
ships and landing craft.

100
00:10:03,300 --> 00:10:05,700
它们必须被设计出来
它们必须被大批建造出来,
They had to be designed. They had
to be built in large quantities,

101
00:10:05,700 --> 00:10:11,651
就在所有的造船设施都被要求为进行大西洋
(反潜)战役(而制造护航舰只和商船)的时候
at a time when all ship-building facilities
were required to fight the Battle of the Atlantic.

102
00:10:13,779 --> 00:10:16,800
到1944年春天,登陆舰艇也已建造完毕
By the spring of 1944,
the landing craft,too,were built

103
00:10:16,800 --> 00:10:24,080
并已为在恶劣作战条件下进行的
密集,不断排练的入侵训练作好准备
and ready for intensive,constantly rehearsed,
invasion training in tough battle conditions.

104
00:10:44,769 --> 00:10:47,854
许多参与"霸王行动"的部队将从空中入侵
Many Overlord troops
would invade from the air.

105
00:10:47,938 --> 00:10:53,276
超过20,000名(空降兵)被指定参与
迄今为止战争中最大的空降行动
More than 20,000 were earmarked for the biggest
airborne operation of the war so far.

106
00:10:56,947 --> 00:11:00,116
一些突击部队将不得不攀登悬崖
Some assault troops
would have to scale cliffs.

107
00:11:00,201 --> 00:11:06,247
在条件恶劣的(英吉利)海峡的海域中
训练 可能和真的登陆战一样致命
Training in rough Channel waters
could be as deadly as the real thing.

108
00:11:15,383 --> 00:11:22,555
在那些同样海域的对面,冯·伦德施泰特
和隆美尔对如何应对入侵有不同的看法
Across those same waters,Von Rundstedt and Rommel
had divided views on how to meet the invasion.

109
00:11:24,058 --> 00:11:26,351
冯·伦德施泰特,(德军西线)总司令,
Von Rundstedt, the commander-in-chief,

110
00:11:26,435 --> 00:11:30,188
想要在后方保留一支
机动预备队以在内陆作战
wanted a mobile reserve
kept back to fight inland.

111
00:11:30,272 --> 00:11:33,274
隆美尔,反入侵部队的指挥官,
Rommel, commander
of the anti-invasion forces,

112
00:11:33,401 --> 00:11:35,777
想要在海滩上击退进攻
wanted to repel the assault
on the beaches.

113
00:11:38,400 --> 00:11:42,600
但希特勒的"大西洋壁垒",一连串
由钢筋混凝土(打造的)堡垒,
But Hitler's Atlantic Wall, a chain
of steel-and-concrete fortifications

114
00:11:42,600 --> 00:11:46,913
计划从丹麦延伸到西班牙边境,仍未(建造)完成
planned to stretch from Denmark
to the Spanish border, was incomplete.

115
00:11:52,500 --> 00:12:00,927
隆美尔通过铺设一排排可怕的水下障碍物,包括
几百万枚隐藏的地雷,以作出迟来的努力来填补缺口
Rommel made belated efforts to fill the gaps by
laying lines of formidable underwater obstacles,
including millions of hidden mines.

116
00:12:12,189 --> 00:12:18,111
为了克服这些防御措施,盟军发展出
各种各样设计独特的新发明
To overcome these defences, the Allies
evolved various ingenious contraptions.

117
00:12:18,195 --> 00:12:22,031
为帮助坦克越过沙滩和泥泞和混凝土,
To help tanks over sand
and mud and concrete,

118
00:12:22,116 --> 00:12:25,201
(发明出了)瑞士卷和铺地毯机
the Swiss Roll and the Carpet Layer.

119
00:12:37,673 --> 00:12:44,512
应该用来摧毁海滩障碍物的"首领",并不成功
The Panjandrum, supposed to destroy
beach obstacles, was not successful.

120
00:13:05,326 --> 00:13:09,120
"普路托"...洋底输油管道(的缩写)...
Pluto... PipeLines Under The Ocean...

121
00:13:09,246 --> 00:13:11,998
一种数英里长的可弯曲的输油管道
a flexible pipeline miles long.

122
00:13:13,918 --> 00:13:18,900
"普路托"能将用油轮将石油
运到法国的风险降到最低
Pluto would minimise the hazards of
transporting petrol to France by tanker.

123
00:13:19,840 --> 00:13:26,763
它能在水下每天将超过100万
吨的燃料运到(欧洲)大陆
lt could carry over a million tons of
fuel daily to the continent, underwater.

124
00:13:26,847 --> 00:13:31,434
海岸(石油)泵站被没有危险地伪装了
Shore pumping stations
were innocently camouflaged.

125
00:13:35,105 --> 00:13:38,149
更不寻常地是"桑葚",
Still more remarkable was Mulberry,

126
00:13:38,234 --> 00:13:43,238
两个人造港口 每一个都有多佛港那么大
two artificial harbours
each the size of Dover harbour.

127
00:13:43,322 --> 00:13:47,826
所有的组件都必须被拖过(英吉利)海峡
All the components had to
be towed across the Channel.

128
00:13:47,910 --> 00:13:53,873
由于海峡的天气条件,要待在对岸
是一个非常困难的问题
The problem of staying ashore was a very difficult
one,because of weather conditions in the Channel.

129
00:13:53,999 --> 00:13:59,300
你不可能指望连续超过三或四天的天气
都好到能横跨(两岸的)海滩进行补给
You couldn't expect more than three or
four consecutive days of weather fine
enough to supply across the beaches.

130
00:13:59,300 --> 00:14:02,400
所以,很明显,我们认为
我们必须夺取一个港口
So, obviously, we thought
we'd have to take a port.

131
00:14:02,400 --> 00:14:03,600
那就是为什么我们尝试(夺取)迪耶普
That's why we tried Dieppe.

132
00:14:03,600 --> 00:14:12,058
但我们在迪耶普发现 我们不使用会将我们想要
使用的港口设施炸毁的猛烈轰炸 就夺取不了港口
But we found in Dieppe that we couldn't capture
a port without using such heavy bombardment as
would destroy the facilities we wanted to use.

133
00:14:12,142 --> 00:14:16,271
所以很明显的事就是要把
我们自己的人造港口一起带来,
So the obvious thing was to bring
our own artificial harbour with us,

134
00:14:16,355 --> 00:14:21,317
我们将其称为"桑葚",而每个人
都认为这(想法)绝对疯狂
which we called Mulberry, and which
everybody thought was absolutely crazy.

135
00:14:22,194 --> 00:14:27,156
艾森豪威尔经常与他的指挥官碰面以协调战略
Eisenhower met constantly with his
commanders to coordinate strategy.

136
00:14:27,241 --> 00:14:31,327
他的副手,(包括英国)空军元帅特德,
海军上将拉姆齐,
His deputy, Air Chief Marshal Tedder,
Admiral Ramsay,

137
00:14:31,412 --> 00:14:33,788
布莱德利将军和蒙哥马利将军,
Generals Bradley and Montgomery,

138
00:14:33,873 --> 00:14:36,291
以及空军元帅利-马洛里
and Air Marshal Leigh-Mallory.

139
00:14:36,375 --> 00:14:41,838
一个主要的当务之急就是能够
预测霸王行动开始时的天气
A major preoccupation was the weather that
could be expected for the start of Overlord.

140
00:14:41,922 --> 00:14:47,400
艾森豪威尔将军很早就表明
他想要逐步建立信心,
General Eisenhower made it clear quite early
that he wanted to build up confidence,

141
00:14:47,400 --> 00:14:56,100
(J.M.斯塔格博士 首席气候官)
不仅是对我们作为天气预报者所能做的
(预报)，对他个人来说就是我本人,
not only in what we could do as forecasters,
and I in particular for him personally,

142
00:14:56,100 --> 00:15:06,400
而且他想要知道 他对我用的词和
我用的声音的语调 能有多大的信心
but he wanted to know what reliance he could put on
the very words I used and the tone of voice I used.

143
00:15:06,400 --> 00:15:15,288
他甚至能在我介绍(天气)预报前,
就看出我要说什么 几乎每次(都说对了)
He could tell,even before I presented the forecast,
almost each time what I was going to say.

144
00:15:15,414 --> 00:15:19,042
他用我的脸,我想,作为一种客厅晴雨表
He used my face, I think,
as a kind of hall barometer.

145
00:15:20,085 --> 00:15:23,700
欺骗计划也占用了最高指挥部(的大量精力)
Deception plans also occupied Supreme Command.

146
00:15:23,700 --> 00:15:30,178
在最煞费苦心(的欺骗行动)之中 包括为从
苏格兰出发,进攻挪威的虚假行动进行的准备
Among the most elaborate were fake
preparations for an attack on Norway,
to be launched from Scotland.

147
00:15:30,262 --> 00:15:36,100
以及更可信地,从(英国)南部港口
对加莱海峡的一次主要攻击
And, more credibly, for a main assault on
the Pas-de-Calais from the southeast ports.

148
00:15:36,185 --> 00:15:43,191
一样关键的还有切断通往入侵地区的
德国交通路线的轰炸计划...空中封锁.
Also crucial was the bombing plan to cut German
communications to invasion areas... interdiction.

149
00:15:43,275 --> 00:15:47,654
你必须做的事情是要阻碍(敌人)的交通
What one had to do was to
interfere with the communications.

150
00:15:47,738 --> 00:15:50,615
我认为这也是从迪耶普学到的一个教训
Again, I think this was
a lesson learned from Dieppe.

151
00:15:50,699 --> 00:15:54,661
我们在迪耶普没有意识到
That we hadn't realised at Dieppe

152
00:15:54,745 --> 00:16:04,000
同时拥有来自空中和地面的绝对
压倒性火力是如何地绝对必要
how absolutely essential it was to have an
absolutely overwhelming weight of firepower
both from the air and from the land.

153
00:16:04,100 --> 00:16:09,384
这(种认识)的结果就是,而我认为
这导致了高层很多的困难,
The result of this was,and I think this caused
a good deal of difficulties at high level,

154
00:16:09,468 --> 00:16:16,224
就是仍然认为仅凭自己的力量就能赢得
战争的空军元帅("轰炸机")哈里斯,
was that Air Marshal Harris,who still thought
that he could win the war on his own,

155
00:16:16,308 --> 00:16:25,066
不得不被劝服 使用他的重型轰炸机
来攻击德国的公路和铁路交通线
had to be persuaded to use his heavy bombers
to attack the German road and rail communications.

156
00:16:25,150 --> 00:16:28,152
而我觉得他(对此)抗拒得非常强烈
And I think he resisted very strongly.

157
00:16:28,237 --> 00:16:32,031
他觉得从整场战争的视点来看
这么做真的是分散注意力
He thought it was really a diversion
from the whole point of the war.

158
00:16:32,116 --> 00:16:37,537
但他被命令这么去做,
而轰炸进行得极其有效
But he was made to do it,
and it was done enormously effectively.

159
00:16:45,796 --> 00:16:52,343
1944年春天 (盟军)对道路和铁路目标
以及对机场进行了广泛的空袭
Spring 1944 saw widespread air attacks
on road and rail targets and on airfields.

160
00:16:59,393 --> 00:17:03,563
与此同时,遍布整个英国南部,
兵营正到处涌现,
At the same time, all over the South
of England, camps were springing up,

161
00:17:03,647 --> 00:17:07,609
准备供成千上万的入侵部队使用
ready for the tens of thousands
of invasion troops.

162
00:17:11,113 --> 00:17:16,159
"霸王行动"的集结区域散布
在英国整个南海岸上,
The staging areas for Overlord were spread
the length of England's south coast,

163
00:17:16,243 --> 00:17:23,124
遍及法尔茅斯,达特茅斯,威尔茅斯,朴茨茅斯和纽黑文
round the ports of Falmouth, Dartmouth,
Weymouth, Portsmouth and Newhaven.

164
00:17:34,678 --> 00:17:38,639
现在一切都已为向南的大侵袭做好了准备
All was now prepared
for the great move south.

165
00:17:38,724 --> 00:17:41,601
为了入侵(行动)的交通 道路被开辟出来
The lines were cleared
for invasion traffic.

166
00:17:49,600 --> 00:17:51,400
军事告示 公众禁止越过此处

167
00:17:54,500 --> 00:17:55,800
战争部 禁区 危险 禁止入内

168
00:17:59,600 --> 00:18:01,200
禁区 止步

169
00:18:02,700 --> 00:18:06,000
危险 桥梁修理

170
00:18:09,500 --> 00:18:10,600
危险 坦克在路上 小心驾驶

171
00:18:10,839 --> 00:18:15,384
在大量涌现的军事告示中,
有一个暴露实情的指示牌特别显眼
Amid the rash of military notices,
one telltale sign stood out.

172
00:18:15,400 --> 00:18:17,900
通向南部

173
00:18:59,304 --> 00:19:03,391
这巨大的军事集结到达了
其在(英吉利)海峡的集合点
The vast concentration
reached its Channel rendezvous.

174
00:19:03,517 --> 00:19:09,272
一些风趣的人声称 只是由于防空气球飘动在头顶
才没使英国(因为这么多沉重的装备而)沉没
Some wit claimed that only the barrage balloons
floating overhead kept Britain from sinking.

175
00:19:16,780 --> 00:19:18,900
1944年5月下旬
Late May, 1944.

176
00:19:18,900 --> 00:19:23,327
突击部队被封闭在他们的集结区域内,准备出发
The assault troops were sealed within
their marshalling areas, ready to go.

177
00:19:23,412 --> 00:19:25,580
现在...一次暂停
Now... a pause.

178
00:19:26,456 --> 00:19:29,208
延迟(出发)当然滋生了恐惧
Fear feeds on delay, of course.

179
00:19:29,293 --> 00:19:32,712
我们真的不知道我们什么时候才能出发
And we didn't really know
just when we were going.

180
00:19:35,257 --> 00:19:38,000
吹牛,打牌,把我们所有的钱都输光
Shot crap, played cards,
lost all our money.

181
00:19:38,000 --> 00:19:40,300
有些人赢了钱 我把我的钱都输光了
Some people won money.
l lost all mine.

182
00:19:40,300 --> 00:19:44,557
钱对我来说没有任何用处 当我登上
(法国)海滩 我没有地方花它
Didn't do me any good. I had no place
to spend it when I got on the beach.

183
00:19:45,851 --> 00:19:50,313
口粮,货币,弹药,装备
Rations, currency,
ammunition, kit.

184
00:19:50,397 --> 00:19:54,483
打包和重新打包,检查装备
Packing and repacking,
checking equipment.

185
00:19:54,568 --> 00:19:57,486
确切的入侵日期还没有被披露
The exact invasion date
was not yet revealed.

186
00:19:57,571 --> 00:20:01,115
而大多数人仍不知道他们将要攻击的海滩
And most men still did not know
the beaches they were going to attack.

187
00:20:01,200 --> 00:20:05,870
只有军官和军士被告知了确切的登陆区域
Only officers and NCOs had been
told the precise landing areas.

188
00:20:06,496 --> 00:20:08,915
在(英吉利)海峡对面100英里的诺曼底,
100 miles across the Channel in Normandy,

189
00:20:08,999 --> 00:20:12,335
这些登陆区域由五个滩头组成
these landing areas
comprised five beaches.

190
00:20:12,419 --> 00:20:16,923
由西向东,"犹他"和"奥马哈"
(滩头)等待着美国人(的进攻)
From west to east, Utah and Omaha
waited for the Americans.

191
00:20:17,007 --> 00:20:21,844
"黄金","朱诺"和"宝剑"滩头
则由英国人和加拿大人负责
Gold, Juno and Sword
for the British and Canadians.

192
00:20:21,929 --> 00:20:24,639
但现在一切都依赖天气
But all now depended on the weather.

193
00:20:25,474 --> 00:20:29,000
在5月31日那个星期三的晚上,
(Stagg) On the evening
of that Wednesday, 31 May,

194
00:20:29,000 --> 00:20:34,857
甚至那时我还向艾森豪威尔将军报告
即将到来的这个周末的(气候)条件,
even then I advised General Eisenhower
that conditions for the oncoming weekend,

195
00:20:34,942 --> 00:20:39,600
尤其是星期日晚上和星期一早晨,
霸王行动的关键时刻,
especially over Sunday night and Monday
morning,the crucial times for Overlord,

196
00:20:39,600 --> 00:20:46,160
将会有暴风雨,但我们还是把会议进行下去
were going to be stormy,
but we went on with the meetings.

197
00:20:46,286 --> 00:20:49,997
我不得不出现在艾森豪威尔
将军和他的指挥官面前,
l had to go before General Eisenhower
and his commanders,

198
00:20:50,082 --> 00:20:56,963
在那决定命运的日子...6月1日,2日和3日里,
他们只和我一天碰两次头
who met for nothing else twice a day during
those fateful days...1, 2 and 3 June.

199
00:20:59,424 --> 00:21:05,846
6月3日,尽管最高指挥部对天气
仍很担心,部队还是登船了
On 3 June, despite Supreme Command's concern
about the weather,embarkation went ahead.

200
00:21:05,931 --> 00:21:08,391
部队对可能的突然停止行动一无所知
The troops knew nothing
of a possible hitch,

201
00:21:08,475 --> 00:21:12,770
尽管一些士兵以为这只是另一次演习
though some men thought
it was just another exercise.

202
00:21:14,690 --> 00:21:18,484
当我们一开始登船的时候,
我们还不知道实际的行动日期
When we first went aboard ship,
we had no knowledge of the actual day yet.

203
00:21:18,568 --> 00:21:20,778
我们已登过船很多次
We had been aboard ship so many times,you see.

204
00:21:20,904 --> 00:21:24,782
有六个月,我们都在不停地上下船
For six months,we were
constantly on and off ships.

205
00:21:29,746 --> 00:21:32,200
在英国海峡沿岸的港口和海港里,
ln the ports and harbours
of England's Channel coast,

206
00:21:32,200 --> 00:21:37,670
巨大而又复杂的装载和登船程序继续进行
the vast and complex process
of loading and embarkation went on.

207
00:21:37,754 --> 00:21:44,385
在海峡中,恶化的天气现在使(盟军)
最高统帅面对一个严重的危机
ln the Channel, the worsening weather now faced
the supreme commander with a grave crisis.

208
00:21:44,469 --> 00:21:47,179
那是一个极其紧张的时刻
(Stagg) lt was a time
of dreadful tension.

209
00:21:47,264 --> 00:21:51,809
我们都知道只可能推迟一天
We all knew that there could be
only one day's deferment.

210
00:21:51,893 --> 00:21:54,061
如果不得不再推迟一天
lf there had to be another day,

211
00:21:54,146 --> 00:21:57,700
那所有的登陆舰艇都需要回到基地,
then all the landing craft
would need to return to base,

212
00:21:57,700 --> 00:22:01,068
所以第二天的延期是不可能做到的
so it couldn't be done
on a second day's postponement.

213
00:22:01,153 --> 00:22:06,907
(入侵行动)将必须被推迟整整两个星期
直到下一次合适的潮汐
lt would have to be deferred for a whole
fortnight until the next tides were right.

214
00:22:06,992 --> 00:22:11,203
而到了那时候,我们的大西洋海图
会呈现出如此的黑色(表示多风暴)
And at that time, our charts
were so black in the Atlantic

215
00:22:11,288 --> 00:22:16,876
以至于似乎根本没有发动
这次行动的任何可能性
that there didn't seem to be any prospect
of getting this operation going at all.

216
00:22:16,960 --> 00:22:20,379
我们不知道将要推迟多久
We didn't know how long
it was going to be postponed.

217
00:22:20,464 --> 00:22:24,383
因为天气看起来是如此糟糕,
我们不知道它是否还会放晴,
Because the weather looked so bad,
we wondered if it would ever clear up,

218
00:22:24,468 --> 00:22:29,555
整个行动是否会被取消
而我们会被命令下船
and whether the whole thing would be called off
and we would be taken back off the ship.

219
00:22:34,478 --> 00:22:37,021
部队为行动作好了准备
Troops primed for action.

220
00:22:37,105 --> 00:22:39,190
一个舰队准备起航
An armada ready to sail.

221
00:22:40,025 --> 00:22:42,860
然后,是一个令人扫兴的消息
And, then, anticlimax.

222
00:22:45,072 --> 00:22:50,785
接着我们被告知 入侵行动
已被推迟至少24小时
We were then told that the invasion had
been put back for at least 24 hours.

223
00:22:50,869 --> 00:22:54,246
这当然增添了我们的担心
Of course,this increased our apprehension.

224
00:22:54,331 --> 00:23:00,711
我们会互相长时间交谈,谈论可能会发生的事情,
And we used to have these long conversations with
each other about the kind of things that might happen,

225
00:23:00,796 --> 00:23:04,298
象我们是否会活着离开海滩
whether we'd ever
get off the beach alive.

226
00:23:07,260 --> 00:23:10,638
在一片不确定的乌云的笼罩下,
例行公事继续着
Routine continued
under a cloud of uncertainty.

227
00:23:10,722 --> 00:23:13,516
部队所能做的就是等待
All the troops could do was wait.

228
00:23:19,606 --> 00:23:22,525
(♪ "不要再逃避")
(♪ "Don't Get Around Much Anymore")

229
00:24:16,079 --> 00:24:21,041
随着时间流逝,似乎只有奇迹
才能使"霸王行动"开始
As the hours passed, it seemed that only
a miracle could get Overlord going.

230
00:24:22,419 --> 00:24:29,675
然后,谢天谢地,最令人难以置信的事
在那个星期日的中午发生了
(Stagg) Then, mercifully,the almost unbelievable
happened about midday on that Sunday.

231
00:24:29,759 --> 00:24:34,889
我们注意到在两个低气压之间
可能有一个间隔期
We spotted that there might be
an interlude between two depressions.

232
00:24:34,973 --> 00:24:47,735
到了晚上,我自己对这个平静期的预测的信心
从进一步传来的报告中得到增强,
By the evening, my own confidence in the forecast
for this quieter period had so increased from
further reports that had come in,

233
00:24:47,819 --> 00:24:55,951
我使艾森豪威尔将军和他的指挥官们确信
它(平静期)确实将在周一较晚时候到来,
that I convinced General Eisenhower and his commanders
that it would indeed arrive later on Monday,

234
00:24:56,036 --> 00:24:59,580
就在周日夜间和周一上午的风暴之后
after the storm of Sunday night
and Monday morning.

235
00:24:59,664 --> 00:25:02,500
它的确将在周一晚间到来,
lt would indeed arrive late on Monday,

236
00:25:02,584 --> 00:25:07,087
持续整个周二,很可能延伸至周三
continue through Tuesday
and probably into Wednesday.

237
00:25:07,172 --> 00:25:11,342
第二天上午,6月5日清晨,
The next morning, early on 5 June,

238
00:25:11,426 --> 00:25:15,054
他们再次碰头以确认这个决定
they met again to confirm this decision.

239
00:25:15,138 --> 00:25:20,935
当我能够告诉他们 我们甚至比前一晚更有信心
When I could tell them that we were even more
confident than we had been the previous night

240
00:25:21,019 --> 00:25:26,732
那就是良好的,或改善的,更平静
的间歇期确实会出现
that the fine, or improved, quieter
interlude would indeed come along,

241
00:25:26,816 --> 00:25:32,071
能在最高统帅和他的指挥官们
的脸上看到(他们的)高兴
the joy on the faces of the supreme
commander and his commanders

242
00:25:32,155 --> 00:25:39,828
在(看到他们)前几天的深深
忧郁(的表情)之后,真是个奇迹
after the deep gloom of the preceding
days, was a marvel to behold.

243
00:25:39,913 --> 00:25:46,377
我记得非常清楚
6月5日清晨4:15分
l remember it very well.
4:15 am on the morning of 5 June.

244
00:25:47,671 --> 00:25:50,381
我没列席会议,但我开车把他送到那里,
l wasn't at the meeting,
but I drove him there,

245
00:25:50,465 --> 00:25:55,511
他出来了 当他上车的时候
他真的看起来很严肃
and he came out and he really looked
so serious as he got in the car.

246
00:25:55,595 --> 00:26:00,140
他说,"D日定下来了
现在没什么东西能阻止我们了"
And he said, "D-day is on.
Nothing can stop us now."

247
00:26:03,687 --> 00:26:06,000
这是个历史性的决定
lt was an historic decision.

248
00:26:06,500 --> 00:26:10,734
"霸王行动"的进一步推迟
可能意味着完全取消行动
Overlord's further postponement
might have meant total cancellation.

249
00:26:13,363 --> 00:26:16,500
部队指挥官朗读了一封
来自艾森豪威尔将军的公报
The troop commander read a message
from General Eisenhower.

250
00:26:16,500 --> 00:26:20,200
你知道,"愿上帝祝福你们"
以及所有诸如之类的话
You know,"God speed" and
all that sort of stuff.

251
00:26:20,300 --> 00:26:27,251
我们读了这篇来自蒙蒂的了不起的公报 关于
"在欧洲的战场上狩猎愉快"以及所有这些垃圾话
We read this great message from Monty about "good
hunting in the fields of Europe" and all this rubbish.

252
00:26:27,335 --> 00:26:32,000
很自然,作为士兵,我们觉得
那全都是在胡说八道
Naturally, being a soldier, we thought
what a load of old cods it was.

253
00:26:32,500 --> 00:26:35,800
(英吉利)海峡的海面
从未见到过这么强大的一支部队
Never had Channel waters
seen such a mighty force.

254
00:26:35,800 --> 00:26:40,180
前往法国的是差不多6,500艘各类船只,
Heading for France were
some 6,500 vessels of all types,

255
00:26:40,265 --> 00:26:44,101
由盟国海军引领并护航
marshalled and escorted
by the Allied navies.

256
00:26:44,185 --> 00:26:48,981
滑翔机编队正在等待,涂上它们D日的标志
Glider fleets were waiting,
wearing their D-day markings.

257
00:26:49,065 --> 00:26:54,300
(英国)第一(空降)师将使用滑翔机
和降落伞进入,降落在入侵滩头的后方
The first division would go in by glider and
parachute,dropping behind the invasion beaches.

258
00:26:55,405 --> 00:26:59,199
他们的损失被预计高达每十人中伤亡七个,
Their losses were expected to be
as high as seven out of every ten men,

259
00:26:59,284 --> 00:27:01,785
(对此)艾森豪威尔也知道
as Eisenhower well knew.

260
00:27:03,246 --> 00:27:04,700
他们都有着被涂黑的脸
(Summersby) They all had blackened faces.

261
00:27:04,700 --> 00:27:08,400
他们很快就将跳入纳粹占领的欧洲
They were going to jump Nazi-occupied
Europe in a very short time.

262
00:27:08,400 --> 00:27:11,700
你不断地想,"不知道多少人将能(活着)回来"
You kept thinking, "l wonder
how many are going to come back."

263
00:27:11,700 --> 00:27:13,000
后来,艾森豪威尔将军说,
Later then, General Eisenhower said,

264
00:27:13,000 --> 00:27:21,597
"你知道,凯,正视着一个士兵的脸,
知道你可能正送他去死 是件非常困难的事"
"You know, Kay, it is very hard to look a soldier in
the face,knowing you might be sending him to his death."

265
00:27:26,519 --> 00:27:32,500
在6月5日的最后几小时里,
空降部队出发前往法国
ln the last hours of 5 June,
the airborne troops set out for France.

266
00:27:33,200 --> 00:27:36,800
你会紧张得直打恶心
你不知道你在这里做什么
Butterflies in your stomach.
You wonder what you're doing here.

267
00:27:36,800 --> 00:27:40,032
"我为什么在这里? 我为什么
要志愿参军? 我疯了吗?"
"Why am I here? Why did I volunteer?
Am I crazy?"

268
00:27:40,116 --> 00:27:41,600
一切事情都在你脑海中翻腾
Everything is going through your mind.

269
00:27:41,600 --> 00:27:45,829
你很担心 你知道行动马上就要开始了
You're worried.
You know it's coming up soon.

270
00:27:49,834 --> 00:27:54,380
我很害怕 我当时19岁,我很害怕
l was afraid.
l was 19, and I was afraid.

271
00:27:54,464 --> 00:27:57,466
许多人都害怕那个夜晚
Many men were afraid that night.

272
00:27:57,592 --> 00:28:04,306
他们正在突袭希特勒吹嘘的
"Festung Europa"...欧洲堡垒
They were storming Hitler's vaunted
Festung Europa... Fortress Europe.

273
00:28:04,432 --> 00:28:07,393
在海峡对面 德国人在等待,
Across the water the Germans waited,

274
00:28:07,477 --> 00:28:11,480
不知道何时或何地 打击会降临
not knowing when or where
the blow would fall.

275
00:28:15,527 --> 00:28:17,528
D日
D-day.

276
00:28:17,612 --> 00:28:19,947
前方,是诺曼底海滩
Ahead, the Normandy beaches.

277
00:28:20,073 --> 00:28:24,535
在四年后,这是回来的路
After four years,
this was the road back.

278
00:28:24,619 --> 00:28:33,544
看到这么多 各种形状和大小的船,而且全都
在向一个方向前进 这真是一幅异乎寻常的场景
lt was a fantastic sight to see so many ships
of all shapes and sizes,and all going one way.

279
00:28:37,340 --> 00:28:40,600
有许多男孩写了信并将其交给了朋友
Quite a few boys wrote letters
and gave it to friends

280
00:28:40,600 --> 00:28:44,805
那样朋友们就能把信带回家
或务必使他们的父母收到信
so that they'd take them home
or see that their parents got them.

281
00:28:44,889 --> 00:28:47,224
这是他们的诀别信
lt was their farewell letter.

282
00:28:48,977 --> 00:28:50,100
海浪很汹涌
The sea was rough.

283
00:28:50,100 --> 00:28:53,147
他们把他们的充气斗篷撑起来
以使艇内保持干燥,
And they'd put their gas capes
over them to keep dry,

284
00:28:53,231 --> 00:28:57,693
而这使他们恶心
因为他们得不到足够的新鲜空气
and it made them sick
cos they didn't get enough fresh air.

285
00:29:00,155 --> 00:29:03,574
我(的船上)有几个人晕船了,他们都呕吐了,
I had several men get seasick,
and they upchucked,

286
00:29:03,658 --> 00:29:06,000
而他们不得不用他们的头盔来接呕吐物
and they had to use their helmets
to catch it in.

287
00:29:06,000 --> 00:29:07,300
我们把头盔里的呕吐物从船的一边倒到海里
And we'd throw them over the side.

288
00:29:07,300 --> 00:29:10,456
它们被冲洗干净后 还给了(呕吐的)弟兄
And they were washed out
and given back to the men.

289
00:29:10,540 --> 00:29:13,600
你会感觉绝对地糟糕透顶,(我是指)身体上的,
One felt absolutely dreadful,physically,

290
00:29:13,600 --> 00:29:17,100
只能向上帝发愿 希望整件事情会快点结束,
and just wishing to God
that the whole thing would be over,

291
00:29:17,100 --> 00:29:19,923
或至少我们能登上陆地
or at least that we could get onto dry land.

292
00:29:32,020 --> 00:29:35,314
在5:30,登陆舰队抵达法国海岸附近
At 5:30 the armada
was off the French coast.

293
00:29:35,440 --> 00:29:40,736
在一次规模庞大的空袭之后,
是一次毁灭性的舰炮轰击
After a massive air assault,
a devastating naval bombardment.

294
00:29:52,165 --> 00:29:54,166
在你目所能及的范围里,
As far as your eye could see,

295
00:29:54,250 --> 00:29:57,169
你被各种舰艇所包围,
you were surrounded
with craft of some sort,

296
00:29:57,295 --> 00:30:01,089
而每艘船都在从它的炮塔里
一枚接一枚地向外发射炮弹
and it was just sending out
shell after shell out of its turrets.

297
00:30:04,385 --> 00:30:07,721
德国人大吃一惊并目瞪口呆,
The Germans were surprised and stupefied,

298
00:30:07,806 --> 00:30:10,265
但一些炮组很快恢复了过来
but some batteries soon recovered.

299
00:30:18,149 --> 00:30:20,567
那远不止是恶心
It was far just more
than sickness.

300
00:30:20,693 --> 00:30:22,500
有些人(大小便失禁)拉在他们的裤子里
Men loaded their pants
and everything else.

301
00:30:22,500 --> 00:30:24,700
之前我极少看到过那种情况
l had rarely seen that before.

302
00:30:24,700 --> 00:30:28,450
我知道战士们(紧张得)犯恶心,
他们中许多人怕得要死
l know the men were sick,
many of them were very sick.

303
00:30:39,170 --> 00:30:45,000
到这时候 海浪正把登陆艇抛上抛下,
我敢说,(颠簸幅度有)六或七英尺
By this time the waves were pitching the craft
up and down,l would say, six or seven feet.

304
00:30:47,095 --> 00:30:49,200
许多男孩被(登陆舰放下的)网给缠住了
A lot of boys got caught in the nets.

305
00:30:49,200 --> 00:30:54,852
我们花了好长时间才使他们松脱
他们的腿被挂在那里了
We had quite a time getting them loose.
Their legs got caught in there.

306
00:30:55,979 --> 00:30:59,356
烟雾,烟雾 有许多炮弹从我们上方飞过
Smoke, smoke. There were
a lot of shells coming over us.

307
00:30:59,440 --> 00:31:05,696
所有的烟雾,黑色的烟雾,就像远处的一座火山
(爆发一样升腾而起) 如同你在电影中看到的那样
All smoke, black smoke,just like a volcano
from afar that one would see in the movies.

308
00:31:27,927 --> 00:31:30,012
对滩头的冲击...
The run-in to the beaches...

309
00:31:30,096 --> 00:31:34,641
对美国人来说是6:30,
对英国人和加拿大人来说是7:30
6:30 for the Americans,
7:30 for the British and Canadians.

310
00:31:34,767 --> 00:31:39,313
在所有的等待,训练,强化之后,
After all the waiting,
the training, the toughening,

311
00:31:39,397 --> 00:31:41,481
正戏开场了
this was it.

312
00:31:42,942 --> 00:31:46,945
我们是首批攻击者,我们是第一(攻击)波
We were the first attackers,
we were the initial wave.

313
00:31:47,071 --> 00:31:49,781
在第一波中总会有大量伤亡,
There's always great losses
in an initial wave,

314
00:31:49,866 --> 00:31:55,078
所以我们每个人都必须在海滩上存活至少30分钟
so each of us had to be given at least
30 minutes to live on the beach.

315
00:32:09,886 --> 00:32:18,018
在完全的空中优势的保护下,第一攻击波
为夺取五个入侵滩头 疾行和匍匐前进
Protected by total air supremacy,the first assault waves
raced and scrambled for the five invasion beaches.

316
00:32:18,102 --> 00:32:23,857
士兵们对离开登陆艇,逃离晕船感到如此高兴,
The soldiers were so glad to get off
the landing craft,to escape the seasickness,

317
00:32:23,942 --> 00:32:28,111
以至于那时候他们准备去任何地方
that they were just ready
to go anywhere by that time.

318
00:32:33,117 --> 00:32:35,500
对五个突击师团的战士来说,
For the men of the five assault divisions,

319
00:32:35,500 --> 00:32:42,042
D日刚开始的那几个小时
是死亡,恐惧,勇气,
those first hours of D-day
were hours of death, fear, courage,

320
00:32:42,126 --> 00:32:46,046
计划出错,和迅速应变的几小时
of plans gone wrong,
of rapid improvisation.

321
00:32:49,008 --> 00:32:53,845
我们本以为会有一片畅通无阻的海滩
(可以)指示我们应该如何前进
We expected a clear beach with an indication
as to exactly how we should proceed.

322
00:32:53,930 --> 00:32:56,807
我们甚至被告知宪兵队会在那里迎接我们
We were even told that the military
police would be there to greet us.

323
00:32:56,891 --> 00:33:01,311
事情变得很明显 那就是滩头
处于一种相当混乱的状态中
lt became quite obvious that the beach
was in a considerable state of chaos.

324
00:33:01,396 --> 00:33:05,565
在接近海岸过程中,有登陆艇
撞上水下的障碍物和地雷
On the run-in, craft ran into
underwater obstacles and into mines.

325
00:33:05,650 --> 00:33:09,111
它们中的一艘压到了一枚地雷,
登陆艇的前半部,
One of them went over a mine.
And the front half of the craft,

326
00:33:09,195 --> 00:33:12,155
以及其中的人员,直接被炸飞到空中
with the personnel in it,
went straight up in the air.

327
00:33:12,240 --> 00:33:16,368
当那艘登陆艇被炸飞
海水呈现出一种不同的颜色
The sea was quite a different colour
when that craft blew up.

328
00:33:21,249 --> 00:33:24,042
一些部队在错误的区域登陆
Some units landed in the wrong area.

329
00:33:24,127 --> 00:33:26,700
一些遭遇了未曾预料到的轻微抵抗,
Some met unexpectedly light resistance,

330
00:33:26,700 --> 00:33:30,132
其他人几乎是在海岸线上被(火力)扫倒
others were cut down
almost on the shoreline.

331
00:33:30,216 --> 00:33:32,718
美国人遭到了失败
The Americans got the worst of it.

332
00:33:34,721 --> 00:33:35,700
我以为我活不下来
I didn't think I'd make it.

333
00:33:35,700 --> 00:33:40,800
我觉得没有任何办法可以穿越海滩并幸存下来
you know,I didn't think there was any way
to get across that beach and survive.

334
00:33:40,800 --> 00:33:44,104
我真的以为那就是我的末日
l really thought it was my last day.

335
00:33:51,654 --> 00:33:54,865
第一个人,那个中士,
The first man, the sergeant,

336
00:33:54,949 --> 00:33:58,577
起身看看我们还得开多远才能到达陆地,
raised up to see how far
we had to go to reach land,

337
00:33:58,661 --> 00:34:01,163
(突然)向后倒下 死了
and fell back dead.

338
00:34:02,957 --> 00:34:07,300
我们被告知 空军将派来重型轰炸机
We had been told that the air force
would gonna come in with the heavy bombers

339
00:34:07,300 --> 00:34:11,757
并会为我们在海滩上炸出弹坑
以让我们有地方藏身
and would gonna crater the beaches for us
to give us a place to hide.

340
00:34:11,841 --> 00:34:14,384
而这并没有发生
And this did not take place.

341
00:34:18,890 --> 00:34:21,200
真是糟透了 每次我爬起来,
It was bloody awful.
Every time I got up,

342
00:34:21,200 --> 00:34:24,900
我都以为是纯粹的恐惧使我的膝盖发软,
l thought that it was pure terror
that was making my knees buckle,

343
00:34:24,900 --> 00:34:31,109
直到我终于冲到页岩 我才意识到
在我的那些口袋中有大约100磅的沙子
until I finally hit the shale and I realised
that I had about 100lbs of sand in those pockets.

344
00:34:38,000 --> 00:34:43,538
我清楚地记得 我拿着我的双刃短刀
在人们的背上(轻轻)戳着 看看他们是否还活着
l remember distinctly taking my trench knife and
pressing it in people's backs to see if they were alive.

345
00:34:43,623 --> 00:34:45,700
如果他们还活着,我就踢他们
或说,"我们走"
lf they were alive, l'd kick 'em
or say, "Let's go."

346
00:34:45,700 --> 00:34:48,000
随后,我在检查了两三个人后逐渐明白
Later on,it dawned on me
after I checked two or three

347
00:34:48,000 --> 00:34:52,506
有些人活得很好 但他们不肯转过身
只是绝对的恐惧(吓坏了他们)
that some were more than alive but they
wouldn't turn around. Just absolute terror.

348
00:35:01,849 --> 00:35:06,311
在英国人和加拿大人负责的三个滩头,
(德国人的)抵抗程度有所不同
On the three British and Canadian
beaches, opposition varied.

349
00:35:06,395 --> 00:35:11,108
在"黄金"滩头,当一支部队攻打
一个据点长达八个小时,
On Gold, while one unit was hammering
at a strongpoint for eight hours,

350
00:35:11,192 --> 00:35:14,194
另一支只用40分钟就离开了海滩
another was off the beach in 40 minutes.

351
00:35:14,278 --> 00:35:20,033
在"朱诺"滩头,加拿大人损失惨重但还是推进了
On Juno, the Canadians suffered
heavy losses but advanced.

352
00:35:20,118 --> 00:35:24,079
在"宝剑"滩头,战斗血腥但又短暂
On Sword, the fighting
was bloody but brief.

353
00:35:24,163 --> 00:35:28,625
许多守卫者走出他们的地堡投降
Many defenders emerged
from their bunkers to surrender.

354
00:35:28,709 --> 00:35:33,421
而在"犹他"滩头,到D日结束的时候,
美国人进展顺利
And on Utah, by the end of the day,
the Americans were doing well.

355
00:35:33,506 --> 00:35:36,883
他们抓了(许多)俘虏,建立了一个稳固的立足点,
They had taken prisoners,
established a firm foothold,

356
00:35:36,968 --> 00:35:39,761
并向内陆推进了五英里
driven five miles inland.

357
00:35:42,682 --> 00:35:46,017
但在"奥马哈"滩头,美国人遇到了困难...
But on Omaha,the Americans
ran into difficulties...

358
00:35:46,144 --> 00:35:49,000
波涛汹涌的海面,牢固的防御工事
rough seas, strong defences

359
00:35:49,000 --> 00:35:52,107
和一个新到达的德国野战师(第352步兵师)
and a newly arrived
German fighting division.

360
00:35:55,069 --> 00:35:58,280
从我所在的地方看,(登陆)似乎失败了
From where I was,it seemed a failure.

361
00:35:59,657 --> 00:36:02,100
当时海滩上有如此多的人
At that time there were just
so many people on the beach

362
00:36:02,100 --> 00:36:05,300
你事实上可以从一头走到另一头
全都踩在(士兵的)身体上
that you could literally walk on the bodies
from one end to the other,either

363
00:36:05,300 --> 00:36:08,582
他们不是死 就是伤
that they are dead or wounded.

364
00:36:08,708 --> 00:36:11,585
我看到有人倒在那里 头没了,
I saw people laying out
there with no head,

365
00:36:11,669 --> 00:36:13,962
还有些人手臂被打掉了
and some with arms blown off.

366
00:36:14,046 --> 00:36:17,632
其中一些是我的朋友
真是挺令人作呕的
Some of my friends.
lt was pretty sickening.

367
00:36:21,012 --> 00:36:24,400
在"奥马哈"滩 (美军)花了一整天,
付出了令人痛心的伤亡,
At Omaha it took a whole day,
with grievous losses,

368
00:36:24,400 --> 00:36:27,434
夺取了一个一英里深的桥头堡
to gain a beachhead a mile deep.

369
00:36:28,895 --> 00:36:32,731
那是我有过的最令人悲痛的经历
It was the most heartrending
experience that I ever had.

370
00:36:32,815 --> 00:36:35,700
我希望我永远不再有另一次类似的经历了
l hope I never have another one like it.

371
00:36:36,100 --> 00:36:42,365
回头看去 看到海滩上到处散布着
一个优秀营的(战士们的)遗体
Look back and see the remains of
a crack battalion strewn over the beach.

372
00:36:42,450 --> 00:36:46,870
而(阵亡的)士兵们漂浮在水中,脸朝上
And men floating in the water, face-up.

373
00:36:46,954 --> 00:36:49,706
我们当时缺乏经验,或许这是件好事,
Perhaps it was better
that we were green,

374
00:36:49,790 --> 00:36:52,200
因为如果我那时就知道了
我现在知道的事情,
because if l'd have known then
what I know now,

375
00:36:52,200 --> 00:36:55,503
我很可能就会回到那船上并回英国了
l'd probably have got on that boat
and went back to England.

376
00:37:01,344 --> 00:37:06,223
(这是)不断思念家乡的一天
A day of continuous thinking
thoughts of home.

377
00:37:07,892 --> 00:37:10,143
祈祷的一天
A day of prayer.

378
00:37:10,228 --> 00:37:14,397
而且,毫无疑问,我一生中最长的一天
And, without a doubt,
the longest day of my life.

379
00:37:20,363 --> 00:37:24,241
你感觉你是...恩,你完成了一桩...
You feel that you're...
Well, you've accomplished something

380
00:37:24,325 --> 00:37:29,454
...你以为当它完成后 你很可能已经死去的事情
that you didn't think you would probably
end up being around after it was done.

381
00:37:29,538 --> 00:37:34,251
我觉得我们很自豪 为我们完成了登陆任务
l think we were proud in some way
that we'd done it

382
00:37:34,335 --> 00:37:38,380
也为我们服役如此长时间的陆军,
and that the army
we'd been in for so long,

383
00:37:38,464 --> 00:37:44,177
在吸取了他们如何搞砸事情的各种经验教训后,
and with all sorts of experiences
of how they could bungle things,

384
00:37:44,262 --> 00:37:48,139
使这次入侵行动事实上取得了成功
had actually managed this invasion.

385
00:37:48,224 --> 00:37:52,686
欧,我们感到非常高兴 非常高兴
Oh, we feel very happy. Very happy.

386
00:37:53,813 --> 00:37:57,816
啊,我一生中最好的日子 我想是的
Ah, the best day of my life. I think so.

387
00:37:57,900 --> 00:38:00,735
(法语)最大的快乐
你用英语怎么说?
La plus grande joie.
How you say in English?

388
00:38:00,820 --> 00:38:04,155
我们一生中最大的快乐
The biggest joys in our life.

389
00:38:05,199 --> 00:38:08,994
我们敬佩那些英勇的士兵
And we admire those courageous soldiers.

390
00:38:09,078 --> 00:38:12,789
他们从那么远的地方来解放我们
They came from so far away
to liberate us.

391
00:38:12,915 --> 00:38:17,377
而我们给了他们 我们能给他们的一切东西
And we gave to them
everything we could give them.

392
00:38:17,461 --> 00:38:19,879
苹果酒 和之类的东西
Cider and so.

393
00:38:20,006 --> 00:38:22,465
还有陈年苹果白兰地
Calvados, also.

394
00:38:22,550 --> 00:38:27,721
还有我们的...我们的友谊
And our... our friendship.

395
00:38:28,764 --> 00:38:30,473
还有...
And...

396
00:38:30,558 --> 00:38:35,061
这非常地... 令人动情
lt was very... emotional.

397
00:38:35,146 --> 00:38:36,604
而且...
And...

398
00:38:36,689 --> 00:38:40,025
我们,我们感觉... 我们自由了
We, we feel... we became free.

399
00:38:40,818 --> 00:38:45,071
到了午夜,13万部队已经登陆
By midnight,130,000 troops had got ashore.

400
00:38:45,156 --> 00:38:48,033
在所有五个滩头都获得了立足点
Footholds had been gained
on all five beaches.

401
00:38:48,117 --> 00:38:50,535
伤亡人数: 9,000.
Casualties: 9,000.

402
00:38:55,791 --> 00:39:00,045
D+1日进行了"桑葚"港口的首次铺设
D-plus-one saw the first laying
of the Mulberry harbours.

403
00:39:00,129 --> 00:39:04,466
补给品的早期堆积对霸王行动的成功来说至关重要
The early build-up of supplies
was vital for the success of Overlord.

404
00:39:04,550 --> 00:39:10,096
以比敌人更快的速度 倾入人员
和物资的增援是非常重要的
lt was essential to pour in the reinforcements
of men and material faster than the enemy.

405
00:39:10,181 --> 00:39:11,973
他们也的确大量倾入了(增援)
And pour in they did.

406
00:39:23,110 --> 00:39:26,279
到了D+7日,数英里长的车辆已经登陆,
By D-plus-seven,
miles of vehicles were ashore,

407
00:39:26,364 --> 00:39:29,449
一辆接一辆地从海滩延伸至内陆
stretching inland from the beaches
bumper to bumper.

408
00:39:29,533 --> 00:39:34,412
在一些地点,交通堵塞长达15英里
At some points,
traffic jams extended 15 miles.

409
00:39:36,457 --> 00:39:39,084
在这个关键的阶段,
"桑葚"的两个(人造)港口...
At this critical phase,
Mulberry's two harbours...

410
00:39:39,168 --> 00:39:42,921
英国人的"阿罗芒什",美国人的"圣洛朗"...
Arromanches for the British,
Saint-Laurent for the Americans...

411
00:39:43,005 --> 00:39:46,883
是盟军可用的唯一(两个)港口
were the only ports
available to the Allies.

412
00:39:47,927 --> 00:39:50,428
在6月18日前的四天里,
ln the four days before 18 June,

413
00:39:50,513 --> 00:39:54,516
平均每天登陆的数量为
部队:差不多35,000人,
the average daily landings were
troops: nearly 35,000,

414
00:39:54,600 --> 00:39:59,479
车辆:5,000辆, 必需品:25,000吨
vehicles: 5,000, stores: 25,000 tons.

415
00:40:03,025 --> 00:40:09,197
如果有一样为霸王行动而发明的设备
产生了效果,那就是"桑葚"
lf a single device invented for Overlord
produced results, it was Mulberry.

416
00:40:14,120 --> 00:40:17,080
只是因为艾森豪威尔和国王
(乔治六世)本人的坚持
Only the insistence of Eisenhower
and the king himself

417
00:40:17,164 --> 00:40:20,166
才阻止了丘吉尔在D日过来
had stopped Churchill
from coming over on D-day.

418
00:40:20,292 --> 00:40:24,754
现在,在登陆的几天后,他到
那里看看事情进展得如何
Now, within days of the landing, he was
there to see how things were going.

419
00:40:24,839 --> 00:40:29,050
最高指挥官们意识到
霸王行动的时间表正在落后
The top commanders were aware that the
Overlord timetable was falling behind.

420
00:40:29,135 --> 00:40:34,806
他们现在对行动的第二阶段...
桥头堡战役感到焦虑不安
They were anxious now about phase two of
the operation...the battle of the bridgehead.

421
00:40:53,742 --> 00:41:00,582
盟军正在为(夺取)用于部署集结在他们后面
的大量人员和装备的空间 而痛苦地战斗
The Allies were fighting bitterly for space to deploy
the mass of men and materials assembling behind them.

422
00:41:00,666 --> 00:41:06,337
这是面对一个已强劲复苏的敌人
的缓慢,顽强的推进
lt was a slow, dogged advance against
an enemy who had recovered strongly.

423
00:41:13,137 --> 00:41:18,349
树篱密布的林地乡村
对盟军坦克来说难以通行
The close-hedged bocage countryside
was difficult for the Allied tanks.

424
00:41:19,000 --> 00:41:24,063
到6月10日,盟军只面对三个德国装甲师的反击
(第21装甲师,SS第12师,装甲教导师)
By 10 June, the Allies were opposed
by only three panzer divisions.

425
00:41:24,148 --> 00:41:29,194
另外七个可动用的(装甲)师
还未被德国最高指挥部放出来
The other seven available divisions had not
been released by the German high command.

426
00:41:29,278 --> 00:41:33,781
尽管这样,入侵者(的推进速度)
也跟缓慢地蜗牛爬没什么两样
Despite this, the invaders
were little more than inching forward.

427
00:41:44,300 --> 00:41:53,718
到6月12日,五个滩头已被连成
一个60英里长,20英里深的立足点
By 12 June, the five beachheads had been linked to
give a lodgement 60 miles long and up to 20 miles deep.

428
00:41:53,844 --> 00:41:59,891
古镇巴约现在欢迎自由法国运动
的领导人戴高乐将军的到来,
The ancient town of Bayeux now welcomed the
leader of the Free French, General de Gaulle,

429
00:41:59,975 --> 00:42:04,938
这是自1940年来他第一次踏上法国的土地
setting foot in France
for the first time since 1940.

430
00:42:09,276 --> 00:42:13,488
6月19日,反复无常的英吉利海峡再次发威
19 June, and the unpredictable
English Channel struck again.

431
00:42:17,785 --> 00:42:21,412
整整四天 40多年里最恶劣的一场狂怒风暴
For four days a raging storm,
the worst in June for over 40 years,

432
00:42:21,497 --> 00:42:24,582
把"桑葚"重创到几乎毁坏
battered Mulberry almost to destruction.

433
00:42:24,667 --> 00:42:28,628
船只被(吹得)脱了锚
关键设备沉没了
Vessels dragged anchor.
Vital equipment foundered.

434
00:42:28,712 --> 00:42:34,926
卸载被严重地缩减了
(卸载的)总吨数下降了五分之四
Unloading was drastically curtailed.
Tonnage was down by four fifths.

435
00:42:36,595 --> 00:42:39,222
(盟军)进行了紧张忙乱的努力
来修复(风暴造成的)损害,
Frantic efforts were made
to repair the damage,

436
00:42:39,306 --> 00:42:43,393
因为这次中断已威胁到了霸王行动的继续
for the disruption had threatened
the very continuance of Overlord.

437
00:42:43,477 --> 00:42:46,271
很快 运输再次启动了
Soon the traffic was rolling again.

438
00:42:47,898 --> 00:42:51,025
霸王行动的生命线被恢复了
The Overlord lifeline was restored.

439
00:42:54,947 --> 00:43:01,327
对"桑葚"港口进行补充的一个主要目标
是美军进攻区域内的瑟堡港
A prime objective to supplement the Mulberry harbours
was the port of Cherbourg in the American sector.

440
00:43:01,412 --> 00:43:04,747
到6月19日 美国人已切断了瑟堡半岛
By 19 June the Americans
had cut off the Cherbourg peninsula

441
00:43:04,832 --> 00:43:07,250
并正向北 朝该港口驶来
and were driving north towards the port.

442
00:43:08,544 --> 00:43:10,795
瑟堡戒备森严
Cherbourg was strongly fortified.

443
00:43:10,879 --> 00:43:15,425
德国人希望通过在那里进行
长时间的抵抗来延迟盟军(的进攻)
The Germans hoped to delay the Allies
by staging a long resistance there.

444
00:43:15,509 --> 00:43:17,677
但到21日,在艰苦的战斗之后,
But by the 21st, after tough fighting,

445
00:43:17,761 --> 00:43:20,847
美国人到达了该港口的外围
the Americans
reached the port's outskirts.

446
00:43:33,736 --> 00:43:36,154
26日,(瑟堡的)守备部队投降了,
On the 26th, the garrison surrendered,

447
00:43:36,238 --> 00:43:39,407
只剩下一些据点有待处理
leaving only a few strongpoints
to be mopped up.

448
00:43:39,491 --> 00:43:44,662
战俘鱼贯而出,其中就有守备部队司令
Prisoners streamed out,
among them the garrison commander.

449
00:43:52,421 --> 00:43:57,342
瑟堡是(诺曼底)战役中第一个被占领的主要目标
Cherbourg was the first major objective
to be captured in the campaign.

450
00:43:57,426 --> 00:44:01,846
在瑟堡地区有25,000名德军被俘
25,000 prisoners
were taken in the Cherbourg area.

451
00:44:09,104 --> 00:44:14,275
一些法国妇女正失去她们的德国情人
Some French women
were losing their German lovers.

452
00:44:19,615 --> 00:44:23,910
瑟堡前线正对面的是卡昂镇
Right across the front from Cherbourg
was the town of Caen.

453
00:44:23,994 --> 00:44:27,914
卡昂是德国部队向滩头移动的中心
Caen was the centre for German troops
moving to the beachhead.

454
00:44:27,998 --> 00:44:32,168
自D日以来 蒙哥马利就一直向这里进攻
Montgomery had been
attacking towards it since D-day.

455
00:44:35,255 --> 00:44:40,093
现在,7月初,他终于准备好了(对卡昂的)突击
Now at last, in early July,
he prepared for the assault.

456
00:44:41,595 --> 00:44:43,554
首先 轰炸机飞过去轰炸
First the bombers went in.

457
00:44:43,639 --> 00:44:48,476
7月18日 超过2,000架重型和中型轰炸机轰炸了卡昂
On 18 July over 2,000
heavy and medium bombers hit Caen

458
00:44:48,560 --> 00:44:54,315
使用了近8,000吨的高爆和碎片炸弹
with nearly 8,000 tons of high explosive
and fragmentation bombs.

459
00:44:57,695 --> 00:45:03,700
这是有史以来尝试过的 用于支援
地面部队的最猛烈和最集中的空袭
lt was the heaviest and most concentrated air attack
in support of ground forces ever attempted.

460
00:45:37,526 --> 00:45:40,486
卡昂被命名为"坩埚"
Caen was christened "the crucible".

461
00:45:40,571 --> 00:45:46,284
当它陷落后,(盟军)部队进入的是
一个被瓦砾堵塞的 到处是炸弹坑的城镇
When it fell, the troops entered
a bomb-cratered town choked with rubble.

462
00:45:48,746 --> 00:45:50,913
它的一半被摧毁了,
Half of it was destroyed,

463
00:45:51,039 --> 00:45:55,960
它的居民中有几千人被杀死或受伤
several thousand of its inhabitants
killed or wounded.

464
00:46:07,848 --> 00:46:13,060
对卡昂的人民来说,这是解放...
但付出了令人伤心的代价
For the people of Caen,
it was liberation... at a grievous price.

465
00:46:23,864 --> 00:46:27,992
现在,在七个没完没了的星期后,突破开始了
Now, after seven grinding weeks,
the start of the break-out.

466
00:46:28,076 --> 00:46:30,953
美国人在阿夫朗什取得了突破
The Americans broke through
at Avranches.

467
00:46:31,038 --> 00:46:35,124
他们向西和向南展开 进入布列塔尼
向东前往莫尔坦,
They fanned out west and south
into Brittany and east to Mortain,

468
00:46:35,209 --> 00:46:38,127
并一路横扫至 阿让唐
and swept up to Argentan.

469
00:46:39,755 --> 00:46:43,800
从北面,英国人和加拿大人向南挤向法莱斯,
From the north,the British and Canadians
edged south towards Falaise,

470
00:46:43,800 --> 00:46:49,764
试图合拢一个现在威胁将德军
困在其中的口袋的袋口
in an attempt to close the neck of a bag
now threatening to trap the German forces.

471
00:46:51,600 --> 00:46:59,023
要迅速关闭"法莱斯缺口" 有非常大的实际困难
There were very great practical difficulties
in this closing of the Falaise Gap quickly.

472
00:46:59,107 --> 00:47:02,985
(戴维·贝尔查姆少将 蒙哥马利的参谋长)
对这一边的英国人,加拿大人,波兰人来说,
And it was difficult for the one side,
British, Canadian, Polish,

473
00:47:03,070 --> 00:47:07,782
要理解另一边的美国人的看法 是很困难的
to appreciate the point of view
of the other side, the Americans.

474
00:47:07,866 --> 00:47:11,327
我们正从北面下来,
We were coming down from the north,

475
00:47:11,411 --> 00:47:17,959
从拥挤的,被轰炸过的,难以通行的卡昂地区出发
launched from the congested, bombed
and difficult areas of the Caen sector.

476
00:47:18,043 --> 00:47:24,215
其次,在(法莱斯)走廊北边
面对我们的德国人
Secondly, the Germans facing us
on that north side of the corridor

477
00:47:24,299 --> 00:47:27,093
他们正(竭力)试图使他们的逃生通道保持畅通,
they were trying to keep open
for their escape,

478
00:47:27,177 --> 00:47:34,392
(他们)是在他们已和我们打了
两个多月的地区里(和我们交战)
were in areas where they had been fighting
against us for two months or more.

479
00:47:34,476 --> 00:47:40,690
美国人正从南面更开阔的乡间
向上运动 来和我们会合
The Americans were coming up to meet us
from the south in more open country

480
00:47:40,774 --> 00:47:45,111
而且面对的是 德国人缺乏准备和组织的抵抗
and against much less prepared
and organised German resistance.

481
00:47:47,990 --> 00:47:52,118
法莱斯,这场战役中最血腥的战场之一
Falaise, one of the bloodiest
battlegrounds of the campaign.

482
00:47:52,244 --> 00:47:54,412
这是蒙哥马利的下一个目标
This was Montgomery's next target.

483
00:48:07,000 --> 00:48:12,555
数以百计发射火箭的"台风"式战斗轰炸机
猛烈扫射敌人的交通线和运输工具,
Hundreds of rocket-firing Typhoons
strafed enemy communications and transport,

484
00:48:12,639 --> 00:48:15,516
留下一路燃烧的车辆
leaving a trail of burning vehicles.

485
00:48:21,607 --> 00:48:25,276
8月6日,加拿大人到达法莱斯的市郊
On 6 August, the Canadians
were on the outskirts of Falaise.

486
00:48:39,291 --> 00:48:42,418
他们在16日进入该镇
They entered the town on the 16th.

487
00:48:50,636 --> 00:48:56,724
到现在 只有一条狭窄的走廊
把加拿大和美国的先头部队分隔开
By now only a narrow corridor separated
the Canadian and American spearheads.

488
00:48:59,478 --> 00:49:03,606
德国第七集团军的残余,
大约15个野战师团,
The remnants of the German 7th army,
some 15 fighting divisions,

489
00:49:03,690 --> 00:49:06,400
被压入一个极小的麻袋
were pressed into a tiny sack.

490
00:49:07,986 --> 00:49:10,655
牢笼终于合上了
At last the trap closed.

491
00:49:10,781 --> 00:49:14,450
10,000德军阵亡 50,000人被俘
10,000 died. 50,000 were captured.

492
00:49:15,869 --> 00:49:21,874
对德国人来说,法莱斯是自斯大林格勒
战役以来 最糟糕的灾难之一
For the Germans, Falaise was one of
the worst disasters since Stalingrad.

493
00:49:27,547 --> 00:49:31,968
战俘的人数强调了这次战败的规模
The toll of prisoners rubbed in
the magnitude of the defeat.

494
00:49:32,052 --> 00:49:35,179
但40,000德军逃走了,
But 40,000 German troops escaped,

495
00:49:35,263 --> 00:49:38,307
而这导致了盟军之间的摩擦
and this caused friction
between the Allies.

496
00:49:40,644 --> 00:49:45,000
要是英国和加拿大部队能够行动得更快一点,
Had the British and Canadian forces
been able to move faster,

497
00:49:45,000 --> 00:49:48,859
我们本来很可能把更多的
德国人困在法莱斯口袋里的
we might have trapped many more
Germans in the Falaise pocket.

498
00:49:48,944 --> 00:49:51,195
他们的装备只有极少逃脱了,
Very little of their equipment got out,

499
00:49:51,321 --> 00:49:56,701
(约瑟夫·劳顿·柯林斯少将 美国第七军军长)
但有许多德国人能够逃向塞纳河
but quite a number of the Germans were
able to escape toward the Seine river.

500
00:49:56,785 --> 00:50:00,246
而这太糟糕了
And this was too bad.

501
00:50:00,330 --> 00:50:08,754
我觉得 根本原因或许是英国
参战的时间比我们长得多
l think perhaps the basic reason was that Britain
had been in the war for much longer than we

502
00:50:08,839 --> 00:50:11,257
并已遭受了非常惨重的伤亡
and had taken very heavy casualties.

503
00:50:11,341 --> 00:50:14,218
而美国人是新来的,
And the Americans were fresh,

504
00:50:14,302 --> 00:50:17,555
而他们事实上没有伤亡数字可以比较
and they had had practically
no casualties in comparison.

505
00:50:17,639 --> 00:50:20,433
所以当我们急着向前突进
So while we were anxious
to drive forward

506
00:50:20,517 --> 00:50:25,300
而且只要我们能达成我们的目标 就不太在意伤亡,
and were not too concerned about the casualties
as long as we could get our objectives,

507
00:50:25,300 --> 00:50:32,570
我想很自然 英国和加拿大部队会以
一种更有序,更有节奏的方式来进行战斗
it was natural, I think,that the British and Canadian
forces did it in a more orderly, pacing way.

508
00:50:32,654 --> 00:50:35,823
或许这是蒙蒂性格的一部分
And perhaps this was part
of Monty's characteristic,

509
00:50:35,907 --> 00:50:37,400
也是他的缺点之一
and one of his drawbacks.

510
00:50:37,400 --> 00:50:44,665
换句话说,他从没有以美国指挥官那种方式突进过
ln other words,that he never did quite
drive the way the American commanders did.

511
00:50:44,750 --> 00:50:48,502
我猜这是他的本性的一部分
他是个更谨慎的人,
This was part of his nature, I guess.
He was a more cautious man,

512
00:50:48,587 --> 00:50:54,717
加之这样一个事实 那就是他不能承受
如果有必要 我们可以承受的伤亡
combined with the fact that he couldn't
afford the casualties that we could take
if it was necessary to take them.

513
00:51:02,017 --> 00:51:06,520
法莱斯赢得了"杀戮战场"的名称
Falaise earned the name
of "the killing ground".

514
00:51:07,564 --> 00:51:11,525
屠杀和毁灭是骇人听闻的
The carnage and destruction
were appalling.

515
00:51:17,741 --> 00:51:20,701
艾森豪威尔访问了战场并写道:
Eisenhower visited the battlefield and wrote:

516
00:51:20,786 --> 00:51:25,206
"完全有可能一次走上个几百码,
"lt was literally possible to walk
for hundreds of yards at a time,

517
00:51:25,290 --> 00:51:29,919
全都踩在死去并腐烂的尸体上"
stepping on nothing
but dead and decaying flesh."

518
00:51:58,448 --> 00:51:59,491
巴黎
Paris.

519
00:52:00,575 --> 00:52:04,620
盟军的主要攻势将绕过法国首都
The main Allied drive was going
to bypass the French capital.

520
00:52:04,704 --> 00:52:07,998
在纳粹统治下活了四年的巴黎人,
The Parisians,under Nazi
domination for four years,

521
00:52:08,083 --> 00:52:09,708
终于感觉到了解放
sensed liberation at last.

522
00:52:09,835 --> 00:52:11,752
当德国人开始撤离,
As the Germans began to pull out,

523
00:52:11,837 --> 00:52:16,298
抵抗力量公然出现并进行报复
the Resistance forces emerged
into the open to take revenge.

524
00:52:22,472 --> 00:52:27,059
回想起压迫,轻蔑,羞辱,
Remembering the oppression,
indignities, humiliations,

525
00:52:27,185 --> 00:52:30,521
巴黎人发泄着积压已久的仇恨
Parisians gave vent
to long-stored hatred.

526
00:52:35,986 --> 00:52:39,947
在1940年 他们目睹巴黎一枪未发就陷入敌手
ln 1940 they had seen Paris fall without a shot.

527
00:52:40,031 --> 00:52:45,828
现在 他们以整场战争中在巴黎都
前所未见的一连串暴力攻击 做出了补偿
Now they made up for it in a burst of violence
not seen in Paris throughout the war.

528
00:52:46,872 --> 00:52:48,998
巴黎人只有一种想法...
Parisians had one thought...

529
00:52:49,082 --> 00:52:54,003
报复敌人,清算旧账
reprisal against the enemy,
the settlement of old scores.

530
00:53:05,932 --> 00:53:08,851
黎明已经来临
Morning had come.

