1
00:00:16,349 --> 00:00:22,800
距离日本以南1,500英里的马里亚纳
群岛中的提尼安岛上的诺斯菲尔德
North Field, on the island of Tinian,
in the Marianas,1500 miles south of Japan.

2
00:00:26,401 --> 00:00:31,864
1945年夏天 这是世界上最大的空军基地
In the summer of 1945 this was
the biggest air base in the world.

3
00:00:33,283 --> 00:00:34,200
(1945年)8月5日,在这里,
Here, on August 5,

4
00:00:34,200 --> 00:00:43,042
世界上第一枚铀弹被装进一架以其驾驶员母亲
名字命名的"艾诺拉·盖伊"号B-29型轰炸机
the world's first uranium bomb was loaded into a B-29
bomber...named Enola Gay after its pilot's mother.

5
00:00:44,700 --> 00:00:48,464
第二天早晨,在黎明前,
"艾诺拉·盖伊"号起飞了
Next morning, before dawn,
the Enola Gay took off.

6
00:00:48,548 --> 00:00:51,050
它的目标 - 广岛
Its target - Hiroshima.

7
00:01:56,950 --> 00:02:00,300
1945年4月12日,
On April 12,1945,

8
00:02:00,300 --> 00:02:06,125
美国总统富兰克林·罗斯福突然逝世
Franklin Roosevelt, President
of the United States, died suddenly.

9
00:02:08,169 --> 00:02:11,547
举国都为其过世的领导人致哀
The nation mourned its lost leader.

10
00:02:16,300 --> 00:02:21,890
他已带领他们从12年前经济大萧条的深渊中走出,
He had brought them from the depths
of economic depression 12 years before,

11
00:02:21,975 --> 00:02:26,478
现在他已领导他们到了一场世界大战的胜利前夜
now he had led them to the eve
of victory in a world war.

12
00:02:28,690 --> 00:02:33,360
在他死前的两个月,罗斯福去了俄国的雅尔塔,
Two months before his death,
Roosevelt had been at Yalta, in Russia,

13
00:02:33,486 --> 00:02:37,239
为战后的世界奠定政治基础
laying the political foundations
of the post-war world.

14
00:02:37,323 --> 00:02:43,700
罗斯福和丘吉尔想要在东欧,特别是波兰恢复民主制度
Roosevelt and Churchill wanted to restore
democracy to Eastern Europe,particularly Poland.

15
00:02:43,700 --> 00:02:51,920
他们还请求斯大林确认 俄国会在
德国战败的三个月后加入对日战争
They also asked Stalin to confirm that
Russia would join the war against Japan
three months after the defeat of Germany.

16
00:02:52,005 --> 00:02:54,047
在愉快的气氛中,
In a cheerful atmosphere,

17
00:02:54,132 --> 00:02:58,552
"三巨头"以为他们已达成了协议
the "big three" thought
they had reached agreement.

18
00:02:59,095 --> 00:03:03,724
雅尔塔(会议)真的是这三个人之间关系的顶点
Yalta was really the high point of
the relationship between the three men.

19
00:03:03,808 --> 00:03:07,519
胜利即将来临,德国人正在撤退,
Victory was in the air,
the Germans were in retreat,

20
00:03:07,604 --> 00:03:15,068
所以除了未来的军事事务外,还有许多问题要谈判
and so there was a good deal more talk,
in addition to military matters,of the future.

21
00:03:15,195 --> 00:03:21,000
(埃夫里尔·哈里曼 美国驻俄国大使 1945)
波兰再次成为最麻烦的核心问题
Poland again became the most troublesome point.

22
00:03:21,000 --> 00:03:27,623
而且很有趣 罗斯福和丘吉尔都
觉得他们和斯大林达成了协议
And it's interesting that both Roosevelt and
Churchill felt they had an agreement with Stalin.

23
00:03:28,750 --> 00:03:32,300
波兰的问题...就和所有东欧国家的一样...
The problem with Poland...
as with all Eastern Europe...

24
00:03:32,300 --> 00:03:37,049
是西方领导人想在那里建立
一个自由选举出来的政府
was that the Western leaders wanted
a freely elected government there.

25
00:03:37,133 --> 00:03:41,553
苏联人想要(在那里)建立一个对俄国友好的政府
The Soviets wanted a government friendly to Russia.

26
00:03:41,638 --> 00:03:45,849
他们以为西方理解并接受这一点
They thought the West
understood and accepted this.

27
00:03:46,684 --> 00:03:51,855
从他们的角度来看,波兰将不会
成为西方的一个前哨站...
Poland, from their point of view, was
not going to be an outpost of the West...

28
00:03:51,940 --> 00:03:55,192
(阿尔杰·希斯 美国国务院 1945)
任何一个巴尔干国家也不会
nor any of the Balkan countries.

29
00:03:55,276 --> 00:04:01,500
他们认为他们已和丘吉尔先生
就势力范围达成了诸多协议...
They thought they'd had various agreements
about spheres of influence with Mr Churchill...

30
00:04:01,500 --> 00:04:05,600
如果他们把希腊大致上留在英国手里的话,
if they left Greece pretty much in British hands,

31
00:04:05,600 --> 00:04:13,085
他们就能在匈牙利,罗马尼亚,保加利亚,
特别是在波兰 获得相应的一定影响力
they could have certain proportional influences
in Hungary, Romania, Bulgaria,particularly Poland.

32
00:04:15,880 --> 00:04:28,308
我在雅尔塔的印象是俄国人以为
我们已基本上接受了那个要求
My impression at Yalta was that the Russians
thought we had in substance accepted that demand.

33
00:04:29,352 --> 00:04:33,438
在雅尔塔会议后,罗斯福只活了两个月
After Yalta,Roosevelt lived for only two months.

34
00:04:33,800 --> 00:04:42,239
即使在那时候,他和丘吉尔已被俄国人对在那里达成
了什么共识而作的解释 所唤醒(而不再抱有幻想)
Even by then, he and Churchill had become
disillusioned by the interpretations the
Russians were putting on what was agreed there.

35
00:04:42,323 --> 00:04:48,000
斯大林和罗斯福双方之间
措辞非常,非常严厉的电报往来
The very, very tough exchange of telegrams
on both sides between Stalin and Roosevelt

36
00:04:48,000 --> 00:04:53,500
已使事情变得非常清楚 (那就是)在他死之前,
罗斯福知道斯大林会打破他作出的协议
makes it very plain that Roosevelt, before he died,
knew that Stalin was breaking his agreements.

37
00:04:53,500 --> 00:05:02,000
(安东尼·艾登 亚芬伯爵 英国外交大臣 1945 战后任首相)
我认为事情之所以变糟 是因为军事上的进展加强了俄国的地位
I think it went sour because the military
developments strengthened Russia's hands

38
00:05:02,135 --> 00:05:10,267
在雅尔塔 俄国人还觉得有必要考虑西方的意见,
and that where the Russians had felt it necessary
to be considerate of Western opinion at Yalta,

39
00:05:10,351 --> 00:05:16,189
几个月后他们觉得没这种必要了
因为对他们来说 战争进展得如此顺利,
a few months later they didn't feel any such necessity
because the war was going so well for them,

40
00:05:16,316 --> 00:05:20,610
所以他们对他们作出的一些约定撂到一边(不予考虑)
and therefore they swept aside
some of the engagements they'd got into.

41
00:05:20,695 --> 00:05:24,323
那当然特别适用于关于波兰(的承诺)
That certainly applied
particularly about Poland.

42
00:05:25,800 --> 00:05:28,910
罗斯福已被俄国人视为一个朋友
Roosevelt had been seen
as a friend by the Russians.

43
00:05:28,995 --> 00:05:31,500
他的继任者,哈里杜鲁门,
是一个行动莫测的人物...
His successor, Harry Truman,
was an unknown quantity...

44
00:05:31,500 --> 00:05:34,541
对他们(俄国人)和对他自己的顾问来说都是
both to them and to his own advisers.

45
00:05:35,168 --> 00:05:40,800
当罗斯福一死,我就离开 回去去见杜鲁门先生
I left, as soon as Roosevelt died,
to go back to see Mr Truman.

46
00:05:40,800 --> 00:05:46,000
我想要确信 杜鲁门总统明白我们(与苏联)的关系的立场,
I wanted to be sure that President Truman
understood the position of our relationships,

47
00:05:46,000 --> 00:05:56,480
因为对与我们勇敢的盟友存在的这种温暖的关系
已有如此多的极度乐观的情绪甚嚣尘上
because there had been so much euphoria in the air about
the warm relationships that existed with our gallant allies.

48
00:05:56,564 --> 00:06:02,819
我在罗斯福逝世的一周后回了家
And I got home within a week
of the time Roosevelt had died.

49
00:06:02,904 --> 00:06:06,948
我发现,通过我与杜鲁门总统第一次接触的经历,
I found, my first experience
with President Truman,

50
00:06:07,033 --> 00:06:09,284
我发现他是个热切的阅读者
I found he was an avid reader.

51
00:06:09,369 --> 00:06:12,371
我发现他已读了所有的电报
I found he'd read all the telegrams

52
00:06:12,455 --> 00:06:17,501
并从那些信息中明白了我们将遇到的困难
and understood from those messages
the difficulties we were going to have.

53
00:06:18,878 --> 00:06:26,802
他们的外长,莫洛托夫,在4月23日到达华盛顿
给了杜鲁门一个机会来证明,就如他所说的,
The arrival of their foreign minister, Molotov,in Washington
on April 23 gave Truman a chance to prove, as he put it,

54
00:06:26,886 --> 00:06:29,262
他将"勇敢地面对俄国人"
that he would "stand up to the Russians".

55
00:06:29,347 --> 00:06:32,800
正当他的到达点燃了(解决)
棘手的波兰问题的希望,
Even as his arrival raised hopes
on the thorny Polish question,

56
00:06:32,800 --> 00:06:39,272
全世界得知 俄国刚刚已和波兰的华沙政府
签订了一个为期20年的友好协定
the world learned that Russia had just signed a 20-year
pact of friendship with Poland's Warsaw government.

57
00:06:39,700 --> 00:06:42,700
这个波兰政府没有亲西方的成员
This Polish government
had no pro-Western members.

58
00:06:42,700 --> 00:06:43,985
他们全都是亲苏分子
They were all pro-Soviet.

59
00:06:44,070 --> 00:06:47,000
西方领导人生气而又苦恼
The Western leaders were angry and upset.

60
00:06:47,800 --> 00:06:52,869
莫洛托夫见到了杜鲁门和他的国务卿,
斯特蒂纽斯...阿尔杰·希斯的老板
Molotov saw Truman and his secretary of
state, Stettinius... Alger Hiss's boss.

61
00:06:52,954 --> 00:06:55,205
到那个时候...
By that time...

62
00:06:56,707 --> 00:07:02,129
波兰局势已经,用一个温和的词来形容,"成形"了
the Polish situation had, to
use a gentle word, crystallised.

63
00:07:02,255 --> 00:07:05,048
俄国人在前进
The Russians were moving forward.

64
00:07:05,133 --> 00:07:15,976
他们似乎对英国人和美国人希望
(扶植)的那种临时政府毫不理会
They seemed to be paying no attention to the kind of provisional
government that the British and Americans had hoped for.

65
00:07:18,271 --> 00:07:25,277
所以抗议...愤怒的抗议...
到了俄国人那儿也不了了之
Therefore protests... angry protests...
were going to the Russians about that.

66
00:07:25,361 --> 00:07:30,824
于是杜鲁门决定摊牌,而他对此很有天赋
And Truman decided to have a showdown,
at which he was gifted.

67
00:07:31,742 --> 00:07:37,747
在那场合下,如同你从如今的历史书中知道的一样,
On that occasion, as you know from
what is now part of the history books,

68
00:07:39,750 --> 00:07:44,212
他指控莫洛托夫,事实上,违反了协议,
he accused Molotov, in effect,
of violation of the agreements,

69
00:07:44,297 --> 00:07:45,000
那么早(就那么说)
as early as that.

70
00:07:45,000 --> 00:07:53,472
在一场尚未取胜的战争中 对一个重要的盟友
这么摊牌是一件很奇怪的事情...但他这么做了
This was a strange thing to do in
the midst of a war, by no means yet won,
with an important ally... but he did it.

71
00:07:54,599 --> 00:07:58,101
而会谈以莫洛托夫这么说而告终:
And it ended by Molotov saying:

72
00:07:58,186 --> 00:08:00,700
"在我的一生中 我从未被人用这种口气说过话",
"I've never been talked to like this in my life",

73
00:08:00,700 --> 00:08:04,649
而杜鲁门说: "嗯,如果你遵守你的协议
你就不会被人用那种口气说话了..."
and Truman saying: "Well, if you keep your
agreements and you won't be talked to like that..."

74
00:08:04,734 --> 00:08:07,152
就象一个学校老师
just like a schoolteacher.

75
00:08:07,236 --> 00:08:12,616
当时在场的斯特蒂纽斯,第二天早晨
告诉我...他仍然有点被震惊...
Stettinius, who'd been present, told me
the next morning... he was still shaken...

76
00:08:12,700 --> 00:08:15,619
他说, "我觉得整场会议开不下去了"
he said, "I thought
the whole conference was off."

77
00:08:15,703 --> 00:08:19,831
那是一次不成功的对话
Well, that was an unfortunate conversation.

78
00:08:20,875 --> 00:08:25,462
那是杜鲁门进行的首次外交会谈,
lt was one of the first diplomatic
conversations that Truman had,

79
00:08:25,546 --> 00:08:32,385
而我只能说 对杜鲁门来说
这不是一个外交声明
and I can only say that it was not
a diplomatic statement on Truman's part.

80
00:08:32,470 --> 00:08:36,848
他用了彻底的,实在的密苏里语言,
而那是非常明确的
He used good, solid Missouri language,
which was very definite,

81
00:08:36,974 --> 00:08:40,310
而莫洛托夫曾用那种方式和其他人交谈,
and Molotov had talked
to other people that way,

82
00:08:40,394 --> 00:08:43,355
但还没人用那种方式和他谈话
but had had no one
talk to him that way.

83
00:08:43,439 --> 00:08:45,273
所以他非常生气,
So he was very much upset,

84
00:08:45,358 --> 00:08:50,070
而我得出了这种印象 那就是
他认为这是一个新声音,
and I gained the impression that
he thought this was a new voice,

85
00:08:50,154 --> 00:08:54,783
不再是罗斯福,而是一个更具攻击性的总统
not Roosevelt any more,
but a more aggressive president.

86
00:08:55,660 --> 00:08:57,702
当他在两周前宣誓就职时,
When he was sworn in two weeks earlier,

87
00:08:57,787 --> 00:09:00,500
杜鲁门说他将继续罗斯福的政策
Truman had said he would continue
Roosevelt's policies.

88
00:09:00,500 --> 00:09:05,752
但他对莫洛托夫突然的严厉态度
现在令战争部长亨利·史汀生感到担心
But his sudden harshness with Molotov now
worried the secretary of war,Henry Stimson.

89
00:09:05,836 --> 00:09:07,629
在这次对峙的第二天,
The day after the confrontation,

90
00:09:07,713 --> 00:09:13,093
史汀生告诉了杜鲁门一些他认为
能改变与俄国打交道方式的事情
Stimson told Truman about something he thought
could transform America's dealings with Russia.

91
00:09:13,177 --> 00:09:16,388
史汀生的传记作者,麦克乔治·本迪
Stimson's biographer, McGeorge Bundy.

92
00:09:16,472 --> 00:09:19,300
史汀生写信给杜鲁门,
Stimson wrote to Truman,

93
00:09:19,300 --> 00:09:26,982
"我觉得我应该尽可能快地和你谈论
一桩高度机密的事情 是非常重要的"
"l think it is very important that I should have a talk
with you as soon as possible on a highly secret matter."

94
00:09:27,066 --> 00:09:30,235
"在你就职后不久 我就向你提起过它,
"l mentioned it to you
shortly after you took office,

95
00:09:30,319 --> 00:09:34,990
但考虑到你承受的压力 此后就没有强行告诉你此事"
but have not urged it since on account
of the pressure you've been under."

96
00:09:35,074 --> 00:09:39,244
"然而,它对我们现行的外交关系有如此重大的意义
"lt, however, has such a bearing
on our present foreign relations

97
00:09:39,328 --> 00:09:44,416
而且对我在这个领域的所有想法
都有如此重要的影响,
and has such an important effect
upon all my thinking in this field,

98
00:09:44,500 --> 00:09:49,838
以至于我认为你应该不再耽搁地知道此事"
that I think you ought to know about it
without much further delay."

99
00:09:49,922 --> 00:09:59,000
第二天,4月25日,史汀生向杜鲁门解释说
他对外交政策的看法...史汀生的看法...
The next day, April 25, Stimson explained to Truman
that his view of foreign policy...Stimson's...

100
00:09:59,000 --> 00:10:10,900
是被即将来临的原子能的前景,以及与俄国分享
原子秘密所可能交换获得的条件 所支配的,
was dominated by the imminent prospect of atomic
power,and the terms which might be got from Russia
in exchange for sharing atomic secrets.

101
00:10:11,736 --> 00:10:18,116
这是杜鲁门第一次得知原子弹
的具体消息和它的外交潜力
lt was Truman's first detailed news of the
atomic bomb and its diplomatic potential.

102
00:10:18,200 --> 00:10:22,203
他请求史汀生担任一个决定其军事用途的委员会的主席
He asked Stimson to head a committee
to decide its military use.

103
00:10:23,623 --> 00:10:28,293
到这时,在极其秘密的状态下,
两种原子弹已被开发了出来,
By this time, in great secrecy, two
kinds of atomic bomb had been developed,

104
00:10:28,377 --> 00:10:34,341
一种基于铀,另一种则基于一种人造元素,钚
one based on uranium, the other
on a man-made element, plutonium.

105
00:10:35,051 --> 00:10:39,179
铀弹不需要测试...但只有一枚
The uranium bomb did not need testing...
but there was only one.

106
00:10:39,263 --> 00:10:42,349
钚弹...更容易大批制造...
The plutonium bombs...
easier to produce in quantity...

107
00:10:42,433 --> 00:10:44,517
在使用前将必须被试验
would have to be tested before use.

108
00:10:44,602 --> 00:10:47,145
第一枚到7月将准备完毕
The first would be ready by July.

109
00:10:47,855 --> 00:10:52,100
美国空军的一支特别部队已开始练习相关战术
A special unit of the American Air Force
had begun practising the tactics involved

110
00:10:52,100 --> 00:10:58,323
即高度精确地投下一枚非常大的炸弹,然后尽快地逃离
in dropping one very large bomb, with great
accuracy,then getting away as fast as possible.

111
00:10:58,407 --> 00:11:02,000
它的指挥官是保罗·蒂贝茨上校
lts commander was Colonel Paul Tibbets.

112
00:11:02,000 --> 00:11:10,800
到这时为止,任何误差不超过500或
600英尺的轰炸都被认为是准确的轰炸
Up to this point,anything in the way of an error in
bombing up to 500 or 600 feet was considered good bombing.

113
00:11:10,800 --> 00:11:14,964
所以我告诉他们:"如果你们从25,000
英尺高度投弹 误差有100英尺,
So I told them then: "lf you have
a 100-foot error from 25,000 feet,

114
00:11:15,049 --> 00:11:16,883
你只是投在了分界线上"
you're just a borderline case."

115
00:11:16,967 --> 00:11:19,260
"我要求误差小于100英尺"
"l want it less than 100."

116
00:11:19,345 --> 00:11:22,347
我立即被告知,"你做不了这个"
l was told immediately,
"You can't do this."

117
00:11:22,431 --> 00:11:26,518
所以我说, "我不知道为什么不行"
他们说, "从来没人这么做过"
And so I said, "l don't know why not."
They said, "Nobody's ever done it."

118
00:11:26,602 --> 00:11:28,700
但我说, "那不是为什么完成不了它的理由"
but I said, "That's no reason
why it can't be done."

119
00:11:28,700 --> 00:11:31,500
我说,"他们告诉我,熟能生巧"
I said, "Practice, they
tell me, makes perfect."

120
00:11:31,500 --> 00:11:34,859
所以我说,"我们将(不断)训练 你们要
练到你们能做到(投进100英尺)为止"
So I said,"We'll practise and
you'll practise until you do it."

121
00:11:44,203 --> 00:11:47,200
从他们在马里亚纳群岛的前沿基地,
From their forward bases
in the Mariana lslands,

122
00:11:47,200 --> 00:11:53,294
美国B-29轰炸机已经在用
更常规的武器攻击日本的城市
American B-29 bombers were already attacking
Japan's cities with more conventional weapons.

123
00:11:53,379 --> 00:11:56,589
起初,结果很不理想
To begin with, the results were poor.

124
00:12:00,000 --> 00:12:05,473
柯蒂斯·李梅将军发展出一种新战术:
低空燃烧弹轰炸
General Curtis LeMay developed a new
tactic: low-level incendiary raids.

125
00:12:06,434 --> 00:12:13,606
用空中摄影 你能勾勒出一个大致的区域,但不很精确
With aerial photography you could outline
a general area,but not much precisely.

126
00:12:14,358 --> 00:12:17,000
你不可能避免造成附带伤害,
You just couldn't avoid
doing collateral damage,

127
00:12:17,000 --> 00:12:27,203
我确信我们烧掉了许多与战争工业毫无关系的日本建筑物
and I'm sure we burned down a lot of Japanese buildings
that had nothing to do with the war industry at all.

128
00:12:28,080 --> 00:12:33,585
当然 这是战争中一件不可能避免的悲哀的事情
This, of course, is one of the sad
things of war that can't be helped.

129
00:12:33,919 --> 00:12:39,799
1945年3月9日,2,000吨燃烧弹被投在了东京,
On March 9, 1945, 2,000 tons
of incendiaries were dropped on Tokyo,

130
00:12:39,884 --> 00:12:42,844
摧毁了这座城市16平方英里的面积
destroying 16 square miles of the city.

131
00:12:44,096 --> 00:12:46,431
80,000个平民死亡...
80,000 civilians died...

132
00:12:46,515 --> 00:12:50,935
那晚在东京死的人 比在(德军)
闪击轰炸中整个英国死的人还多
more that night in Tokyo than
in the whole of England in the Blitz.

133
00:12:51,020 --> 00:12:54,439
大多数人在火风暴中窒息而死
Most suffocated in the firestorm.

134
00:12:54,565 --> 00:12:56,483
李梅现在一座接一座城市地攻击
LeMay now attacked city after city.

135
00:12:56,567 --> 00:13:00,153
看来似乎只用B-29就可能打败日本
lt looked as if the B-29s alone
might defeat Japan.

136
00:13:00,237 --> 00:13:03,948
直到阿诺德将军(美国陆军航空队司令)
问了这么个直接的问题
(LeMay) It wasn't until General
Arnold asked the direct question

137
00:13:04,033 --> 00:13:05,742
"这场战争将持续多久?",
"How long will the war last?",

138
00:13:05,826 --> 00:13:08,953
我们才坐下 并对这个问题作了一些思考,
and then we sat down
and did some thinking about it,

139
00:13:09,038 --> 00:13:17,587
而结论指出 在9月1日左右我们就不会再有目标可炸了,
and it indicated that we would be pretty
much out of targets around 1 September,

140
00:13:17,671 --> 00:13:19,672
而随着失去目标,
and with the targets gone,

141
00:13:19,757 --> 00:13:24,594
我们看不出到那时候还有什么仗可打
we couldn't see much of any war
going on at the time.

142
00:13:32,311 --> 00:13:34,500
到1945年春天
By the spring of 1945

143
00:13:34,500 --> 00:13:39,692
面对美国的空中和海上力量 日本很无助
Japan was helpless in the face
of American air and naval power.

144
00:13:40,820 --> 00:13:45,031
日本大多数商船队和海军已被击沉
Most of the Japanese merchant fleet
and navy had been sunk.

145
00:13:46,075 --> 00:13:51,329
一场有效的封锁已切断了日本
与她在海外的军队的联系,
An effective blockade had cut off Japan
from her overseas army,

146
00:13:51,413 --> 00:13:54,207
令她绝大部分的空军因为缺乏燃料而无法升空,
grounded most of her air force for lack of fuel,

147
00:13:54,291 --> 00:13:57,627
并使她的人民受到了饥饿的威胁
and threatened her population
with starvation.

148
00:13:57,711 --> 00:14:03,800
美国战斗轰炸机(在日本上空)随意漫游,
支援那毁灭性的火攻空袭
American fighter-bombers roamed at will,
backing up the devastating fire raids.

149
00:14:05,594 --> 00:14:11,766
许多日本政治家意识到 他们的国家支撑不了多长时间了
Many Japanese politicians realised that
their country could not hold out much longer.

150
00:14:16,105 --> 00:14:24,195
4月1日:美国部队在日本土地...
距离本土仅350英里的冲绳岛上登陆
April 1: American troops land on Japanese soil...
Okinawa, only 350 miles from the mainland.

151
00:14:24,280 --> 00:14:26,865
他们面临凶猛的抵抗
They face fierce resistance.

152
00:14:28,409 --> 00:14:36,100
但随着战役开始,日本不断增长的主和派促成了
一个由铃木(贯太郎)海军大将领导的新内阁的任命
But as the battle starts,the growing peace party in Japan
secure the appointment of a new cabinet,led by Admiral Suzuki.

153
00:14:36,200 --> 00:14:46,000
(加瀬俊一 外交部官员 1945 战后日本首任驻联合国大使)
当铃木内阁成立时,军事形势糟透了,
When the Suzuki cabinet came into existence,
the military situation was deplorable,

154
00:14:46,000 --> 00:14:54,350
此外,我们国家的经济困境也十分明显
and, moreover, the economic plight
of our nation was quite apparent.

155
00:14:54,435 --> 00:14:56,769
军事当局...
The military command...

156
00:14:58,105 --> 00:15:05,695
试图挤出,可以这么说,国家的最后一滴血,
tried to squeeze the last drop,
so to speak, of the nation's blood,

157
00:15:05,779 --> 00:15:10,450
就为了更努力地继续打这场无用的战争,
in order to prosecute harder
the useless war,

158
00:15:10,534 --> 00:15:19,584
但对任何明白事理的人来说 事情
变得很明显 我们已经山穷水尽了
but it became evident to any sensible man
that we were at the end of our tether.

159
00:15:24,381 --> 00:15:28,343
(木户幸一候爵 日本最后一任"内大臣" 甲级战犯)
军队中的年轻军官,那些极端主义分子,
The younger officers in
the army, the extremists,

160
00:15:28,427 --> 00:15:33,765
觉得我们应该战斗到底,直到每个人都被杀死
thought that we should fight to the bitter
end, until every man had been killed.

161
00:15:34,516 --> 00:15:39,103
但陆军大臣,阿南(惟几)将军,不同意
But the war minister,General Anami,didn't agree.

162
00:15:39,188 --> 00:15:43,691
他认为如果我们继续战斗到美国人入侵本土
He thought that if we fought on
until the Americans invaded the mainland

163
00:15:43,776 --> 00:15:47,320
然后在海滩上狠狠打击他们的军队一次,
and then hit their forces hard
on the beaches once,

164
00:15:47,404 --> 00:15:52,825
那么我们就能通过谈判达成
对日本更有利的和平条件
we could then negotiate peace
on terms more favourable to Japan.

165
00:15:56,413 --> 00:15:58,831
但杜鲁门不会谈判
But Truman would not negotiate.

166
00:15:58,958 --> 00:16:02,085
他在5月,德国战败后这样告诉国会
He told Congress so in May,
after Germany's defeat.

167
00:16:02,169 --> 00:16:08,883
我们的要求一直是,也仍然是,无条件投降
Our demand has been,and it remains,
unconditional surrender.

168
00:16:11,762 --> 00:16:22,981
我要整个世界都知道 这个方针
必须也将会保持不变和不受阻碍
I want the entire world to know that this direction
must and will remain unchanged and unhampered.

169
00:16:26,610 --> 00:16:29,529
杜鲁门现在面临两个主要问题:
Truman now faced two major problems:

170
00:16:29,613 --> 00:16:31,800
如何在欧洲应付俄国人,
how to deal with the Russians in Europe,

171
00:16:31,800 --> 00:16:36,661
以及是否要求他们兑现他们加入对日战争的承诺
and whether to ask them to fulfil their
pledge to join the war against Japan.

172
00:16:36,745 --> 00:16:41,624
在德国,俄国的和西方的部队互相敬酒,
ln Germany, Russian and Western
troops exchanged toasts,

173
00:16:41,709 --> 00:16:44,900
但丘吉尔已经在给杜鲁门发送紧急信息
but already Churchill was sending
urgent messages to Truman

174
00:16:44,900 --> 00:16:48,400
警告说 一张铁幕正在欧洲被俄国拉下
warning that an iron curtain was being
drawn down in Europe by Russia.

175
00:16:48,400 --> 00:16:54,429
"三巨头"必须赶在,如他所说,
"民主的军队消失"之前 迅速会面
The "big three" must meet quickly before,
as he put it,"the armies of democracy melted".

176
00:16:55,848 --> 00:16:59,434
而杜鲁门有了一个新国务卿,詹姆斯·伯恩斯
And Truman had a new secretary
of state, James Byrnes.

177
00:16:59,518 --> 00:17:07,483
伯恩斯想要 在俄国人能加入(对日战争)并在亚洲
也给西方国家造成麻烦前 结束对日本的战争
Byrnes wanted to finish the war against Japan
before the Russians could join in and cause
problems for the West in Asia, too.

178
00:17:07,568 --> 00:17:22,665
在我的脑海中一直存在这个想法 那就是我们应该
在俄国人介入前结束这场战争 这一点是很重要的
lt was ever-present in my mind that it was
important that we should have an end to
the war before the Russians came in.

179
00:17:22,750 --> 00:17:28,000
但史汀生想要在原子弹准备好之前
避免在欧洲或远东作出草率的决定
But Stimson wanted to avoid hasty decisions in
Europe or the Far East before the bomb was ready.

180
00:17:28,000 --> 00:17:33,634
他写信给杜鲁门:"在任何这种纠缠交织的问题中,
He wrote to Truman: "Over any
such tangled weave of problems,

181
00:17:33,719 --> 00:17:37,200
原子秘密将是占首位的"
the atomic secret would be dominant."

182
00:17:37,200 --> 00:17:47,065
"在外交中进行这么大赌注的赌博 不把你的
王牌捏在你的手里 似乎是件很糟糕的事情"
"It seems a terrible thing to gamble
with such big stakes in diplomacy without
having your master card in your hand."

183
00:17:48,192 --> 00:17:50,526
杜鲁门让史汀生放心...
Truman reassured Stimson...

184
00:17:50,611 --> 00:17:58,201
"三巨头"会议被故意推迟到
7月15日"以给我们更多的时间"
the "big three" meeting was postponed until
July 15 on purpose "to give us more time".

185
00:17:58,285 --> 00:18:01,800
哈里·霍普金斯,得到斯大林信任的罗斯福的密友,
Harry Hopkins, Roosevelt's
close friend whom Stalin trusted,

186
00:18:01,800 --> 00:18:07,293
在5月底被派往莫斯科 给波兰问题暂时降降温
was sent to Moscow at the end of May to take
the heat temporarily out of the Polish issue.

187
00:18:07,377 --> 00:18:10,838
他回报说 他已经平息了事情
He reported back that he
had smoothed things over.

188
00:18:10,923 --> 00:18:16,803
斯大林也已自发地保证 在8月8日加入对日战争
Stalin had also promised...unprompted...
to join the war against Japan on August 8.

189
00:18:16,887 --> 00:18:22,934
当霍普金斯还在莫斯科,史汀生的委员会得出了结论
While Hopkins was in Moscow,Stimson's
committee reached its decision.

190
00:18:23,018 --> 00:18:32,026
这个研究原子弹的委员会一致建议
它应该尽快地,没有警告地,
The committee studying the atomic bomb unanimously recommended
that it be used as soon as possible, without warning,

191
00:18:32,111 --> 00:18:36,030
被用来对付一个主要的日本军事机构
against a major Japanese military establishment.

192
00:18:36,115 --> 00:18:38,908
只有这样,史汀生认为,
Only this, Stimson thought,

193
00:18:38,992 --> 00:18:44,000
才能造成一种可能导致日本投降的心理冲击
would provide the psychological blow
which might induce Japan to surrender.

194
00:18:44,000 --> 00:18:53,400
尽管他同意杜鲁门的一些顾问(的这个建议) 即日本人
应被下达一个明确表明他们能保留天皇的最后通牒,
Although he agreed with some of Truman's advisers
that the Japanese should be given an ultimatum
which made it clear they could keep the emperor,

195
00:18:53,400 --> 00:19:00,263
但在原子弹至少被试验之前
他反对宣布这个(最后通牒)
he opposed announcing this until
after the bomb had at least been tested.

196
00:19:00,347 --> 00:19:02,223
但在战后他写道,
But after the war he wrote,

197
00:19:02,307 --> 00:19:06,400
"根据最终的投降来看,的确有可能,
"lt is possible,in the light
of the final surrender,

198
00:19:06,400 --> 00:19:17,572
一次更明确和更早的表达美国愿意保留
天皇的阐述 可能使得战争更早结束"
that a clearer and earlier exposition of American
willingness to retain the emperor could have
produced an earlier ending of the war."

199
00:19:18,907 --> 00:19:21,784
6月18日:华盛顿
June 18: Washington.

200
00:19:21,869 --> 00:19:27,123
在他取得欧洲的胜利后 艾森豪威尔
将军受到了英雄般的欢迎
General Eisenhower is given a hero's
welcome after his victory in Europe.

201
00:19:27,207 --> 00:19:29,200
那一天在白宫,
In the White House that day,

202
00:19:29,200 --> 00:19:34,964
杜鲁门被要求批准他的参谋长
联席会议在11月入侵日本的计划
Truman is asked to approve his joint chiefs
of staff's plans to invade Japan in November.

203
00:19:35,632 --> 00:19:38,301
我们收起我们的文件 并开始出门,
We gathered up our papers
and started to go out,

204
00:19:38,385 --> 00:19:40,636
(约翰·麦克洛伊 助理战争部长 1945 战后任世界银行行长)
杜鲁门先生注意到了我 并说:
and Mr Truman spotted me and said:

205
00:19:40,721 --> 00:19:46,142
"麦克洛伊先生,不表达他自己的观点 谁也不能
离开这个房间...其他人都已经(说了他们的意见)"
"Mr McCloy, nobody gets out of this room
without expressing himself...everybody else has."

206
00:19:46,226 --> 00:19:50,479
"你觉得我有任何其他选择吗?"
"Do you think I have any other alternative?"

207
00:19:50,564 --> 00:19:55,193
我朝史汀生上校看过去...
他总喜欢被人叫作上校...
l looked over at Colonel Stimson...
he always liked to be called Colonel...

208
00:19:55,277 --> 00:20:00,114
他在一次大战中是一个团的上校(团长),
而不喜欢被人叫作"部长"...
he'd been colonel of a regiment
in World War I,rather than Secretary...

209
00:20:00,199 --> 00:20:04,076
我朝史汀生看过去 他点点头,他说,"说吧"
I looked over at Stimson
and he nodded, he said, "Go ahead."

210
00:20:04,161 --> 00:20:07,830
所以我开始说了,我说我认为
So I started in, and I said that I thought that

211
00:20:07,915 --> 00:20:17,215
如果我们这时候不开始考虑这场战争的政治结束 而只
考虑军事结束的话 我们应该去把我们的脑子检查检查
we ought to have our heads examined if we didn't,
at this point,begin to think in terms of a political
culmination of the war rather than a military one.

212
00:20:17,591 --> 00:20:21,500
我说我会给他们一些条件...
And I said I'd give them some terms...

213
00:20:21,500 --> 00:20:25,389
我会传递一条信息给他们,
我会把(投降)条件具体讲清楚
I'd send a message over to them,I'd spell
out the terms just about what they were.

214
00:20:25,474 --> 00:20:29,810
我记得杜鲁门先生说,"嗯,那
你的条件是什么? 你会怎么做?"
And I remember Mr.Truman said, "Well,
what are your terms? What would you do?"

215
00:20:29,895 --> 00:20:34,899
当时我对投降条件的实际用词还没什么准备,
l hadn't quite prepared for the actual dictation
of the surrender terms at that point,

216
00:20:34,983 --> 00:20:37,068
但我开始说起来 我说,
but I started in and I said,

217
00:20:37,152 --> 00:20:39,987
"首先,我会说你们能保留天皇,
"ln the first place,
I'd say you can have the mikado,

218
00:20:40,072 --> 00:20:42,448
但他得是个立宪君主...
but he's got to be
a constitutional monarch...

219
00:20:42,532 --> 00:20:45,660
你们必须得有一个代议制政府"
you've got to have a representative
form of government."

220
00:20:45,744 --> 00:20:51,040
"你们能够购买,但不能控制,外国原材料
"You can have access to, but not
control over, foreign raw materials

221
00:20:51,124 --> 00:20:54,794
那样你们能有一个可行的经济..."
我尽我所能解释清楚
so you can have a viable economy..."
l spelled it out as best I could.

222
00:20:54,878 --> 00:20:57,713
"除此之外,我还会说,
我们已拥有了一种新武器,
"And I'd say,besides that,
we've got a new force,

223
00:20:57,798 --> 00:21:06,055
而它是以一种能使战争形态发生
革命性变化的新能源的形式存在的,
and it's in the form of a new type of
energy that will revolutionise warfare,

224
00:21:06,139 --> 00:21:10,726
其毁灭性超乎一切预料"
我说我会提到原子弹
destructive beyond any contemplation."
l said I'd mention the bomb.

225
00:21:10,811 --> 00:21:15,815
嗯,提到原子弹,即使在那个很晚的日子,
在那个经过精心挑选的团体里,就像是...
Well, mentioning the bomb, even at that late
date, in that select group,it was like...

226
00:21:15,899 --> 00:21:20,820
他们全都被震惊了 因为它是
如此一个被严格保守的秘密
it was like they were all shocked because
it was such a closely guarded secret.

227
00:21:20,904 --> 00:21:24,500
这就好比在耶鲁大学提到"骷髅会"
(耶鲁一个秘密精英社团)一样,
It was comparable to mentioning
Skull and Bones at Yale,

228
00:21:24,500 --> 00:21:26,500
而这是你不应该做的
which you're not supposed to do.

229
00:21:27,452 --> 00:21:31,914
但杜鲁门先生说, "这是我正试图去触及的那种事...
But Mr Truman said, "This is the sort
of thing I was trying to reach for...

230
00:21:31,999 --> 00:21:33,791
把所有那些条件都讲清楚"
get that all spelled out."

231
00:21:33,875 --> 00:21:37,878
那时史汀生插话了 并表示支持我的立场,
At that point Stimson did come in
and joined in support of my position,

232
00:21:38,005 --> 00:21:43,384
不过后来伯恩斯先生,他当时是国务卿,他并不在场,
but then later on Mr Byrnes,who was then
secretary of state,who was not present,

233
00:21:43,468 --> 00:21:47,700
否决了让他们保留天皇的想法
vetoed the idea of offering them the mikado.

234
00:21:47,700 --> 00:21:59,650
你只能够猜测 如果我们用我所指出的这种形式把包括
保留天皇在内的那些信息传递给日本人,可能会发生些什么
One can only speculate as to what would have
happened if we had put the message to the Japanese
in the form that I indicated,including the mikado.

235
00:21:59,735 --> 00:22:04,488
我总有这种感觉,鉴于我们拥有的一些信息
l always had the feeling, in view of
some of the information we've had since

236
00:22:04,573 --> 00:22:11,662
由于就日本军方一些真正的急性子表现出的倾向而言,
of the tendency on the part of some
of the real military hotheads in Japan,

237
00:22:11,747 --> 00:22:14,498
考虑到这或许是最好的出路,
to think that this was perhaps
the best way out,

238
00:22:14,624 --> 00:22:19,128
我们可能能够避免扔原子弹
that we might have been able
to avoid the dropping of the bomb.

239
00:22:19,713 --> 00:22:24,050
到这时,冲绳战役几乎结束了
By this time,the battle
for Okinawa is almost over.

240
00:22:24,134 --> 00:22:26,260
12,000个美国人阵亡
12,000 Americans had died,

241
00:22:26,345 --> 00:22:30,931
这是入侵本土可能付出的代价的一次血腥预示
a bloody foretaste of what invasion
of the mainland might cost.

242
00:22:31,850 --> 00:22:35,102
对日本人来说,教训还要更严酷
For the Japanese,
the lesson was harsher still.

243
00:22:37,731 --> 00:22:39,940
10万人死亡
100,000 died,

244
00:22:40,025 --> 00:22:45,946
而且,在这场战争中第一次,他们的士兵成千地投降
and, for the first time in the war,
their soldiers surrendered in thousands.

245
00:22:49,534 --> 00:22:52,745
当最后的抵抗在6月22日结束,
As the last resistance ended,on June 22,

246
00:22:52,829 --> 00:22:57,583
新的日本内阁第一次开始采取寻求和平的行动
the new Japanese cabinet made
its first move towards peace.

247
00:22:57,800 --> 00:23:07,000
最终,我们不得不与我们的军事对手...
也就是美国和英国进行谈判
Ultimately,we had to conduct negotiations with our military
opponents...that is to say, America and Britain...

248
00:23:07,000 --> 00:23:20,189
但最高指挥部明确地拒绝考虑
任何开始与敌方进行对话的想法
but the high command refused categorically to entertain
any idea of starting conversations with the enemy powers.

249
00:23:20,273 --> 00:23:27,613
在敌方阵营中剩下的唯一(可对话)的强权就是苏联,
The only great power left out
of the enemy camp was the Soviet Union,

250
00:23:27,697 --> 00:23:35,913
因为名义上(日苏之间)仍然还存在一份中立条约,
because of the fact that nominally
there existed still the neutrality pact,

251
00:23:36,039 --> 00:23:43,879
所以这是唯一一扇打开着的
可以进行和平努力的窗户...
and so this was the only window open
for peace endeavours...

252
00:23:43,964 --> 00:23:47,675
而这扇窗面向北方
and this window looked towards the north.

253
00:23:47,759 --> 00:23:52,888
所以我们与军方领导人据理力争,
And so we argued it out
with the military command,

254
00:23:52,973 --> 00:23:58,000
军方领导人最终,勉强地,
and the military command finally, reluctantly,

255
00:23:58,000 --> 00:24:12,741
答应了我们的请求 那就是为了到达最终的目的地,
也就是华盛顿和伦敦,我们(应该)开始与苏联谈判
acceded to our request that we start negotiations
with the Soviet Union in order to arrive at the
final destination,which was Washington and London.

256
00:24:13,200 --> 00:24:19,000
但斯大林会见的是中国外交部长
(王世杰),而不是日本外交部长
But it was the Chinese foreign minister, not
the Japanese,that Stalin had been meeting.

257
00:24:19,000 --> 00:24:25,921
一支庞大的日军仍然占领着
中国的部分地区,包括满洲
A huge Japanese army still occupied
parts of China, including Manchuria.

258
00:24:26,047 --> 00:24:32,428
俄国人和中国人正在磋商
斯大林向那支日军进攻的条件
The Russians and Chinese were negotiating terms
under which Stalin would attack that army.

259
00:24:32,512 --> 00:24:36,682
当杜鲁门在7月7日出发去欧洲
会见斯大林和丘吉尔时,
When Truman sailed to Europe on July 7
to meet Stalin and Churchill,

260
00:24:36,766 --> 00:24:41,645
通过被截获的消息,他知道了
日本想要结束这场战争,
he knew, through intercepted messages,
that Japan wanted an end to the war,

261
00:24:41,730 --> 00:24:45,357
但不是无条件投降
but not unconditional surrender.

262
00:24:45,442 --> 00:24:49,778
杜鲁门和伯恩斯现在有几个可选择的选项...
Truman and Byrnes now had
several options open to them...

263
00:24:49,863 --> 00:24:52,490
他们可以修改投降条件,
they could modify the surrender terms,

264
00:24:52,574 --> 00:24:55,868
他们可以鼓励俄国人入侵满洲,
they could encourage the Russians
to invade Manchuria,

265
00:24:55,952 --> 00:25:01,332
他们可以展示原子弹,他们可以入侵日本本土
they could demonstrate the atomic bomb,
they could invade Japan itself.

266
00:25:04,000 --> 00:25:08,714
但杜鲁门决定 他将没有警告地在日本投下原子弹
But Truman decided that he would drop
atomic bombs on Japan without warning.

267
00:25:08,798 --> 00:25:14,595
仅此一点,他希望,就能在俄国人
参战前 迅速结束太平洋战争
This alone, he hoped,would end the Pacific
war quickly,before the Russians joined in.

268
00:25:14,679 --> 00:25:18,800
而这能极大地加强美国在欧洲讨价还价的能力
And it would immensely strengthen
American bargaining power in Europe.

269
00:25:18,800 --> 00:25:25,272
当杜鲁门在7月15日抵达"三巨头"会议时
已经作出(投放原子弹的)决定
The decision had already been taken when Truman
arrived for the "big three" meeting on July 15.

270
00:25:28,000 --> 00:25:33,400
第二天早晨,就在黎明前,
在新墨西哥州遥远的沙漠里的一个地点,
The next morning, just before dawn,
at a remote desert site in New Mexico,

271
00:25:33,400 --> 00:25:40,955
罗伯特·奥本海默("曼哈顿计划"负责人)和
设计并建造了原子弹的团队目睹了第一次原子爆炸
Robert Oppenheimer and the team that had designed and
built the bomb witnessed the first atomic explosion.

272
00:25:41,039 --> 00:25:46,585
我记得印度教的经文,
"薄伽梵歌"中有这么几句话:
I remembered the line from the
Hindu scripture,the Bhagavad-Gita:

273
00:25:46,670 --> 00:25:56,804
(罗伯特·奥本海默 全国广播公司录像)
毗湿奴(印度教主神)试图说服(阿朱那)王子
他应该恪守职责(参加战斗),
Vishnu is trying to persuade the prince
that he should do his duty,

274
00:25:56,888 --> 00:26:03,310
为了给王子留下深刻印象
他展现了他有多条手臂的神身
and to impress him
takes on his multi-armed form

275
00:26:03,395 --> 00:26:09,525
并说, "现在我变成了死神,世界的毁灭者"
and says, "Now I am become death,
the destroyer of worlds."

276
00:26:11,736 --> 00:26:14,989
我想我们都以某种方式想到了那句话
l suppose we all thought that,
one way or another.

277
00:26:15,490 --> 00:26:21,954
这枚钚弹爆炸的威力相当于20,000吨TNT炸药
The plutonium bomb exploded
with a force of 20,000 tons of TNT.

278
00:26:23,373 --> 00:26:27,876
位于爆炸点的沙漠被变成了玻璃
The desert at the point of the explosion
was turned into glass.

279
00:26:28,500 --> 00:26:32,339
到1945年7月 日本的经济正在崩溃
By July 1945 Japan's economy was crumbling

280
00:26:32,424 --> 00:26:36,093
而她的城市面对B-29轰炸机的空袭毫无防御能力
and her cities were defenceless
against the B-29 raids.

281
00:26:36,177 --> 00:26:38,804
尽管她的陆军依然几乎完整,
Although her army
remained virtually intact,

282
00:26:38,888 --> 00:26:41,890
但日本的战争工业被粉碎了
Japan's war industries were smashed.

283
00:26:45,520 --> 00:26:48,230
100万平民已死亡
One million civilians had died.

284
00:26:49,774 --> 00:26:52,526
还有数百万人无家可归
Millions more were homeless.

285
00:26:52,611 --> 00:26:57,740
美国空军对日本离投降只有几周时间毫不怀疑
The US Air Force had no doubts
that surrender was only weeks away.

286
00:26:58,533 --> 00:27:00,900
对他们来说 这是一个绝望的局面
(LeMay) It was a hopeless situation for 'em.

287
00:27:00,900 --> 00:27:07,708
B-29轰炸机正在随意飞临日本上空
而他们对此无计可施
And the B-29s were flying over Japan at will
and they couldn't do anything about it.

288
00:27:08,835 --> 00:27:14,048
我们能够在不遭到什么抵抗
的情况下随意摧毁任何目标
We could destroy any target at will
without much opposition.

289
00:27:14,132 --> 00:27:17,843
(柯蒂斯·李梅将军)
所以在他们所面对的这个无望的局势下,
So with this hopeless situation
they were facing,

290
00:27:17,927 --> 00:27:21,600
他们没有了继续战斗下去的意志
they just didn't have the will
to continue.

291
00:27:21,600 --> 00:27:29,396
事实上,在他们实际投降前的大约三个月里
他们一直在试图停止这场战争
In the matter of fact, they'd been trying to get out of
the war for about three months before they actually did.

292
00:27:29,481 --> 00:27:33,275
他们已请求俄国人当中间人,
They'd asked the Russians
to be an intermediary,

293
00:27:33,401 --> 00:27:36,904
试图通过谈判结束战争,
to try to negotiate them out of the war,

294
00:27:36,988 --> 00:27:43,160
而俄国人一直在拖延 直到他们把欧洲战事结束掉
and the Russians had been stalling till
they'd got the European war finished

295
00:27:43,244 --> 00:27:49,833
那样他们能在太平洋战争结束前参战
so they could get into the
Pacific war before it ended.

296
00:27:52,000 --> 00:28:01,220
在斯大林和莫洛托夫离开莫斯科去参加十年之内的最后一次
"三巨头"会议前,他们拒绝接见日本大使(佐藤尚武)
Stalin and Molotov refused to see the
Japanese ambassador before they left Moscow
for the last "big three" meeting for ten years.

297
00:28:02,138 --> 00:28:05,641
(美国)战争部长史汀生也在波茨坦
Also at Potsdam was Secretary of War Stimson.

298
00:28:05,725 --> 00:28:09,728
他把原子弹试验的具体消息
传达给了杜鲁门和伯恩斯...
He passed on detailed news of
the atomic test to Truman and Byrnes...

299
00:28:09,813 --> 00:28:13,190
而他在他的日记中特别提到,
他们都非常高兴
who, he noted in his diary,
were immensely pleased.

300
00:28:13,274 --> 00:28:16,402
"总统为这个消息而感到极其振奋
"The president was tremendously pepped up by it

301
00:28:16,486 --> 00:28:20,030
(麦克乔治·本迪 史汀生的传记作者)
当我看到他时 他再三地对我谈到此事"
and spoke to me of it again
and again when I saw him."

302
00:28:20,156 --> 00:28:24,785
"他说它给了他一种完全自信的新感觉"
"He said it gave him an entirely
new feeling of confidence."

303
00:28:24,869 --> 00:28:28,872
而当第二天 史汀生告诉
丘吉尔这次成功的试验时,
And when Stimson told Churchill
about the successful test the next day,

304
00:28:28,957 --> 00:28:37,381
丘吉尔说他现在明白了杜鲁门为什么
会这么兴奋了 而他也有同样的感觉
Churchill said he now understood how this pepping-up
of Truman had taken place and that he felt the same way.

305
00:28:37,465 --> 00:28:42,200
英国人和美国人现在就 是否告诉
俄国人关于原子弹的事进行了争论
The British and Americans now debated
whether to tell the Russians about the bomb.

306
00:28:42,200 --> 00:28:50,519
一些人主张说 它作为一个外交杠杆的完整作用
只有在它被投在了日本以后 才会变得明显
Some argued that its full weight as a diplomatic lever
would only become evident after it had been dropped on Japan.

307
00:28:50,603 --> 00:28:54,106
在一次会议后,就当我们休会时,
After one of our meetings,
just as we adjourned,

308
00:28:54,190 --> 00:28:57,700
(安东尼·艾登 亚芬伯爵 英国外交大臣 1945)
杜鲁门和他的翻译走向斯大林
Truman went up with his interpreter to Stalin

309
00:28:57,700 --> 00:29:06,952
并简要地告诉他 我们已经发现了什么
以及原子弹的效果会是怎么样的
and told him briefly what we had discovered
and what the effect of the atomic bomb would be.

310
00:29:07,078 --> 00:29:12,400
而斯大林所做的只是点了点头
并十分简略地说了声"谢谢",
And all Stalin did was to nod his head
and say "Thank you" quite curtly,

311
00:29:12,400 --> 00:29:15,794
他的表情没有任何变化
他对此事的反应仅此而已
and his expression changed in no way
and that was all there was to it.

312
00:29:18,506 --> 00:29:20,900
这非常令人失望
(McCloy) It was a tremendous disappointment.

313
00:29:20,900 --> 00:29:25,971
我们本以为他会对此事大吃一惊
但他就象它不存在一样没有理会
We thought he would be flabbergasted at this thing
but he just passed it off as if inexistent.

314
00:29:26,055 --> 00:29:27,200
他是否知道它(的存在),
Whether he knew about it,

315
00:29:27,200 --> 00:29:33,562
他是否不想对此显示出任何强烈的情感,
whether he didn't want to show
any great emotion in regard to it,

316
00:29:33,646 --> 00:29:35,314
我不得而知
l don't know.

317
00:29:35,398 --> 00:29:39,318
(约翰·麦克洛伊 助理战争部长 1945)
我所知道的是他大踏步地
All I know is that he took it
very much in his stride

318
00:29:39,402 --> 00:29:45,699
而且多少令我们失望地,继续
讨论议事日程上的下一件事
and, somewhat to our disappointment,
went on to the next item in the agenda.

319
00:29:45,784 --> 00:29:53,040
而这令史汀生十分沮丧 因为他本来以为,
And this rather dismayed Stimson
because he thought that,

320
00:29:53,124 --> 00:29:54,600
一旦披露了此事,
once having disclosed this,

321
00:29:54,600 --> 00:30:01,131
苏联方面会立即强烈要求坐下并与我们商谈
there would be immediately a great rush on the
part of the Soviets to sit down and talk to us

322
00:30:01,216 --> 00:30:06,845
关于这东西(原子弹)未来可能的影响
以及它未来会如何使用
about the future implications of this thing
and what the future uses of it would be.

323
00:30:06,930 --> 00:30:09,223
但他根本没有得到任何鼓励
But he got no encouragement at all.

324
00:30:10,517 --> 00:30:17,400
史汀生的战术失败了..."三巨头"在
原子武器的全部威力被揭示之前就会面了
Stimson's tactics had misfired...the
"big three" had met before the full power
of the atomic weapon was revealed.

325
00:30:17,400 --> 00:30:25,739
史汀生还害怕 从此以后,国务卿伯恩斯会利用
原子弹来试图对俄国人直接施压要求让步
And Stimson feared that from now on, Secretary
of State Byrnes would use the bomb to try to
lever direct concessions from the Russians.

326
00:30:26,449 --> 00:30:38,293
我倒觉得伯恩斯先生有一些这种想法 那就是
这东西在外交交易中将会是一种支撑点
l rather think that Mr Byrnes had something
of the thought that this would be a sort of
point of leverage in diplomatic exchanges,

327
00:30:38,378 --> 00:30:42,130
尽管我认为史汀生先生...或史汀生上校...
whereas I think Mr Stimson...
or Colonel Stimson...

328
00:30:42,215 --> 00:30:46,301
对原子弹的使用有不同的看法
had a different idea
of the use of the bomb.

329
00:30:46,386 --> 00:30:51,682
他写信给总统 敦促就核问题
(与苏联)进行直接谈判,
(Bundy) He wrote to the president to urge
direct negotiation on the nuclear issue,

330
00:30:51,766 --> 00:31:05,821
并争辩说 与俄国的关系"或许可能被我们处理
与俄国解决原子弹问题的方式 而不可挽回地恶化"
and argued that relations with Russia "may perhaps
be irretrievably embittered by the way in which
we approach the solution of the bomb with Russia."

331
00:31:05,905 --> 00:31:09,116
"因为如果我们现在没有找他们商量
"For if we fail to approach them now

332
00:31:09,242 --> 00:31:15,622
而只是在把这件武器炫耀地挂在我们
的屁股上之后 才同他们谈判的话,
and merely negotiate with them having this
weapon rather ostentatiously on our hip,

333
00:31:15,707 --> 00:31:23,463
他们对我们的目的和动机的怀疑和不信任将加深"
their suspicions and their distrust of
our purposes and motives will increase."

334
00:31:23,548 --> 00:31:27,000
随着原子武器现在几乎已准备好投入使用,
With the atomic weapons
now almost ready for use,

335
00:31:27,000 --> 00:31:30,888
对杜鲁门来说 是时候向日本人
发出一个最终的最后通牒了...
it was time for Truman to issue
a final ultimatum to the Japanese...

336
00:31:30,972 --> 00:31:34,099
史汀生的建议再次被拒绝了
and again Stimson's advice was rejected.

337
00:31:34,183 --> 00:31:42,482
杜鲁门和伯恩斯决定通过给日本人一个保留
他们天皇的机会 来不改变无条件投降的原则
Truman and Byrnes decided not to modify the
unconditional-surrender formula by offering
the Japanese the chance to keep their emperor.

338
00:31:42,942 --> 00:31:47,500
我的希望是 日本人民现在将意识到
My hope is that the people
of Japan will now realise

339
00:31:47,500 --> 00:31:57,956
进一步抵抗现在联合起来实施法律
和正义的各国军队 将是绝对徒劳的
that further resistance to the forces of
the nations now united in the enforcement
of law and justice will be absolutely futile.

340
00:31:58,082 --> 00:32:07,925
对日本人来说 仍然有时间...但只剩极少时间...
来拯救他们自己 免于威胁着他们的毁灭
There is still time...but little time...
for the Japanese to save themselves
from the destruction which threatens them.

341
00:32:08,384 --> 00:32:15,557
(詹姆斯·伯恩斯 全国广播公司录像)
它的真正目的就是向他们保证 他们将拥有决定权,
The very purpose of it was to assure
them that they would have the decision,

342
00:32:15,642 --> 00:32:27,611
与此同时 不在我们之间开始
一场关于天皇地位的争论
and at the same time not to start a controversy
among ourselves about the position of the emperor.

343
00:32:28,655 --> 00:32:32,324
当"波茨坦公告"被发表时,
When the Potsdam proclamation was issued,

344
00:32:33,701 --> 00:32:41,333
(加瀬俊一 外交部官员 1945)
东乡茂德外相和我一起通宵工作了许多个夜晚,
Foreign Minister Togo and I worked
together many sleepless nights,

345
00:32:41,417 --> 00:32:46,713
我把这份公告拿给外相看
and I took this proclamation
to the attention of the foreign minister

346
00:32:46,798 --> 00:32:50,759
并解释了它的实质
and explained the substance of it.

347
00:32:50,843 --> 00:32:55,472
东乡立即说这份公告是可以接受的,
Togo at once said this was acceptable,

348
00:32:55,556 --> 00:33:01,311
他立即去皇宫 并请求觐见(天皇)
and he immediately went to the palace
and asked for an audience.

349
00:33:01,396 --> 00:33:11,405
(裕仁)天皇赞成东乡的意见 那就是应该
立即接受这个公告 并结束这场战争
The emperor approved Togo's judgement that this
should be accepted and the war be terminated at once.

350
00:33:11,489 --> 00:33:19,663
东乡外相在内阁会议上说 我们能在
天皇地位不受影响的情况下结束这场战争
Foreign Minister Togo said in the cabinet meeting that
we can stop the war without the question of the emperor.

351
00:33:19,747 --> 00:33:22,416
我们能够无疑地保留天皇
We can keep the emperor all right.

352
00:33:22,500 --> 00:33:24,918
但那时候我们...
But at that time we...

353
00:33:25,003 --> 00:33:26,100
日本政府...
the Japanese government...

354
00:33:26,100 --> 00:33:36,596
(迫水久常 内阁书记官长,即战后的官方长官 1945)
向俄国人请求了一些...中间人...调解...斡旋...斡旋,
asked some... intermediate...mediation...
mediation...mediation to the Russians,

355
00:33:36,681 --> 00:33:39,641
所以许多内阁大臣说,
so many cabinet ministers said,

356
00:33:39,726 --> 00:33:43,478
"这样吧, 让我们再观察局势一段时间"
"Well, let us see the situation for a while."

357
00:33:43,563 --> 00:33:49,234
铃木(贯太郎)首相宣布
日本将对该最后通牒不予理会
Prime Minister Suzuki announced
that Japan would ignore the ultimatum.

358
00:33:49,318 --> 00:33:52,446
也许俄国会拯救日本的名誉
Perhaps Russia would save Japan's honour.

359
00:33:52,530 --> 00:33:56,658
毕竟,斯大林没有签署波茨坦公告...
After all, the Potsdam Declaration
had not been signed by Stalin...

360
00:33:56,743 --> 00:33:58,618
他可能仍在调停
he might still mediate.

361
00:33:58,703 --> 00:34:02,372
斯大林告诉了杜鲁门日本人的提议
Stalin told Truman about the Japanese approaches.

362
00:34:02,457 --> 00:34:07,002
杜鲁门对此全都知道...日本的密码已被破解
Truman knew all about them...
the Japanese codes had been broken.

363
00:34:07,086 --> 00:34:14,000
两个领导人同意不理睬这些和平试探
杜鲁门在8月3日启程回国
Both leaders agreed to ignore the peace feelers
and Truman sailed home on August 3.

364
00:34:14,000 --> 00:34:21,975
由于得不到日本人的反应,他授权空军
在他们一准备好时 就(在日本)投下原子弹
With no response from the Japanese,he authorised the Air
Force to drop the atom bomb as soon as they were ready.

365
00:34:22,060 --> 00:34:27,000
日本外相东乡(茂德),在绝望中发电报
给他在莫斯科的大使(佐藤尚武):
The Japanese foreign minister, Togo, in
desperation cabled his ambassador in Moscow:

366
00:34:27,100 --> 00:34:34,362
"由于相对于目前的事态 损失一天
时间都可能造成一千年的遗憾,
"Since the loss of one day relative to this present
matter may result in a thousand years of regret,

367
00:34:34,447 --> 00:34:38,200
我请求你立即与莫洛托夫会谈"
it is requested you immediately
have a talk with Molotov."

368
00:34:38,910 --> 00:34:42,370
但莫洛托夫仍然不肯会见日本大使
But Molotov would still not meet the ambassador.

369
00:34:42,955 --> 00:34:44,372
(1945年)8月6日,
On August 6,

370
00:34:44,457 --> 00:34:48,085
就在俄国人说他们会进攻日本人的两天之前,
two days before the Russians had said
they would attack the Japanese,

371
00:34:48,169 --> 00:34:52,700
"艾诺拉·盖伊"号出发
开始它1,500英里的征程
the Enola Gay set off
on its 1500-mile journey.

372
00:34:52,700 --> 00:35:01,848
(保罗·蒂贝茨 广岛轰炸飞行员)
我注意到 当我(把飞机)滑行出来的时候
在飞机停靠的区域有几百个人在那里,
I noticed as I taxied out that there were several hundred
people that were in the area the aircraft were parked in,

373
00:35:01,933 --> 00:35:05,268
有一些在控制塔前面...
there were some in front of the control tower...

374
00:35:05,353 --> 00:35:11,691
人们出来看 正在发生什么事
却并不真的知道他们正在看什么,
People were out there to see what was going on
without really knowing what they were looking at,

375
00:35:11,776 --> 00:35:13,527
但这是一件与众不同的事情,
but it was something different,

376
00:35:13,611 --> 00:35:17,489
所以他们想要成为此事的一部分,
想要看看什么事情正在发生
so they wanted to be part of it,
wanted to see what was taking place.

377
00:35:17,573 --> 00:35:20,400
有一枚炸弹 有一架飞机将运载那枚炸弹,
There's one bomb and one aeroplane
was going to carry that bomb,

378
00:35:20,400 --> 00:35:25,705
而那是飞行大队指挥官蒂贝茨上校,
和他的全体机组人员
and that's the group commander,then
Colonel Tibbets, with his full crew.

379
00:35:25,832 --> 00:35:31,419
(查尔斯·斯威尼 广岛和长崎轰炸飞行员)
我的机组被指派 在轰炸期间在他的右翼编队飞行,
My crew was assigned to fly in formation
on his right wing during the bombing,

380
00:35:31,504 --> 00:35:32,600
因为两个原因...
for a couple of reasons...

381
00:35:32,600 --> 00:35:34,000
有人必须飞到那里
somebody had to fly there

382
00:35:34,000 --> 00:35:38,135
而且我被他安排飞第二次任务,
and I was scheduled by him
to fly the second mission,

383
00:35:38,219 --> 00:35:41,638
如果有第二次任务的话
if there were to be a second mission.

384
00:35:41,722 --> 00:35:47,477
我们还会有第三架飞机飞在左翼
它将就在轰炸前掉头回去...
We were to have a third aircraft flying on the left
wing who would drop back just before the bombing...

385
00:35:47,562 --> 00:35:49,271
它装备有摄像机
he was equipped with cameras.

386
00:35:49,355 --> 00:35:54,151
我们将在看不到彼此的情况下飞头三个小时
We were to fly unseen by each other
for the first three hours

387
00:35:54,235 --> 00:36:01,116
然后早晨6点在硫磺岛上空8,000英尺会合
and to make rendezvous at 8,000 feet
over lwo Jima at 6 a.m.

388
00:36:01,200 --> 00:36:03,493
计划就是这样
This was the plan.

389
00:36:03,578 --> 00:36:07,956
我们十分成功地会合,然后我们有
大约一个半小时或稍长一段时间
We made the rendezvous quite successfully,then we
had about an hour and a half or a little over that

390
00:36:08,040 --> 00:36:13,044
在太平洋上空的一个美丽夜晚
以一种懒散的队形一起飞行,
to go along in a lazy formation on
a beautiful night out over the Pacific,

391
00:36:13,129 --> 00:36:16,464
有月亮 还有看起来象粉雾一样的云团...
with moons and cloud puffs
that looked like powder puffs...

392
00:36:16,549 --> 00:36:20,093
那是个安静,祥和的夜晚,相信我
it was a quiet, peaceful
evening, believe me.

393
00:36:20,178 --> 00:36:24,306
没什么事发生...在飞机里有一些交谈,
Nothing much went on...
a little bit of talk in the aeroplane,

394
00:36:24,390 --> 00:36:27,225
但在一次任务中那总是很正常...
but that's always normal on a mission...

395
00:36:27,310 --> 00:36:29,000
但然后你会有一段平静期,
but then you'd get a quiet period,

396
00:36:29,000 --> 00:36:34,566
而当我们在飞的时候 我猜每个人
都在做梦或什么的,因为很安静
and we were...while we were going along,I guess everybody
was dreaming or something, because it was quiet.

397
00:36:36,611 --> 00:36:39,800
在8月6日早晨8:15分,
At 8:15 on the morning of August 6,

398
00:36:39,800 --> 00:36:46,745
在广岛上空32,000英尺飞行的
"艾诺拉·盖伊"号,投放了它的炸弹
the Enola Gay, flying at 32,000 feet,
released its bomb over Hiroshima.

399
00:36:46,829 --> 00:36:49,998
就在负荷离开飞机的一瞬间
(Tibbets) As soon as the weight
had left the aeroplane

400
00:36:50,082 --> 00:36:52,334
我立即进入这种急转弯,
I immediately went into this steep turn,

401
00:36:52,460 --> 00:36:55,212
在我后面的斯维尼和马魁特也同样急转,
as did Sweeney and Marquart behind me,

402
00:36:55,296 --> 00:37:00,884
我们试图在我们自己和冲击点之间拉开距离
and we tried then to place distance
between ourselves and the point of impact.

403
00:37:01,510 --> 00:37:07,600
就这次轰炸而言,那枚原子弹从它离开
飞机到它爆炸 有53秒钟时间
In this particular case,that bomb had 53 seconds
from the time it left the aeroplane until it exploded.

404
00:37:07,600 --> 00:37:12,000
那就是从轰炸高度坠落所花的时间...53秒
That's how long it took to fall
from the bombing altitude...53 seconds.

405
00:37:12,000 --> 00:37:16,566
而这当然给了我们足够的时间转弯
And this gave us adequate time,
of course, to make the turn.

406
00:37:16,651 --> 00:37:21,821
我们刚转好弯并以水平飞行姿态飞离
Now, we had just made the turn
and rolled out in level flight

407
00:37:21,948 --> 00:37:28,036
这时似乎有人抓住了我的飞机
并在非常剧烈地摇晃它,
when it seemed like somebody had grabbed hold
of my aeroplane and gave it a real hard shaking,

408
00:37:28,120 --> 00:37:31,998
因为这是上来的冲击波
because this was the shock wave
that had come up.

409
00:37:38,589 --> 00:37:44,761
这是我很高兴能感觉到的东西
因为它给了我一个解脱的瞬间...
This was something that I was glad to feel
because it gave me a moment of relief...

410
00:37:44,845 --> 00:37:49,266
毕竟,在致力于(投掷)那枚炸弹一年多时间后,
after all, having worked on that bomb
for well over a year,you know,

411
00:37:49,350 --> 00:37:52,227
在我驾驶那架飞机转弯的那53秒时间里
that 53 seconds of time while
I'm turning the aeroplane

412
00:37:52,311 --> 00:37:55,480
我一直想知道"它到底会不会爆炸?"
I'm wondering "Is it or
is it not going to work?"

413
00:37:55,564 --> 00:38:01,111
当然,击中我们的冲击波表明它已经奏效了
And, of course, the shock wave
hitting us was indication it had worked.

414
00:38:01,195 --> 00:38:04,990
所以我感觉已经取得了成功
Therefore I felt that success
had been achieved.

415
00:38:05,074 --> 00:38:12,000
当原子弹爆炸时 我看到一记
黄色的闪光 我被埋没在黑暗之中
When the bomb came l saw a yellowish flash
and I was buried in the darkness.

416
00:38:12,081 --> 00:38:17,711
我的家,一幢有八间房间的两层楼木制建筑,
The two-storeyed wooden building that
was my house, with eight rooms in it,

417
00:38:17,795 --> 00:38:21,464
被炸坍成碎片 并把我盖起来
was blown down to pieces
and covered me up.

418
00:38:24,427 --> 00:38:26,845
当我恢复意识时
When I regained consciousness

419
00:38:26,929 --> 00:38:30,056
我周围的一切都一片漆黑
everything was pitch dark all around me.

420
00:38:30,182 --> 00:38:33,643
我试图站起来,但我的腿断了
I tried to stand up,
but my leg was broken.

421
00:38:33,728 --> 00:38:39,107
我试图说话 我发现我的六颗牙齿已经掉了
I tried to speak and I found
that six of my teeth had been broken.

422
00:38:39,233 --> 00:38:43,069
然后我意识到我的脸被烧伤了
我的背也被烧伤了
Then I realised that my face was burnt
and my back was burnt.

423
00:38:43,154 --> 00:38:48,491
有一条伤口从一边肩膀一直划到腰
There was a slash right across
from one shoulder down to the waist.

424
00:38:48,576 --> 00:38:52,412
我爬到了河岸 而当我到了那里
I crawled to the river bank
and when I got there

425
00:38:52,496 --> 00:38:56,916
我看到数百具尸体沿河漂流而下
I saw hundreds of bodies
come floating down the river.

426
00:38:57,001 --> 00:39:03,882
到那时我才震惊地意识到 整个广岛都被炸了
And it was then that I realised with
a shock that all Hiroshima had been hit.

427
00:39:08,054 --> 00:39:11,181
我们扔下那枚炸弹的那天 天气很晴朗...
The day was clear when we dropped that bomb...

428
00:39:11,265 --> 00:39:14,601
那是个晴朗的阳光照耀的日子
能见度不受限制...
it was a clear sunshiny day
and visibility was unrestricted...

429
00:39:14,685 --> 00:39:16,936
所以当我们转了一圈飞回来,
so as we came back around,

430
00:39:17,021 --> 00:39:20,815
再次面对广岛的方向,
again facing the direction of Hiroshima,

431
00:39:20,900 --> 00:39:24,235
我们看到这股蘑菇云升起来
we saw this cloud coming up.

432
00:39:24,320 --> 00:39:28,907
到这时候这云...现在(离投下原子弹)
有两分钟了...这云已上升到我们的高度
The cloud by this time... now two minutes
...the cloud was up at our altitude.

433
00:39:28,991 --> 00:39:31,400
我们当时在33,000英尺高度,
We were at 33,000 feet at this time,

434
00:39:31,400 --> 00:39:32,410
而这蘑菇云就在那里
and the cloud was up there

435
00:39:32,495 --> 00:39:36,539
并在以一种沸腾的方式继续向上升...
and continuing to go right on
up in a boiling fashion...

436
00:39:36,624 --> 00:39:39,084
它在翻滚和沸腾着
it was rolling and boiling.

437
00:39:39,168 --> 00:39:46,174
地面上什么都没有 只有一种黑色的,沸腾的...
The surface was nothing but...
a black, boiling...

438
00:39:46,258 --> 00:39:48,600
我能说的唯一东西,就象是一桶沥青...
the only thing I can say,
like a barrel of tar...

439
00:39:48,600 --> 00:39:51,054
很可能是我能给出的最好描述
probably the best description I can give.

440
00:39:51,138 --> 00:39:53,000
这正是它看下去的样子
This was exactly the way it looked down there.

441
00:39:53,000 --> 00:39:55,000
在之前曾是一座城市的地方...
Where before there had been a city...

442
00:39:55,000 --> 00:39:59,600
与众不同的房屋,建筑和你能从
我们的高度看到的一切东西...
distinctive houses, buildings and everything
that you could see from our altitude...

443
00:39:59,600 --> 00:40:05,652
现在你除了下面这黑色的,
沸腾的废墟外 什么也看不见
now you couldn't see anything except
this black, boiling debris down below.

444
00:40:05,778 --> 00:40:09,447
我们尽可能快地拍了照
We took pictures as rapidly as we could.

445
00:40:09,532 --> 00:40:13,701
在那之后 我的当务之急
就是"是离开这里的时候了"
My immediate concern after that
was "lt's time to get out of here."

446
00:40:13,786 --> 00:40:20,667
我遇到了排着漫长,无休止行列的逃难者
I encountered long, ceaseless lines of escapees.

447
00:40:20,751 --> 00:40:26,756
他们所有人的身上都什么衣服也没有
All of them had no clothes
whatsoever on their bodies.

448
00:40:28,342 --> 00:40:40,061
而他们的脸上,手臂和胸口上的皮肤
正在剥落和下垂着...
And the skin from their faces, arms and
breast peeling off and hanging loose...

449
00:40:40,146 --> 00:40:45,191
但没有说任何话
and yet without any expression.

450
00:40:45,276 --> 00:40:49,028
他们在一片深深的寂静中逃亡
ln deep silence they are escaping.

451
00:40:49,113 --> 00:40:54,117
我还以为这是一队行进着的鬼魂
l thought it was a procession of ghosts.

452
00:40:55,119 --> 00:41:01,249
话传了回去 基本上意思
就是 轰炸条件很清晰,
The words went back basically to the effect
that the bombing conditions were clear,

453
00:41:01,333 --> 00:41:05,753
目标已被击中,结果比预期的还要好,
the target had been hit, the results
were better than had been anticipated,

454
00:41:05,838 --> 00:41:08,000
而那信息被传了回去
and that message was sent on back.

455
00:41:08,000 --> 00:41:14,679
在那之后 有一个让每个人说上个
几分钟 让他们一吐为快的建议
From there on it was just a proposition
of letting everybody talk for a few
minutes and get it out of their system.

456
00:41:14,763 --> 00:41:16,723
兴奋过去了...
The excitement was over...

457
00:41:16,807 --> 00:41:20,400
很快它就成了一次很普通的返航飞行
pretty soon it became a rather
routine flight back home.

458
00:41:20,400 --> 00:41:26,691
事实上,它足够普通到 我让
鲍勃·刘易斯和自动驾驶仪飞那架飞机
As a matter of fact,it was routine enough that
I let Bob Lewis and the autopilot fly that aeroplane

459
00:41:26,775 --> 00:41:30,570
并到后面去 睡了一会觉
这也是我30个小时里第一次睡觉...
and went back and got some sleep
for about the first time in 30 hours...

460
00:41:30,654 --> 00:41:32,530
而我已经准备好了
and I was ready for it.

461
00:41:32,615 --> 00:41:34,000
一场漫长而持久的战争,
A long drawn-out war,

462
00:41:34,000 --> 00:41:45,000
你开始从疲劳,穷困,疾病和诸如
此类的副作用那里 得到伤亡人员
you begin to get casualties from the side-effects of
exhaustion, privation,disease and things of that sort.

463
00:41:45,085 --> 00:41:54,177
所以尽可能快地将战争结束是
相关的每个人的一种道德责任
So getting it over with as quick as possible
is a moral responsibility of everyone concerned.

464
00:41:54,261 --> 00:41:58,056
我们的确知道战争结束了
Now, it's true that we knew
the war was over

465
00:41:58,140 --> 00:42:01,184
如果我们只要再等一段时间 它就会结束,
and if we just waited a little while
it would be over,

466
00:42:01,268 --> 00:42:04,020
因为日本人正在谈判,
because the Japanese were negotiating,

467
00:42:04,104 --> 00:42:07,106
我们知道这点 因为我们已破解了他们的密码
and we knew this because
we'd broken their code

468
00:42:07,191 --> 00:42:09,859
我们正在收听他们的通讯
and we were listening
to their communications.

469
00:42:09,944 --> 00:42:16,783
但我相信杜鲁门总统使用它
是作出了一个正确的决定...
But I believe that President Truman
made the proper decision to use it...

470
00:42:17,952 --> 00:42:21,246
因为它很可能加速了谈判进程
because it probably hastened
the negotiations

471
00:42:21,330 --> 00:42:24,624
而即使我们只节省了一天,
and even if we just saved one day,

472
00:42:24,708 --> 00:42:27,377
对我来说这也是值得的,
你必须这么做
to me it would be worthwhile,
you have to do it.

473
00:42:28,420 --> 00:42:31,798
我认为这是绝对没有必要的,
l thought it was absolutely unnecessary,

474
00:42:31,882 --> 00:42:36,427
因为到这枚炸弹被投在了广岛的时候
because by the time
the bomb was dropped on Hiroshima

475
00:42:36,512 --> 00:42:42,433
我们正在和苏联政府进行谈判,
we were conducting negotiations
with the Soviet government,

476
00:42:42,518 --> 00:42:45,895
期待早日结束战争
looking towards an early end of hostilities.

477
00:42:45,980 --> 00:42:50,650
我们已完全精疲力尽了
And we were completely exhausted.

478
00:42:50,734 --> 00:42:57,949
而海军和陆军也慢慢地变得...
And the navy and army, too,
were slowly becoming...

479
00:43:00,828 --> 00:43:06,874
更愿意接受和平的想法
more amenable to the idea of peace.

480
00:43:06,959 --> 00:43:10,628
这是一个谈起来令人震惊的话题,
lt's an appalling subject to talk about,

481
00:43:10,713 --> 00:43:18,636
(埃夫里尔·哈里曼 美国驻俄国大使 1945)
美国有意和无意地,对它的使用有大量的负罪情结
and the United States has,consciously and unconsciously,
a great deal of guilt complex about its use.

482
00:43:18,721 --> 00:43:24,976
但杜鲁门是根据军事必要性
来作出这个决定的
But Truman made the decision on
the basis of the military necessities.

483
00:43:25,060 --> 00:43:32,150
而我认为一个公正的分析,特别
是来自于日本人自己(的分析)...
And I think an impartial analysis,
particularly from the Japanese themselves...

484
00:43:32,234 --> 00:43:36,112
更多的证据正在出现
他们本会狂热地继续战斗下去
more evidence is coming out that
they would've fought on fanatically.

485
00:43:36,196 --> 00:43:42,118
你知道,尽管已经投降,他们的确
在一些岛上继续狂热地战斗下去
You know, they did fight on fanatically in
some of the islands,in spite of the surrender.

486
00:43:42,202 --> 00:43:50,209
而天皇本不会有勇气来终止战争,
或得到支持来终止战争
And the emperor wouldn't have had the courage to
have called it off,or the support to call it off.

487
00:43:50,753 --> 00:43:56,007
当我听说原子弹的事 我是如此惊讶,
When I heard about the atomic bomb
l was so astonished,

488
00:43:56,925 --> 00:44:01,929
我坦白地说道,"美国人很残酷"
and I frankly said,
"The American people are brutal."

489
00:44:04,767 --> 00:44:10,021
我不知道美国人是否真的文明开化了
l wondered if the American people
were really civilised.

490
00:44:10,147 --> 00:44:21,282
但与此同时 我觉得这可能成为
日本结束战争的一个关键
But at the same time I thought this may
become a key for Japan to end the war.

491
00:44:24,662 --> 00:44:32,627
日本政府要再用两天才意识到
原子弹是什么以及它干了什么
lt was two days before the Japanese government realised
what the atomic bomb was and what it had done.

492
00:44:32,711 --> 00:44:36,214
70,000人已死在了广岛
70,000 had died in Hiroshima.

493
00:44:36,298 --> 00:44:39,133
另外70,000人受伤
Another 70,000 were injured.

494
00:44:39,218 --> 00:44:44,555
这座城市97%的建筑物被摧毁或严重损坏
97% of the city's buildings
were destroyed or severely damaged.

495
00:44:44,640 --> 00:44:51,729
杜鲁门总统听说这个消息时,
称之为"历史上最伟大的事件"
President Truman, on hearing the news,
called it "the greatest thing in history".

496
00:44:51,814 --> 00:44:59,028
日本内阁中的议和派希望这枚
原子弹能说服主战派接受投降
The peace group in the Japanese cabinet hoped that the
bomb might persuade the war faction to accept surrender.

497
00:44:59,113 --> 00:45:02,198
当内阁在8月9日上午开会时,
As the cabinet met
on the morning of August 9,

498
00:45:02,282 --> 00:45:05,368
它收到了进一步受到打击的消息
it received further shattering news.

499
00:45:06,328 --> 00:45:11,666
前一天晚上,在莫斯科,莫洛托夫
终于接见了日本大使(佐藤尚武)
The previous evening, in Moscow, Molotov
had finally received the Japanese ambassador

500
00:45:11,750 --> 00:45:16,045
并直言不讳地告诉他 俄国即将对日本宣战
and bluntly told him that Russia
was about to declare war on Japan.

501
00:45:16,672 --> 00:45:20,717
8个小时后...正好是德国战败的三个月后,
Eight hours later... exactly three months
after the defeat of Germany,

502
00:45:20,801 --> 00:45:22,400
就如斯大林承诺的那样...
just as Stalin had promised...

503
00:45:22,400 --> 00:45:26,556
俄国向满洲的日本军队发起了进攻
Russia attacked the Japanese army in Manchuria.

504
00:45:27,391 --> 00:45:31,000
日本人想让俄国人调停的希望破灭了
Japanese hopes of Russian mediation were at an end.

505
00:45:31,200 --> 00:45:37,984
美国人想在俄国人介入前
结束战争的希望受到了挫折
American hopes of finishing the war before
Russia became involved were thwarted.

506
00:45:43,532 --> 00:45:45,616
在同一天上午的晚些时候,
Later that same morning,

507
00:45:45,701 --> 00:45:49,704
美国人在长崎投下了一枚钚弹
the Americans dropped
a plutonium bomb on Nagasaki.

508
00:45:49,788 --> 00:45:52,290
它杀死了60,000人
lt killed 60,000 people.

509
00:45:52,374 --> 00:45:58,546
但即使现在 日本好战分子
仍坚持一种没有占领的投降
But even now the Japanese militants held out
for a surrender without an occupation.

510
00:45:59,715 --> 00:46:04,135
主和派只想保留天皇的地位
The peace party wanted only
to preserve the emperor's position.

511
00:46:04,720 --> 00:46:06,929
第一次,为了打破僵局,
For the first time,
to break the deadlock,

512
00:46:07,014 --> 00:46:11,100
天皇裕仁,被找来作决定
the emperor, Hirohito,
was called in to decide.

513
00:46:12,227 --> 00:46:14,979
他选择了和平
He chose peace.

514
00:46:15,063 --> 00:46:20,860
我永远也不会忘记那时侯的情绪
(Hisatsune Sakomizu) I shall never
forget the emotion of that time.

515
00:46:20,944 --> 00:46:27,492
每个人都开始哭泣,所以我看着天皇的脸
Everybody started to cry,
so I looked at the emperor's face.

516
00:46:27,576 --> 00:46:30,912
他只是保持沉默,
He just kept silent,

517
00:46:31,663 --> 00:46:38,795
但他手上戴着白手套...
but he wore white gloves on his hands...

518
00:46:39,922 --> 00:46:47,136
他擦拭了他自己的脸几次,
He wiped his own face several times,

519
00:46:48,263 --> 00:46:54,352
所以我们能够知道天皇本人,
so we could know the emperor himself,

520
00:46:54,436 --> 00:46:57,814
天皇陛下本人,正在哭泣
His Majesty the emperor himself,was crying.

521
00:46:58,690 --> 00:47:07,073
我永远也不会忘记当时在这个房间里的情绪
l shall never forget the emotion
in this room at that time.

522
00:47:07,900 --> 00:47:09,000
(标准晚报:东京接受波茨坦公告 有条件投降)

523
00:47:09,000 --> 00:47:12,000
(标准晚报:东京接受波茨坦公告 有条件投降)
8月10日,日本人表明 如果允许保留天皇的话 他们将会投降
On August 10, the Japanese made it known they would
surrender if the emperor were allowed to stay.

524
00:47:12,000 --> 00:47:16,000
(国际先驱论坛报:盟国权衡日本的和平努力
裕仁的君权是个问题 B-29不升空 第三舰队空闲)
8月10日,日本人表明 如果允许保留天皇的话 他们将会投降

525
00:47:16,000 --> 00:47:21,420
(纽约时报:盟军将让裕仁受占领军司令
管制,麦克阿瑟被提名担任此职务)
8月12日,盟军发出了一个不确定的答复
On August 12,the Allies sent a noncommittal reply.

526
00:47:21,547 --> 00:47:24,882
到这时,日本的陆军已接近于(发动)叛乱
By this time,Japan's army was near revolt.

527
00:47:27,600 --> 00:47:36,143
(児玉誉士夫 极右翼民族主义政治家 甲级战犯)
即使一千枚原子弹已被投下,即使日本已被彻底摧毁,
Even if a thousand atom bombs had been dropped,
and even if Japan had been completely devastated,

528
00:47:36,228 --> 00:47:40,231
你必须记得 日本的荣誉岌岌可危,
you must remember that
Japan's honour was at stake,

529
00:47:40,315 --> 00:47:42,942
当时日本人的自尊
the pride of the Japanese at that time

530
00:47:43,026 --> 00:47:48,447
觉得结束战争的唯一光荣的方法不是投降,
who felt that the only honourable way
out of the war was not to surrender,

531
00:47:48,532 --> 00:47:50,867
而是战死到最后一个人
but to die to the last man.

532
00:47:51,702 --> 00:47:56,205
美国人投下了敦促日本人投降的传单
The Americans dropped leaflets
urging the Japanese to surrender.

533
00:47:56,331 --> 00:48:01,586
这些(传单)几乎打乱了主和派的精心部署
These almost upset the delicate
manoeuvrings of the peace party.

534
00:48:04,882 --> 00:48:07,900
那有可能导致许多麻烦
That could have caused a lot of trouble.

535
00:48:07,900 --> 00:48:14,700
(木户幸一候爵 掌玺大臣 即"内大臣" 1945)
全国各地的平民和士兵都完全没意识到正在发生什么
Civilians and soldiers all over the country
were completely unaware of what was going on.

536
00:48:14,700 --> 00:48:20,813
如果他们发现政府实际上正在和美国议和,
If they had found out that the government was
actually negotiating peace with the United States,

537
00:48:20,898 --> 00:48:24,108
局势有可能变得不可收拾
the situation would have become impossible.

538
00:48:24,192 --> 00:48:27,653
那甚至可能引起一场革命
lt might even have led to a revolution.

539
00:48:27,738 --> 00:48:33,868
所以我觉得我们必须尽可能快地达成一个最终决定
So I felt we had to reach
a final decision as fast as possible.

540
00:48:39,082 --> 00:48:44,712
8月14日,天皇再次与一个意见
分裂的最高战争委员会开会
Once again, on August 14,the emperor
met a divided Supreme War Council

541
00:48:44,796 --> 00:48:48,966
并告诉他们 他们必须接受同盟国的最后通牒
and told them they must accept
the Allied ultimatum.

542
00:48:49,051 --> 00:48:53,429
他本人将在第二天发表广播讲话
He himself would broadcast the next day.

543
00:48:53,513 --> 00:48:56,641
那天晚上,一群低级军官攻入皇宫
That night, a group of junior officers
invaded the palace

544
00:48:56,725 --> 00:49:00,019
并试图夺取录有天皇讲话的录音
and tried to seize the recording
of the emperor's message.

545
00:49:00,103 --> 00:49:03,856
他们没找到它 政变失败了
They couldn't find it. The coup failed.

546
00:49:03,941 --> 00:49:05,358
8月15日中午,
At noon on August 15,

547
00:49:05,442 --> 00:49:12,365
日本人民第一次听到了他们的天皇的声音
the Japanese people heard their
emperor's voice for the first time.

548
00:49:17,371 --> 00:49:24,919
"这场战争", 他告诉他们,
"已进展得未必对日本有利"
"The war", he told them, "has developed
not necessarily to Japan's advantage."

549
00:49:25,003 --> 00:49:31,133
"再者, 敌人已开始使用
一种新的且最残忍的炸弹"
"Moreover, the enemy has begun to use
a new and most cruel bomb."

550
00:49:31,218 --> 00:49:33,552
"如果我们继续战斗,
"Should we continue to fight,

551
00:49:33,637 --> 00:49:40,101
将不仅导致日本民族之最终崩溃和灭亡,
it will not only result in an ultimate collapse
and obliteration of the Japanese nation,

552
00:49:40,185 --> 00:49:45,648
也将彻底毁灭人类文明"
but also the total destruction
of human civilisation."

553
00:49:45,732 --> 00:49:50,569
"因此,我们必须忍受难以忍受之事"
"We must, therefore,
endure the unendurable."

554
00:49:52,739 --> 00:49:59,328
当天皇通过广播向全国讲话时,
When the emperor addressed the nation
through his broadcast,

555
00:49:59,413 --> 00:50:08,170
我知道100个人里有99个都感到吃惊
l know that 99 men out of 100 were taken aback.

556
00:50:08,255 --> 00:50:12,842
他们预计天皇会敦促他们继续战斗
They expected the emperor
to urge them to fight on.

557
00:50:13,969 --> 00:50:19,473
所以震惊是巨大的
So the shock was tremendous.

558
00:50:20,350 --> 00:50:31,900
所有那些说他们必须战斗到最后
的陆军军官,尤其是年轻军官,
And all the army officers,particularly the younger ones,
who said that they had to fight to the bitter end,

559
00:50:31,987 --> 00:50:35,072
自然感到幻想破灭了
were naturally disillusioned.

560
00:50:35,157 --> 00:50:46,834
一些军官甚至试图抗议内阁作出的投降决定
Some even tried to remonstrate with the
decision taken by the cabinet for surrender.

561
00:50:52,215 --> 00:51:00,890
在某种程度上 可以说原子弹轰炸和俄国
对日本的突然进攻 加速导致了战争的结束
In a way it could be said that the atomic
bombings and Russia's sudden attack on Japan
helped to bring about the end of the war.

562
00:51:00,974 --> 00:51:03,350
如果那些事件没有发生,
lf those events had not happened,

563
00:51:03,435 --> 00:51:08,272
处于那个阶段的日本 很可能不会停止战斗
Japan, at that stage, probably
could not have stopped fighting.

564
00:51:16,865 --> 00:51:20,326
战争已经结束了,但死亡没有
The war had ended,
but not the dying.

565
00:51:21,161 --> 00:51:25,998
辐射病...美国人对此未曾预料到...
And radiation sickness...
which the Americans had not foreseen...

566
00:51:26,083 --> 00:51:28,667
将在未来的岁月里再杀死几千个人
would kill thousands more
in the years to come.

567
00:51:37,719 --> 00:51:40,346
1945年9月2日早晨:
The morning of September 2, 1945:

568
00:51:40,430 --> 00:51:45,392
美国战列舰"密苏里"号在东京湾下锚
the United States battleship Missouri
is anchored in Tokyo Bay.

569
00:51:46,311 --> 00:51:49,105
新的日本外务大臣重光葵,
The new Japanese foreign minister,Shigemitsu,

570
00:51:49,189 --> 00:51:53,651
一瘸一拐地登舰 来签署投降文件
limps on board to sign the surrender document.

571
00:52:06,248 --> 00:52:09,700
盟军指挥官,麦克阿瑟将军
The Allied commander, General MacArthur.

572
00:52:09,700 --> 00:52:23,973
我现在邀请日本天皇和日本政府
以及日本帝国统帅部的代表
I now invite the representatives of the emperor
of Japan and the Japanese government and
the Japanese lmperial General Headquarters

573
00:52:24,099 --> 00:52:29,728
在指定的地方签署投降协议
to sign the instrument of surrender
at the places indicated.

574
00:52:29,813 --> 00:52:35,067
外交大臣的助手,(加瀬)俊一,观看了仪式
The foreign minister's aide,
Kase, watched the ceremony.

575
00:52:35,152 --> 00:52:42,533
我看到这艘巨型战舰上到处
都有(总人数达)好几千的水手,
(Kase) I saw many thousands of sailors
everywhere on this huge vessel,

576
00:52:42,617 --> 00:52:48,706
就在我们前方是胜利各方的代表,
and just in front of us were
delegates of the victorious powers,

577
00:52:48,790 --> 00:52:52,960
穿着闪耀着金光的军服
in military uniforms
glittering with gold.

578
00:52:53,670 --> 00:52:55,421
看着他们,
And looking at them,

579
00:52:55,505 --> 00:53:02,136
我不知道日本怎么会以为她能打败所有那些国家
l wondered how Japan ever thought
she could defeat all those nations.

580
00:53:04,389 --> 00:53:10,269
让我们祈祷 和平现在将被恢复到这个世界,
Let us pray that peace
be now restored to the world,

581
00:53:11,563 --> 00:53:16,442
而上帝将一直维护它
and that God will preserve it always.

582
00:53:17,360 --> 00:53:21,322
(投降仪式的)这些进程到此结束
These proceedings are closed.

