ALL THINGS FAIR
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
On Mating
Lectures on Sexuality
by Carolus Linnæus
The discharge of semen generally
begins by the 14th. Year, -
- when men first indulge in the act
of love, and it continues thereafter -
- until the age of 50 or 60,
when it comes to an end.
And when the semen
starts to flow, -
- the hair round the pleasurable
members grows, the teats swell, -
- the voice changes, etc.
Both sexes are stirred by Nature -
- towards mating more easily
than before, -
- when they scarce noted
the difference between each other.
- The time has come.
- Are you really sure?
- Yes.
- Offenders will be prosecuted.
- I don't care.
- Two centimetres. Check.
- Let's see now.
- We don't have the time.
- Postponed until next recess.
- Postponed until next recess!
- What is his name?
- Stig.
He's cute.
- He lives in the same building?
- Yes, the same floor.
Mikael Bengtsson.
- Orvar Bergmark.
- Grunt-Orvar.
- What?
It has to be Runt-Orvar to be funny.
Isisdor Blecker.
How long was it?
How long did he say it was?
- Bengt Dahlström.
- How long is it?
Roger Hansson.
Krister Kristensson.
Bo Larsson. Lars Larsson.
Sune Malmberg.
Sture Mårtensson.
Albert Nilsson.
I was class monitor last term.
Can I be monitor now?
Yes, we can keep order
in the class together.
- It will be good.
- Helge Persson.
- Stig Santesson.
- The Stockholmer.
- Are you from Stockholm?
- Yes, I left two years ago.
I am too, I left three days ago.
My name is Viola J-son Gryter.
I'll write it on the blackboard.
Some ladies piss
themselves when they come.
What did you say?
They piss when they come.
Why?
It's like, wide open inside.
Wide open, like a door.
Maybe they just forgot
to go to the toilet before.
Don't you understand anything?
The dick is still inside.
- Maybe it's when they come a lot.
- Probably.
I hope we'll get along well
during this spring term.
- You just staying one term, Miss?
- We'll see. Take out your books.
- Show us now, Izzy.
- Use the tape-measure.
It's stuck in his fly.
We don't have all day.
- A full pass.
- Is it two?
- Yeah, he's right.
- There are 28 times 25 pennies.
- That's right.
- Stop, that's cheating.
- Yes, he's a Jew. It doesn't count.
- Doesn't count?
No, they have more hair than us.
It's cheating.
I didn't cheat. Look. It's hair!
What the hell else could it be?
It's not that, Izzy. You're a Jew.
- Christ, sure I'm a Jew, so what?
- It doesn't count.
You've got thicker hair than we have.
Outside the racetrack tote.
If he was a horse.
- You didn't say anything before.
- No, but that's how it is now.
Wait Izzy.
You get 25 pennies back.
- What fucking 25 pennies?
- His stake.
- He can't compete. He gets it back.
- Why? He knew it from the start.
- What did he know?
- That he's a Jew.
Look in the mirror,
his beak takes up the whole mirror.
But this time we'll let him off.
Give him his 25 pennies.
And you should be damn grateful.
"He came like a storm an April night
and had a tankard round his neck."
Do you know who this was?
His name begins with C.
- Time's up, 5 minutes.
- She looked, I've got 3 left.
Hell no, one at the most.
He is the storm.
- Are you asleep? It's full of flies.
- His name is Carlsson.
- We'll look at the excerpt once more.
- Left.
Thank you for today.
Sit down. Your name is Stig?
The fact that I haven't shouted at you
may persuade you to think -
- that I haven't noticed
your little... eccentricities.
Nothing could be more wrong.
Chewing of the same gum is bad.
It promotes infectious diseases.
The note you passed around...
However, I may allow you
to continue your little speciality.
I've never considered the fly
to be a useful animal.
I don't know how many you've killed,
but I am very impressed.
- I think you missed one.
- Two.
One behind the widow's son
in the picture, and another...
You will stay
and clean up the place of execution.
How? Is water all right,
or should I use a little soap too?
Use your imagination.
- And the note...
- What note?
- The note you passed around.
- I don't know where it is.
Right hip-pocket.
Would you please read it?
I'm all ears.
- I can't do that, Miss.
- Are we no longer able to read?
Yes, but I can't do it, Miss.
"How many times does a cock go
in and out during normal sex?"
"Prize for the right answer."
You gentlemen have a rather
exaggerated idea of male potency.
All answers, except perhaps Olle's,
are wishful thinking.
- The flies.
- What?
That one, for instance.
- All bodies removed, Miss.
- That one there.
- Good-bye.
- Good-evening.
Sigge...
Sigge!
- Don't hang your hat on the elk.
- Where is Sigge?
First I heard he had a quick leave,
then Kalle came and said, -
- it was postponed indefinitely.
And I made brown beans.
- Was there a letter?
- Under the mermaid.
Little mermaid.
- Save the batteries, Mum.
- An extra news report.
German forces west of Stalingrad
have suffered severe losses...
He lost a kilogram, but he's still
too fat for welterweight.
- You going to a party?
- Oh, I just felt...
- I wanted to look nice for Sigge.
- How much too fat?
- Two.
- Kilograms or tonnes?
Tonnes. The limit is 67.
Then he should fight Carlström.
- Is that Strong Arvid?
- Yes. Toughest guy in the army.
In other words...
Every bite is a safety risk!
"Transfer to submarine service
has not been confirmed."
- Not confirmed...
- Submarines?
He gets panicky in a lift.
I'm just going up to the attic.
- I'm in sort of a hurry.
- You're going to the cinema.
I'm late.
Chocolate, sweets, cream cakes.
- Let's take the tables.
- No. Leave them for the museum.
- Help me.
- Do you know this one?
Music, music, music...
A technical problem. You can buy
chocolate while you wait.
We don't want chocolate.
It's 5 minutes late
and then it breaks down.
- And it's not the first time.
- I'll have some chocolate.
- You buying the whole box? Hurry.
- Anyone else...
No. Start the film.
That's the last time I help you.
You have to learn to be on time.
- If Pettersson had shown up...
- It'd be my last coconut ball.
Damn it, I don't want
to lose my job just because...
And put your hat on.
If Pettersson sees you
with no hat on, you'll see stars.
Good boy.
Then they have orgies.
- Orgies?
- I can't hear, what's that?
When a lot do it together.
- A lot do it together?
- Yes.
- Is that the same as group sex?
- What's group sex?
- Same as you said, what is it...?
- Orgies.
- Quiet!
- He's good around the house too.
- Yes, he is.
- He always empties the garbage.
- And the rugs?
- What?
- Does he help with the rugs too?
Always.
You sit in the window a lot.
- God, you know what we forgot?
- Radio language lessons.
- Aasen... Norway.
- That's him.
There are a few of us here
round the microphone.
And there are thousands throughout
Scandinavia listening to us.
There are thousands in the whole
of Scandinavia listening to us.
...we here
and you listening to us in Sweden, -
- Denmark, Norway,
Finland and other places.
And you who are here and you
listening to us in Denmark, -
- Sweden, Norway,
Finland and other places...
- What do you think?
- You're improving. You'll do it.
- Sigge.
- Hi.
- How long are you staying?
- Just till tomorrow.
- Did you buy a ticket?
- No, the girl likes the navy.
- She's Danish, right?
- Yes. You on submarines?
I didn't pass the test,
but I'll do it again.
I want to get underwater.
Imagine, just a thin steel skin
between you and the icy water.
Cheek to cheek with death.
Can you think of anything nicer?
No, it sounds cheeky. As long
as you don't have claustrophobia.
- Claustro...
- Phobia.
- Fear of lifts.
- I'm not scared of lifts, am I?
I've never seen you in one.
I take lifts, you take the stairs, -
- and there are
no stairs in submarines.
That's her... That's her.
If you stay until after the 9 show,
we can walk home together.
- Is Dad home?
- Was my hat hanging on the elk?
- No, well then.
- That's a point.
- Help me.
- When will you learn to undress?
I didn't say you were home.
They'll really be surprised
in the morning.
What're you doing? The black-out.
You should know about that.
- When are the finals?
- They never tell you anything...
Not until the last second.
As long as they don't stop me
fighting Strong Arvid.
I'd like to get revenge on him.
But maybe he has been moved.
They can't move people to suit
the army boxing championship.
Now I really feel like I'm home.
What did you think of Lone?
What did you talk about?
She talked a hell of a lot.
Usually Danish isn't hard.
I didn't understand a word she said.
Some dialect,
north Jutland or something.
Sigge...
What if she said she had syphilis?
I'm just looking up a word.
I usually do that... Did it,
when Mr. Möllerström was here.
- What's the word?
- Words I don't understand.
We just have a small dictionary
at home, there's not much in it.
- I understand. What's the word?
- The word now?
You mean now, Miss?
- Mediocre.
- Moderate ability.
- Now you don't have to look it up.
- Thank you.
- Are there more words?
- No...
I just wanted to see
if it says anything else.
Well? What did it say?
Mediocre, Latin mediocris.
Mediocrity,
person of moderate ability.
Work of no particular value.
I didn't know
the noun was mediocrity.
Obviously,
we learn something new every day.
Good-bye.
- When does it have to be back?
- Before 5, he's going fishing.
How is your turtle today?
Thanks for asking.
- What is it Albert?
- I don't know if you can stay.
Don't worry.
- Good-bye.
- What's he doing?
- Looking up a word.
- What's Sticko doing?
- What the hell are you doing?
Since Albert hasn't returned, I need
someone else to go to the map room.
I'll help you.
That was the maths teacher.
- What number was it?
- 62.
- It wasn't the German measles.
- Good, sit down.
Stig better take that back.
Only he knows where it goes.
Miss, it's the monitor's job.
The nurse was a force majeure.
Yes, indeed.
- Do you see anything?
- No.
Sit down, it's not
the first aeroplane to fly over.
- But it's a flying fortress.
- Sit down.
Plexiglas on the way.
- How many are there?
- Five.
You can carve Plexiglas with a knife.
- Any bullet holes?
- Are there some in the tail fin?
- What's wrong? You look sick.
- No, I'm not sick.
Maybe I am after all... Yes.
- Let me feel.
- I'd better go home to bed.
- Christ, that's my bike!
- You'll get it back tomorrow.
- Have I done wrong?
- No, you haven't.
Don't come unannounced.
My husband may be home.
You said he has a car.
What make is it?
American.
It has a deer on the front.
- A Dodge. Colour?
- Blue.
Darker than your eyes.
- He usually parks it in the garage.
- So I just look there.
No, it's not that easy.
Sometimes it's in the street.
There are 4 streets.
Check all 4, for Christ's sake!
A tip. At home he mostly sits
in the kitchen listening to music.
If you hear Beethoven,
it's strictly verboten.
For safety's sake
always use the kitchen stairs.
I never listen to music.
I'm tone deaf.
But certain signals reach me
all the same.
- What subject do you study extra?
- English.
I should... We drank juice.
Or rather, I drank juice,
and my teacher drank... coffee.
I was just drying the glasses.
Oh, I have to go to work.
- Listen to this.
- What?
- Aunt Bertha broke her leg.
It serves her right.
Be easy with your extra pupils.
That one was a nervous wreck.
The first in bed lies under.
Come...
Don't be afraid. Come.
Miss, did you see
what the Stockholmer did?
No...
When I took down the map...
He pushed me against the wall.
- Then he ran away with the map.
- We'll deal with that later.
Where did I buy it?
I bought it in London.
I just managed to outfit myself.
The last travelling Father did.
He sat in his chair.
The cars just had to wait,
while we wheeled across Bond Street.
The Rolls and the Bentleys.
Daddy smiled once, just once.
And then the war came.
Don't talk about Daddy,
not about Daddy.
- You're talking about your father.
- I only do that in intimate moments.
And your father. I want to know
all about you. What does he do?
He hunts elk. An elk hunter.
A seasonal worker?
- That's just in the autumn.
- We're so poor.
No, he's a private chauffeur,
for managing directors and such.
But he did shoot an elk once,
but he said he "downed" it.
He drove a few aristocrats
to their hunting grounds -
- and then they sat him on a stool
and put a gun in his hands.
Not shot, "downed".
It's at home, takes up half the flat.
It's smaller than yours.
We have to duck when we pass it.
Olle! Olle!
- Where is your hat?
- Can't I work without it?
Are you crazy?
It's to keep your hair in place.
- Go in and sell, for God sake!
- But nobody wants any.
Go in.
Chocolate, sweets, cream cakes.
Nobody wants any.
Start the film.
Olle! Olle...
Move, okay? 3 minutes to go.
- Seconds leave the ring.
- Last round...
Third round.
Get up! Sigge, up!
One, two, three...
Eight, nine, ten. Out!
Sigge! Sigge!
Stop. I'm first...
Anyway, elders come first.
Will we make it?
We'll begin with the air raid alarm,
which sounds like this.
Are you sure
that's the Stockholm accent?
Viola.
Viola, happy birthday.
I didn't go to Nässjö.
Viola!
Well, hello, where's the wife?
- Has she gone on an errand?
- Yes.
- Are you behind in English again?
A vase. Just perfect.
Tchaikovsky. Romeo and Juliet.
- The girl on the balcony.
- Yeah, I know.
Straight gin.
Not bad.
But you should see the plans
I drew for my real innovations.
This is just small potatoes.
A bit of hocus-pocus for customers.
But not without
a certain elevating effect on turnover.
There's a lot...
You think of a lot of things, -
- when you sit behind the wheel.
And you know, the roads
around Göinge, straight and boring.
You have lots of time.
Lots of time to think
there among those spruce trees.
It's not complicated.
You just regulate the flow
with a little bolt on the back.
If you're away, or made some
unwise New Year's resolutions, -
- you can stop the flow
and turn it on again January 2.
Understand? As easy as pie.
You know, this is just peanuts.
A little gimmick for customers,
but it makes an impression.
And that's what counts
in my business, making an impression.
Take my name.
It's not Kjell as on my sign.
Kjell is no good, boring.
Christ! No, no...
It's only by the pastor
and my sign that I'm named Kjell.
My real name... Frank.
Frank to my customers.
They think of Frank Sinatra,
and I'm half-way in.
Everybody likes Sinatra, right?
I prefer Mahler myself.
And Beethoven, late Beethoven.
String quartets. Grosse fuge.
Cream for the cat.
Skol, to Beethoven.
- Frank... and your name is?
- Stig.
SLEEP ON.
KJELL IS AT KOLMÅRDEN. V.
Good-morning, Albert.
Is anyone absent today besides Stig?
Is Stig absent?
Yes, I met his mother on the tram.
Hi. We must hurry.
Breakfast break will soon be over.
- Are you finished?
- Yes.
It's coming soon.
It swells, swells...
- Do you want some juice?
- Yes please.
Think of what we talked about.
Stockings made of nylon.
- Nylon stockings.
- Thanks.
That's what Yank parachutes
are made of.
It's like sandpaper round the thighs.
Women aren't so dumb.
Think about it.
Where do wool stockings come from?
The ones that warm ladies' legs?
It comes from curly little lambs.
- And shoes, where are they from?
- From cows.
Yes. Mooo, that's it.
Cows. Milk under their bellies
and leather on their backs.
And let's not forget
the hard-working little silkworm.
The slant-eyed workhorse
from China.
A silent character, certainly, -
- but it works and struggles
by the sweat of its brow.
Not to mention cotton,
which grows in the fields of Alabama.
What do these materials
have in common?
Well, they come from...
From abroad.
But we have lambs and cows
in Sweden. For God's sake, Stig.
- No they come from...?
- From nature?
- Of course.
- They move.
Move, make noises...
well, not all of them.
- Run and play when young.
- Silkworms don't run...
- They lie in cocoons when young.
- Sure.
But the rest. Wool, leather...
They run around and dance and play.
Moo, baa...
And where does nylon come from?
Oily machines in the Pentagon.
On top of all that, it's
a dumb product. Nylon has no voice.
It's not just unnatural,
it's an abomination.
It's misbegotten,
it's worse than that, worse.
It's, it's...
- An anomaly.
- Exactly. Exactly. It's...
- It's an...
- Anomaly.
That's it... Skol to wool!
- What's on at the cinema tonight?
- "They Died With Their Boots On".
- Skol!
- To wool.
Dad's home. Your hat.
- You bought a gramophone record?
- Wait. Listen.
Was it expensive?
Stig bought a gramophone record.
It's Sigge's gramophone.
He can't use it.
But Sigge's at sea, Seymor.
I'll listen later.
Let the cat out!
Can't you hear me?
Jesus Christ!
- You old bastard!
- What did you call me?
- Stop it, boys!
What does the stocking say?
You don't have to explain,
if you don't insist on it.
Sit down.
Sit down!
Swedish? Or English?
You must speak it perfectly by now.
Explanation, the young man asks.
But can the husband keep calm?
There are certain things -
- that shouldn't be
in a certain place at a certain time.
A lady's garter, for example.
On top of everything violet.
Where should it not be, -
- when the old salesman comes home
after a week on the road?
In the back seat of his car.
If it happens to lie there,
who should definitely not find it?
His wife, of course.
Wrong thing, wrong place,
wrong finder, wrong time.
Well, he sells ladies underwear.
Couldn't the garter have come
from his sample collection?
No.
No, it couldn't.
It was in fact used.
What an idiot!
That garter cost me a son.
Nothing could repair that.
One week after the wedding.
And then, violet, the colour of sin.
Of course, booze was to blame.
You don't know what you do,
what you did, what you should do.
It simply just tastes too good.
Sticko. How are you? I'm fine.
There's a new match
next Thursday. Sigge.
It's true...
It's the same language.
I can't fit it together.
I can't fit it together!
The rule for going on the wagon.
Avoid hotel dining rooms.
You have to sleep in a hotel,
but skip dining rooms.
Imagine, Lilly's Farewell played
by some dusty dining-room trio, -
- when you're sitting there
hungering for Mahler.
Then it's tempting
to order two whites and a brown.
And wash down the misery.
And they have dandruff
on their collars, all three of them.
There they are.
Emil, Emil!
Once more.
Shoot now, Emil.
Now we'll drink a toast.
- Skol.
- Skol, and welcome.
- Stina, more presents.
- There's no name on this one.
Have I got an unknown admirer here?
You'd better watch out, Seymor.
- What will you use that for?
- I don't understand.
- What's so funny about the duck?
- A family secret.
- Curt, play another piece.
- Yes, do that.
- I want to show you something.
- What?
- What do you want to show me?
- You'll see.
Stand there.
Don't look before I tell you to.
Now you can look.
Do what you want with me.
Don't be shy.
This is what a woman looks like.
I've thought of everything.
I locked the door.
The others won't come for a while.
You saw how many cakes were left.
You don't have to worry
about me getting pregnant.
It tells on the package
how to use them.
I've thought of everything.
If there's a lot of blood...
If I could explain...
- If I could explain, Lisbeth...
- You don't have to explain. Just go.
If your mum asks about me,
say I ate too much cake.
- Listen, I found that quotation.
- I want to hear this now.
- Just turn it down a bit.
- No, I want it like that.
Why are you with Frank?
Why did you get married?
He is my hostage.
Frank is a hostage I took once.
You should have seen
all the gentlemen who courted me.
They would always think
before opening their mouths, -
- so they never spoke.
These were courting "cavaliers".
Well-tailored, with nothing inside.
I called them courting canailleries,
scoundrels.
Scoundrels who were just
after my father's money.
And when Frank came, you should
have seen my aunts' faces.
He brought fresh air into the salons,
they couldn't stand that.
But I got air
and could begin to breathe.
But that air is used up now.
Shouldn't you let your hostage go?
Why don't you divorce?
He must have someone to come
home to.
You've seen it for yourself,
otherwise he'll sink down.
Are you sure of that?
I know where
to buy cheap condoms.
If you buy five hundred,
you get them for half price.
What do you want 500 condoms for?
You have no use for one.
Advance planning.
Like, if you fuck three times a day, -
- then you will use them
in less than six months.
Only rabbits fuck three times a day.
And they don't need condoms.
Nobody is forcing you to buy.
- You said you're off booze.
- I know, but there are reasons.
You come to a house of mourning.
There should be spruce twigs.
The gramophone plays suitable
music. Kindertottenlieder.
NYLON HYSTERIA IN AMERICA
- Toten.
- What?
It's toten. They're not hottentots.
No, I can't speak German.
But I hear that it's sad music.
- Children's death. Kindertoten.
- Yes, yes...
Toten or totten,
they die in any case.
- "Nylon hysteria in America."
- It will soon be here.
- It's just a matter of time.
- Maybe it's a fad.
- It'll pass.
- No, no.
Once women wrap their thighs
in sandpaper, you can't stop them.
It's sad that they don't know better,
but I mean if...
You mean I should give in
and begin selling sandpaper?
Never... Never!
Christ,
it's not primarily about money.
It's really, it's...
- An anomaly.
- Exactly.
But...
Even if...
Even if what?
- It's too late anyway.
- Why is it too late?
Go down in the cellar and you'll see.
You mean you've...
Remember that batch of wool pants?
Yes, on Lundavägen.
Suspiciously cheap. You bought it?
I couldn't resist at the price.
- Was it a big batch?
- Barely room in the cellar.
- So you rented Anderbjörks' cellar.
- Christ no, it was full!
Whose cellar, Frank?
I'm thinking about the price.
You couldn't rent...?
Yes, the Goat's.
Not the Goat's...
Yes, the Goat.
But that's not all.
No? Another bargain-price batch?
- Yes, but not wool.
- No. Not wool.
Could it be silk? No.
What the hell! Why not silk?
Was it silk?
- Feinberger...
- And the Goat's cellar was full?
- You could hardly close the door.
- So you had to rent another place?
- Yes, so what?
- Where? That crook Karl Ohlsson?
Yes, more expensive than the Goat's.
It was packed full of crap.
I had to empty it.
It was a hell of a job.
I would like to see their bedroom.
The old lady had jam everywhere.
Every day, for weeks...
- I've already written it, Miss.
- Do as I say.
THE COAST IS CLEAR. 7.30 P.M.
- May I go to the toilet, Miss?
- Of course.
GIRLS
- That's all for today.
- Thank you.
- The turtle didn't hurt you?
- You promised...
I wasn't talking about Stig.
I said the turtle.
You learned something anyway.
- You talk like them up there.
- What good is that to me?
You can talk to the turtle
in the Stockholm dialect.
COME TO THE BOX. STIG.
Weren't you going to the john?
It's vacant now.
- But I've been already.
- I mean, for safety's sake.
Yes, you're right.
Welcome aboard.
Where did she go?
Strange... Without clothes.
Damn. It's moving.
We'll just go along.
- Where did you learn all that?
- At work.
I sell chocolate in the cinema:
Film kisses and stuff...
I'm so happy.
I shall give some of the names
so you will understand the effort-
- that has gone
into finding the men of The Wolf...
- Hot?
- God yes.
The whole factory wanted open
windows except that bitch Holm.
She can't stand fresh air.
They were closed all day.
We'll have milk for dinner.
I traded coupons with Svea.
Rydbergs are famous for, five letters?
Santa... Santa Claus.
You knew it.
You should drink milk.
That's where the calcium is.
- Predator, 4 letters, with an L in it?
- Wolf.
- You knew that too.
- No, I didn't think of it.
We gave you milk
when you were small.
That's why you and Sigge
have straight backs.
All the kids who didn't get milk
have crooked backs.
- What is it?
- Nothing.
That's why he's such a good boxer.
The Central Dairy did it.
I'll go and unpack now.
The crown
has taken over the ship now.
This is an important role.
It was equipped with echolocation.
Wolf's jaws... The Wolf.
- What's wrong with you?
- It's nothing.
You look like you're going to faint.
Puberty.
Sven Jerring's report
from the salvage ship Belos.
- No.
- Any adults at home?
No, just me.
I'll stay until you've read it.
The submarine Wolf
just finished trials at sea outside...
Everything all right?
I'll close the door.
Now a report from the west coast
on the rescue work.
Belos here.
We have no information...
I'll do that.
- Are you going to help?
- I usually do.
Something has occurred
that will be reported on radio...
How long have you known?
Why didn't you say anything?
Sit down. I didn't know anything
before we did the crossword.
- Predator in 4 letters.
- An L in the middle.
I knew then. I got Sigge's letter.
He and I had a code.
From the kids' pages.
A line from dot to dot gives a picture.
Remember the giraffes?
It was always giraffes.
But this time it was a wolf's jaws.
Then I knew he'd got his wish,
to serve on that damn submarine.
- I knew nothing before that.
- Why weren't we informed?
We were. A telegram.
I hid it behind the books.
I couldn't... I'm sorry, Mum.
I intended to tell you a number
of times, but I just couldn't.
I thought, if there's no danger,
I didn't want to worry you.
And there is no danger, Mum.
They've sent out all the ships.
- All the ships are searching.
- They're all searching now.
One... The back row.
That will be 1.50.
Lieutenant von Döbeln in person, -
- ready to hit
the French at Hamburg.
It's 30 years ago
since my first battle.
And now I must beg to get
a little whiff of gunpowder.
Well, there'll be no rattling...
I'll see if I can find him.
From headquarters
to General von Döbeln.
- Please seal this.
- Yes, General.
Sorry General but my betrothed...
- At least let me try to explain.
- Awful! I won't talk about it.
I never want to see you again.
I wish you'd move away.
Or that we would, so I don't happen
to meet such a disgusting person.
It's open!
- We have to talk.
- Look who's here.
Look who's here, a rare guest.
Give me the glass,
you might cut yourself.
So you don't want to screw
the little schoolteacher today?
No biology lesson
with practical application?
It doesn't suit you now, right?
Not in the hooky-playing mood?
I'll show you, by Christ!
Unbutton me!
Didn't you hear what I said?
Unbutton me.
Undress me, undress me!
Undress me, then take that off!
Take it off...
Didn't you hear what I said?
Take it off!
That's it. My brassiere too.
No cheating,
you know exactly how to do it.
Unbutton it there.
That's it, open the clasp.
Let go!
There. What do we find here?
No messing with the food.
The entrée first.
You haven't forgotten
your table manners, have you?
I need some advice.
I'm listening.
It's about a pupil
I've had problems with for some time.
Stig, please stay behind.
- It's over, after that bottle.
- I don't know what you mean.
I asked you to stay
because I feel I have to flunk you.
- You won't be in my class...
- Flunk? What the hell is this?
You will not be in my class next year.
The official explanation will
be repeated absence from class, -
- without a parental note.
Also, fail tests in my subject,
which is personally offensive.
You know
the unofficial explanation...
I can't stand to have you
in my classroom any more.
It happens to be a place
of education, not a rabbit farm.
Stop!
Why are you lying? You know
why I wasn't present at your lessons.
I was in your bed waiting for you
to come home for a fuck.
- Don't talk like that.
- What?
Do you think it was something
special? It was just ordinary fucks.
Silence!
- Are you afraid I'll tell?
- Who'd believe you?
Please leave the classroom.
Albert...
Stig.
This was a hard decision, -
- what with your family situation.
Nonetheless,
we are all in agreement -
- that you shall repeat Class 3
next year.
We don't see this as punishment.
We see it as a favour.
We want to be certain that
when you leave your old school -
- you will take with you in life
everything it has to give you.
We want you to leave the nest,
fully fledged.
And then she cut out my marks...
How much have you had to drink?
How much did you drink?
- I can take the helmet off.
- No, keep it on, sit down.
- It just tastes too good.
- You know she's lying.
You know why I didn't have a note
when I was absent.
Don't you? I need your help now!
- Can I offer you something?
- You can offer me the truth.
You know she's lying.
She lies like hell.
Talk to her, Frank, or Kjell,
or whatever the hell you're called.
You don't...
It doesn't have to be official, -
- but you must talk to her.
Can't you do something?
But you'll do anything to creep
to that pussy once a year, right?
There's nothing left. She's torn
wide open between her legs.
"Storks saw us here in Skåne..."
Sit down.
Stig.
It's something about his brother.
They found The Wolf.
- A flying fortress.
- Do you see it, Nisse?
- Two engines out.
- It's coming right here.
What's wrong? It's coming here!
Petrol.
- It's burning.
- Was that the monitor in 3B?
Anything broken?
They are pumping the dry-dock
out rapidly.
Soon the mystery will be revealed.
A mine has blown a gaping hole
in the hull.
The explosion was so powerful
the hull almost broke in two.
Fractures are visible.
It's a miracle it didn't break
in the middle during salvage.
The Wolf went straight
to the bottom.
It hit a rock there
and the bows caved in completely.
It must have been terrible.
This is the last time a Swedish
navy ship will be named "Wolf".
Recovery of the bodies of the 33
crew members began immediately.
A crane lowered them one after
the other onto navel houseboats.
All the crew members
were immediately identified.
I've rewound the film, -
- and I've run that news reel
at least 20 times for you.
Now I'll go up and shut it off.
Then we'll go home.
It's best that way.
It must be twig...
We would have written notes for you
if you just asked us.
If you were so tired
of all that night work.
It's just a matter of time
before the god RA comes up.
- Night work?
- Yes.
Sometimes you didn't get home
til after we'd gone to bed.
I never saw a sick note,
or whatever they're called.
Note of absence.
I can't forgive myself.
Some mornings you looked exhausted.
I shouldn't have let you go
to the cinema night after night.
What is it, Stig?
- What is what?
- There's something else.
It's not only Sigge
and failing in school.
Surely you can tell me,
I'm your mother.
Another time,
when you're older and wiser.
Where's Dad?
Urban Sahlin.
Stig Santesson.
Not present.
Karl-Erik Schön.
FEAR OF THE LORD
IS THE BEGINNING OF WISDOM
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org