The Phantom of Morrisville
[Demo subtitles]
Order full set from nespor@gmx.at.
It was a misty, dark night.
In the light drizzle, the guard of
Middlesouthborouch Stone prison...
cracked open a window
and bid his sight in vain
to penetrate the
impenetrable fog.
-You wouldn't let a dog out in this weather.
-He mumbled and closed the window again.
Out of the shadow of the prison wall,
two figures appeared.
The bigger of the two, Dixi, called Stick,
pulled a short pistol out of his pocket.
-What is it?
-Asked the smaller one,
called Rosie.
If it's anybody but Micky,
I'll bring him down without hesitation.
One could hear light footsteps.
The third gang member, Micky,
alias Chicken, was coming.
-All right?
-The weather will pass.
If something unexpected doesn't come up,
Manuel Diaz will be freed tonight.
-Let's go.
-You talk too much.
Before the boss is free, I'm in charge.
Let's get to work!
Thread.
String.
Rope.
Few men succumb to sleep,
when their life is at stake.
Only one could fall asleep
on Death Row.
Your last wish, prisoner.
-I wanted a banjo and a manicure set.
-The prison head forbid it.
It contained a file.
Pliers, saw.
O.K. Coil it up.
Second, wait,
although you aren't exactly beautiful
-Unharness time and wait a moment
-Third window on the left, not the fourth.
And let it come back
Let her be happy with me
My darling, who I like
Let my flag be in rags
Let tomorrow be lost in darkness
Let the Devil himself
hold me in his clutches
I don't know, the work fear
When it has to be
Let the punishment come
I'll bear it as a man
Let the executioner come
Let the black wall come
I'll be laughing
Please now,
Second, wait my star, my glow
Just no hurry
Just wait a moment
I'm missing
that light
You know, the one I like
The one I like
-The one I like
One day when it suits
And I'll be a big lord
I want to leave on a big ship
Across the blue ocean
No one there will know
That I escaped from prison
I could hang out at the bar
like the Perian sheikh
Ho, ho, ho
Ho and ho and ho
While I can sing yipee yey
I can live anywhere fine
Ho, ho, ho
Ho and ho and ho
When I lose everying yipee yo
Let the devils take me away
I understand why they call him
''singing Manuel''.
He won't be quiet until the morning.
-You don't love singing, jail keeper?
-On the contrary, I like listening to it.
And I'll be having fun
I want whisky in a barrel
And a leather jacket
And I'll go, yoho
Sleeping with the Sheriff's wife
Ho, ho, ho
Ho and hou and hou
While I can sing yipee yey
I can live well anywhere
-He's a great singer.
-Yes, Father.
And an even greater crook.
From the luxurious study of M.C.
Pellham, the press magnate
Ladies and Gentlemen,
came this announcement:
Allan Pinkerton calls M.C.
M.C. calls Allan Pinkerton.
One moment, madam.
Tea? Whisky?
My dear Pinkertone, tonight at midnight
there will be a wedding at Morrisville
between Sir Hanibal Morris,
and Clarence Hamilton.
You'll attend as a representative of our newspaper.
It'll be a pleasure.
Thank you, sir.
Do you know Alan?
Who is the lady?
My mysterious benefactor.
During my studies at Oxford,
she always appeared at Christmas.
She had me called to the dean's office,
and there she kissed me on the forehead.
Then she disappeared again.
-How did you come to her?
-She came to me, with an unreasonable request.
I told her that I won't send my
best criminal reported to the wedding.
But she came up with 51% of the shares of
our newspaper, so I couldn't say no.
-I wouldn't want to refuse a lady something.
-I understand.
Sir Morris is entitled do such an honor.
We studied together, served in India at one regiment.
I was there when he proposed to his first love.
-I didn't know he had been married.
-Engaged, dear boy.
I was called off, when he introduced his
fiancee to his family.
-Financial reasons?
-Oh no. Social ones.
Poor Hanibal fell in love with Miss Arabella.
-Pardon me.
-What Sarah Bernhard was on stage,
was Miss Arabella in the circus.
She enjoyed great successes in both hemispheres.
-The whole world knew her.
-Tamer?
-Show rider.
-I understand.
That wasn't the worst of it.
Old lady Morris liked horses too.
Tea please.
When she found out that Arabella's
mother is a hairy lady
and father is a clown
she refused to accept a daughter of
such socially unacceptable people.
There is something in that story that
somehow excites me.
-What happened next, did they break up?
-Actually yes.
She disappeared without a good-bye.
-And Sir Hanibal?
-He was angry.
After some time he got a letter. Not a love
letter, but entirely impersonal.
It said that Arabella would like to use
the first opportunity to tell him
that he is the father of a child that
he will never see.
Signature, dot, and that's it.
Poor Sir Hanibal.
Go there and make at least a column
out of Hanibal's naivety
for our Sunday paper.
Yes, sir.
A propos, Allan,
can you fly a plane?
-A little bit.
-Then that means something.
You'll take my personal biplane.
Good luck.
Hello?
Allan's manly,
chisel-sculpted face,
is a sportsman's face,
which has only one belief.
Belief in himself.
There's something of a falcon in his eyes,
but on the bottom of those two
steel grey wells
await the waggery warm
sparks for the one,
who Allan Pinkerton
hasn't met yet.
The glorious notes of the organ
in the Morrisville chapel
rang solemnly
into the velvet night.
Sir Hanibal Morris,
do you take Clarence Hamilton
as your lawful wedded wife?
Yes.
And you Clerence Hamilton,
do you take Sir Hannibal Morris
as you lawful wedded husband?
Yes.
From this moment you'll go
a together to eternity.
Heartiest congratulations.
Rose.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
Second, stop,
although you are not exactly beautiful
unharness time
and stay a while
And let her return
Let her be happy with me
My dear, who I love
Hello, Brumpby.
Old, brisk Scotland Yard slave.
How is it that you are always there,
when something happens?
How is it that you look like
a policeman, even at a wedding?
So far, it resembles a funeral.
Advise me Brumpby where can I
get myself a bit civilized?
Miss Mabel, this is my personal
enemy, Allan Pinkerton.
Journalists say
that he should be a detective.
He could be a good journalist,
if he didn't worry about
Scotland Yard matters.
Look after him and disregard
his appearance.
In reality he looks worse.
Sir Hannibal's secretary.
Excuse me, please.
Thank you, Brumpby.
-Where am I?
-In your bedroom, my dear,
by your husband.
Forgive me, Hannibal,
that I fainted.
-I was upset.
-Don't worry, darling.
-Do you feel better?
-I'm fine now.
-something serious, Doctor?
-Normal wedding fainting.
Could my wife attend the ancient ceremony then?
In exactly 8 minutes she will be fine.
Otherwise however, she'll be sick for
2 to 3 weeks.
-Why are you giving me this?
-I'm not giving, I'm returning.
-Oh I see.
-But then I could think that you sent me this.
If you value your life, leave!
-Which one is yours?
-Choose.
What will you do, Brumpby?
Look, I'm already old,
and for a few years
I will not spoil my character.
How about you?
I'll stay, too.
-My god, Manuel, you're alive?
-I'm alive. And how.
-Don't forget that I am the wife of another.
-I do not forget.
But you have a short memory.
When night falls and smells of violets
The moon unfolds nets in the pool
Nothing in the world burns more acutely
Than loneliness
When my dust
taints the stars of heavens
A nightingale knocks in quiet bushes
All I think about is you,
my dearest
It saddens me to have empty arms
I have empty arms
Like a poor man's palm
So bleak as an empty house
So I roam the world
And I pay tax to Love
For which I'll once lose my mind
I have empty arms
like a deaf flower
and bleak as a dry savanna
I sing softly
And I can only envy
Covers, which count your heartbeat
I would like to take you to who knows where
To a dew-strewn meadow in the spring
I hope I'll succeed one day
But now I have empty arms
My arms are desolate
Like a sea plain
As empty as blind eyes
I sing softly
And I pay taxes to Love
And the whole world is shipwreck
shipwreck, stranded wreck
Here, give it to me!
You came too late.
Given where I'm coming from and how
they treated me there
I'm coming just in time.
-You escaped from prison.
-From Death Row even, darling.
-What If I call the police?
-You do not need a phone for that.
That old dick Brumpby,
is sitting downstairs. Call him.
And we'll see what the law and Sir Morris
say, when I show them this.
Mercy. Don't ruin me.
Leave.
Leave from my life.
-My wedding gift will be your compensation.
-Don't tug it.
Or you'll damage the clip of
Morrisville emeralds.
So what next?
-I could send you money.
-How much?
So you can live a carefree life.
-You couldn't get that much.
-I'm not saying now. But in time.
Hanibal made me the universal
heir of his vast fortune.
Now we're talking, girlie.
I would be foolish fool, if I
I was content with a bit,
when I can have everything.
How so?
If you belong to me, then so does
everything that's yours.
But it will be mine only
after Hanibal's death.
-I do not want to think about that.
-You don't have to.
-I'll take care of it.
Excuse me?
I'd like to introduce you to
an old Morrisvillian ceremony.
Take this cup, which you'll hand to Sir Hannibal.
This man, Sir Elvud Georg Morris,
got married at the beginning of the 17th century.
His rival in love, Commodore
Campbell Patney, decided
that with the help of bribed servants
he would poison Sir Elvuda.
Fortunately Sir Elvud's favorite hunting dog
jumped into his master's lap and overturned
the poisoned cup.
His master ordered him to lick up the
spilled wine.
He licked once, twice,
and after the third lick dropped dead.
-What was the name of the dog?
-Bahadur.
He was posthumously promoted
to the peerage.
To avoid a similar case repeating,
we have a habit in our family since 1608
that the wedding cup, which
the bride hands her husband
is first tasted by the dog,
Bahad's descendant,
and then his master drinks.
Followed by a normal
wedding festivities.
-To your health.
-To yours.
Barely did Clarence appear ...
Barely did Clarence appear,
there was whispering in the choir,
how beautiful she was.
How beautiful.
Seven.
Indeed lucky number.
Do you know who was born on 7 July?
-La Fontaine.
-Also. And who else?
Wait. R. B. Sherriden.
And then?
Well, me.
Call Berry.
fifty-seventh Earl Berry of Bahadur.
The dog instinctively sensed that
the wine was poisoned.
Do not touch, hands off!
It's a police matter.
Get a box; we must send it off for analysis.
Analysis can be done on site.
Is the laboratory open?
We would need to
bring one more witness.
-There's one.
-Please.
-I am innocent.
-No one suspects you, dear.
Still, I'd like to talk with you
alone.
Come with me, please, to the terrace.
-The devil! That's a bit much!
Caliber 45 mm pistols of Belgian production
with a long barrel.
Do you think that bullet was meant for me?
I don't want to jump to conclusions, but...
-someone here is striving for your life.
-But who?
-You always write things down?
-Recently yes.
There are moments
when I forget the whole world.
Now we'll see,
if your hypothesis is correct.
This, please, mix it with the wine.
Here.
Not yet, please.
I'll tell you.
-Now!
Congratulations, Inspector there was
strong poison in that wine.
Very strong.
Reputation, Pinkerton, wrongs the tigers.
They are not nearly as bloodthirsty
as human beasts.
-What about that up there?
-Beasts are also among the animals.
-The one inside it was a friend of yours?
-No, a cook.
-That touches a man.
-Of course.
You can not imagine, what woodcock on wine
he used to cook.
-Where was I?
-At human beasts.
As if by magic
a gun appeared in Allan's hand.
The bullet jammed in the barrel.
What's going on?
Did somebody shoot?
Sir...
I wanted to, but I didn't shoot.
What if it was a lady?
We can consider it certain,
that the offender...
We can not exclude,
that the crime was committed by a woman.
That the perpetrator took a spear from the
other room
and tried to kill your Lordship with it.
After an unsuccessful attempt he fled the scene,
or escaped through the window.
Thus, the perpetrators must be sought
in the garden,
and due to the speed at which he moved,
also outside the garden.
-Well, and if we exclude the other ...
-Your procedure, Inspector
although strictly logical,
it won't get you very far.
If you exclude all thos who could not have
committed the crime,
you'll conclude that it could have been
commited by anyone else.
-Do you know a better method?
-Certainly.
I know that the crime could not
have been committed by a woman.
May I ask, why not?
Try to pull the spear out of the oak
panel and you'll find out.
Inspektor, the tip is poisoned.
I think Pinkerton, that you're right.
A woman couldn't have done it.
-I'm rarely wrong, sir.
-What do you think you, Mabel?
I am convinced, that Mr. Pinkerton isn't wrong.
Sir Morris sought happiness,
and almost found death.
Allan Mabel and seek nothing.
But it seems
that they found each other.
There are, however, at the beginning of the road,
and clues lead who knows where.
[End of demo subtitles]
Order the full subtitles from nespor@gmx.at. License for home use: £4.50