THE CZECH STATE FUND FOR THE SUPPORT
AND DEVELOPMENT OF CZECH CINEMATOGRAPHY
I made this journey
tense with excitement
at what I might find at its end.
JARA CIMRMAN,
RECUMBENT, DORMANT
Idea and Screenplay
If my suspicions proved correct,
it would stun the cultural world.
Title role created by
Zdenek Sverak et al.
While working on my latest book,
I read hundreds of as yet
unedited theatre reviews.
There I encountered the name
of an unknown playwright.
He isn't in the textbooks,
His plays aren't in the archives.
Cast
Music
Sound
They were curious dramas.
They had premieres
but were never repeated.
The author usually left hastily
and by the back door.
Sometimes the audience hurled
chairs at the stage as well.
Edited by
Yet there were always actors
willing to work on his next play.
Production
Camera
Directed by
I decided to visit the place,
where they say he was last seen.
- But you told me Liptakov.
- No, I said Dvorak's Sychrov!
- Right after the pond, he said.
- We're 120 kilometres wrong.
- Who was he, this Cimrman?
- No idea, maybe a local poet.
Now we'll never get to Sychrov.
Why don't we stop for a swim?
Is there anywhere we can
swim here?
Look, a museum of feathers!
Shall we go and take a look?
It's all one to me.
Do as you please.
- Well, my friends...
- Excuse me, Professor Kingsley...
Come with me, my friends,
to this museum.
But Professor Kingsley has come
from London because of Dvorak.
Just a moment, please.
- We must cope with this somehow.
- How? We're 120 kilometres off!
What shall I tell him?
Say Dvorak spent his holidays
here. Or his brother did.
Come friends, let us go!
I must explain to you...
The world's greatest writer,
inventor, painter,
physicist, skier
and philosopher
of the last 100 years
was the great Czech
Jara Cimrman.
We may dispute the fact,
we may even disagree,
but there is nothing else,
that can be done about it.
Please follow me.
- How many of your are there?
- Nineteen.
I'm not with this party.
Thank you.
You are standing in the last
known residence of Jara Cimrman.
This shop belonged
to Josef Lesner.
Now let us proceed to
the adjacent room.
Kindly shut the door.
Here Lesner's family lived and
stripped feathers in winter.
On the table you can see heaps
of feathers.
When did Man actually first
use feathers for warmth?
This is a bit boring.
We'll go on to the next room.
WILD GOOSE
CHICKEN PLUCKED - UNPLUCKED
This is the master's room.
The objects displayed were
definitely used by Jara Cimrman.
Note the bed, chair and shelves
supporting personal effects
and on the hanger the wool
socks sported by Cimrman in bed.
The slippers have been left
where he slipped them off.
BED
INK POT, PLATE, CUTLERY,
CHEESE CO VER
PARAFFIN LAMP
CHAIR
SLIPPERS
CUPBO ARD
HALF-SMOKED CIGAR
ALARM CLOCK
NIGHTSHIRT
WOOLLEN SOCKS
Excuse me, but who is Cimrman?
A photograph of the owner
of the house, Josef Lesner.
No likeness of the master
has come down to us.
We know only that from childhood
he had a T-shaped facial scar.
Kindly come out into the yard.
Dvorak's father.
On this chopping block Cimrman
personally chopped wood.
The metal section is original,
but the handle of later date.
- Is the block still in use?
- Well, I chop wood on it.
Kindly walk over to the school,
I'll catch up with you.
This was once the Sirotky pub,
the school was on the 1st floor.
Cimrman taught here briefly.
Let's go upstairs and look down.
This way please...
No, no, please come this way.
Please look in this direction.
In this direction, 320 km away,
lies Vienna.
It was there that Cimrman was
born and spent his first years.
Unfortunately we do not know
the year of his birth.
Just one photograph survives -
his elder sister's birthday.
The small girl is Jara Cimrman.
He wasn't told he was a boy
because his parents wanted him
to wear his sister's cast-offs.
His father looks more like
a grandfather
but he was 80 at the time,
after all.
He still managed to father one
healthy and one genius child.
Longevity was a feature
of the Cimrman family.
They usually lived to around
a hundred.
The mill was Vojtech Kalvoda's.
Cimrman's partner at cards.
Kalvoda was a good card player
but he never won against Cimrman.
This way please.
- Never won. How do they know?
- I told them so.
Cimrman took a photo of the mill
with a camera of his own design.
The moustachioed man in the
centre is the miller Kalvoda.
In May 1914 he gave Cimrman two
sacks of flour for the picture.
Beyond those hills,
SCHOOL YEARS, PRAGUE 18??
Cimrman, in his sister's clothes,
was enrolled in the Minerva
girls' school.
In some subjects, for example
"training for motherhood",
he was only an average pupil.
In others, especially technical
fields, he was so brilliant
that he actually took over
from the teacher at times.
His feats on the sports ground
also amazed his teachers.
He soon noticed differences
between himself and class-mates.
Differences that in the junior
classes had been slight.
INTIMATE GIRLHOOD MOMENTS,
ALWAYS IN THE CENTRE
But no one took his anxieties
very seriously.
His girlish figure even won him
special distinction,
when the painter Josef Manes
asked the school for a model.
Not many people know that
the much admired calf
of Manesian women is the Czech
calf of Jara Cimrman.
The fateful turning-point
in his young life
came during the traditional
garland-floating ceremony.
A seemingly insignificant
accident
shattered Cimrman's subjective
idea of the female body
suddenly confronting it
with brutal objective reality.
The prudish upbringing that
concealed from young people
the basic facts about
human physiology
led Cimrman to draw only one
possible conclusion.
If I'm a woman with what
I have under my skirt,
then our lady gym teacher
has to be a man!
This episode was the end
of Cimrman's girlhood.
From this moment he inscribed
himself in history as a man only.
JARA CIMRMAN,
INSPIRING
Soon he was a new star in
the firmament of world science.
He inspired the greatest minds
of his time.
Hey, you've torn down my
telegraph wires!
Try it without the wires,
Marconi old chap!
Thanks!
Permit me, Eiffel?
Yeah, er...
Well, um...
No... wait a moment. Gentlemen,
please, just try again.
- No, no...
- Listen, Johann Strauss junior,
try staying with that A Major.
You think so?
Gentlemen, put in a "G"
and a C Flat there.
I've got an idea
for an operetta for you.
Well...
What are you working on,
Dr. Chekhov?
I'm writing, "Two Sisters".
But isn't just two a bit
measly, Anton Pavlovitch?
JARA CIMRMAN,
ARRIVING TOO LATE
But he had no luck
with his own discoveries.
I've just discovered
the telephone!
Just now!
But he was here just now.
You must have met him. Some...
Graham Bell.
I've just invented
the cinematograph!
Man, are you unlucky!
They were here a moment ago.
Two brothers, from France,
they just left.
Don't tell me I'm out of luck
this time. Take this down!
I have just invented...
the fuse,
the electric light bulb,
the accumulator,
the dynamo
and the electricity meter.
Edison.
He was here just now.
Don't you have anything else?
Well... I might have...
but...
- I don't know.
- Out with it!
What is it?
A bikini.
There now, you see,
at least something.
J. Cimrman...
One bathing suit...
in two parts.
And next time
mind you come earlier!
This explosive is 3-4 times
more effective than gunpowder.
Gunpowder...
- And your name again...
- Alfred Berndhard Nobel.
Alfred Bern...
Take this down quick!
I've just invented dynamite!
We are now at the Cimrman
mineral spring.
The water is rich in carbonates,
potassium salt and iron.
If you drink it, you'll be
pregnant in a year - they say.
The truth is that it has
beneficial effects on health
and is said to be why the
local inhabitants live so long.
Excuse me, please,
I have a question.
What was Cimrman's nationality?
Czech father, Austrian mother,
born in Vienna, a year's school
in Prague, then living in France?
He felt he was a Czech
at heart.
Is there any written
evidence for that?
No.
Let us proceed please.
This is where Rusalka lived.
Who?
Rusalka.
- The water-nymph.
- Ah...
JARA CIMRMAN,
CREATING, PRAGUE 1897
Cimrman!
Jara! Is that you?
Marold!
- Ludek! - What brings you here?
- I'm on my way back from Paris!
You must come with me at once.
Thank you, Mr. Melichar.
We'll continue tomorrow.
- Where are we going then?
- I'm working on a big commission.
In Stromovka Park.
- Hello there, Kaplan.
- Hello!
What are you cobbling together
now then?
- The turbine, but I'm screwing up.
- Just keep at it!
I terribly appreciate your views.
How are you, Vrchlicky?
It's something completely new.
It opens up unimagined
horizons for painting.
- Good morning, Mr. Marold.
- Hello, Johnny.
That's the Kubelik.
Very talented.
A panorama.
The Battle of Lipany.
You'll fall, Krizik!
Excuse me, aren't you Cimrman
by any chance?
And aren't you by any chance
Karolina Svetla?
Where have you been hiding,
you rascal?
Remember how you took me
to that cross by the stream?
I've written it up.
A whole 230 pages of it.
Myslbek, look who's here!
Welcome, Cimrman.
Excuse me, I'm in a rush.
Pardon me...
- Look where you're going!
- Dvorak!
So you're home from New York
then?
Home's the best. You should
settle down too, Cimrman.
Absolute realism. You can't
tell the real from the painted.
- Hello, Holub!
- Hello, boys.
- Absolute realism...
- Excuse me for a moment...
Good morning, Doctor Holub?
Is it Africa again this year?
He's staying home, he is.
He's travelled enough.
It would seem not.
Jansa does the landscapes.
And I do the figures.
We've nearly finished.
I'm terribly curious
to know what you think of it.
Behold!
It's not in a frame on a wall,
You're right inside it.
Can you feel that magical space?
You could just reach out your
hand and touch the things.
You don't know where the border
is, where the painting begins!
It's not bad, Ludek, but
why stop halfway?
What do you mean?
The unity of reality and art
doesn't go far enough.
Essentially it's just
another picture.
People will come and gawp at
it as they gawp at circuses.
- But you can't go any further.
- 'Course you can.
If you like Ludek, I'll show
you how far a painter can go.
- He's right...
- Liz, you're never on my side.
That's not true, but
Mr. Cimrman's right about this.
Thank you Ludek.
Thank you for the inspiration.
So you don't want to work
with me then.
I shall lay the sea
at the feet of Prague.
Good, Mr. Bejcek, very good!
And now move on a little!
Swish it round properly Liz,
so there aren't any puddles.
And get rough with that
blue on the horizon!
Don't be scared of the contrast.
It's the sea! It's elemental!
Watch out, there's
a seagull there!
- Pass, Joe!
- Hello Sir!
Sir!
You promised we'd be able
to train today!
Today we'll finish painting it,
and tomorrow it can dry,
and the day after tomorrow
you can help me roll it up.
This work of art obviously
upsets the government.
Vienna has allowed Prague a sea
for a mere 30 minutes!
Friends, when our ancient
astronomical clock tolls five,
let us enjoy our brief permitted
view of the sea,
given to us not by nature,
like other nations
but by the Czech artist
of genius
Mr. Jaroslav Cimrman.
Moreover I firmly believe
I firmly trust,
that the day will come,
when this our Czech sea
will adorn Prague not just for
a graciously permitted moment,
but its waves will forever wash
the walls of Old Prague houses,
at least every Saturday afternoon
and all day Sundays.
Soft, the clock sounds five!
Soul to soul and arm in arm
Let us form a chain immense
No ruin will our union sunder
No vile sword divide us
Traitor don't you even dare...
What?
I was saying that I envy
your future wife.
My future wife?
Love and art, Lizzie,
don't go together.
Why not?
Real love in the end
always means family.
Just think, Lizzie, how many
many tasks I have before me.
A 3-beat motor, talkie movies,
raise reputation of Comenius.
If I had a family the list would
be: 3 litres of milk,
half a loaf, collect jacket
from cleaner's.
- Shall we take a closer look?
- Yes let's...!
Disperse!
Get out of here!
Pronto!
Pack up that rubbish!
- Did you hear be?
- Get going!
Disperse I said!
- So disperse!
- Don't stand here!
- What are you gawping at?
- Disperse, continue!
Never mind. Back to work again!
What are your plans now?
To split the atom.
No! I'll do that later.
First I'll split the monarchy.
JARA CIMRMAN,
DESTROYING, KONOPISTE, 1909
Vroom...
Stop!
Climb down!
Move it!
- Do you need a hand?
- Ouch!
Well, Winner? How did it go?
Your highness, like driving you.
Everyone cheered.
- Anyone fire at him?
- Nobody, your Highness.
- And how did he behave?
- He didn't give us any trouble.
Except on the square he stuck
his finger up his nose.
Ah... Many thanks.
The walls of Konopiste Chateau
could tell you
just how much Cimrman hated
being inside them.
For love of his oppressed nation
he formed an audacious plan.
to strike at the heart of the
monarchy, in the Habsburg family.
Despite his friends' warnings
he resolved on a heroic deed.
He became home tutor to the
children of the heir to the throne
Frantisek Ferdinand d'Este.
Cimrman, give that Nyvlt
a dressing down.
What are you
teaching them now?
The Habsburg Monarchy,
cradle of nations.
Right, when you've finished,
join me in the gunroom.
Let's sum up then, kids. What
kind of system's a monarchy?
- Well? Rott...
- A rotten system.
And the best state system's
what kind of system?
- A Repu...
- ...blic.
- But what aren't we going to do?
- Tell Daddy.
Herein!
Dammit, so COME IN,
donner-wetter.
Deer, Your Highness!
- It the 57th today!
- Throw them out for me Cimrman.
Rak, go the stables and catch
me some more deer.
Listen,
I've just had a telegram
from Vienna.
His Majesty the emperor has
fallen ill.
The bastard.
As it knew I was aiming at it.
This year the flies are
particularly timid.
- I'm sure you know what that means.
- It will be a rainy year.
And that won't improve
the emperor's health.
Precipitation high
Funerals nigh.
- Is that a Czech proverb?
- Yes, but it applies to Austrians.
A bit of flu doesn't
mean anything yet.
But it's the duty of the heir
to the throne to be prepared...
for the emperor's sudden demise.
Could you write me a
coronation speech?
You said you were a writer.
Your Imperial Highness,
I'm a Czech writer.
You Habsburgs have been oppressing
my nation for 300 years.
Why should I have to write
you a coronation speech?
Oh, you patriots...
Cimrman, as soon as I'm on the
throne, everything will change
National individuality
will develop unhampered.
What more do you want?
I'm willing to co-operate on
a coronation speech only,
if the rights of my nation
are expressly mentioned in it.
Good, then we're agreed.
The beginning will be as
usual.
My nations.
We, Franz II... and so forth
Here's a list of my titles.
Dammit!
They've left out Duke of Tuscany
again, the dimwits.
Hey, Slavs, our Slavic tongue
still slibes...
Then shove in a pious bit about
how gutted we are that he's gone.
You know best how to stir
the emotions, you're a writer.
Here's my political programme
in numbered points.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
And a bit of padding at the end,
you know, spice it up.
So go and do your best.
You're writing history.
...long long live the Slavic
spirit, live for ever...
...and may His Majesty the
Emperor soon recover.
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name,
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done on Earth
as it is in Heaven.
Give us this day our
daily bread
And forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive them
that trespass against us...
Would you like the formulation
"Broken by pain the nations stand
by the coffin of the emperor"?
Fine, put it in.
And what about the army?
Should we leave them broken too?
- Yup, break the army too.
- Good.
Wait...
You're right. I'll leave it out.
Get a move on, lump!
It's taking ages!
Wipe you eyes, you crazy cow!
Forgive me, Your Imperial Highness,
but the likeness...
- And on Wednesdays it always Nyvlt.
- All right, get along with you!
I'm already off.
There's another bit I'm not
sure about, your Highness.
Broken by pain the army and navy
stand at the bedside of the emp...
The idea of cruisers by the bed...
Leave it in. It sounds nice.
Broken by pain...
- I kiss your hand.
- So how's it going?
- Welcome, Your Imperial Highness.
The girls did what they could.
- There's always a first time.
- I think you'll be satisfied.
When Ringhoffer sees this,
he'll die laughing.
...a great success.
So what have you prepared for
us this time, Your Highness?
Time for a surprise,
dear Ringhoffer.
I hope you haven't let on
to him Sophie.
Telegram for His Highness.
Thanks.
You see Nyvlt, when the hunt's
over the archduke will disappear
and the coaches line up
for the tour of the village.
You'll be in the first.
Come on, let's try the hands
routine we learned yesterday.
Long live Franz Ferdinand!
You see, it was good.
And one more time, drive!
Long live the successor!
And don't pick your nose!
You're a Hapsburg! If you've
something in your nose, blow it!
I don't like it. I'm bored.
Oh no you don't Nyvlt, not that.
Look at your hands!
Just look at them!
Fratricide, patricide,
unclecide and auntcide.
You strangled pretty well
all your relatives.
If you weren't his double, you'd
be sitting in prison for life.
So better think twice.
Cimrman, the old man wants
to see you at once.
So you'd better think twice!
How much game did you bag?
I heard a fantastic number.
- 270 thousand
- Well...
What's the matter Franz?
It's happened at last.
- The emperor?
- Hm, yup.
Calm down Sophie, go back to them.
As if nothing had happened.
Well, at long last!
Yes your Highness?
I have just received a telegram
from the Imperial Office.
Mirvald, commence!
A courier is on his way
with important news.
Not another word, you understand?
The news is extremely important,
and cannot be sent by telegraph.
Do you think the emperor is dead?
I think I shall be making my
speech in hours, not days.
Archduke, the rabbit hunt is
ready for Yourself and the guests.
Welcome to my estate,
where a rabbit hunt has been
prepared for you.
Come, we'll go over it one
last time.
I'd looked forward to the hunt
but this is more important.
My nations! The Almighty has
seem fit to call to himself
my noble uncle.
These sad events determine
our ascension to the throne.
Broken by onerous pain
the nations of the empire
stand over the coffin of the
immortalised emperor and king.
Our life's purpose will be only
the good of our nations.
We shall love all alike, but
especially our beloved Czechs.
- Is it there?
- You promised me it would be.
Especially our beloved Czechs...
- Come on, don't be scared...
- Climb up...
Baron, do you see that?
Yes.
Come gentlemen.
- Where do you get all your ideas?
- Truly fantastic!
Congratulations, Your Highness!
This is a hunt no one will
forget in a hurry.
You have surprised us.
...that we may lead our nations
to peace and prosperity.
We, Franz ll.
It's basically fine. But I
would repeat "broken by pain".
Your Highness!
Read it, Cimrman,
I can't concentrate.
Dear Ferdinand, I am returned
to health and hard at work.
I think the other members of
our Habsburg family
should do more to earn their
keep.
I'll do Sarajevo again this year.
But next year it's your turn.
For now I have other tasks
I want you to get on with.
I'll expect you tomorrow at
That ghastly good health
of his!
What's so bad about dying
a natural death?
What don't those lazy anarchists
chuck a bomb at him?
Am I going to have to strangle
him myself?
Do I have to strangle him myself?
With my own hands, eh?
- Ouch...
- That's his double...
- A murderer I gather...
- Absolute twins...
Let go of me, ouch...
He broke through the bars
It's not out fault, Highness.
It's awful, Franz.
He's recovered again.
We'll just have to go on waiting
waiting.
Come on, we must get ready
for the journey.
Nyvlt, just look at those
hands of yours.
Look at your hands!
But I washed.
With soap.
In a few hours you'll hold
the world's fate in those hands.
But mind you don't throttle him.
You must just choke him a bit.
I know. Until his eyes goggle,
then I loosen my hold.
And then you get him to sign
this piece of paper here.
Wait, I need to add something.
P.S.!
That'll show him!
Hey, why don't we
do a runner?
Sit down!
Nyvlt, you haven't grasped
anything.
Just think, one day your children
will open a history book
And there it will be
"Hus, Komensky, Smetana, Nyvlt"
Nyvlt!
Welcome nephew.
How are you?
How are your mother and brother?
How is your tuberculosis? Tell me!
Give him it.
Read that.
Read it me yourself, lad.
Just read it!
I can't read.
Your Imperial Majesty,
His Highness has problems...
So I shall read it myself.
Mindful of the place occupied in
the empire by the Czech nation,
we do decree that from
the 1st of January 1910
the empire will be renamed,
Austria-Hungary-Bohemia.
Franz Josef in his own hand.
P.S. I shall learn Czech.
Sign it. If you don't sign it
I'll strangle you.
Just you try.
Come here then.
- Damn you, you're still strong.
- You've seen nothing yet.
Now watch...!
You rascal, who taught you that?
That's how Machane strangles!
Nyvlt!
- Machane! - Hey, lad, how long
have you been doubling?
- Since last year.
- I've been at it two years.
- And what's old Fuka doing?
- He's in the nick.
He's a real original!
Mr. Cimrman,
this man's a mate of mine.
We were in jug together in Bory.
Schluss, the end,
bloody nothing.
What a fool I look now!
- Look here, Your...
- Shut up!
Your whole nation can go
and jump in the river!
Go to the devil!
What a louse I've been
harbouring in my fur coat!
I much prefer Hungarians,
and even Hungarians I can't stand.
- What about your promises?
- I don't know of any.
I mean to your beloved Czechs!
It's in your speech.
My coronation speech?
I'll cross it out, in red ink.
Yes! Now I see your true
colours. Your real reforms!
No I realise.
There's no talking to you.
- Goodbye Mr. Teacher.
- Goodbye.
Annihilate the Habsburg
breed! To the very roots!
Will you come and see us
sometimes?
Of course I will.
Stamp on the last,
the breed of vipers!
I curse your whole disgusting
Habsburg line!
Innkeeper, couldn't you
light a fire in here?
- Not until six.
- By then we'll be frozen stiff.
Come on then, let's finish
rehearsing.
Tomas, take it from
"...I deceived you Papa".
Couldn't we do "Hadrian
from Rimsa"?
We all know that one...
It would be a guaranteed success.
Friends, listen to me.
This play of mine is
a guaranteed winner.
We just can't keep on repeating
these stupid farces.
We must educate the audience.
That's the mission of theatre.
Or "The Miller and his Child"!
We all know that one too.
We've had that one. Kopecky
did it here with his puppets.
All right, so you're still upset
about "The Cross-Eyed Tailor".
I admit it wasn't one of my best.
But "The Hour of Truth" is
incomparably better.
The protagonist Tomas Edel
will appeal to these folks.
Just imagine it!
Lied to all his life, and
he suddenly discovers the truth.
- Well, I wouldn't be worried.
- Of course not! Thanks Charles.
They'd go for The Miller again.
And we're better than puppets.
- Well...
- Friends,
I guarantee that "Hour of Truth"
will have them applauding.
This time you'll be taking
bows as well.
You know what?
As far as I'm concerned
I'm not going to risk it.
I'll take the ticket money, pack
up and meet you in Pelhrimov.
I hope we finish with
"Wind from the Mountains"?
But that's unnecessary Aggie.
This time we'll manage without.
- "Wind" must be there or I won't be.
- That little scene always works.
I can't see any reason why
she shouldn't do it.
Me neither...
- Better safe than sorry.
- It's the best you've written.
Oh all right then, we'll
keep it in reserve.
I couldn't sleep, I couldn't
stop thinking about it.
I looked for you, but
couldn't find you anywhere.
I went for a walk.
And then I saw her.
She wore a black mantle
and a veil over her face.
That mysterious figure
in the garden was me.
You Karla?
But I thought it was Hedvika.
- Hedvika was giving birth to your
child at the time. - My child?
But I thought it was
Adolf's child.
Adolf never even met Hedvika.
But if Hedvika gave birth
to my child...
- then you Karla must be...
- Yes, Tomas.
I'm your sister.
That's impossible!
She's right, Tomas.
- But brother-in-law, you said...
- I'm not your brother-in-law.
I don't belong to the family
at all. I'm a stranger.
But that entirely changes
the situation.
Not entirely. You see,
I'm not actually your aunt.
- You're not my aunt, Auntie?
- Don't call me Auntie. Not any more.
But if so, then I have been
deceiving you, Papa.
Don't reproach yourself, son.
In fact I'm not your father.
In fact I'm your son, papa.
And mama?
She is your granny.
How awful. I'm an orphan then.
But that's not so important.
What's important thing is that
I've finally learnt the truth.
What rubbish!
Who do they think we are?
- Shame on you!
- I paid 50 hellers for this!
Go and get stuffed!
Give us back our money!
- Time for "Wind from the Mountains".
- Wind from the Mountains!
What's going on?
- A terrible wind is rising.
- The famous Mountain Wind.
My granddad used to tell
me about it.
It comes back every 100 years.
Hold on tightly,
or it'll carry us all away.
Karla's already being blown away!
Catch her, somebody!
Look, my papa and mama,
I mean my son and granny,
can't withstand the wind either.
Help!
I can't hold out any longer!
My strength is leaving me!
I wonder if we'll ever see
each other again?
The wind from the mountains
is pitiless.
Is it possible? It's carrying off
Vavak's fence like a feather.
Look, Tomas, Vavak's pub!
It's flown off too.
Poor Vavak. He's lost everything.
What's a couple of hellers for
a theatre ticket in comparison?
How very true.
Let's go!
It's something people
should realise.
Get a move on!
A storm!
Better turn off the lights or
lightning might hit the mains.
Friends!
Let us all stay in our places!
Anyone who moves is sure to
be struck dead by lightning.
Stay put! The awful mountain
wind is sure to drop soon.
After his escape from Pacov
Cimrman's trail disappears.
It only reappears shortly before
the 1st World War in Liptakov.
- And it was here he died?
- It was here he was last seen.
- So where did he die?
- Perhaps he didn't die.
Well, no one can live forever.
And 1914 was in a way
the end of his life story.
He belonged to the old days
before that First World War.
And did you know him personally?
Little girl, where might I find
the teacher Miss Cimrman?
Your lady sister gave everything
to the village people.
Except she said to give Jara
her clothes, if he turns up.
That you used to wear
her cast-offs.
Yes, as a boy.
Excuse me...
Good morning.
Good morning, Mayor.
Sit down, children.
Until the new teacher arrives,
you'll be taught by the brother
of our late lamented teacher.
He'll be teaching you in Czech.
If anyone objects, Conrad,
his parents can send him
to the German school in town.
- And mind you behave well!
- Goodbye Mr. Mayor.
Now then children, can you name
our great and famous Czechs?
- Hus!
- Very good.
Who else?
- Comenius.
- Right.
And you?
- Schiller.
- That's a German.
Who else?
- Good morning!
Nobody else?
- Well? - Smetana.
- Correct, Smetana.
Anyone else?
Oh dear, I haven't introduced
myself. My name is Cimrman.
So how do you like our beer?
Marvellous. Czech beer is
the best in the world.
Well, there's Bavarian...
Well, we can debate about it,
we may even disagree with it,
but there is nothing else
that can be done about it.
If you only knew what swill
they drink abroad.
In London, New York, Pest.
Globe-trotter eh?
You a travelling salesman?
- I am primarily a writer.
- You don't say!
- And what have you written?
- Mainly plays.
The Burgtheater,
the famous theatre in Vienna,
wanted to put on my piece
"Scribbled-on Cuffs".
It's all about secret policemen.
But the Archduke forbade it.
- He didn't like it then.
- He doesn't like me.
I don't like him either.
But I really miss his kids.
How many beers have you had?
This is my second.
From what you say I'd have
thought it was your tenth.
Tyrs forces his Sokol movement
boys to climb polished poles.
But, children, where can you
find polished poles in nature?
So now vault over the goat!
Teacher Sir, will we be vaulting
over horses as well?
When you're bigger. We can only
take on tasks we're ready for.
And now, children, follow me.
Come here and I'll tell
you something.
Look, children. In life you'll
meet obstacles.
Tyrs says, "Jump, climb, but
never ever crawl!".
But I say, "You can crawl too,
but then stand up
straight again!".
So now you. Crawl, stand up
straight, crawl, stand up...
Well, that would work as well.
Children, Tyrs would force you
to race in shorts.
But Mary, when the gamekeeper
chased you out of the wood,
did you have time to change
into shorts?
So children,
Ready, steady, go!
One, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, never mind...
nine, ten, eleven...
It happened on the embankment
when the car stopped.
The papers say it was some
student or other.
Don't you believe it!
But it's in the papers. They read
it on the square in Tanvald.
Look here...
Group together kids,
hands behind your backs...
I'll believe that in Sarajevo
they shot at the archduke's car.
But the archduke definitely
wasn't in it. Bet you anything!
The papers say it was him!
That's what they say now, maybe,
but when we get the real story
they'll say it wasn't
the archduke but his double.
His double?
Did you hear that?
What did he say?
That it was apparently
the archduke's double.
The archduke's double!
His name was Nyvlt.
Apparently his name was Nyvlt!
Nyvlt? Man alive,
stop pulling out legs like that!
It would blow all our work
to the winds!
But it's true. The archduke was
busy with his accession speech
so Nyvlt used to go on his tours
for him.
Look here, Mr. Cimrman.
A pious chap like the archduke,
wouldn't write a funeral speech
before the emperor was dead.
That would be blasphemy!
Friends...
What seems like blasphemy to you,
is common in high politics.
The emperor dies,
the heir sits on his throne,
and can't start hurriedly
writing some speech just then.
He already has to have his
accession speech in his pocket.
And it always begins
with how the emperor is dead.
And that's just how me and
the archduke wrote it:
My nations!
Broken with pain,
the nations stand over the coffin
of the immortalised emperor.
I just don't believe
that the old emperor would
let himself be buried alive.
The emperor...
will outlive us all.
The emperor will outlive us all.
Yes! Here it comes. My nations!
So the archduke's day has come
after all.
I wonder if he left it the way
we composed it...
It was my most ardent wish
to be able to save my nations
from the grievous sacrifices
of war...
I don't know that bit.
The machinations of the enemy
force me after years of peace
to take up the sword.
Franz Josef I.
- The Serb isn't one to give in.
- So the emperor wants war?
That new minister does.
Who knows where it will
all end?
Children, today is goodbye day
so I shall run and you count.
Konrad, make me
a starting line!
- And you Mary, give me a signal.
- Ready, steady...
Children, I also wanted to tell
you to obey your new teacher,
and compete honourably
and always count slower,
for the little ones.
- So now Mary...
- Ready, steady...
Please teacher,
Henlein's crying!
Henlein, why are you crying?
What's the matter?
I don't know.
Konrad, crying won't put
anything right.
This war isn't history's
last word.
You will live to see
different times.
Now I must dash.
Ready, steady, go!
One, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, ten...
The children counted and counted,
and then the sun went down
but Cimrman hadn't returned.
And then the angelus sounded
and the children had to go home.
Probably they realised their
teacher wasn't coming back.
...off to fight the Serb,
don't know why, don't know why...
Tralala...
Tum - tum tum ta -
tum tum tum tum tum ta...
Excuse me, can one view any
manuscripts in the museum?
- Yes.
- And could I stay over?
You can sleep
in the history feathers.
But you mustn't smoke there.
I was tormented by an idea
so fantastic,
that I was afraid to express
it even to myself.
But it led me to do something
I would condemn in anyone else.
To peek through the window
to see that old lady on her own.