FILMEXPORT HOME VIDEO
Presents
MORALITY ABOVE ALL ELSE
ScreenplaY W
Story bY
Director of Photography
Music by
Architect
Sound Editor
Starring
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Cast
Directed by
The film was made in 1937
Fantasy is a monster that has
devoured much of me.
Wrote Henrik Ibsen at the age
ofsixty to an eighteen year old girl.
I believe this needs no comment.
Fantasy is human evil, which we must
reckon with,
which, however,
we must not give up fighting.
In short, fantasy should be
limited to its very essence,
othen/vise, it leads to Iechery,
immorality, and crime.
Or one starts writing poems
and that is sometimes as bad.
I shall end with my usual words:
Morality above all else.
Thank you.
Who is wearing that strong perfume?
It is you, isn't it?
A pleasant scent, isn't it?
- Why are you wearing perfume, eh?
There's nothing bad about it.
- Perfume is an immoral invention.
It incites fantasy and has a hidden
intent. Do you understand? - Yes.
Very well.
Morality above all else.
Couldn't it wait after I leave?
Tell me, why do you wear make-up?
- She wants to please our eyes.
Morality above all else.
Good day.
Who was that?
- Professor Karas.
What a true gentleman!
A paragon of virtue and morality.
How did it happen to him?
Good day.
What's up?
What's the matter?
I found this at lvan's desk.
I was studying history.
And this is what interests you
the most from history, eh!
Very well.
We shall discuss it later.
And I found this in Eve's room.
My idol, I cannot sleep,
as I keepthinking about you.
I would like to walk with you
hand in hand through life,
though, unfortunately,
neither can I or you.
To whom did you write this?
- No one.
Don't lie.
You had to write it to someone.
I was just fancying
what it would be like,
if I were passionately in love
with someone.
Fancying, I see.
It's that fantasy again.
Does mother have fantasy?
Or do I have any
I'll get that fantasy of yours
from your heads!
You'll get an austere governess!
She'll keep your fantasy on a leash.
And as to you!
I'll take care ofyou myself.
I beg your pardon, sir, there are
ladies waiting foryou in the hall.
I'm coming.
The committee ofthe Society for the
Elevation of Morality.
My dear ladies.
What a pleasant surprise!
To what do I owe such an honour?
Dearest professor!
But ladies! The committee decided
that I am to speak.
Dearest professor
She's always moved to tears.
- We are coming to you with a mission.
The committee of our society
took the liberty
Took the liberty, dearest professor
To name you foryour merits
in the field of morality
as the honorary chairman
ofour society.
My dear ladies, I am truly moved.
I do not know how I could desenle
such an honour.
I indeed accept.
On 16th ofthis month
a ceremony will be held in our hall
at the occasion of the revelation
of your bust,
which we shall order
- At our expense.
There you are, master.
- Thank you.
It is nice.
What do you think?
- Very nice.
You did a magnificentjob, master.
- And as soon as it resembles him,
everyone will recognize him.
- There will be his name on the bust,
so there won't be any trouble.
- Don't forget the motto, master.
Morality Above All Else.
Don't let it distract you, I'll
pick it up - Be so kind, please.
Master Konrad's atelier.
- This is Doctor Mach speaking.
Is Professor Karas there, miss?
Good day, sir, this is Eva Karasova.
Can I give a message to my father?
Eve, tell your father to come
to the phone.
He can't because ofthe bust.
- He got busted?
He's sitting for his bust.
Yes, I'll tell him, just a moment.
Father, you are to go to the phone.
Doctor Mach wants to speak with you.
Ask him what he wants.
- He wants to talk to you.
He's saying it's urgent.
Tell him to say what he wants.
I have nothing to hide.
Mrs. Karas, your husband is a true
paragon of virtue.
You should be proud of him.
- I am.
Father, Iamto tellyou
- What's this? Why are you whispering!
Speak aloud.
Isaid I had nothing to hide.
I am to say one word.
And you'll know what it means.
What word?
- Duckling.
What's this supposed to mean?
What kind of a sillyjoke is this?
- Ajoke? Here's the telegram.
I am coming on Wednesday with the
Paris Express, tell father. Duckling.
That's terrible.
- Why? You like her, don't you?
I do. But understand me in this
situation! It's a disaster.
You see what I told you?
You should have confessed long ago.
You've been promising that child for
years that you'd take her home.
You don't have the guts to tell your
wife what will come to light anyway.
Such a secret can't be kept forever.
Vera can't do with a mere picture
of you that you send her each year.
- Stop this reproach.
Call her that she can't come under
these circumstances.
Why under these circumstances?
- Imagine a honorary chairman ofthe
Society for the Elevation of Morality
having a child born out of wedlock.
Why did that duckling make you
so furious?
It was Mach, you see? He always
has such childish ideas.
He really gets on my nenles.
- I don't seem to understand.
Such an innocent word.
- Let me explain.
Ivan, Eve, leave the room!
You don't have to hear everything.
Hurry up!
Nothing escapes your ears, eh!
To the duckling. When I was a child,
we went to school together.
I had a flat nose
end blue eyes,
so they used to call me Duckling.
And it still makes you angry? I don't
understand. - Neither do I.
Hullo? Professor Karas speaking.
- Hi dad, it's me, Duckling.
I've just arrived.
You're happy, aren't you?
I see, look in the left drawer.
But it's me, dad!
It must be there somewhere.
Try to remember, where you put it.
Who are you talking to, dad?
It's me Vera, your Duckling.
I'm staying at the Bristol, room 112.
Come over.
That's impossible, Duck...
You see, it keeps haunting me.
Hullo! What?
You must find the draft.
Wait, I'll be right there.
They lost the draft of my lecture.
I must go back. I'm sorry.
A beautiful city.
I didn't imagine it like this at all.
Miss is here for the first time?
For the first and for the last I hope.
- You don't want to return?
On the contrary.
I've decided to stay here.
I see. Is there anything else
you need, miss?
No, thank you. I'll ring the bell.
- Yes, miss.
Well.
Pardon me.
Tony!
- Let me go! I forbid
This is not possible.
Come here.
My Duckling.
What a miracle. Let me see you.
I can't even speak.
You look so much like your mother.
You rascal! You're so alike her
deliberately to move me to tears.
Ifyour mother didn't die then,
Iwould have married her.
The tub will flow over.
You're staying here, Tony?
- Don't call me Tony.
I can't call you daddy and you've
always signed your letters as Tony,
not to disclose yourself.
And all of a sudden you don't like it.
And all of a sudden you think
you can be cheeky
just because you've moved me
to tears?
You can't call me Tony.
I'm a reputable person here.
And no Tony!
Listen, you don't need to wear
so much perfume.
Why not? - Why not?
Perfume is an immoral invention.
Why did you come anyway? You're
getting me into a terrible situation.
You've been promising to tell your
wife about me for years.
That I could stay with you
like other children.
It's quite complicated, my dear.
I don't know how to explain.
You know that after the war I married
into a wealthy and honourable family.
I couldn't even think of confessing
that I have you then.
I promised Iwould re-educate my wife
and instead
She re-educated me. I'm up to my
ears in it. I got so tainted
with that false morale that I proclaim
morality to be above all else.
You do not!
- I certainly do.
They appointed me to all sorts
of positions.
They'll also reveal my bust.
- A bust? That will be fun.
I must see it myself.
- No! You must leave at once.
Don't drive me out, your wife
and children can't think
that you came into the family as a
- Now then!
Morality above all else.
You're doomed, dad.
- Be sensible, my dear.
Doctor Mach will see to everything,
you'll go to the mountains,
it's very nice there. I'll arrange
my matters and join you in few days.
But, daddy.
- Don't make it worse.
Do I have any other choice?
- Splendid. I knew you were my girl.
My dear girl. What is this?
What are you doing! Stop it!
I won't say farewell.
As we'll be seeing each other soon.
Write a letter to Doctor Mach
afteryou get there so that I know
where to find you. Good bye.
Now I'm wearing perfume!
What a swell daddy I have!
One can't choose one's parents!
Detective stories.
Good day.
You're studying, that's fine.
What are you studying?
Czech, very well.
Logarithms, splendid.
Children, remind me tomorrow
that I have to sit for the bust.
Good day.
- Good day.
Who is wearing that strong perfume?
I'd like to know myself
who is wearing that
Come here, Eve!
Ivan!
Madla! Come here!
It's high time.
I'm going to my room.
Good day.
What can I do foryou?
Is father here?
- No.
It's so nice.
You're still here?
- Yes.
I'm leaving.
- Good bye.
I'm really leaving.
Yes, madam, at eight o'clock.
I won't keep dinner waiting for me.
It's good that you reminded me
of the governess.
I'll call the English college
straight away.
Good day, madam.
Do you know who it was?
- No.
Your father's wife.
Really? And you're going over there
for dinner tonight?
I envy you.
What did you say about the governess?
They need a governess for their
daughter.
You've never seen such a muff.
Perhaps you could go
What are you laughing at?
- Nothing. Just a silly idea.
Miss Gregorova?
Vera Gregorova, room 112.
She checked out and left.
- Are you sure? - Yes.
You're a fine chap.
Thank you. You've made my day.
Have you got change?
Never mind, keep it. Thank you.
You must add one more plate
for the governess.
Go upstairs and ask her, whether
she needs anything. - Yes, ma'am.
I like her, mummy.
I like her too.
She has English manners.
You must be nice and kind to her.
And obey.
And I don't want to hear
any complaints about you, Ivan.
There's no need to worry, mummy,
I won't take notice of her.
You poor boy, you'd be glad
if she took notice of you.
Quiet, children, father is coming!
Good evening.
Well, what's new?
I've hired a new governess for Eve.
- Very well.
Is she decent?
- I think you will like her much.
She's not very pretty, but she has
distinguished manners and she's modest.
That's alright. Is she here?
- In the guest room.
Why such a beaming smile, dear?
- Never mind. Something turned out well.
Mr. Mach is coming over to dinner.
- What? Doctor Mach?
He'll be telling his ambiguous jokes
all evening and I truly dislike that.
What's this supposed to mean?
What ill manners
Ah, the governess.
Come downstairs, please.
l'll introduce you to my husband.
Missis
- Gregor, how do you do?
Excuse me, I feel rather unwell.
What happended to the professor?
- I have no idea.
What are you doing, dear!
Good evening, madam.
- Good evening. Thank you.
What's the matter?
- Anthony. -What?
Anthony?
What's the matter with you?
What's wrong?
Nothing. I was introduced
to the new governess.
But I feel better now.
What are you talking about?
Let me see.
It doesn't look good.
I'll send over my physician.
Good morning, Doctor Jilovsky.
Come in, doctor.
It was a terrible night, sir.
He kept waving his hands and yelling
that morality is above all else.
You see, madam, that's the point.
The professor should not overdo it
with morality.
Besides, it's nothing serious.
He can get up, he can work.
It will do him only good.
I'll call on him once more
just to make sure he's fine.
Good bye, doctor.
- Farewell, madam.
I beg your pardon.
Excuse me.
My name is Doctor Jilovsky.
- Karas Junior. - I see.
Tell me, who is that pretty blond?
A pretty blond here? Impossible.
- I've seen her upstairs a moment ago.
I have no idea at all.
- Who is living in the house?
Me, father, mother, sister.
- Is she pretty?
That depends.
And her governess.
- She must be pretty then.
I wouldn't say so.
- I really don't understand.
What did I forget.
Oh yes. My watch. Thank you.
Pardon me.
- Are you a doctor? - I am.
Tell me, how is father?
The father of the boy?
- He's much better.
Is it serious?
- No, not at all.
I'm ready.
I'm coming.
Who is it?
The professor's daughter.
The boy was right.
- Pardon? - Never mind.
How is the professor anyway?
You know what, miss?
- Yes?
L'll spare some time foryou one day.
Good bye.
I've got you.
You must leave immediately.
But, daddy.
I'm glad I can live with you.
- This is an impossible situation.
Look, Tony, don't be so
Well, professor.
- Don't call me Tony or professor.
But, professor.
- l'll dust you behind, I swear.
Youth must be treated with utmost
caution.
As it leaves strong impressions
on the human soul.
Be very strict with my daughter.
You may leave.
I've got out ofthat quite well.
- What?
What? Never mind.
- You shouldn't be so strict on her.
Do you think so?
Hullo!
You may go.
What do you say to her?
She's made the best impression on me.
She did? I'm most pleased.
That you're satisfied with her.
Yet, I don't find her much appealing.
Iwould dismiss her.
- Why?
We'll have a different English lesson.
I've got my own methods.
Well, the most important word
for a woman is sex appeal.
What does it mean?
Of course, you don't know it.
Sex appeal is the woman's charm.
What good is it?
Listen, do you believe in storks
carrying babies?
Oh my.
- It'll be tough work with you.
Tell me, why are you standing
like that?
How should I stand?
You're standing like this.
While you should stand like this.
And you walk like this.
While you should walk like this.
As if dancing.
Why are you so sheepish?
Iam not.
- Put a bit of life into it!
It's fun.
You mustn't be so buttoned-up.
Be yourself.
If something crosses your mind,
don't be ashamed and do it.
Look!
Try it yourself.
I can't do it like that.
Kneel.
Put your head to your knees.
Ouch.
Do I have sex appeal now?
It's much better.
Once more.
One, two, three!
Good Lord!
Continue.
With ease and confidence.
Hop, hop, and hop!
It's your turn.
Hop, hop. Watch out!
And hop.
Give me that chair, quick!
Don't be afraid! Higher.
- Higher!
And our next lesson will be French.
Stop it, I beg you.
It's no laughing matter.
I see horrible things.
You must help me get rid of the girl,
or it will result in a disaster.
I've been living in constant fear
for a week in my own house!
I, who was always so morally
confident,
I'm afraid now to look
to face of my own wife.
Inclusive of my children.
That's what you get for not
admitting such an adorable child.
She is adorable, that's quite true.
Alright, I shall acknowledge her
as mine, ifthere's no other option.
But only after the bust is revealed.
I can't do it now.
I keep running from the house, just
to find peace for a moment.
One can truly repose here.
It's so quiet.
Good day.
We came to raise your spirits.
That's so attentive of you.
It proceeds splendidly.
It will be soon finished, won't it?
It is so beautiful.
You've captured the professor
remarkably, master.
You're so fortunate, Miss Eve,
to have such a fine father.
You must be proud of him.
Am I right?
That moral balance.
That honest look in his eyes.
That clear conscience.
As a rule, twinges of conscience
appear in the last resort.
One begins to regret
one's wrongdoing
either immediately before it is
disclosed,
or aflen/wards.
Thereby, I do not mean criminals,
who accept punishment as a risk,
but a normal decent man,
who had committed something
in his youth and suddenly
it all begins to
I shall end with my usual words:
Morality above all else.
Farewell.
Good day, professor,
could I have a few words with you?
I don't want to backbite,
yet I must inform you,
as our chairman.
Mrs. Nyklasova will surely try
to ingratiate herselfwith you.
She is like that.
She pretends to be a saint, while
she's chasing men like the Devil!
I've rented a summer house
with her once, so I know her.
She doesn't wear that long skin
out of morality.
If you'd only see her legs, sir.
Thank you for warning me.
Good day, professor,
I'm so glad to see you.
I don't want to backbite,
but Mrs. Roubalova,
she's actually a miss.
She doesn't do anything
from dawn till dusk
than calling on everyone and
scandalmongering. It's like a race.
While it's the last thing
she should be doing. She
You don't say!
Brought up by foster parents?
Some people, eh?
- Indeed.
Excuse me, I must be off.
Good day. - Good day.
What a coincidence, professor.
But since we've met,
I must tell you something.
I don't want to backbite,
but Mrs. Drazna, our secretary,
the one that is always moved
to tears.
It's not out of her emotions.
She drinks pure rum. - Rum?
Just ask her to breathe on you.
Thank you.
Ah, the secretary.
What can I do foryou?
Professor, I don't want to backbite,
but
Jamaican.
My Dearest, Since I have been
watching you mould my father,
I feel our souls could understand
each other.
What is it?
Nothing.
- Give it to me.
What's this supposed to mean?
Nothing at all.
Let's be sincere. Confide in me,
as if I were your sister.
My sister?
Hullo, Doctor Mach?
It's me, Karas. It's out.
She told herjust now.
What? I'll be right over.
Does he know that you love him?
He hasn't even noticed me yet.
- I'm not surprised.
Wait, what could work on him?
Take off your glasses.
You know you have quite nice eyes?
I do?
- Why do you wear glasses?
I can't read very well without them.
- Why do you wear them all the time?
In our family, we all wear glasses.
- So you won't be wearing them.
I'd get catch, if I didn't.
- Quiet.
It would be terribly bad luck, if
that gentleman didn't take the bait.
Smile.
You see, that's much better.
Why do you wear your hair combed
behind your ears?
Mummy says that a girl should not
attract too much attention.
Othen/vise, men tend
to become impertinent.
On the other hand though, one does
lack too little attention.
Let me see.
A bit of fantasy.
You're quite a pretty girl.
Take these clodhoppers off.
Take these shoes.
Here's a dress.
And here's a bit of female charm.
I'm curious what the girls are doing.
So I am eavesdropping.
And I clearly hear my daughter,
the legitimate one,
say to the other, the illegitimate one:
My sister?
It's quite clear, isn't it?
Nothing can make me go home.
- Don't be so furious.
You're out ofyour minds!
What's this supposed to mean!
Madam, your daughter,
as she should look like.
I can't get over the shock.
This can't be happening.
And you are a governess!
- I've got my methods.
Fine methods, Isay! Eve!
Go to your room and get changed!
And you too.
Father will be home any minute.
If he saw what bad influence
you have on her!
Let me explain, madam.
There's no need!
- She is young and wants to look nice.
I'm telling you no, no and no!
No, I'm not going home!
What will you do?
- What will I do?
I don't know yet. But I'm not going
home. Definitely not now!
Good Lord, that girl is giving me
hell. I see horrible things.
Look at what has become of me.
MY family, my dignity and honesty,
even/thing is gone!
Only that bust will remain
as a monument ofshame and hypocrisy.
Pull yourself together and go home.
They don't know what happened to you.
I'm not going home.
Don't ask such things.
There's nothing to it, madam.
Stop it, don't embarrass me.
Why don't you want to tell me?
Very well, if you want to know.
The last time he kissed me
was on my birthday.
That was last year on March 15.
That's almost nine months ago.
It's pretty long ago.
Tell me, did you never want to
please his eyes?
I beg your pardon!
My husband likes me as I am.
And that's enough for me.
Don't you think he could like you
even more?
Such silly questions!
Besides, it's understandable with
young girls as you or Eve.
But me?
- Forgive me, madam.
Did he ever bring you flowers?
- Yes, before we were married.
And wouldn't it make you happy,
if he brought you flowers every day?
Every woman must be pleased. If she's
good looking and has sex appeal.
Don't be indecent, miss!
Well, I'm here.
- So what?
I came to see, if father is here.
He's not.
But I'm here.
So what?
- I'm here, look.
Well look at you! Is this possible?
Is it really you?
Let's have a look.
You look very nice!
- Look, I've got sex appeal.
He took the bait!
I'm here.
I must go now.
Excuse me, Iforgot my watch here
some time ago.
Here, sir?
- In the professor's room.
Just a moment.
I'll ask the madam.
Good day, miss. How is the professor?
- He's well.
Miss! - Yes?
What was it that I wanted to say?
Nothing, perhaps.
- Tell me,
what do the covered statues mean?
- That it's a moral and honest family.
Why don't they put them in the attic?
One wouldn't see that they are
so honest.
Miss, I'd like to ask you something.
You know what, sir?
- Yes?
L'll spare some time foryou one day.
Miss, could you spare three seconds,
please?
No.
- Just three seconds.
One, two, three!
Quite thick glasses, eh?
At least six dioptres.
It is you!
Just for a moment, please!
You must help me.
Sit down.
Pull yourself together.
Give me the key.
I don't have it. - The key?
Yes. - l'll ring the bell.
There's nothing to be done now,
when everything has come to light.
I'm with you, don't be afraid.
- I see horrible things.
I've heard that before.
Good day.
- Good day.
Come on.
Come here. Stand here.
What's happening here anyway?
- Nothing, sir.
Has my wife calmed down?
- I don't know about anything, sir.
You see!
- Did she say something?
Nothing at all.
- Very well, let's go in.
She said nothing. That's even worse.
- Come in.
How could that happen, doctor?
Such illness comes suddenly, madam.
It's the weather. It's in the air.
Is it serious?
- It isn't. Don't worry.
He'll stay in bed for a few days.
- How dreadful!
How dreadful!
You'll give me twenty crowns.
- Lie down!
You'll give me twenty crowns
for each day in bed.
Alright, just stay in bed!
What if someone comes here?
It's so dreadful!
Here we go!
On the top ofthat you were away
all day.
Don't be surprised, madam.
- I know he has plenty of work to do.
But he could call at least.
It is hard to say such things
over the phone.
Believe me, I'm heartbroken.
I understand.
It is your child, after all.
You are so wise.
So prudent.
- We mustn't lose our head.
Believe me, I'm so unhappy
to cause you so much trouble
with the child.
Why are you apologising?
It's my child as well.
What?
It's rather hot, isn't it?
The doctor is with him.
With whom?
With Ivan, of course.
What is so amusing, sir?
I beg your pardon, madam,
it's my illness.
You're such an addle head!
- I see that myself.
What is this?
Come here!
What are you wearing?
Let me see!
What's all this?
Who did this to you?
She looks nice, doesn't she?
What pretty girls I have, eh?
I won't stand this!
You won't be wearing this!
And you as well!
Let them be. They're young and
they want to look nice.
Well
Wednesday. I can't come round.
He kissed me for the first time
four days ago. It was breathtaking.
I felt dizzy.
And I'm feeling dizzy even now.
S/rup three times a day.
- I won't swallow that.
Prescribe me some raspberryjuice,
or I'll recover at once.
Besides, I'm getting bored. I've been
in bed for 4 days. I've had enough.
No, I need you to be sick.
In that case, you'll give me thirty
crowns for each call. Alright?
Alright.
Dearest wife,
Dear Caroline,
I can't go on like this.
I must confess.
Tony, I miss you so much.
Come to my room tonight when
everyone is asleep.
At least for a little while.
You will have a fever tonight.
I must stay here.
Alright, but you'll give me
fifty crowns.
Caroline? - Yes?
- What are you writing?
Orders for the maid for Saturday.
Will it take you long?
- No.
Is the time on the clock correct?
Yes.
Am I disturbing you?
- Not at all. What did you want?
I have something to tell you.
I just remembered.
I've met the counsel's wife today.
She spoke so highly ofyou.
How everyone admires you.
What a spotless man you are. So moral,
honourable with a clear conscience.
A paragon ofan irreproachable man
and husband.
But Iwanted to
- I know you don't like to hear it.
But I am very proud ofyou.
Just imagine, what gossip people
say about others.
I'm not afraid with you, though.
Iwould swear on you.
What was it that you wanted?
It seems you've put me off with
fair words It wasn't so important.
I won't confess then.
My sweet little girl.
You rascal. You've got silly ideas.
Just imagine if someone saw me.
Don't put letters under my door.
Just imagine if someone found them.
I'll put them in the library, then.
In the dictionary.
But you must fetch your mail daily.
Who would ever think of something
like that. Our professor.
Such a decent man.
Now tell me what to do.
I can't get over it.
My husband and that woman.
How she crept into our house.
And now, she enticed away our father.
My poor, abandoned children.
Calm down, madam.
Oh WY-
You see and they keep saying that
morality is above all else. - Quiet.
Good morning.
How's Ivan?
Is he feeling better?
How did you sleep, madam?
Sit straight, Eve!
Good morning!
Excellent, breakfast is sewed.
Something turned out very well.
How did you sleep?
What's with you, Ivan?
How are you feeling?
How is he, doctor? - He's better.
That's splendid.
Pass me the butter, please.
And put that a bit closer as well.
Over here, thank you.
I had a good night's sleep.
Did you sleep well, dear?
There
Very well.
Oh dear, it's late.
I won't be ready in time.
I must write my lecture.
Tell the maid to bring it to my
room, will you?
Fetch your books, Eve,
and come upstairs.
Don't let it upset you, madam.
l'll settle the matter myself.
What can Ido foryou?
Why are you looking at as ifyou
wanted to eat me alive?
Let's not waste time.
You are probably not aware ofwhat
you have done last night.
Ifyou were, you would have to be
ashamed of yourself!
I beg your pardon!
- Don't interrupt me!
I'll tell you the truth.
The boy wasn't ill at all.
I stayed here only to be close
to you.
And if you want to know,
I fell in love with you!
Stop it!
Ifthere's some virtue left in you,
then pack up and leave this house!
But let me explain.
Wait!
You can be calm now, madam.
She will leave the house, after
what I have told her.
Thank you for your concern, doctor.
Although it seems you are quite
agitated yourself.
Don't be amazed.
I thought better of her.
Until all ofa sudden
Tony, I think it will come to light.
Put 2,000 crowns into this book
and Iwill leave today.
I will write the rest in my letter.
Blackmailer!
Good Heavens, my dear,
what happened?
Tell me what's wrong.
You have a fever.
I'm so glad you're still here, doctor.
Come upstairs, please.
- What's the matter?
My Vera, I mean the governess
Come!
That's out ofthe question.
- I beg your pardon!
Forgive me, professor, but I have
my reasons.
You can't be serious!
It is your duty as a physician
to attend those in need!
As you wish.
But you will stay here.
Let me be and leave!
- I'm not here to amuse myself.
Leave me alone!
- I won't ask you.
Lie down.
- How dare you! - Quiet.
That's the limit.
- Hush!
What people dare to do nowadays!
- Enough! Take a deep breath.
Don't breathe.
- That's easy for you to say.
What do you dream about?
- You flip!
Sit!
No, I look awful like that.
Show me your tongue.
It's pretty sharp.
Do you feel any pain?
I do and quite big.
Where? - In my heart.
- I see. That's none of my business.
That's enough!
l'll speak now as a patient.
And wipe the dust everywhere,
please.
And I had to promise daddy
that lwon't tell anyone.
It would never cross my mind
that you are his daughter.
You see, you bugbear.
I've suspected you
of such awful things.
You should beg my pardon now.
Easy, easy.
No intimacies.
Just imagine that after so many years
of exemplary family life,
he runs wild with a governess.
- With that new governess?
I beg your pardon, it's my illness.
- I'm so unhappy.
You're not jealous, are you?
I think I am.
Calm down. I'm going with you
and I'll put things in order.
Farewell, professor.
You're leaving already, doctor?
Tell me, how is the miss,
is it serious?
You can be calm,
she is in good health.
Miss!
I must talk to you.
- Yes, madam.
I don't understand why I should
confess just now. What's going on?
You're a silly foot. You were ringing
the alarm when nothing was going on.
And when something is going on,
you know nothing about it.
What should I know?
- What should you know?
Your whole family saw you
enter Vera's room.
When?
- When? Last night.
Alright, Iwill confess,
but how am I supposed to say it
in front ofthe children?
- The children saw you too last night.
The children saw me too?
- They did.
Say it in front of everyone.
Young people today are quite
different.
This is terrible. I will confess,
but don't leave me, please.
I won't. But let's go.
I see horrible things.
- Go on.
No.
- Really.
Watch out, father is coming!
You are here?
That's good.
Come here. I mean there's no need,
since you're already here.
I want to tell you something.
Be quiet, please.
My dear wife, children and you.
After long consideration,
I have decided that
Sit straight, Eve.
The thing is,
I have something to tell you
What? I'll gladly
Don't kick the table, Ivan.
In short, I have
- In short, he wants to confide in you.
Yes. I'll put it straight.
There's no other way, is there?
What did I tell you, Ivan.
Be quiet, please.
Break the news with care.
I have a child born out of wedlock.
Pass me the thumb-stall, Eve.
I'm telling you I have a child
born out of wedlock.
Why don't you do something,
be angry!
Why should I be angry?
I know it already.
Daddy!
Morality Above All Else.
Hurry up, children.
I can't be late for my own
revelation.
Good Lord, I'm so nenlous,
I wish I didn't have to go there.
What's taking mother so long?
I don't know.
- Go and get her, hurry!
Mummy is coming.
Oh my.
- What's that oh my!
Oh my!
Mummy, you look very nice.
- You're so pretty.
Pretty? She's beautiful.
At last.
And you're wearing perfume.
What happened to you?
You're amazed at how I turned
even/thing upside down, aren't you?
I almost forgot this.
I couldn't stand it for a long time.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Now, let us hear a word
from our dear chairman.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Morality above all else.
I beg you, let me finish.
It's true I always declared morality
to be above all else.
Yet, one must not exaggerate.
Over the last few days, I dealt with
a minor matter in my private life
and found myself absorbed
in thought about my motto.
And I asked myself:
What is morality?
I consulted handbooks, I browsed
through various brochures,
I even noted this from
an encyclopaedia.
Just a moment, it will interest you.
I have it right here.
Morality. Aset of rules recognized
in a certain society
the rules in the society
to be kept.
This clearly implies
that we know nothing.
Let me tell you something practical
about morality from my own experience.
Morality cannot be taught.
We carry it inside ourselves.
Morality is a pan ofour character
and of our conscience.
What's moral for one person isn't
necessarily moral for another.
If young and pretty girls, who
rightly want to please our eyes,
wear make-up and perfume, they can
still be honourable and moral.
On the other hand, less attractive
and older women, who would
like to please our eyes,
yet it would be of no use to them
They have no other option than
to guise themselves in principles,
which they call morality.
After all, this is confirmed
by the fact
that members of morality societies
are not young and pretty girls,
but quite on the contrary.
Morality is a question of opinion.
Nevertheless, we must not confuse it
with shyness and hypocrisy.
All that is natural and truthful,
is also moral.
I've just remembered something.
It certainly is not moral to pretend
to be moved to tears by one's own
morality, but it definitely is
more moral to admit that I'm flushed
from pure rum.
Jamaican.
And don't believe that long skirts
always mean morality.
Sometimes, they only hide
splay feet.
Very well. There's one more thing
I'd like to say.
It is definitely more moral to tell
the truth to someone in the face,
than to backbite and pretend
to be a friend.
Very well.
Finally, I would like to say that
this day will always be a warning
for me to act honestly
and to speak the truth.
And if I do lie someday
then let this statue of mine,
this cold metal,
grin at me in malicious irony.
The End
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/85z78
Help other users to choose the best subtitles