FORTY-FOUR MUTINEERS
Chin up, chaps!
Yes. Chin up, chaps!
They are afraid of our courage.
We are not alone. They are.
They have already died, we are starting to live.
Thank you. Old man. The march will be easier now.
Oh, dear boys...
So many mothers, so many women!
My dear Julka. Forgive me.
I promised you to come back.
Don't be angry with me and don't be sad.
A short time together. But what a nice beginning!
It is said love at first sight is only found in novels,
but I do not believe that.
What did our meeting have in common with a novel?
As soon as I saw you I was lost.
I had no place where to hide and could not run away.
I was like paralyzed.
My legs, arms and head.
And I felt a terrible beat in my chest.
Nothing like that had ever happened to me.
A peculiar feeling.
Though I was confused I felt well.
Julka was inscrutable.
I never knew what she was going to do.
Kiss me, Viktor.
I have never been kissed.
That is not a trifle.
I was afraid of fainting.
She probably did not like it.
However. It was a nice day so both of us were silent.
Far and wide was nobody and nothing
but flowers around and the sky above.
Then a small cloud came and I realized
it's time to introduce myself to her father.
As all women. Julka pretended she was angry
but I knew nothing in our lives would us do part.
All right, but I worry you are hard of hearing.
Hard of hearing?
I said Marka was expecting too.
I heard that.
Who else?
Me.
Shout or tear your hair but do something!
A baby... a girl.
Say it will be a girl.
Of course if you want it.
What a feeling!
You don't know what it means to be a father.
I really don't. Tell me.
We must get married soon.
If you wish...
- How to say it to your father? - He already knows.
Mr. Kolibec. War!
We are at war!
On the following day I had to leave.
You were standing by the carriage.
I can see and hear you as if it were now.
You said: It doesn't matter we couldn't get married.
I know you will come back.
Our girl will have a good father.
I was with you before every attack.
Promising you I'd return home.
I have killed nobody and can embrace you with clean hands.
None of us wants to kill. Nor my friend. Tono,
nor father Gulej and his son.
We are scared of fire but we must go.
We must...
Father, what's going to happen?
Stop crying! Don't be a disgrace to our regiment!
Just cry. My boy.
I was scared to death before the first attack.
It is growing calm, we are to move along.
Here, for my wife. Go and see her.
We shall both get back and live with our wives again.
Damn. Why don't they start?
Here. For my wife.
If she became a widow, let her marry my brother.
Don't worry, my son, I will save you.
When we start. Stay close to me.
Let's go in the name of God.
Good heavens. Father!
Father!
What's going to happen?
Don't worry. Ondrik!
Father!
Go away!
Come back. Our officers will shoot you to death!
Not a step more. Anyway. We are in Russia.
- What are you saying? - Nothing.
I am to surrender, no matter what!
Bet the Russians are waiting for us with music.
Oh my God. We have already been taken captive.
Who would have imagined the end will be so nice.
Our Lord performs miracles also in wartime.
All right, let's go!
My Lord, what have you allowed?
What a shame!
If I had a bullet, I would kill myself.
Halt!
Is this the way to bring prisoners?
I shall teach you a lesson, band of tinkers!
Forward!
...I award the soldiers Kolibec and Mikles
four days off near the main camp.
They start today at noon...
Did you hear the story about the two tinkers?
They are said to have taken fourteen Russian prisoners!
- Two against fourteen? - People say.
Two tinkers entered the Russian positions last night
and took forty Russian prisoners!
A colonel among them too.
A colonel?! Two generals!
- The award - silver crosses. - And three stars each!
They'll become members of the Emperor's Guards.
Did you hear? Three stars each. That would suit us.
Three slaps would suit us.
Look for a canteen. I'd like to wet my whistle.
Rum is the best!
Attention!
Get ready!
Fire!
You should have been here three hours ago!
You may leave!
I shall kill him.
Bloody war!
What have you done to people?
- What's wrong? - I can't go on.
Lucky you. At least you'll go on leave.
Forward!
Victor. Don't leave me here! Don't go to Russia without me!
Stop talking such nonsense!
I am back in a minute to move you away.
Here.
Forward!
I see you are awake.
What is your name?
Where am I?
In the Orloff Guberniya now,
but once you are well, the tsar will invite you to Moscow.
Just breathe, Austrian, I am going to bring you gruel.
Do you know me?
I know you didn't mean to stab me.
Neither did I.
We are humans, why to kill?
Come here. Julka, I'll show you your Daddy.
I don't want him!
Give him your hand. He is your Dad.
Give me a razor to shave him.
Welcome. Mr. Kolibec. I am the mayor.
I asked the medical officer to come in case it was typhoid.
I have to report everybody from Russia.
As we don't know the day or hour of our departures
I am here with all the believers to...
No!
In the presence of my father and my family I ask you
to become my husband
and I want to be your good wife forever.
My dear Julka...
First a little spirit, then shaving.
- Anything wrong with him? - Yes.
I don't care.
He hasn't registered and has a Russian uniform. In my view, he is a deserter.
...to have and to hold. From this day forward.
For better, for worse, for richer, for poorer,
in sickness and in health until death parts us.
That God has joined, men must not divide.
Dear Mr. Janciarik,
I feel like kicking your behind.
I've been longing for that.
I know, Colonel. But you cannot.
Who would bring you cognac,
cigars and something to your pocket? Be reasonable!
- You are an old bastard. - I am.
Sign it!
The government will pay ten crowns more for a coffin.
Everything is more expensive, why not funerals?
Bloodsucker!
You would prefer all in the camp to die.
He who must die shall die. There is enough mob here.
How many dead do we expect tomorrow?
Go now, or I really kick you out.
But Colonel... Thank you.
Counts, Lords and Jews are not afraid of the war
Since the Slovak boys shed their blood in the war.
I swear it is true!
Hey. Buddy, come closer!
- Is somebody dying? - Me. Come and cheer me up.
You'd better not wish that. I am a gravedigger!
We shall meet at your funeral.
Die. Die!
Tono Mikles!
For fuck's sake...
This is a joke... You were killed!
You too.
Where have you been?
In hospitals, half a year on the Italian front
and then here with typhoid fever.
- How long have you been here? - Thirteen days.
You should have died long ago.
- What is it? - Ulcer. They say.
Let me see!
Shit, not an ulcer! You're as fit as a fiddle!
Leave it to me. Doc.
And you. Why are you not in the workshop?
Here... I found a very good craftsman.
He could work here.
All right, I'll transfer him.
What did I say? You are out of it.
He looks around and knows who to make a coffin for.
He's already been here... vulture.
- What have you got with him? - Me? Well...
Stop staring, or I'll smash your face!
The snooper's coming! Let's run away!
Don't show me corpses. I need men!
I am showing what I have. Captain.
A real mess. The emperor needs soldiers
and here - fifteen men die every day.
- We lack drugs. - For heaven's sake. Get it!
You will provide me with fifty men by the evening!
I don't want cognac, my father has three distilleries.
What beastly stuff!
You didn't want to do it yourself, now you have to.
- Shut up! - You shut up!
You are safe here. Janciarik will save us from the front.
I don't care!
You are like him. Both of you use the war to make money.
Asshole!
I have nothing from it but he has already bought two houses.
While there are jerks like you. He will buy a third one.
All right. Viktor. All right.
Take a brush and paint!
- I'd rather die. - Just wait with dying.
Somebody's waiting behind the wire.
Misko. Come here!
Come on. Don't worry!
Two nickels for you, accompany him to the fence.
Follow me.
I am glad to see you at least.
I've looked for you very long!
Thank God you are healthy.
I have some cake for you.
Help yourself!
The guard has noticed us!
All right, buddy.
Speak. Say anything, I just want to hear you.
- What's the news at home? - Bad times. Poverty, hunger.
They take everything. There's nobody to protect us.
What about us?
People say the war will go on.
Bring some clothes tomorrow, I am going to flee.
Clothes for two, also for my companion.
Wait here tomorrow in the evening.
A good wife.
Mine will not bake for me ever again.
Why not?
How to tell you?
It's been two years I am gone and now my son was born.
- No more troubles then. - The only thing to please me.
We run away tomorrow.
What? Where shall we run?
Take everything out!
- How is this one doing? - Perfectly! He is a skilled painter!
It's a pity I can't keep you here.
There are battles on all fronts.
Now that everything begins so well.
Sixteen dead today.
I wish the war lasted at least three years longer!
You bastard! Do you know whom you?
Assholes!
Calaga Jan. Step forward!
Bachleda Jozef. Step forward!
Kolibec Viktor... step!
We only eat at command, did you forget?
Yes, I did.
What will you eat during the journey?
Emperor will take care of me.
I'll have a thundering good time.
Is that why he transports you in the pig wagon?
Why are the old soldiers transported like pigs?
And I... Why did he come here?
He may begin to smell foul!
One day. A certain captain Adler came into our wagon.
The Italians were driving us out of Monte Grappa.
Too crowded, so the captain was with us.
We were glad because he had been mean.
There was a lamp like the one here.
Light suddenly went out.
And in the darkness, who knows how.
The captain suffocated to death.
I know who killed him.
I was in the wagon. Tono Mikles.
- I did not do that. - I know.
You heard it but now you're boasting here.
From now on. You needn't lie.
Now I tell you who strangled captain Adler.
The dead ones did.
The hundreds of soldiers he sent to the grave.
And the survivors witnessed he had had a stroke.
I know you! Matej Frujak!
You were a lance corporal then and didn't wear a moustache.
Let's speak as equals now.
Wait. Corporal! We are not equal.
They believe you. Not us.
They let you have a gun. We haven't even got bayonets.
Don't take it to heart, we all will be sent to the front line.
What if we say: Enough!?
Those who said it are dead.
Those who betrayed them ended worse!
- Remember that! - I shall.
I'll think of it when you are being hanged.
We stopped.
Let them let us out. I want to go out!
You only?
Open. Corporal! We are not animals to be locked here.
I only can open it at the captain's command.
Go and ask him to give the order!
And we want warm meals! And drinkable water!
Ask him if we shall piss our pants!
Two of you accompany me.
You and the hero of Monte Grappa.
Captain. Corporal Frujak reports to you!
Good.
- And what about these two? - The ranks' representatives.
They ask warm meals and drinkable water.
Lo and behold!
Thank you.
How many we are! What a force!
I will come earlier. Prepare a bath for me.
Yes. Sir!
Do not forget, or I'll punish you!
Punish...
Marica, are you going?
- Where to? - To the station to welcome our people.
- Your people? - The Slovaks. Soldiers!
Soldiers again!
Maybe somebody familiar will come
and will tell me how my mother is.
All right. Go.
Why does she like him?
Excuse me...
Hello, Ervin.
I report my arrival from the camp recruitment.
Have a seat and speak.
The convoy has arrived.
I know. How many pieces?
- Five hundred and three. - Later, Ervin.
All right.
Danica, cognac please!
No! Turkish coffee!
Ervin is good.
Ervin is back. And the convoy is here.
Five hundred and three pieces.
The decay is obvious everywhere. The camps are full of Bolsheviks.
No fear! We shall clip their wings!
Austria is not Russia.
There will be alarm tomorrow, and then down and up,
down and up!
In two days, they will lick our hands.
But do not forget to isolate the recruits!
I have them over a barrel, major. So firmly.
- Anybody from Priechod? - Nobody knows but God!
What about somebody from Rajec?
- Are you from Rajec? - Why?
- Do you know the teacher Pagac? - So you're his son!
You have grown!
- I shall come and see you. - Do please.
- Who is it? - I have never seen him
but he can be of use.
Who are they, young lady?
The Tatra boys. The Slovaks!
A long journey. Poor boys, they must be hungry.
Hand them this, it suits you better.
Do it, I feel ashamed.
What of? Look!
Catch!
We got some snack!
A nice welcome by Kragujevac.
They could have used clean paper.
Wait!
It is not ordinary paper.
Brothers! Refuse to fight for Austria-Hungary.
Go over to the Serbians!
Gosh. What a Serbian snack!
- Was the parcel from you? - Oh no! From the Serbians!
We had enough poverty and hunger.
Think of your tearful mothers, wives and children!
Stop this fratricidal war!
Stop bloodshed!
Brothers. Lay down your arms! The Serbian Guerrilla Committee.
- What arms? - The pocket knives.
- What about our bare hands? - Nothing.
But we must know what to do when we get rifles.
Nothing. We won't get them before we're in the front line.
If we let them send us there.
Of course, one man can do nothing.
If all of us say no, they can't force us.
That's it. To become united!
The Serbians are in the mountains and hold on.
They are at home but we don't know the surroundings.
There are people hating the war as much as we do!
Here it is!
Attention!
I am looking... for... an acquaintance.
Welcome. Compatriot!
How are you? Have you been here long?
Over half a year. As a typist in the command.
It is up there. Isn't it?
Yes.
Why are there the two machine guns in the windows?
I do not know.
And when shall we be sent to the front line?
Don't ask me.
In any case. I must be going. I am on duty.
Attention!
- Well? - We are like in prison.
Neither we nor the recruits are allowed to go to town.
They fear we'll get lost.
- How many recruits? - The whole company.
The kids who are forbidden to talk to us.
Not to dull their minds.
We are about four hundred.
Most of us from the Russian captivity.
None of us will go to the front line.
I like that.
We all agree about not going to the front line.
But while the two machine guns are aimed at us,
when we stand in the yard as firm as a rock.
The two guns will knock us down!
What of it? The machine guns! I shall steal them tonight!
And put them under the pillow, nobody will notice that.
It's a pity you are not a general. The war might have been over.
The machine guns cannot disappear
but the pins from them can.
The machine gun cannot shoot without the pin.
What brains!
I would like to see the dupe who will dare to remove them!
I know a man who wanted to steal the whole guns.
First, we must copy the leaflet.
Get paper. Letters, or something like that.
Where shall we get paper?
Tono is the only one who can get it.
Assholes...
What's the matter?
I wonder why you are dumb in the evenings.
You haven't finished talking about this miracle.
Don't you believe it is gold?
I do but you said it was magic,
it fell from the heavens down to your grandfather.
Well. From the heavens...
My grandfather... he was young then...
he had neither a cow nor a goat. But a magpie.
- A magpie? - Magpie. The bird.
They were so poor they wanted to eat it.
One day. The magpie returned
and left this ring on the windowsill.
Then my grandfather's life turned out for the best.
He gave the ring to my mother. She gave it to me
and I will give it...
The night guards are having a good time.
We'd better go in.
Don't worry, I am here!
Come in!
Branko! Get in. Fast!
Branko...
Go out! Slow them up if they came back!
Your brother?
I suspected Branko was with the guerrilla fighters.
You must help us. We must get him to safety.
Well, see you!
Don't get up, the horses get startled.
- See you! - Let's go, Pista!
Do you fear your date will be hijacked?
Major. Are we going to search the garden.
We are looking for a dangerous guerrilla.
Guerrilla?
Here he is! Take him!
This is where major Von Dreznik,
a terror of Serbian guerrillas. Is staying.
I had six of them hanged the day before yesterday.
Leave!
More water.
Why is my bath not ready?
Sorry. I forgot.
- Not to forget again! - Major. Please!
Pack up and go to the barracks!
Tomorrow you begin to work with the Bolsheviks!
Inspection Officer.
- Come in. Tono. - Coming.
Wait here, in case somebody enters.
All right.
Here you are. Envelopes too.
There are many of us who want to write our wives.
- If you can. 50 at least... - All right, I fetch more.
And some ink into a bottle!
- And a pen! - All right!
My Lord, help me!
- I haven't got a small bottle! - Try to find!
- I've got it! - So have I.
Where there's a will there's a way!
- Bad to work in the dark. - It is!
Cripes. A swine slept here!
- Oh, here you are! - Here.
Here.
Thank you.
Play a merrier one. Or leave it!
Well, you are real poltroons!
Here you are. Wiseacres.
Write the leaflets.
Not to drag me through the mud anymore, here are the pins.
Is this how you enter?
The soldiers Durica a Badanik report arrival.
That's the way.
Choose whichever you want.
I bet it is him.
We saw a pretty girl at the station.
We wondered what her name was.
One said Anna. Another Jelka,
and the third one Katka...
Marica.
Company. Down! Up! Down!
Up!
One. Two!
Down!
Up!
At the double!
One, two...
About turn!
What is it, you bastard!
- Where is sugar? - Be reasonable!
I cook from the ingredients I get. Ask the officers where the sugar is!
Major. I report the first battalion is drilling.
There are 11 officers and 290 men present.
What is the next order?
The mob can make an awful scene
but if a grenade blew up nobody could catch them!
Quick march! One, two!
Right turn!
Order arms!
Nice, boys!
When the Italians see you, they will be scared to death.
About turn!
Shoulder arms!
- There was not time enough. - About turn!
Straight ahead!
Company halt!
Prepare to shoot!
Aim! Order arms!
- Now, the speech. - Yeah. Brainwashing.
I praise the fourth company for the nice drill!
Such soldiers are not scared of the enemy.
Your discipline is a paragon.
The old company will show even better discipline.
They need not feel ashamed.
- They need not! - Give us proper food!
We're starving!
We want to go on leave as the Hungarian infantry!
Stop the war like in Russia!
Step forward!
Those who want leaves. Step forward!
Nobody? Good!
The old company, down!
Up!
Down!
Get up! Up!
Son of a gun. Up!
Don't be silly, boy!
I won't get up. They must kill me!
Batman Badanik, step forward!
You too! You too!
- What did the batman say? - I don't know.
What did he say?
Quiet!
I won't punish this case but mind your mouth!
I am responsible for you to the emperor.
Leave!
- What crossed your mind? - I didn't want him
to maltreat you because of me.
But next time hold out your face.
At the double. And down!
You will remember this. Bolshevik mob!
You will find out what captain Deutsch is like!
Bloody tinkers and woodcutters!
Give the recruits cartridges!
Ervin, don't be silly.
One. Two! One. Two!
Down!
Up!
At the double!
Down!
Up!
At the double!
Together, men!
Given a whistle. We stop.
- Given a whistle. We stop... - Given a whistle. We stop...
One. Two! One. Two!
Down!
Up!
Get up!
For fuck's sake. Up!
Fuck you, up!
At the double!
Men, stay calm. Wait for the whistle.
Wait for the whistle.
Company halt!
The old company, down!
The fourth company, get ready!
Aim!
The old company, down!
The old company. The last time. Down!
The fourth company. Fire!
Oh. Jehovah Adonai...
The fourth company, get ready!
Company, quick march!
The old company. At my command,
muster!
Quick march!
- Why are you so chirpy? - We are resurrected!
And I was socked on the jaw!
Hello, old man!
- Where are you staying? - Here, at Grosnica. In the old manor house.
Good, we'll come and see you.
Here, give this to our men.
The password is The Tinkers. In case...
What case?
Oh my!
It's a scandal!
Such an officer must be taken to court martial!
I should slap your face and rip off your stars!
Stay in the barracks on Sunday.
I don't care if the Bolsheviks beat you up.
On Monday, you will present the rebels. Now leave!
Wait!
It is Colonel's birthday today. We are invited.
You will stay for an hour. No word about today's case!
Pagac!
My dear wife, I am a long way from you,
but I will come back even from the very end of the earth.
How is it going, boys?
Don't worry, you'll be all right.
You'll go home soon. Go to join your folks.
Viktor, come and see this!
Have your hand and foot ever been bound?
- Why? - I just wonder.
These men do it perfectly.
What is their intention?
The tinkers will probably be awarded medals.
Men, we are locked up!
The corridor door is locked!
And I aimed at him all the time.
When the lieutenant stood about twenty steps ahead,
I pulled the trigger and!
Wake up!
- Does Hojdak stay here? - Here!
Captain wants to talk to you.
Excuse me. With his mouth or hands?
You are asked to come too.
You are asked to come too. - Here!
I am looking for you too.
Well. Let's go.
- Where are you going? - Out. To post a letter.
You mustn't go to town! Come back!
Assholes!
Aside. Mob!
Captain offers us a glass of wine and a talk.
Go there or write. Here is the address.
Tell her not to worry.
Well!
Who whistled in the parade ground?
Do you know or don't you?
- I don't. - I don't.
- I don't.
Don't you?
Tell our men the things...
Quiet!
...are under my mattress.
We need men to force open the weapon storeroom door.
Are you crazy? It is an uprising!
It has begun this morning.
If we stop we shall be killed one by one.
Don't be silly! They are not to be hanged.
Tono and Hojdak can manage, but the boy will not stand it.
Let's go!
Don't suffer for somebody else. Say who it was.
This is for you to recall!
- Asshole! - What did you?
Asshole!
Don't beat him!
Don't beat him, I know who it was!
Who? His name?
I don't know but I can show you.
Let's force open the storeroom door!
What shall we do if there is no rifle?
- The recruits have them. - But without cartridges.
The recruits are locked up.
We must let them out.
Hojdak is being escorted.
Men. Disperse!
Friends. They are beating us!
Not so loudly!
Son of a bitch!
What happened?
Our men are being beaten. We must get them out of there.
Quiet. Men!
The two of us and other ten men go to the gate.
Select them! Tie those whom you do not trust!
I suggest to tie the corporal and both lance corporals.
No! If they betray us we shall kill them.
You will not.
All right. Join us to the gate.
We do.
We go to the gate together.
If we go together we shall be killed
by the machine guns in the middle of the yard.
The guns cannot shoot! Tono removed the pins.
Come here!
Fine. Four rifles more.
When they enter, stand behind their backs.
But carefully! If a shot is heard, we are lost.
To the door!
Attention!
Why are you fighting. Bastard?
Where did you serve in the Italian front?
With dogs.
What dogs?
Pulling sledges with gun machines.
Captain, please...
I think something is going on.
- Where? - The old company.
- What's going on? - They are being led away!
Hold out, tinkers!
Men. The rifles!
Alarm!
Damn it!
Open!
The machine guns!
Fire!
Where shall we question the captain?
Here. Or in the yard?
By all means. Here.
Jesus Christ!
Call the dragoons, they hate the infantry.
The rebels have cut off telephone in the whole town.
They are not stupid.
Unlike their commanders.
Post a battery of artillery to the front
and the Bosniaks to the side.
Not to make waves in the town. We let the rebels go out.
I prefer an open struggle in the field.
Oh my God, what is going on?
Nothing, madam, go on dancing!
We are strong because we stick together!
We want to finish this war!
We want peace like in Russia!
Who starves in this war? The poor! Our women and children!
Counts. Barons and manufacturers are not afraid of the war.
That is the fact our fathers had already known!
Who knows who we fight for?
For the rich people!
That's it, for the rich!
From now on, we shall do so for ourselves!
We shall gain different orders!
- How can we? We are few! - There are many of us!
We get in touch with our men at Grosnica.
And with the Serbians in the mountains.
The others will follow us.
But we must maintain order!
They shall not defeat us!
I think corporal Matej Frujak should lead us!
Nobody and nothing.
Where are those bloody bastards?
I would like to say goodbye to the major.
The major is mine. Such was my promise.
If I am not able to revenge. There are my related by blood.
That is our custom.
The murderer shall die by our hands.
Come.
Stipa. Come back to me!
Stipa, come back!
The liaisons from Grosnica have not come back yet.
I am afraid dragoons may have pounced upon them.
We must find out if we can expect some help.
- I am going there. - Don't hurry.
The roads are probably occupied.
You must cross the field.
There is a shorter way, along the brook.
- Do you know it? - I used to go there.
- Come. Stevko. - I am going too.
Go! I will stop the company near Grosnica!
Who shall we shoot at?
Everything is rubbish.
- Stop! The password! - Tinkers.
- Come in. - Have our men come?
They have. We are ready now.
Kolibec Viktor!
Closer!
- Dubnicky Ondrej! - Dead.
- Valovic Martin! - Missing.
- Gajdos Juraj! - Dead.
The first. The second - the third. Step forward!
Forty-three... forty-four.
Forty-four.
Take off your caps and shirts!
Julka, I wrote you I would come back
even from the very end of the earth.
I look forward to how our girl will be friends with me.
She will not.
She will never know her father.
I wish she never experienced such violence.
I wish she never experienced a war!
I promised Marica to come back.
You did a good thing.
She probably doesn't know what happened. That's better.
Better, Stevko.
She has come.
Stipa. Darling!
We wanted to go to my parents' house after the war.
You will be well off there.
We all will be well off.
There will be no more wars after this war.
People will become wise.
They will find a human speech.
Man will say to man:
What is the use of wars?
What is the use of killing one another?
THE END