Look at those bees.
They have been making honey
for thousands years
to keep their species alive.
One bee dies, another takes
its place.
They die because of frost,
diseases and people.
But the hive lives on forever.
The Slovak Film Institute
presents
THE MILLENNIAL BEE
Based on the novel
by Peter Jaros
Story:
Starring:
I do not remember we have ever
gathered honey in June.
We may have two crops
as in the Nile valley.
A birthday present for you.
The map of Europe.
Wow, Debrecen.
And here, Venice.
I still long for journeys abroad.
Leave then as soon as possible.
The Paris Commune started
a new era, with new countries,
old maps will not be valid.
On behalf of the firemen's guild
let me wish you all the best.
The golden helmet will protect
you from storms and fire.
From women's anger too?
There is no protection
against that!
It is worse than fire and water
together.
They are witches.
- No, Valent.
- Do not be scared.
You do not love me.
Once you are a student
you will forget about me!
I will not, if you are mine!
Oh my God, bees!
I love you all the same!
Look what you have done!
Dear friends, let me propose
a toast to Martin, our master bricklayer,
who has travelled
all over the world.
Bees!
We wish you all the best.
What is that?
Calm down, do not move!
They are but bees,
they will not hurt you.
They will eat us alive!
I shall smoke the bees to death!
Who is the asshole
who startled them?
Good afternoon, Father.
Run away!
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
You will see what a son
I shall give to Hungary!
Have a drink with me, Gersch!
I shall father three Hungarians!
I can make you a Hungarian!
I doubt you can,
I am a Jew.
I shall arrange it!
What kind of a Hungarian are you?
Your father was a Slovak.
But I am a Hungarian!
Give me the bottle!
You have one in Budapest.
One pen, one shepherd.
And an asshole with a sabre.
I shall get the bill
through the Parliament
that those who refuse to be
Hungarians
will be castrated!
What kind of a nonsense is that?
You were not a bad pupil.
But you are a bad teacher.
Hungarian is the official language.
Fools make speeches,
wise men love girls.
- You do look pretty.
- It is still aching.
Why do you not speak
our language?
Get out of the way!
Trying to sting a Hungarian
nobleman,
you, the bee of Pichanda?
Let her be or I will kill you!
I shall have you all arrested!
Come on!
Watch out!
No!
Bees sting, Belan!
- I was stung by a bee yesterday.
- Come on, Maria.
Kristina, where are you?
Come to dance to the ballroom!
That is Matej.
Speak to him at least.
He must not see me now!
Bloody bees!
The old wizard will stay
in the pub till the morning.
He thinks he is still young!
I am closing.
Mr. Gersch!
I want to convert
to your faith,
I will learn Hebrew and study
the Talmud.
Jozef, one must not betray
the faith of one's fathers.
One should keep it.
To hell with your fathers' faith.
You worship Yahve,
you Virgin Mary.
And I, as people say,
the whale.
Call Marta, please.
A farewell dance for Jozef.
A sad song.
He is joining us.
I would like to be a Jew.
And I a Christian.
Golden rain.
Yellow rain.
Pink.
And now green. Why not frogs?
Frogs, a French delicacy.
On June 20, 1896
I celebrated my sixty.
But I feel strong.
I still have the same thoughts
as forty years ago.
I even see similar signs.
When I went to work abroad
for the first time
and saw mushrooms sticking
out of snow.
I started to pick them up
and then I met Zelka.
Have you forgotten me, Martin?
No, I have not, Zelka.
Let us play cards.
I cannot. I must go to Debrecen.
We used to see each other
more often.
You are still pretty.
What is that? What is going on?
The fish has closed its mouth.
- What fish?
- A whale.
- Stop lying!
- You lied to me.
You married a richer girl.
Randomize them.
- What is going on?
- Do not worry.
When the fish opens its mouth
we shall run out.
Meanwhile, we can drink, eat
and play cards.
In good humour and Christian
understanding, Zelka and I spent
four days inside the whale.
I will not let you go!
I will come back, do not worry.
I will bring you such a scarf
that will attract bees.
No, no bees. Birds
and butterflies instead.
I know what is pulling you.
You'd better think of the grave
and eternal salvation.
And what else?
Mother, what is the matter?
Scissors!
Open your mouth!
Hold her head!
Here is the bastard.
God warned us.
He sometimes punishes
even the just ones.
Fish... What does that mean?
Women, perhaps? That could be.
Welcome, Martin.
I was dreaming about you.
About the time when we were
very young.
Do you remember?
- What?
- Oh, nothing.
You are still attractive.
and I am...
You wanton old devil!
Are you looking for a lover?
I have been atoning for our sin
all my life,
but now you, old goat,
want to tempt me again?
Just let us have a talk.
Do not be angry.
How about a game of cards?
Do you have a pack?
On St. Peter and Paul's Day
grass needs mowing
so we, the bricklayers,
become farmers for a while again.
The men go to meadows
to mow all the days.
Forgive me.
Women at home go to beds late
and get up early.
They bring meal to the mowers.
The men are sweaty, tired,
in need of a shave.
The women are affectionate then.
Kristina, does your mother
keeps an eye on you?
I do it myself!
- Stop! Give me a kiss.
- After the wedding.
- Give me your hand.
- On the wedding day.
- Then beat me.
- After the wedding.
Now. I cannot stand it anymore.
My dumplings!
Look what you have done!
We can clean them.
What turmoil was it in the pub?
As if you wanted a war
against the emperor.
Against monkeys, perhaps.
I read that the English claim
two African islands.
Pemba and Zanzibar.
They are very small.
Perhaps there will be war.
Because of the two islands?
Africa might be the reason.
Africa means wealth.
Did you cook this, Kristina?
She will learn when she marries.
Our wine has always been fine.
Young women, old wine.
I hear you are going to study
in Prague, Valent.
He would like to be a lawyer.
During holidays you could teach
my daughter German.
- Do you agree, Martin?
- He can decide himself.
I do not teach young ladies.
I will pay you.
The young Pichanda is here.
Welcome, Valent.
Leave us alone, Mother.
- Are you in love?
- No, I am not.
- And you?
- Me either.
But I would like to be.
- The textbooks?
- Will these do?
We'd better start.
Do you like me?
I am paid for German lessons.
Sure. But I choose the topic.
Love.
Where have you been?
I teach German.
You teach Hermina?
She wants you, you know?
I need every penny.
You know I am leaving
next month.
Is she prettier than I?
Do you not want me anymore?
I do, I love you.
Oh my God, you are
so beautiful...
Forgive me, oh Lord.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Samo.
Are you going to help us?
We can manage.
Are you joining your father?
There is plenty to do at home.
Go and earn a lot of money.
That is all my wife understands.
Gagos, is there going to be the war?
Three things are needed for it:
money, dough, and loot.
Suppose there is?
I would know about that.
Twenty-nine, thirty...
Leaving?
This will protect you.
Always and anywhere.
Gold?
To my teacher
from his grateful student.
Valent, this is her hair!
She wants to bewitch you!
You are the only one I love!
I shall not give you it!
Oh Lord, forgive me.
I shall not give you to anybody!
A ball lightning!
- Do not pull so fast.
- I do not.
Look.
Who did that?
That must be investigated!
A week before
St. Bartholomew's Day
a large glowing ball rolled
through our village.
All of us sighed with relief
when it was beyond the village at last.
But at the crossroads it hit the mill.
Fire!
My poor children!
Where shall we go?
Form a chain!
The mill burnt down
for the third time.
Come to the taproom, Marta.
We can make much money now.
The miller ended up badly.
The government should help him.
Everybody needs the mill.
Why are you moaning?
You have fixed wages,
and a pension on top of it.
If I am not dismissed!
It is all nonsense.
He is satisfied, can you see?
He has set fire himself.
Nonsense!
There is one poor man more.
I built him a chimney
the other day.
He has not paid yet,
and will never do so.
Now that we have the railway
we should build houses here
and send them by rail
all over the empire.
What for?
We could build Vienna and
Budapest here, by the river,
and then transport there.
We would transport nothing away
if Vienna were here.
I would open a bank
and employ all of you.
A bank? You?
He will ruin Rothschild.
Oskara, a banker!
Oh, Yahve!
We all are God's children.
The miller...
- Who knows where they are going.
- Somewhere to Hungary.
On St. Michael's Day, 1896,
I put together a team
of bricklayers,
maybe my last one.
There was Dropa, the barber
who cuts our hair,
then the Left-hander Svanda
whose left arm is stronger
and is used instead of
common sense,
Gunar, nicknamed the Sage,
Greben, nicknamed the Fish,
as he never speaks,
and my son Samo, nicknamed the Bee.
Finished. Next, please!
Come on, Jozef! Get him, boys!
I shall kill myself!
Do not worry!
The young Nader joined us too.
Still in love with the Jewess.
The barber's red-headed sister Stazka
joined us as a cook.
Good you are going with us.
Nobody will touch my sister!
Not another word or I shall give you
the trim like Jozef got.
Look, the sun is rising!
Go home, Zanzibar!
We did not have to come
here then.
How much do you want then?
Thirteen guldens each,
eighteen to the foreman.
The truth is somewhere
in between.
I propose ten to each worker,
fifteen to the master.
And I give you some advance.
Good. Give us forty
and we shall pay to our cook.
Damn! What an asshole?
- Who are they?
- The police will defend you.
We can manage ourselves.
Do not be scared of them.
What do you want?
You will not build here
until bricklayers' wages
are increased.
We are on strike.
It is none of our business.
I need money, I will work!
Wait, listen to him!
I have not a land as you have.
I only have what I earn
with my hands by the wall.
I have got four children
but I have not been working
for two weeks, as I believe...
You are workshy!
...the people like him
will yield at last.
You are right.
We can go to Tisovec,
there is work too.
Of course not! You got advance!
Here it is!
And this is for the beer
we drank yesterday.
You are silent but you help.
Men, we shall pay you some beer!
If I had Rothschild's millions,
I would assemble a bricklayer
driven by steam!
Sage!
Why are you laughing?
It would toil instead of us.
We all would become bankers.
We would eat, drink and dance
till daybreak.
The Left-hander is
already dancing.
I was stung by the bloody bee!
Why did you flail?
Lunch break!
I would like to be a bee.
I would fly and drink beer.
Without the passport
as far as Budapest!
I would not like that.
There would be no man
or a woman.
You know how the bees do it.
I do not. How do they do it?
Once in the whole life.
Mind your soup!
Have you ever kissed a girl?
My sweet fish.
I will give you anything.
What is going on here?
We are drinking milk.
Stop smiling or I slap you!
I can love whoever I want to!
If you only heard him sing!
I like him!
You are stupid!
He is mute as a fish.
Come on, sing us a song.
- Go ahead, sing.
- Sing, Juro.
God /oves the young ones
When they k/ss //ke doves.
O/d fo/ks have a bad score
/f they do not /ove anymore.
Water!
You are handsome now.
The pretty Jewess
will like you again.
I would not discourage you
even if he worshipped a whale.
What is that about the whale?
People say that about bricklayers
who go astray.
My and your grandfathers
once roamed as far as Madagascar.
By land and by sea.
There were no trains then.
What a country! Everybody naked,
and burnt black by the sun.
And the women there!
Incredible!
Your grandfather married
three of them.
How did they speak?
They taught the natives
the Slovak language.
Stop turning his head!
But it is true!
Our grandfather said it too.
What happened next?
There is no place like home.
Despite having many kids there
they returned home,
to our native place.
If all those black children
arrive here
there will be more of us
than the Austrians and Hungarians
together.
Who says the Slovaks have
no colonies?
Get up, men!
The Hungarian land is ahead!
Get up, lazybones!
Somebody has left his tools here.
Where is Jozef Nader?
He has longed for his Jewess.
He seems to have taken off.
What a bugger!
Who will do his work?
Let us move off, we may
catch up with him.
Let him be, we have much to do.
We had good luck at Miskolc.
We were hired by Baron Csernak
who had spent all his life
collecting pictures and statues.
In the hall there stood
a statue of Diana
which took the men's breath away.
Like Virgin Mary.
But with no clothes on.
You lecherous scoundrels!
Oh, what melons!
We made a good deal,
except there was no advance.
We got some female helpers instead,
swarthy girls from the south,
voluptuous, buxom beauties.
Would you like to have me, Julca?
- What do you say?
- Do you want him?
You are a good man
but Duri is better.
Better.
And what about me?
If you want to earn, go on building!
Work cannot be postponed!
What a crew of bricklayers you are!
After chasing women all night,
you cannot hold a brick
on the following morning!
Hear that, Fish? Sing now!
It was strange that the Baron
had vanished
and no one knew
when he would return.
Remember when we erected
the wall near Budapest
and the police chased after us?
Hopefully that will not happen again.
Do not worry, Sage,
we are no greenhorns.
Foreman, I have brought
you money!
Roll out a barrel of wine!
I was not sure I could get the money.
I had to gamble a day and night
at Mayhofer's and won!
Did you worry I would not come?
I both did and did not.
Some statues are very valuable.
Is my Diana away?
She is back in her place.
I underestimated you, foreman.
Julca, sing for these fellows!
Let them remember us well!
Nobody will believe us.
Not a word about that at home.
On the contrary, exaggerate!
Nobody will be able to distinguish
between the truth and lies.
I did it!
Let us go, bricklayers!
Let us go.
If I were not here,
you would be led astray too.
We are at home, jump down!
One day you will break
your necks!
I go as the first, Father.
Where is the boy pelting along?
To try his luck.
To see his beloved.
What can you tell me
about Jozko Nader?
He has been sitting at Gersch's
and drinking like a fish.
Your dog is waiting for you!
Zanzibar, you are here?!
Stop embracing,
our job has ended.
You can keep your money,
my daughter is not for sale.
I do not want to buy Maria.
- But she will be unhappy.
- Do not worry about that!
Where have you been so long?
Good-bye then.
If you prefer Belanyi...
Have a drink with us. I pay it.
Is everything all right, Jozef?
I arrived too late.
But she will have my child.
- Mine!
- We all are God's children.
Then why did you not let me
have her?
What is going on here?
He married her to a merchant.
- I shall kill myself.
- I too.
Stop drinking and get
some sleep!
You all but complain.
I am the Millennial Bee.
I know everything
about your forefathers,
about you and will know
about your children,
about your grandchildren
and great grandchildren.
Why do you not marry me?
No, I want Maria!
I shall take an axe
and kill them all.
Use your head instead.
Remember, you are a builder.
A builder...
He has walled her in.
You brought her up badly!
She is innocent!
Kiss me, let them see it.
Shall I punch you out?
Go tell it to the marines.
You have led me on!
It is the heathen Pichanda
who is responsible!
Come out, or I'll drown you
like mice.
My mother will never forgive us.
Die there!
Stop crying, Maria.
This is how my son, the Bee,
got his bride.
A month later there were
two weddings in the family.
Kristina married Matej,
and Samo married Maria.
Keep an eye on him.
I am an easy-going guy.
- And what about you?
- He gave me a fan.
My mother's grandmother
and your grandmother's mother
were cousins.
Well, will you join us
on the railway?
No. I prefer to be a bricklayer.
On the railway you get
regular pay.
Other people would be glad.
Children will come...
When bricking, I earn as much
as on the railway in a year!
You do look pretty!
Drunk into a stupor!
You will not leave anymore.
The stories with the whales...
What do you want?
You should not have married him.
After all, one day
you will be mine.
If you do not catch me,
I will not want you.
Why did you not write me?
Have you got another girl?
Kiss me. Do you not love me anymore?
Leave me alone.
All right then, but hurry up,
I am cold.
Oh my God, you are so beautiful!
The crazy Hungarian.
You did not give me Maria.
But I will find a woman for me.
Do you think you have won?
What do you want, Belan?
Mr. Belanyi for you!
Take it easy! Have a drink!
I shall castrate all who fail
to give Hungary sons.
- Me too?
- You too.
- And yourself?
- Myself too.
Go ahead. Show you are a man!
I will. Where is my sabre?
You had none.
The Belanyis will die out.
You have stolen my wife
and my sabre!
My thumb!
Pity he missed.
He might have made an ox
out of a bull.
For Heaven's sake,
I am bleeding!
You scoundrels!
Are you tired of life? Go home!
- Who are you?
- Jan Pichanda.
Matej, your nephew is here!
Janko, stop crying!
Let me see how many you have.
I am to pick more for you
than you can eat.
And where is Samo, your father?
On the railway.
- Some for Aunt Kristina too.
- Yes, for Kristina too.
If we got the eight-hour
working day,
you would be at home
with your young wife now.
At least this is what could
open your eyes.
Why should I criticize the people
who feed me?
Do they?
That is only the beginning.
Then the rise in your wages
and pension will come.
And when you are ill,
you will get money.
- Do you employ anybody?
- Anybody who is one of us!
What is it on your head?
Our cows allows only my wife
to be milked,
so when she is out,
I must deceive the cow
in this way.
Are you trying to deceive me too?
Here, read it and think of it.
We must have a child.
It is so sad without children here.
You know it does not work.
We can adopt one.
No. I want my own child!
Our child!
Wait...
Have you seen my Julo?
Strawberries in the winter.
Who was?
The last day of December 1899 arrived.
On the last day of the 19th century.
I parted with my pipe.
No fire or time has touched it so far.
It is midnight.
The New Year is here.
Father, a new pipe.
You may smoke in the new century.
It will certainly survive me.
- A happy New Year, Father.
- A happy New Year, son.
A happy New Year, Mother.
To you too.
I wish you good luck, Maria.
And you, my dear,
change your ways!
Oh, young men...
They will wake the children up.
A new era! New times!
They are in a sound sleep.
- This will be their century.
- What will it bring?
It must be better than ours.
The best that has ever been.
To the century of fraternity,
equality and liberty!
Valent wants to make us all equal!
Why do you think I study law?
Long live freedom!
Long live socialism!
Gentlemen, I drink to love.
Liduska...
I have been looking for you.
A parcel for you.
The parcel belongs to all!
- Who is it?
- A fool.
Help yourselves,
genuine Slovak cheese!
Why have you brought it here?
I could not stay at home alone.
All right. Shall we dance?
Leave some to us too!
Here is a letter.
Let us read it aloud!
In this way, damage bypassed us.
But it did not bypass
the old Ondrej Nader.
"Nader's son, Jozef,
who loved the pretty Jewess,
suddenly disappeared
and was found
hanged in the smokehouse
between sausages.
He was black like a native
Malagasy.
Let us take down a statement.
Will you help me?
Jozko, what have you?
No one else has died
and no young girl
has been raped.
Have a good time
and come home soon.
Sincerely yours
Father and the whole family.
Best regards from Hanka.
Who is Hanka?
My six-year old niece.
But you wrote her. Do not lie.
- He who lies...
- He... what?
Oh my God, you are
so beautiful...
Gently... gently...
Oh my Slovak man.
Come here, my little one.
He is hungry.
We are getting old,
it is time to think
of our eternal salvation.
We go to confession on Saturday.
Shall we buy him?
Jano has taken the scythe
away from me!
Do not worry,
you will not be sold.
Did you hear me, you old
cunning fox?
I do not wish such a pain
even to my worst enemy.
I have terrible rheumatics
in my knee.
Hurry up, Martin!
Do you not see I cannot bend
my knee?
You are not going then, are you?
I would not be able to kneel
and do not want to embarrass you.
You are so proud
that you will come to a bad end.
Come closer.
The comrade Karoly is to speak
about the resolutions passed
by the Socialist Congress in Paris.
We do not understand Hungarian!
The representatives of nine
socialist parties in Paris.
Stop it! This is our common cause!
Biro, go up there and translate.
Quiet! He is going to translate!
I speak Slovak. Silence!
The proletariats' demands
formulated by Jaurais
are based on the following points:
an eight-hour working day,
a ban on the child labour,
a fixed minimum wage
for workers,
because we all depend
on their labour.
Welcome, Fathers.
You seem to avoid the church,
so I have come to see you.
We must have a serious talk.
Then let us go to the bee-house.
It is a quiet place.
Some pests have been damaging
the crops.
- What is this?
- Nothing for you, Reverends.
Oh, Pichanda, Pichanda...
I have never seen you
in the confessional.
You care for the crops
but not for your soul.
Have a swig, Fathers.
But let me ask you something
as both of you are here.
Christians live here,
and Muslims here.
There are Buddhists, and there Hindus.
All believe in their own god.
Which of them is the right one?
There is the only God.
I think the truth is
in the middle
like the sting of the bee.
The truth is in each human.
You and your philosophising!
But your wine is excellent.
And the colour!
With this wine here
we can settle my confession.
A game of cards?
Preferans?
For a penny?
The old wizard made them drunk.
What have you for me?
They are carrying him in.
Matej!
- It is me, Julo Mitron.
- What do you want?
- I cannot live without you.
- You have a wife.
I do not want her.
She has given me no children.
I have none either.
Yet I live on.
I have been thinking of you
for ten years.
Waiting for something to happen.
When you got married
I almost died.
God forgive me.
When he was killed in the woods,
my inner voice said:
You deserved that.
You should not have married her.
Go away.
I shall leave Matilda.
Or I shall kill her
or you shall be mine.
Do not cry.
Here, for you. Do not forget me.
I will not.
Mother, your son is home!
Welcome, Valent.
Do you like lollipops?
There are so many children here!
Valent is here!
Samo, you have got a moustache.
And you a bow-tie.
Valent, it is nice of you.
Australia... and it is new.
How are the things in Prague?
Pretty lively, Father.
Is there going to be
a revolution?
The world has to be built
before it can be torn down.
We do not want to tear it down,
we are builders.
Sir,
my gracious master invites you.
What a handsome gentleman
you are.
Go to the kitchen.
I have capital and experience,
you are educated and have
a keen mind.
The factory is extending
production
and the old Wikelhofer has
offered me partnership.
I would like you to join me
in business.
But I have not got a penny.
I can lend you, I trust you.
When shall I pay you back?
You invest five thousand
and get ten thousand back.
Then you invest ten thousand,
and will get fifty thousand.
Then you will pay me back.
Or the things can develop
in such a way
that you will never have
to pay me back.
So late?
This is the third time
I have been here today.
Sorry, I was busy.
I know, you were
at Haderpan's place.
You will stay at home now,
won't you?
I do not know.
Everything is getting
more complicated.
I must serve people,
you know, justice.
I am a lawyer.
Are lawyers not allowed to love?
- Now? Here?
- Kiss me.
I love you.
You are still beautiful.
Give me a hug.
God forgive me.
Poor children...
- Your mother saw us.
- Never mind.
You are divine,
better than others.
So you do love me after all.
You will be a businessman,
after all.
I have not decided yet.
I must discuss with you first.
You do not need our advice.
You have already made
a decision.
- They will want you to get married.
- I shall not marry Hermina.
Do you want to make me drunk?
I can stand much.
We shall see.
Do you want to seduce me
with this?
Show me what it hides!
Let go of me!
Sorry.
I know you do not love me.
I have been loving you
for a long time.
I am still a virgin.
Oh God, you are so beautiful.
I feel embarrassed
when you are looking at me.
Friends, our efforts,
our skills,
and our money are changing
the world.
If we defend our capital well,
we shall become a great nation.
Toast to my wife, Hermina.
I hope she will defend me.
May I have this dance?
That is nothing for us.
Good-bye, freedom!
My dear children,
you go together well.
I never dreamt of this.
They will get along well, Martin.
I have rented a house for them
where they can bill and coo.
Let us hope so.
May a dove fly over your nest,
May you make love full of zest.
Here is a golden crown for bride,
The groom is full of pride.
May a bonnie child arrive one day,
This is what I wish to say.
Sacrilege!
You have pinched the crown
from the church!
From the statue of Virgin Mary!
You will burn in hell!
Valent is right, times are rough.
The young blood is needed
to cope with this world.
If I had your money
I would discover another America.
I can lend you.
Go and discover a rich island.
I will buy it then.
How much do you need?
What did you say?
I cannot hear a thing.
It is that buzzing.
When it does not suit him,
he is deaf.
I really cannot hear anything.
The sea.
The men keep chasing you,
Kristina.
I can see it.
I live an honest life.
You need a man, a husband.
I am fine alone.
I know a good, pious man.
- Who?
- Dropa, the Barber.
The old Barber?
He lives alone as you do.
A young widow invites sin.
I shall find a way for you!
And you, stop pretending to be deaf.
She must get married!
The eve of St. Vincent's Day,
1905, was very cold.
Even while writing my fingers
are numb.
I was listening to the bees
in the hive.
They are still alive.
Incredible!
Zanzibar, have you ever seen
anything like this?
Frozen!
Why is Slovakia not
on the equator?
Black beasts.
The wine is frozen.
Do not catch a chill, Samo.
Work keeps me warm.
I am frozen to the bones.
What is wrong with the dog?
It has frozen too.
This is hard too.
They never shut the windows.
Wine...
It is warming me up.
What is the old wizard doing?
Go upstairs, children.
Grandpa has fallen down!
- Father!
- Oh my God, what happened?
- Blood!
- That is wine.
He has swallowed a piece
of glass.
What happened? He is not breathing!
For Christ's sake!
Come, Mom.
My poor old man!
Zanzibar!
His track ends here.
He could not have disappeared.
Maybe he followed grandpa
up there.
Up there?
Where is he laid out?
You were a good chap.
Too bad you have gone so early.
You led us all over Hungary,
as far as to Vienna.
Do you remember when he set out
for Debrecen
and ended up with his girlfriend?
In the bowels of a whale.
Our Martin seems to have grown
now that he is dead.
The coffin is too small.
He has grown in it,
has become larger.
He was as tall as I.
In the army we were
the same size.
If I had something to measure...
Without the shoes!
Watch if someone is coming.
- What happened?
- It jumped out.
As I said, he has grown taller.
Somebody may grow after he dies.
Life kept pressing him down,
now that he is dead,
he is relaxing and stretching.
Stop chattering!
Go to the door!
Someone is coming! Hurry up!
For Heaven's sake,
let us run away!
Through the window!
Hold!
Have a drink in father's memory.
To his health.
- We worried you would not come.
- I am a busy man.
Did he mention me
before he died?
He died alone.
Alone? How could you?
Slow down, we are going downhill!
The coffin is sliding down!
I cannot hold it any longer!
Stop!
Father does not want to go
to the grave.
If the stream was not frozen
it could take him to the sea.
Maybe as far as Madagascar.
Mother should keep the house
and a part of the land.
We can share the rest.
As you think.
You have four children.
You can rent my part.
You will pay me back
when you have money.
Thanks.
- And you, Kristina?
- I need nothing.
Matej left me enough.
Wait, I will see you home.
I hear Hanka is expect...
Could you give her money
from me?
You have to do it yourself.
Or have you lost courage?
What do you want?
Had I known you were
expecting...
No! No!
I will support you both.
The child will not have
a father.
I will bring it up myself.
Go away!
I hate you!
I only wanted to help.
I had better be dead
and not to have met you.
God almighty! What is this?
A fallen star, I guess.
Damn it!
It is hot!
It is iron.
Nothing!
It is hard.
Go to bed.
I know where you have been.
With Kristina!
I prefer to poison you
not to suffer!
What nonsense is it?
I did not mean it!
Do not be cross.
Julo... I love you.
Where have you been?
They want to marry me off.
You must not get married.
If Matilda and I had children,
I might leave you in peace.
Look, what I brought you.
A heart.
I have forged it from a star.
Salty.
Dear Kristina,
we are meant for each other.
Julo, my Julo...
This is the last one.
Drink, men, Belanyi pays today.
What do you need so many
horseshoes for?
You will never be able to wear
them out
even if you put them
on your own hands and feet.
I shall shoe a regiment.
Yet there will be one left
for your mouth.
Better save two
for Austria-Hungary.
The empire has been hobbling.
Will you, the Hungarian yeoman,
put up with that?
The bell tolls for you, socialists.
We shall not spare any.
I am shaking with fear.
Six hundred sixty horseshoes
make forty-six guldens.
All right.
Put one gulden more.
Wait!
Do not worry, blacksmith,
the army will pay
for everything.
That was not the deal!
Is the word of a Hungarian gentleman
not good enough for you?
We cannot eat words.
If you have no money, get off!
Have you gone mad, blacksmith?
Who do you think you are opposing?
Load the goods!
Look out, Palo!
Here is your helmet!
I shall show you who is
the master in this land!
Greedy lot!
You will pay for this!
I shall denounce you!
What will happen if he does so?
He would not live to see
another day.
The police are coming!
Let us run to the brook!
Come back!
Run away, they beat everybody!
Here we are.
Police!
They are approaching the mill!
Hurry up and tell your father!
Let us hurry up home!
The Hungarian bastard!
I am back at night!
Do not look back!
This is my death-bed.
I have not done anything bad!
I am innocent!
Policemen!
With sabres!
He has done nothing bad.
What is going on here?
You have done nothing bad,
they must set you free.
Let him be!
Daddy!
Now you stopped laughing
on the other side of your face.
I will pray for you!
Your buzzing has stopped,
you bee of Pichanda!
You think you can act as if you were
on familiar terms with the emperor!
I do not understand.
Speak Hungarian!
Are you a Social Democrat?
Yes, I am. Is it illegal?
It is not,
but you have insulted
His Majesty,
the Austro-Hungarian emperor.
It counts as conspiring
to incite a riot.
What riot?
You bully working people.
Sit down!
Shut up! You are impudent!
My eye...
Who could have thought?
Bloody Hungarian shorty!
He would let us hanged
for a couple of horseshoes.
You must keep to this theory.
Deny all the rest.
It was a row over horseshoes,
no political statements.
Belanyi has no witness.
Samo, have you gone mad?
Why do you meddle in politics?
You should have kept your mouth shut
about the socialists.
- That is my business.
- Your business?
You forgot I am a lawyer?
That I have a high position
and reputation?
What reputation?
Hanka died during miscarriage.
I did not know that.
Why are you staring at me?
I offered her help.
I will do my best.
Somebody helped him.
Do you hold well?
He is heavy.
Is that Belanyi?
Yes, that is him.
Whose well is it?
Mitron's.
He is in prison.
Who could have done it?
He asks who it did.
He must have fallen there himself.
He was always drunk.
Look, a naked woman!
I have seen such.
When we were bricking.
Silence! She is coming.
My husband is not in
and I have no time for you.
Is he chasing girls?
Good morning.
Welcome, Samo.
How dirty they are.
Are they robbers?
No, it is your uncle.
We came to thank Valent.
He did not take any actions.
Belanyi drowned himself.
Well, we will not keep you long.
Give our regards to him.
Samo, you can stay.
Why do you not sit down?
Thanks, we had been sitting
long enough.
Let us dandle it.
Anosta and Pichanda!
Give your tools back and leave!
- What is wrong this time?
- You do know very well.
You foment a rebellion,
and Pichanda was in prison.
You still owe me the last pay.
Ask your socialists to pay you.
They will grant you a pension too.
And here is your pension,
bastard!
Help! Put me down!
You are assaulting a public official!
The yoke is loose.
- Why do we plough?
- To have grain for bread.
Plough me in,
I shall turn into cakes.
Bread is one of man's
best inventions.
Father, look!
What is it flying over there?
- Bats!
- In daylight...
Catch me one, I shall draw it.
Do not be frightened.
How pretty you are!
Karol, draw us, not birds.
Birds are prettier.
Have you ever seen
something like this?
The moths have eaten the bees.
Strange things have been
happening in the world.
If it does not rain,
we shall have no bread.
You are right.
Have a nice day, Mr. Pichanda.
Do you know about some work
for bricklayers?
The situation is very bad.
Try in the Hungarian land.
And is there going to be a war?
Three things are needed for it:
money, dough, and loot.
Suppose there already is?
On St. Joseph day, our houses
and fields were flooded.
I took a washtub
and went for a row with the
children around our house,
when our Lord let us have
the sea for a while.
Oh, the sea...
Where is the water now?
The men want me to join them
to America.
Greben and the Fish go
to Pittsburgh.
I could earn lots of money.
I shall not let you go.
I would die here without you.
Your God does not give us rain.
In America, gold falls
from heaven.
Not now.
The baby is on the way.
- It will be a girl.
- A girl.
We shall name her Maria.
The sun set the grain on fire!
Pichanda's grain is on fire!
It is raining!
I am all wet.
Close your eyes.
You stung me with your nose.
When I grow up
I will buy you a ring.
- A genuine gold ring?
- Genuine.
Lovers, lovers!
Matilda is going to take a bath.
Water, water!
Julo, come!
Come inside, Matilda!
Stop making a fool of yourself.
Something white is falling!
Ice.
Hail...
We complained about the drought
but then heavy hail
destroyed the little crop we had.
Many men decided to go
to America.
I made another decision.
I put together a team of bricklayers
like my father used to
and we set off to the south.
This is not our train!
Americans, get off!
Which is ours?
Hurry up! It is moving!
Daddy, come back!
My feather has blown away.
Catch it, Eva!
Here you are!
Besides the old ones,
the Left-hander, the Genius
and the Barber,
we took our sons along,
the young Svanda, and my eldest
boy Jano.
Anosta joined us too,
as he was fired.
Do you not perforate
the tickets?
For such a wage?
I do not give a damn
about the railway!
We should have known that!
You would not have gained anything.
Perhaps, you will go on foot.
- Why?
- We are on strike.
We will not be paid the fares
back, I suppose.
I am going to complain.
In vain.
We were fired,
but they strike.
Our time will come.
Let us ask those men.
Is there any job
for bricklayers?
Job?
Look, so many people,
all jobless!
They are as poor as we are.
The land belongs to those
who work and cultivate it!
If the farmers back
the proletariat,
landless peasants will not be
exploited any more.
The land will be parcelled out
and given to the poorest!
Let us join them!
I came here to make money,
not politics.
The Left-hander is right.
We do not belong here!
You are wrong,
this is our place.
Palo, stick to me!
Daddy!
It is going to be hot here...
Where is Janko?
Come! Fast!
Janko, get down!
Hide yourself!
Give me a hand.
What are you doing?
Have you all gone mad?
Dad is back!
- What is that?
- Try it. Potato sugar.
Mommy, look, sweets.
Where is Janko?
No! No!
Where did you leave our Janko?
He will not be lying here
anymore.
How can one disappear so easily?
Grandpa's dog vanished too.
I saw Eva crying.
- I will marry her.
- No, I will.
Stop it!
Where was your God
when Janko was shot?
It is a decisive meeting.
A common meeting
with nationalists.
We shall show them
what socialists can do.
Leave me alone.
It is a great day for us.
Hurry up.
We are going to be late.
I quit with politics.
We fight those who killed
your son.
If we win, nobody will ever
shoot at people!
Your Janko did not die in vain.
- He was my son.
- We all are sons.
- Karol has drawn Eva!
- That is not her!
Her hair looks like Eva's.
Come and have a look.
He has also drawn this.
Are you going with us?
Get out!
You too!
As you wish.
Naughty boy!
Just like his grandfather.
God forgive him.
If you draw ugly things,
you shall not get to heaven.
Is Eva ugly?
- Fetch me some water.
- Painter, shame on you.
Put my boots off, Samko.
Where are the grandpa's
pictures?
Grandma, are you all right?
She is in heaven.
They are together now.
I have financial problems.
My father-in-law's money
was not enough.
I invested too boldly.
I need my money from you.
Now when mother is dead...
if you want to keep the house,
you will have to pay me back.
You are mad.
When our father died, you said...
I could give away,
because I was not rich.
If I fail to put together
all my assets now,
I am lost. Try to understand me.
Shall I understand you?
We have nothing to eat!
Why did you get mix up
with the socialists?
You could still work
for the railway.
- You...!
- Daddy...
- Are you Karol?
- No, Peter.
Do you like the watch?
Keep it, a present
from Uncle Valent.
Thank you.
Look, Father.
No! My watch!
Stop crying, I will buy you
another one.
But I want this one!
I shall repair it.
- Do not worry.
- I am scared.
We have grown poor,
and the world is getting worse.
Father, what would you do now?
Would you make jokes, or dream
of exotic islands?
We have nothing left,
no house where to live...
Zanzibar is back!
- Grandpa's dog!
- That is not him.
Where are you?
No, Samo, no!
The dog has led me to the mill!
But the mill burnt down twice
and the millers committed suicides.
I am not scared.
We shall be fine here,
you will see.
Kristina, my little darling,
come here.
Matilda... welcome.
Come in.
We have a potato soup.
- Why is she crying?
- She is hungry.
You did not chop wood for me.
He will.
He is hungry too.
Only God us do part.
Or death.
Have you ever thought of that?
- Are you moving?
- To the mill.
Father, my watch works.
They have brought in our bees.
It is really ticking.
You are very handy.
- I have repaired it.
- Let me see.
It is the one from Uncle Valent.
You will become a master.
I know a watchmaker,
a good chap and a Social
Democrat.
Propaganda again?
This is where the bees
will be buzzing!
I want to go to America too!
Take us with you!
Do you not worry you could
burn down as your predecessor?
It has happened to me
several times.
I tell you something.
I worry about the future
of the Slovaks.
Some say they are Hungarians,
some Germans...
Those over there leave
for America.
What will be with us
ten years later?
We shall fit under a wagon canvas.
Do you think there will be
nobody to whom to mill?
There still will be
enough people.
You have children at least.
You are their teacher.
What are they like?
Peter is clever with his hands.
And Samko will take over your mill.
Peter will become a watchmaker.
And Karol will be
a great painter.
I almost forgot.
I have paints and canvas for him.
He must study at the Academy.
- Thank you.
- Not at all.
He has a great talent.
I had dreamt of becoming
a painter
...but what am I now?
A bad teacher.
I am far from having made
my dream come true.
Work!
It is starting!
It is running!
What a machine, isn't it?
Put a trough underneath!
- Wow, it is falling!
- Raise it!
Eat, good ghosts!
It is so soft!
And watch over us well.
She was so scared, and now...
I am going to bake bread
right now.
This is for cakes.
Children, it is a God's gift.
You have become a businessman.
Prepare some chests
for all the money.
Oh, forget it.
I, a businessman?
What is a businessman?
Uncle Valent is one.
Shall we be rich too?
Would you like to be rich?
You all will be trained
in useful trades.
Back to school again?
I would rather be rich.
To better times in the new mill!
Cheers!
Kristina, cheers!
Hurry up, Marta, serve the drinks!
Why are you closing your eyes?
Why are you pricking me?
- I? I am shaven.
- You do it with your nose.
Father wrote me to join him
in America.
Would you like to go with me?
What will you give me?
Let us go right now
by a steamer across the ocean.
- Are you afraid of it?
- No!
Catch me then!
But I am supposed to take over the mill.
Then I shall go
with another boy.
I would follow you to the ends
of the earth.
Let us get married.
Do you want me?
Yes, I do.
Turn around.
Do not look!
I am not looking.
I will be yours
till the day I die.
Kiss me.
I am dizzy.
The whole world is spinning around.
Instead of coming back,
your father takes you from me.
- Why do you not go?
- Who would stay here?
Will we ever see you again,
Samko?
Eva, give my regards
to you father in America.
Let him not forget
that we are relatives.
Remind him of his promise
to send me a ticket.
Then I shall take a ship
for America.
To become a banker.
If Grandfather were alive,
he would join us.
The life seems somehow
sadder now.
My father used to build
even in his sixty.
The world was different then.
We only can be saved fighting
against capital.
- The proletarians must...
- You and your politics!
And you had better go to balls
instead of meetings.
Obey your father, watchmaker.
Look, what a machine!
I have already seen such.
- It is called automobile.
- What does he want here?
That is your uncle.
When I win the lottery,
I will buy one too.
Sister-in-law...
Why did you not let us know?
What a nice mill you have!
Having made you sell the house
I helped you.
- Kristina... yours?
- As you see.
You know Hermina.
But you have not seen
this one yet.
This is my daughter, Hilda.
Why don't you come and see us?
I am too busy.
Your son is getting married,
- but I have no present.
- No need.
Is that Karol's work?
- How is he doing at the Academy?
- We seldom hear from him.
You have moved our father's
bee-house.
Our old bee-house.
Maps, engravings...
How small everything seems.
You are big now.
I needed the money badly,
but then I invested well.
Now I can help you.
I have a special order
from the army,
my business has been
flourishing.
My mill too!
It is nice here.
Watch out for the bees!
Like back then when Father
turned sixty.
Come here to take pictures!
Let us go.
Do not touch it,
you will dirty it!
We all will be in the picture.
Steady!
Say cheese!
Let us hide!
My hat! Catch it!
Hold the horse!
Pray, everybody.
The Day of Judgement!
Miller, are you in?
What is going on?
Shut the door!
It has finally happened.
Did dogs tear you, Gagos?
The successor to the throne
has been assassinated in Sarajevo.
Where did you hear that?
Believe the old Gagos.
There is to be a war.
Do not believe that!
They will only shoot a little.
They will teach the Serbian
rabble a lesson!
I hope you will not be laughing
on the other side of your face.
The war is good business
for them.
I think that they will involve
the whole world in it.
The Socialist International
will not allow that.
You cannot imagine
what our party can do.
Your party will not give
a damn about us.
Poor people will be killed,
as always.
Our boys, then we.
We, the bricklayers,
can benefit from the war.
We will be busy with ruined
houses twenty years.
What if a bullet finds you?
The death even avoids me.
Teach the Serbian mob a lesson!
Long live the war!
At them, boys!
Why do you not join the army?
If I were your age, I would
do so right away.
It is an honour to fight
for our fatherland.
I cannot. I am a Russian spy.
What did you say? Follow me!
Let him be!
They are my apprentices.
What do you want from him?
Release me!
Let him be!
The other one too!
Soldiers!
Open the mill!
From now on you will grind
for the army!
Open the mill, we bring corn.
You will grind for
the Austrian-Hungarian Army.
I have more work
than I can manage.
I leave several men here,
you have three days to do it.
What shall I get for that?
It is your patriotic duty.
We confirm that you work for us,
and you will stay at home.
Give orders to your soldiers,
not to me!
I shall not do that!
Csolle!
What do you want? Blame it!
Let him be!
Samo, they will kill you!
They will harm you,
do not go against them!
We can seize your mill.
At your service!
Ten men to assist the miller!
Lieutenant is a tough man,
be amicable.
Hold on, boys!
Use your heads.
Even a horse would die here.
Here, have one.
Vavro, I am deserting.
It is now or never!
No!
Captivity is worse than death.
- I hope you will not regret!
- The Russians will kill you.
Better than to be dying here.
I am going too.
You will be shot dead!
The whole Vienna can kiss my ass.
Have a nice time here, Vavro.
Goodbye, Austria.
Deserters! Shoot!
Stop them!
We are Slovaks! The Slavs!
We are alive!
This is the second night
I dreamt of my dead father.
He was sitting at table
with our children
and I was shooting at them.
It was breaking my heart,
but I was doing it anyway.
Pray.
The dead call the alive,
but we are helpless.
If I had not the mill,
I would now be killing people.
Who knows why.
What a wonderful horse!
Would you make an equestrian
statue for me?
- Who will pay?
- The army.
Here you see our students
working on a classical composition.
Nice.
An armchair!
Painting is a nice job.
Une chose interessante!
You are doing a fine job, boys!
But now, your motherland
does not need
your gift and hands,
it needs your brave hearts.
Inter arma silent musae!
Remember that well.
Translate that, student.
In a time of war...
the Muses fall silent.
A Slovak! I like the Slovaks.
Fight bravely!
We shall meet
in the battlefield, boys!
Go on drawing!
Goodbye!
Take care of yourself!
Remember us!
The worst thing is gas.
It killed my son in the trench.
Drive!
The belt pulley!
Dear Father and Mother,
I wanted to become an artist,
but it is not sure
since I must wear a uniform.
The Left-hander's son is here.
He takes it easy.
The world has thousands faces,
I draw them whenever I can.
I would prefer not to sleep at all.
At night, memories haunt me.
Your faces, our village
as I saw it when I was small.
Look into the shed
and under the floor!
That is all.
- What do you keep in the shed?
- Your grandmother!
Look there!
Even the bees have more sense
than we, they sting at least.
Dear Samko,
I tried to find in the map
where the wind had carried you.
You probably have not heard in America
about the war, that kills people here.
When you were born,
we used to cut grass up
in the hills
and carried you in a sheet,
since you could not walk yet.
Oh my God, the postman!
Go away!
- Our Julo is still alive.
- Thanks heaven.
That is all right.
Oh my God!
They got him!
You killed her!
Take it easy.
We must survive.
We just have to break the war's neck
the way the Russians did.
But we are stupid
and let the emperor die in bed.
If I had dynamite,
I would blow up all military transports.
- Other trains would come.
- But not through this tunnel!
Why do you not shoot generals
instead of the poor?
- Halt!
- What do you want?
No trespassing!
- We cannot even walk here.
- He would surely fire.
What a rat!
Welcome, Your Excellency.
I am glad to see you, sir.
Your leather is the basis
for our war success.
I am glad you are pleased.
Where is he?
Faster!
Hold this!
- What is that?
- A few grenades.
Easy, or it will blow up.
You are an anarchist.
What do you need them for?
We shall see.
Enough to blow up
the railway station.
I know what to do
with them.
Whoever is hungry he is invited
to join us.
There is going to be
a dinner party.
You all will eat.
I am going to treat you.
Samo is raving like his father.
Join us, Father.
We are going to feed the hungry
just like Jesus Christ.
That is blasphemy!
I am going too!
Father, surrender!
- Which one has arrived?
- Karol.
Welcome home, son.
Unharmed?
Thanks God, he is all right!
The Italians attacked us with gas.
We nearly went blind,
so I am on leave now.
- What have you got there?
- Grenades.
Come, you know how to handle them.
Mother, there is going to be
an explosion!
Matilda, come along!
Fish!
Look at all the fish!
Watch the bones!
This table has been set for you.
Eat and enjoy yourselves!
Come everybody, join us.
Nobody will cry or starve anymore.
We shall all meet in the land
where the sun never sets.
Welcome!
Slovaks!
This table is set for you.
You have been hungry too long.
Wine and dine,
and be happy for a thousand
oncoming years...
- Where do you come from?
- Madagascar.
So you are at home at last.
What about a game of mariage?
Look at our country.
- Beautiful, isn't it?
- Like a paradise, Dad.
The party is not over yet.
Our leave is over, we must go.
Take care of yourself.
The time has passed
like a dream.
When shall we see you again?
A few shots more, then we are
back at home.
Biro died, the railwayman.
You too...
Are you in?
A wire.
Sign here.
Read.
You put too much salt
into the soup.
Now we are both alone.
Let us stick together!
- Are you alive, Palo?
- My leg hurts like hell.
The main thing is we survived.
Doctor, I cannot feel anything.
Change the bandage, nurse.
Advanced gangrene.
- Will you cut my leg off?
- Have a rest now.
Have a sleep.
I prefer death
to the life with one leg!
No!
I do not want!
Go to hell!
I shall not have it cut!
Leave me alone!
No, no...
My leg...
Scream, you will feel at ease.
I do not want it to be done!
Lift him!
Karol, I do not want!
They have cut off my leg.
Do you hear?
Karol!
We have honey, fine and sweet,
For Saturday and all the week.
- Are you not glad?
- I am.
Not now, Marek.
I do not remember we have ever
had so much honey.
There used to be even more!
Do not write all the time, Dad!
- Now look what you have done.
- You threw it in there.
Wait!
You will be sticky.
Let it be!
Honey is all over your body.
I could eat you, you are so sweet.
What is in it?
Do not tell my wife.
He must have died in hospital...
I have my grandfather's chronicle!
...since they are sending his things.
Some leave even less stuff.
I have been bringing bad news
almost to every house.
They brought us delicious
watermelons.
Suddenly a strange thing
happened.
The farmer's wife popped her eyes out
and stuck out her tongue.
Can you hear, Father?
It is funny.
The men were staring,
thinking she had gone mad.
But I took a knife
and made a hole in her throat.
Only then could she take a breath.
She would have died,
as a bee had stung her
in her tongue.
Such a small creature,
but it can kill a human.
Think then what man can do.
Anything.
If he wants to.
Father...
Where are your boys, Samo?
None has left.
These are bad times
when fathers outlive their children.
Take the hive, do not worry.
The bee is born to build
and when its life is threatened
it defends itself using its sting.
- Even at the cost of its own life?
- Even then, my son.
Do not go away, my son.
The war is not over yet.
A bricklayer works
in bad times too.
We are going with you, Father.
We all shall go.
All of us.
Get up, we are going to work!
Bricklayers, we have a job!
Samo Pichanda is our leader!
I have brought you your coat.
We are going to block
the tunnels!
We shall wall them up.
To our victory!
Vivat Austria!
Emperor, look!
Focus your field glass.
What is he doing there?
Halt! Come back!
Come here!
Halt, or I shall shoot!
Whistle.
Just whistle.
I am waiting for you.
Come on, gentlemen,
the table is set for you.
Cast:
Executive Producer:
Director of Photography:
Directed by:
Edited by:
Patrik Pass, Judita Fatulova
Music:
Petr Hapka
Sound:
Pavol Sasik
Made by Slovak Film
Bratislava - Koliba
-= www.OpenSubtitles.org =-