Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
I was still young then,
living in my father's house
And having a great time like in paradise
But once when the wind blew
the smell of the sea
I couldn't resist my desire
to go far away.
I left behind the comforts of home,
and went in search of adventure.
We were sailing for so many days and
nights that we couldn't count them.
But the sea means not only white clouds
and clanging strings.
Soon our fate played
a different song for us.
All our reserves were used up.
And nothing but sea and sea
all around us.
In vain were we looking for a shore.
And longing to see a piece of land
on the horizon.
All our hopes were lost.
We didn't even dare to think
that this could go on.
The dark phantom of hunger
was hanging above us
Over the immense endless sea
there death was grinning
Only fishes could save us
from starving to death.
The sea was full with them.
But how to catch them?
The last fishhook...the last hope.
The evil mark of inevitable fate
reminded us again of the sad end.
We were lying on the ship
overwhelmed by starvation,
Watching greedily those beautiful fishes.
We were envisioning them on barbecue.
But they were swimming too far
from us and couldn't be caught.
They may have felt we had no
good intentions toward them.
One night a big fish came to our ship.
I collected my last strength
and tried my luck.
Finally...
Fate was on my side.
But what a wonder!
The fish talked
It was only whispering
but still, it was talking.
It begged and asked for release
It promised me a reward,
the nicest one the sea can give.
To a hungry poor fellow like me
it offered a huge fortune.
No one was watching
and I always was a good guy.
It persuaded me after all,
so I let it go.
And I did right.
The reward was worth it.
Next morning I felt sorry for my deed.
But before I could confess
to my hungry mates...
Land!
Far from us and surrounded by sea
there was a beautiful island
We saw a lot of coconut trees
And we believed that we were heading
for a paradise
Which would end our suffering.
We had nuts galore
But hunger made us so week
That we couldn't break a single one.
blood
Blood was gushing from the soil.
Nothing but blood...a waterfall of blood.
We soon understood
This wasn't an island
But the back of a huge whale.
It had been sleeping there for ages
so a palm garden blossomed on it.
The strike with the axe woke it up.
And it was too bad for us.
The sea swallowed our ship
and my friends too.
Even I was going down.
I was desperate and saying goodbye
to life already.
But my lucky fate brought me to the fish
Which I had set free.
It saw me and recognized me.
And my only good deed
redeemed me.
Before I could think
it took me on its back
and brought me to the surface.
It was about time.
I badly needed to breath.
I couldn't last any longer down there.
We were swimming nearly a whole day
and when the sun was setting down
We finally reached an unknown shore.
It didn't look welcoming but I was glad
to have a firm land beneath my feet.
I was crying with joy.
No
No one will ever make me return
to the sea.
Farewell fish
Thank you for your help.
I don't want even to hear about adventure
any more.
I feel good here.
This old and wise elephant
had mercy for me.
And brought me on his back to the city.
Suddenly I sensed the sweetest
smell in the world.
The smell of fresh bread.
But fate wasn't done with me.
That night a thief slipped
into the sultan's palace.
He stole all the sultan's treasures
down to the last coin.
And no clue was left of where
gold, jewels, and thief were gone.
When the sun
rose in the sky the next day
I was still sleeping peacefully
But not for long.
The steps of the sultan's guard
were rumbling around me.
I couldn't understand what was going on.
Why were they coming around me?
Why are they watching me?
What do they want?
I didn't do anything.
I was bounded like a criminal
and was led to the sultan.
The sultan was angry and snarling
and trying to force me to admit that
I had stolen his treasure last night.
His jewels and pearls
I was trembling for my life.
I couldn't understand
why was I being treated like this
Then I saw the baker and he said...
It's him
The thief
Yesterday he gave me pearls for
a loaf of common bread.
So he is the thief.
Yesterday he gave me those stolen pearls,
The baker didn't stop yelling.
But the wise sultan thought it over.
How come the baker got
the pearls yesterday
while the theft occurred last night?
There's something wrong here.
So he made the princess come and asked
if this is her pearl necklace.
The Princess was watching it
for a long time and then said:
Release that innocent man,
these aren't my pearls.
I have never had such a nice necklace.
I was saved.
Then the sultan invited me to his court
And there was so much food and drink
that it made the table bow down.
Since then I have abundance of everything.
Also the baker was satisfied.
He had become the main provider of bread.
The princess kept the nice pearls.
So we all were happy and content.
Then in the golden age
of princesses and roses
I was living by sultan Muhammad
He was a passionate hunter.
Whenever he went hunting
I had to accompany him
For a poor sailor like me
it was a great honor.
He liked me so much that he never
did a step without me.
Pity that he was so heavy.
He made my back ache.
But I didn't complain a bit.
At least not aloud
So much I appreciated
the friendship of a powerful sultan.
And there was another bound to keep me
in the sultan' palace.
The strongest one.
The princess.
The sultan's daughter
She didn't know I loved her
It was my secret.
Hold tight, no worry,
just come in...in...in.
Stand up, there's a guest for you.
Stand up.
Hold tight...tight...tight.
Let him be...let him be!
Scoundrels!
I'll show you.
Let him be, let him be!
Let's go, let's go.
Good old parrot - my only real friend
in the sultan's court - saved me.
He lacked neither heart nor guts.
Attention!
Turn around.
March now!
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
When the alarm rang
I was far on the sea.
Far from sleepy princess,
far from fat sultan.
I was going away
saying to myself
I would let nobody
ride on my back ever again.
I sculled all night long to get myself
as far as possible from the sultan.
I knew he wouldn't forgive me
and would hunt me down.
By sundown I glimpsed a little island
not far from me.
There was a funny rock
in the middle of it
resembling a huge egg.
Is there a bird capable of
laying eggs so huge?
But it isn't a rock either.
What could this be
for lord's sake?
The sultan's soldiers!
What should I do know?
How could I escape?
The sultan is holding me already.
Now he will show me.
This is my end.
It was an enormous horrible bird.
Without the slightest sound I took cover
under its wings like a timid mouse.
When I saw its appetite
I crawled into the darkest place
beneath its vans.
When the night came I stayed
buried in its feathers.
But I couldn't sleep a bit
because of fear.
Not before the morning
was I able to sleep a bit.
Only for a while.
But I wouldn't wish anybody
to awake like this.
The height made me dizzy.
We flew the whole day
And I had to be careful so the beast
doesn't notice...
There was an illegal passenger.
It would be bad for me.
I saw with my own eyes...
the terrible creature catch an elephant.
Good that it flew away.
But what about me now?
I stayed on my own
And I wondered ...
What will I do alone?
This unknown forest frightened me.
I realized that this poor old man
couldn't walk.
And wanted me to carry him.
He will surely show me the way
to good people.
So I had mercy on him.
But what a bad idea!
The oldster clung on to my back
kicking me like mad
hitting me like a horse
And I just couldn't get rid of him.
Is my back only for burdens?
Am I a pony or a donkey?
I must get rid of him whatever it takes.
But even hippo's stomach wasn't strong
enough for this bully.
I was plodding with the codger
hungry and thirsty all day long.
I would give half of
my life for a gulp.
Now! look what luck gave me!
There was a cask in front of me.
Nice cask!
Castaways must have forgotten it here.
Finally a drink.
The thirst was killing me.
But I didn't get one gulp...
The codger was thirsty too.
And how thirsty!
Like he had no bottom, no limits.
And not a drop was left for me.
It was wine
Luckily for me!
Even bad things bring good sometimes.
The oldster cheered up, forgot to hold on
and tumbled down.
He forgot about me and went on
fooling around like a comedian.
He got wiped out by the wine
And I felt good.
As if I got rid of the weight
of a mountain
My lucky star hadn't left me yet.
Castaways accepted me like one of them
And we set for the sea
towards new adventures.
I always longed for adventures but
in the end I learnt
That happiness is as fickle
as a butterfly
Only sea has never let me down.
It lead me to
the greatest adventures of my life.
The sea was always my faithful friend.
My faithful mate.
When the sky cleared up we
sailed to a large rocky island.
We hoped it wasn't a wasteland.
We needed some help and went
in search of good people.
It was a terrible discovery.
We had been caught
by a human eating giant.
Alas! What a destiny!
We had to escape whatever it takes
otherwise we would serve as his dinner.
Lucky for us that he couldn't see us.
He begun to destroy all the castle
He wanted to kill us, destroy us
Smash us apart
He wanted his revenge
and he nearly succeeded
It was a close call.
We managed to sail away just
out the giant's reach.
But then he heard
the splash of our paddles...
He could tell our position
And it was the end for us.
Nobody but I survived all that horror.
Here I was again sailing like a poor
castaway
In an old cramped cask.
It was my ship now.
My last rickety hope
I was sailing hungry and thirsty
through all those days and nights.
I was saying goodbye to life already.
I felt my death coming
So I felt asleep weak and desolate.
The sea didn't let me down.
It helped me as usual.
During my big sleep
seahorses pulled me to a little bay.
And I was sleeping and sleeping
After waking up
I couldn't believe my eyes
Instead of endless sea
I saw a marvelous garden.
I have never seen
so much beauty put together.
I was stupefied by the scent of flowers
and sweet music.
I begun to think I had come
into the world beyond.
Into paradise.
It was a paradise for real
But a forbidden one.
Probably paradise of some sultan.
I would have hard time
if caught.
I mustn't show up
Now this was too much.
I couldn't watch this.
I was starving to death...and here...
such beautiful apples
I must have at least one
even if they cut me up.
Now I had here a sultan's dancer
instead of the apple!
What a mess!
Could I let her go?
She would reveal my presence.
But then the little dancer
started to like me.
However I had a huge fear of the sultan.
The little dancer recognized
the sultan's ring.
He must have lost it during his bath.
She explained to me that this ring
has an evil power.
A man pointed at with a finger
wearing the ring looses his head.
The power of the cruel sultan
was built upon this.
And now we own the ring.
We needn't to worry and hide anymore.
She was dancing with joy so long
that we were found.
It was the end.
I was so scared that
I completely forgot the ring.
I was dragged right
in front of the sultan...
Who was sitting on the throne
with a hand in plaster...
So the suitors wouldn't see...
He had lost his evil power.
In the last moment I recalled...
The ring's magic power
and gave it a try.
Then I was elected to be
the governor of the whole country
I gave my first command.
I ordered a huge banquet
of the most delicious dishes
So I, a hungry sailor,
only on the throne could eat my fill
Then I gave my second and last order
I wanted a new ship for a long sailing.
Why, I wouldn't sit on the throne when
the sails could bring me wherever I like
When the ship was finished I said
goodbye to the city and the people
Let them rule themselves
without the magic ring
For a last time I waved goodbye to
the dancer who wouldn't leave her home.
On the wide open sea
I threw the ring into the water
No one would find it there
and that was good.
Now I was happy...
having a nice new ship
and sailing for another adventure.
My native land...
That meant music
and singing of nightingales.
as well as the scent of juicy meadows
and charming flowers
I believed I wouldn't find
more delightful place in the world
than this one.
Nonetheless all that beauty didn't beat
My desire for sea.
The sea, it was my greatest love.
We were astonished
Our ship was going through waves like mad
rushing forth pulled by the force of
a magnet mountain.
When we understood
it was too late
We weren't the only ones whose destiny
was to be smashed
by the horrible island's shore.
And the magnet mountain had
never spared a castaway.
With determined effort
we fought the mountain
Soon we saw it was a pointless battle.
We threw out the anchor
in a last hopeless attempt.
Maybe...
The sea will have mercy
for the faithful sailor Sinbad
Really!
A huge old turtle
The strongest creature in the sea...
Dragged our ship out of reach of
the lethal power of the mountain.
And we were saved.
Once out of harm's way I realized
it was no miracle
but a display of friendship
Oh what would an old sailor
do without friends?
Dear good turtle,
we will never forget.
We raised the sails again
and set them to friendly winds.
A few days later the sea brought us
to another island
None of us knew this mountain.
And it was a funny mountain.
The air full of sounds
of bugles and drums
Swords and spears everywhere
like in an upset wasp nest
I felt that we should avoid this place.
But my curiosity was stronger.
I ordered to anchor at a safe distance.
An old sultan ruled over the island
He was then angry with the whole world.
His daughter had disappeared
had got lost...
Had been kidnapped
or escaped with someone
For there's no anchor that could
hold a girl's heart...
when it's affected by love.
But it wasn't what sultan wanted to hear
He had ordered to catch her,
bring her, and punish her
So all the guardians and soldiers were
hunting for fugitives
in every which place
The sultan was so furious that he went
searching for the daring kidnapper himself
He had chosen the most competent
helper in the palace
and the skillful tracker didn't
hesitate to answer the call of duty
But the pursuers couldn't get a glimpse
of this mysterious stranger
What was this old pilgrim
looking for here?
Why is he hiding.
The sultan not having trust in anybody
except his four-legged snooper
was walking and searching,
searching and walking...
from sunset till sundown
through the whole island
They didn't skip anything
There was no single house or court
they didn't search
The crafty couple couldn't
disappear just like that
They searched each hole and slit
They searched also places
nobody else would.
When the night came and the dark
shrouded the miserable island
at our galion
There the mysterious stranger appeared
I was curious and a bit scared
For I didn't like at all
the events on the island
This funny old man wanted to buy my ship
The whole ship!
-No way
I won't sell my vessel for nothing
Not even for a bag of gold coins
but this wasn't an ordinary bag
It would throw out gold coins
with a secret sign
A waterfall of gold,
an endless goldmine
And only by another sign
the gold steam stopped
I couldn't resist this
And I traded the old ship for
the magic bag
You may encounter an opportunity
like that only once in a century
This was the only missing item!
The sultan's daughter
and her kidnapper himself
They were running away on my ship
And I stayed on a poor bark
in the angry sultan's empire
The only thing to give me some courage
was the magic bag
I hoped I wouldn't be lost even there
with all those gold coins.
I payed to my devoted mates...
From now on everyone
would have to be on his own.
I was led to the sultan like a criminal.
To save myself
I offered him the gold
It was wrong to think
that a few coins would appease him
While the sultan was rejoicing in my gold
I managed to hide on the island
Oh, how much I longed for my old ship
But it was carrying away the mysterious
stranger and the pretty princess
The next day I was woken up
by a gold rain
I understood at once
They can't stop the magic bag
But they're happy
They are all rich now
But the golden flood brought
happiness to nobody
not even to the sultan
The gold rush seized all
the people on the island
And everyone wanted everything
The more gold there was
the more they wanted
And the gold was growing
so the mountain was covered
with glittering metal
The shining gold became
the brightest lighthouse on the sea
It attracted the pirates
from the whole world
They were coming from far away
for the appealing power of gold...
was stronger still than the one
of the magnet mountain
as well as the magnet mountain
the gold one meant disaster and perdition
Everyone coming by it became
addicted to the gold rush
This terrible disease seized
the whole island
What was the matter with people?
I asked myself unable to believe
my own eyes
And the gold stream...
rolling through the island like a lava
on a vulcano wouldn't stop.
What more would I have witnessed...
If the ever growing mountain didn't
suddenly start to go down to the sea
For the land didn't bear
the weight of all the gold
So the island disappeared in the waves
The terrible doom was inevitable
When the sea quieted down again
Only birds and swimming quadrupeds
remained in the place
where the proud island had been
towering to the sky
Among the castaways there I came up
Maybe only because I did not wear
a money belt filled with gold
I was swimming like no other
sailor had been before
And I was wondering apprehensively
Where my live galleon would bring me
After many hard and long days
and longer still nights
My high bred steed and I reached
an island and we were saved
There I was alone again
with my desire for unknown
accompanied only
by the caws of seagulls
But their call didn't lure me
back to the deep sea this time.
I had my fill of the sea already
and was grateful to be on dry land.
What a surprise!
A city in the middle of a jungle
The gate was wide opened
so I didn't hesitate
I was astonished to see men running
from me as from the plague
Then I understood
My pony was the cause of their dismay
They had never seen
a horse on this island...
And may have taken it
for some bloodthirsty beast
Even the master of the island himself
recoiled from my four-legged mate...
And ordered to his human team
to haste away
The fearful sultan sent for the
heavy artillery to chase away the aliens
I didn't even think of running away...
realizing that my good pony was
the cause of this misunderstanding
I stepped in front of the sultan to explain
I gave him my respects as everyone
coming in peace...
and wanting no harm
The pacified sultan send away the artillery...
and wanted to please us.
He gave to my pony
the most exquisite delicacies possible...
as a peace offering.
It wasn't so easy to persuade him
that horses don't live on meat
and carry patiently men on their back...
so they needn't to go on foot.
The sultan was more and more
delighted by my horse
Suddenly he offered the greatest treasure
for the horse
Yes!
The really magic carpet
I had heard so much about
First I believed it was a jest
But the sultan really wanted to trade...
For he was just too heavy
for the little carpet
But I lifted off with it like a bird
"The horse! Bring the horse!"
as if I heard the sultan
Luckily I didn't see what was next
I would have felt for the poor horse.
I didn't need to envied birds
their freedom now.
I myself had wings
and all the world below
Let the carpet bring me where
it likes to and if there's an adventure
I will pass it
The days took turns with the nights
And I woke up there like in a cradle
One day the carpet brought me to
the shores of some unknown country.
And soon above towers and roofs
of a nice city.
I had never seen
so marvelous palaces before.
As if attracted by the fabulous beauty
I decided to visit the city
I started to look for
a proper place to land
No! This wasn't a friendly welcoming
I won't let my carpet get ruined.
Nor will I be discouraged.
Other means than force were needed
in this proud city.
I flew away
to think it all over in peace.
While the guards were still
trying to find me above,
I slipped through right under them.
I didn't arouse the slightest suspicion
A piece of luck...
the friend of the courageous
was on my side
The streets were then full
with people watching...
the noble procession of an Indian prince
who came for wooing
But what a funny wooing!
I heard that the sultan's daughter...
was bewitched by an unknown spell
Each night when all fell asleep,
she disappeared from her room
and no one knew what
happened to her then.
The people felt sorry for the sad girl
living locked up in the highest tower,
watched by armed guards,
but in vain.
So the sultan had declared that
she would be the wife of the one
who would save her from all that magic.
This night too, the princess was
sleeping behind bars and 10 locks.
Even the Indian prince was on watch
with a specially trained falcon
Now! The mystery begins!
Princess changes into a dove
to slip through the bars.
But where is she heading?
What will happen next?
I decided that I would solve this.
I tried in vain to find
the dove after the flight
She disappeared in the deep night
Only in the morning, when the last
shreds of dark dissolved...
did I find her again,
and understood everything.
It was love what had given her wings
and brought her as a dove
to her beloved.
I never hesitated
They escaped at the last moment.
I had no regrets.
Let the magic carpet serve them
and bring them to a place...
Where they wouldn't need
to hide their love.
Now I had only a boat again
And it wasn't bad anyway
Even the birds above were happy with
the good ending...
In which a faithful love won
And a sailor came back to
where he belonged.
I liked the peace on the
wide open sea at sunset.
I played lullabies then
Calling sleep for me
as well as for the waves
Really?!
The sea sultan
The master of all seas
Almighty lord of all castaways' fates
Why was I invited?
Had I perhaps made him mad with my lute?
I had sung so many songs
without any consequences.
Why am I now here in the depth
of the underwater sultan's empire?
I soon had the answers
Play a lullaby,
Right away!I want to sleep,
he ordered me.
There was no other choice.
So I was playing for
the sultan and his daughter
What a fate?
The lute always my savior before
will be my perdition now
I'm not a fish, I can't breath
under the water
I was suffocating
It really was time to do something.
While I was escaping
from the sultan's watery empire
a cruel battle was finishing
at the surface
The blood-colored sea was rocking
one last ship
Which I found the most beautiful one
in the world when I could breath again
I didn't find a living soul
in the whole wreck.
I was alone.
Next day when I said hello
to the sun again,
refreshed by the sleep,
I raised the only remaining sail
And I put my trust in
the friendly wind.
I sailed slowly,
waiting patiently for my ship
to bring me somewhere.
After a few days there was
an island in front of me.
A green one and, I guessed,
also a huge one.
I turned towards it with a new hope.
I entered a peaceful bay
and encouraged by my curiosity
I threw the anchor there.
After just a few steps in
my exploration of the island
I became a captive of funny people
Then I understood that
this is a kingdom of apes
avoided by all proper sailors.
First I couldn't complain.
They were very hospitable.
They brought me all
that their island offered.
They insisted they I had to stand
with them and learn their way of life.
A very easy way that all
little monkeys are able to learn
I saw well that they weren't
going to ever let me go,
That they were serious about it.
I could only obey them.
One night with a bright moon
my decision was made.
I was sick of it all here
The bigger was my humiliation
the stronger was my desire to escape.
Silently I set for the bay
Where my ship was still anchored.
In vain did the ship wait
And there were even harder
ape lessons for me
My protests that the living in branches
isn't worthy of a sailor didn't help
No sailor bussiness, squawked they,
this is an ape's empire
I thought then
they must take me for an ape.
But the truth was even worse.
I was only a toy for the
amusement of those scoundrels.
No!
I will no longer be
all the jungle's laughing stock
But I didn't know how to trick
the tricky apes
Only when I saw a bunch of grapes
I had a wonderful idea
They had wanted to teach me
the ape's ways
I would pay back with teaching them
something of human ways
As I had expected the apes
became easily my good pupils
My revenge was slowly coming together.
When the barrel was full
The sun and time completed the work
They even drank the wine without
needing to be taught
After all that fun and dance
the ape's nation fell asleep
It was the time I had been
waiting for so long
Nothing could stop my going
to the bay now
Just away as fast as possible
from this unbearable island
Not wanting to loose any time
I set off a little boat and
went to the wide sea
Where I always felt the most free
despite all dangers
Goodbye green island!
And let your inhabitants sleep well.
Once more I was welcomed
by the sea-gulls
I was happy about their yelling
about the splashing of paddles
and waves and about the new voyage
Dear mercy sleep
capable of injecting a divine relief
even into the biggest suffering
I don't know how long I had been
sailing hungry and thirsty
lost and alone
Only tricky dreams and phantoms...
those companions of exhausted castaways...
brought me into the world of plenty
letting me forget the cruel reality
I was happy at least for a little while
But how dreadful was each awakening.
I felt my end coming
The old friends and faithful mates of my
journeys helped me
They didn't let me starve to death
After refreshing myself
I fought the sea with a new hope
Before long I saw an island
It was desolate and parched
Not a single straw of grass
Anyway I went looking for water
to ease my terrible thirst
I didn't find a spring
but a jug
An ordinary corked jug made of clay
I hoped some drops were left
for a sailor dying of thirst
Now what's this surprise?
A horror
I've released a daemon!
He had been locked in there ages ago and
since had to wait for his liberator
Instead of being grateful
he got mean
There was no kind of death he wouldn't
promise me...
for being imprisoned so long
While he was preparing to fulfill
his threats...
A trick occurred to me
I told him, I just couldn't believe that...
he, being so big, could fit into such
a little vessel
And the big boaster displayed his skills
for me
It was my moment
Then all I needed to do was
to cork up the jug.
The imprisoned daemon bagged and moaned
But I didn't trust him anymore
Until he had promised me
to fulfill all my wishes...
As long as I own the jug of clay...
I wouldn't agree to release him.
And I gave him the first order
right away
I wanted him to get me out
of this desolate island
After a long journey above the sea
a shore appeared
Soon I desired a wealthy city an by it
There was a huge well
That's where I ordered to land
After fulfilling my wish the daemon
went back to the jug obediently
I felt relief
So he can keep his word
Refreshed I realized
I was among the people again
Also my curiosity woke up again
Who is hidden in that hilarious sedan?
I had never seen such a beautiful face
No wonder that I lost my head
I made a point to be
the helper of that pretty face
And right away I started
But instead of a comely girl
I got acquainted only with...
the capers and jailers of her father
For she was the daughter
of the sultan himself
...of the lord of this country
I had been honored to meet lots of
sultans before so
this one wasn't too surprising for me
and when standing right in front of him
I asked him for his daughter's hand
The sultan hadn't
any understanding for my heart
But why is he so mad?
Am I not an honest sailor?
I was to perish in his prison
for my daring
I was thinking it over the whole night
in the dungeon
If only I could have the jug
But it was in the well
I was lost
I said goodbye to princess and begged her
to be patient
I didn't dare to reveal who is my companion
I was rushing towards my secret
By sunset I reached my goal
Fortunately the jug was intact
Now I will show to
the princess and the sultan
I'm not an ordinary sailor
And I gave orders to the daemon
I want a prince's dress
I want a knight's horse
I want servants and suitors
gold
Jewels and treasures
that make one dazzle
And then
dressed like a magnifico
I went to the sultan's palace
to surprise and dazzle the old master
as well as my future bride
The sultan couldn't get over his ecstasy
He approved the wedding without thinking
without even seeing me
Stupefied as he was by the blaze of gold
and the shine of the precious stones
But the princess said no!
When I had made my plan
it didn't occur to me
That princess in love with
an ordinary sailor
would refuse a rich wooer
The sultan threw a fit
What manners are these?
Disobeying the father and the sultan
equals a rebellion
I give death penalty for that
Marry him or I will make you
loose your head
When the princess recognized me
there was nothing more to think about
Without hesitation
I took her out of the palace
We were going accompanied with servants
carrying things...
A princess can't do without.
We were traveling through mountains
led by sea-gulls in the sky
I knew it was a good sign
I was grateful to them in my thoughts
Why, the sea had always meant
happiness for me
When I glanced around I said to my bride
There in the highest place
I will take care of everything to you
I will built there a beautiful palace
with a golden roof
worthy of you, my love
The jug!
The daemon is free!
He's no longer my servant
The magic vanished
What will I do now?
I was desperate
I had wanted to build
a palace with a golden roof for my love
But the bright blue sky was enough...
for our happiness.
So we lived happily...
under the most beautiful roof
in the world.
Watch more movies for free on
www.FlixTor.to