In a tale by Jan Werich
THREE VETERANS
When we set marching
far out beyond Prague
we'll meet the Turkish army, love...
Stop!
What's up?
- Look!
Look at that!
So what?
A beggar.
It's the same one!
An old campaigner.
Aveteran, huh?
You'll got to be one too.
He's got a medal anďs out begging.
So will you be.
Don't say such things.
Play for us!
It's all here today, gone tomorrow.
Youth, glory,
money...
- Didn't you hear?
Play another song!
- I have no ther song.
Better none at all, then.
You shouldn't have done that.
Come on, I'm thirsty!
Buy another one!
Let's go!
I'll just buy a new handle,
you save up for a barrel-organ.
Screenplay by
based on idea by
in other roles
and others
assitant directors
Script supervisor
assistant editor
2nd camera
camera assistant
stills photographer
Gaffer
production manager
production assistants
production designer
assistant production designer
costume designer
wardrobe
propmaster
propman
make-up artist
make up
special camera effects
animation
Puppeteers
Music by
Played by
conductor
Sound Designer
Editing
camera operator
production assistant
Directed by
made by
processed by
English sub-titles by Doris Kolísková
The old geyser was right.
We've got no roof over our heads,
holes in our boots
and a rumbling tum.
Got a light, Butch?
Hey, Butch, got a light?
My name isn't Butch.
- I know that you are Pankrac.
It's shorter than Pankrac.
Give me a light!
Thanks.
Seen my two brothers around?
E... e...
- Well, yeah.
Never mind, they'll be along.
Want a cigar?
I'm not supposed to smoke.
What I need is coffee.
- You wish.
With rum or without?
- Is that a joke?
Not a bad one, either.
There.
Sugar's in it.
Rum, as well?
Damnit.
What'll you eat?
Bread, buns,
or a piece of cake?
- The cake.
Brambalabum.
As you wish.
I like to see people happy.
Laughter's the loveliest music.
Laugh till your belly shakes!
You must be a docent sort
if you can laugh like that.
I've got to wake my mates.
No, let them sleep.
Here,
have this!
- Just a minute!
Is it okay?
Too small.
- And now?
Where are you,
I can't see a thing!
Chm!
And now?
Now it's just right.
- Oh, great!
Fine, it's yours.
Bye!
Should my brothers turn up,
I'll be waiting under the nose-tree.
Where?
- Like a fig-tree,
only this is a nose-tree.
They know where.
Under the nose-tree.
Where else would I be waiting?
Life isn't fun
all the time,
but some of the time some of the fun
please let be mine!
The gold can be thine,
but friends...
...must be mine!
You sing well, little man.
What a praise!
Such praise deserves a reward.
Catch!
Hop-hop!
Hop!
How much is in there?
- No end to them!
Like it?
- Who wouldn't?
Me.
Eh, hop!
Look.
You keep it!
Hop!
What'll you do without money?
I'll shake some out for you.
Bad, not bad - okay?
Right?
- Yeah.
Come on.
Bad - not bad.
Right.
Having no money?
- That's bad.
Not bad!
Having no heart?
- Not bad.
That's bad!
Being in trouble?
- Is bad.
Not that bad!
Being bored?
- Not bad.
That is bad!
Is bad!
Hey you, Servac...
- Yeah?
Should my older brother look for me,
or
the younger one,
tell him...
...or tell them both
to come and join me.
Life isn't fun all the time,
but some of the time some of the fun
please be mine!
Whatcher want, titch?
Want me to blow?
You don't need to tell me.
Well, that I didn't know
that there are deaf-and-dumb dwarfs
around!
You hear but cannot speak?
Yes, we need more wood,
but dry wood.
Everything's damp in the forest.
That's enough.
A nice toy.
The things one could do with it.
Here you are.
I'm to keep it?
Thanks.
Cherio, dwarf!
Oh, not Mr. Servac,
he prefers tea and cake.
Get up!
Breakfast's ready!
Oh, cake!
- What do you say now?
Where did you?
Good.
If you knew what happened to me!
But what happened to me!
Such a titch came up...
- Mine was even titchier.
Had blond curls.
- No he didn't.
Bad a long cigar.
- No he didn't!
It was another one, then.
Look at that.
Why stay here, mates?
Why are we rotting in the woods?
Let's march off into the unknown.
March?
We'll ride!
What?
Climb in, gentleman!
Great horses.
I love browns.
That was a good trick.
Soft seats,
four horse-power!
A carriage.
Looks like something's wrong.
When I want a carriage.
I want it on the road!
Ah, yes.
I've never worked with these.
There's no instruction leaflet.
Wait.
Whack the whip.
Don't be stupid,
we'll get a driver.
What's your name?
- Whatever you want it to be.
So you'll be Matt.
Go!
No, you'll be Hans.
Germans are tidy people.
Go, Hans!
Isn't it wonderful!
But what'll we do?
I'd like to go fishing.
Let's just laze around,
for five, six years,
then we'll see.
- No,
a soldier revisits places
where he spillt blood.
But why?
Why doesn't he go fishing?
Because he's a soldier.
Not any longer.
We are veteran soldiers!
Don't you forget that!
We're veterans.
We're going fishing.
- No excuses.
Off we go!
To the battlefield!
Stop!
Halt!
That's where it was.
What are you doing with my horse?
Watch this.
There were ten Mohammedans.
I had five men left,
and one seribe.
That's them.
The Turks thought they could do
anything.
Hey, mister!
This is my horse, and my field!
Go away, there'll be shooting.
But I've sown.
Let's go away,
he's sown.
We can't.
This is the battlefield.
Here's the battle.
Mind out, civilian!
- Ouch!
Now I'll show you
how I do with superior forces!
Wait and see, you Turks!
There'll be wheat here.
- There'll be a battle here.
I'm not interested in wheat.
Seram, civilian!
Damm it all!
We can't have this,
no we can't!
Look what happens
when I strum up 20 men!
Please!
Can I go?
No, write it up for history.
The whole victorious battle.
Got ready!
Arms ready!
- Stop it!
Hey, look!
You're scaring the kids.
So what.
Fire!
Come along, children.
Seize the fire!
Don't fire!
Fire and hack away!
They're giving up!
What are you doing?
How can you shoot at someone
who's giving in?
What a mean thing to do!
Get down!
Shame on you!
We'll show you yet!
- Now look at us.
Had we just lazed around
as I suggested,
we'd be better off.
Laze around then.
There's straw, mice too -
three's a lucky number.
I wanted to go fishing,
not into battle like you.
Wearing your uniform?
That's true, why not civies?
I don't know how else to dress up.
Been wearing uniform all my life.
They don't know
I've got a secret weapon.
I can do...
I can do anything with.
I'll make the whole world stand in line.
I'll set up an invincible army
and a navy
and set things straight
on land and sea.
He's crackers.
The we at thing a guy can want,
to save the world by force.
A dangerous illness.
What do we do with him?
- We'll marry him off.
Hurray!
Forwards!
Evil must be hounded out by evil.
What's the bride to be like?
Half angel half bitch.
He won't want just anyone,
now he rules the world.
A Princess at least.
So we find him a Princess.
An angel of a bitch.
She'll tame him.
She'll keep him straight.
Get up, you're getting married.
Wake him up!
- I see.
Now?
Here?
To whom?
- First let's get out of here.
Who can think of something?
- Not me.
I'll show you how
to escape from a jail.
Break it in two.
Hey!
Break it in two!
Excuse me.
Che!
I thought of that too
but I thought I'd make it harder.
Come on.
Let it be.
Come on!
- What's up?
Quickly!
Goddamnit!
Come on!
What's wrong?
Move, Liza!
I'm coming.
The sleigh-party's gone?
Yes.
First a sleigh, now a carriage.
A lot of traffic today.
Well...
- Well, yeah.
Got any cigarettes?
Which do you like?
These with the camel.
Confiscated.
Any more camels?
Yeah.
Confiscated too.
More!
We'd be here till morning.
Here - and open up!
Did you paint that, customs-man?
Yes Sir,
and it's for sale.
Who is it?
- Bosanna.
Are her eyes that far apart?
Even further, Sir.
An angelic little bitch.
Where does she live
and where are weddings hold?
She's a Princess!
Three pieces of gold for and it's yours.
No!
More.
We'll go and find her.
Come on!
Yeah.
Yeah?
I got you.
Three people, one driver, four horses.
You don't say.
Oh, come on!
Under his hat?
With a camel?
Be seeing you.
Welcome, gentlemen,
my name's Vulture.
I'm sure,
You'll want to stay with me.
There is no other hotel.
No choice, then.
Is your place clean?
It's an all-category hotel.
Third with bed-bugs,
second without bed-bugs,
first with coat-hangers.
We'll take first.
- The luggage!
Would you take your hat off?
Here it's the custom,
when you enter a house.
Stuff and nonsense.
- Pankrac.
They have no baggage.
No luggage?
And what's this?
What is this?
What's this, then?
Well - what is this?
Yes, what is it?
And this?
What is this?
Please excuse him,
he's a fly-killer simpleton,
as the English say.
A more fly-boy.
This way, please.
Ah, his Majesty, in person?
This is my hotel.
The Vulture.
Give them a right royal welcome!
My dear hands and feet,
ďyou know what we're doing?
Lazing about.
That's the life.
Will she be home?
Will there be fish?
Come here!
WELCOME, STRANGERS!
What are they doing?
Going to the station to welcome someone.
Hardly, there's no railroad here.
Wave at them,
maybe it's for us.
Hallo!
King Piccolo asks us
for dinner.
Welcome, strangers,
what have you bright me?
Want one too, huh?
Go burst -
with envy!
And what's this?
A field kitchen.
My gift, for the army.
That'll come in handy.
We wage wars often.
Extricator of shells
fallen into the soup.
Isn't that clever!
Let's show them our printing-house.
Well.
My Minister for Information
will explain
how we do it.
I follow the international situation.
Then we either make cannon-balls
show the gentlemen -
or letters from the cannon-balls.
What are you making now?
Letters from cannon-balls.
The situation is favourable for reading.
The more people read,
the worse they shoot.
Watch out.
How about you?
No gift?
Not for you,
but for your lovely daughter.
For Bosanna?
You sly-fox.
I bet you're after her.
Your Majesty.
I saw her portrait
and now can't wait to see her.
I've had enough,
of these everlasting beatings!
Just you try!
Oh, please -
Do calm down.
What a swash-buckler you are!
Do excuse them,
It's their job.
My ancestors.
My Grandpa,
my Great-Grandpa,
my Great-Aunt,
my Grand-Mother-in-Law,
my Grand-Father-in-Law,
good old stabbed Oldfiich,
pst
my dear deceased wife.
She is lovelier than I expected.
Ah, Mother Nature -
where goest thou for inspiration?
Krucifix!
I'm glad you came.
If you please.
Mr Bimbác has a gift for you.
Let's see what you've brought.
Gold or silver,
precious gems?
Costume jewellery.
We don't have that yet!
You may put it on me.
Men like doing that.
Don't see what they see in it.
Isn't it odd.
The Queen an ugly cow,
the King a silly twirp
and what a lovely daughter.
Surprises me, too.
All three daughters turned out well.
I married Rosanna off
to the King of Picardy,
Hosanna to a banker in Vienna
and Bosanna - we have yet to see.
It would have to be a rich suitor
who'd cough up a pile of gold
for the state coffers.
I'll swap my harp for your pouch.
E e.
Why ďyou have so many flies?
Our spiders are lazy.
Why are you such a poor country?
Our subjects are lazy.
How come you have such lovely tooth?
And your eyes,
they're set so far apart.
And yours are full of fire!
I'm a soldier.
They reflect the fire of battle.
What do you do?
I can cook.
Do you want to know what I can do?
Wait, be quite.
You two are fun.
Well...
Now me.
Bosanna can marry any time,
she's of age.
But her bride-groom
must truly tinkle with gold!
Swap your pouch for my harp.
No.
- What's all this whispering?
Bad manners.
Whisper not, want not.
I'll show you something.
It's bottom-less.
- Money isn't everything.
When I need soldiers -
I have them.
When I need street-sweepers -
here we are.
When I need...
Hairdressers - do make some!
As you wish.
Ó ó hm,
A natty thing, that.
Bosanna, I really don't know
who is the richest.
Whom to give preference
should they want your hand in marriage.
I hereby request...
- I also request...
I like the pouch and the harp.
You are right.
Oh, yes.
Let us drink some wine
my friends
and be the wiser.
Drink it all, my friends,
the truth that wine holds
sits at the bottom!
Why?
What what?
Why plunge a dagger in your mate's back?
With a dagger in your back
you'd better turn onto your belly.
You were a sight
when they brought you back
like two felled sacks.
D'you know what he did to me?
No.
He proposed to her himself.
Would you believe it?
I would.
He can't help it.
But you wanted to marry me off!
That was the agreement.
If he wants to get married,
I'll strum up a similar one for him.
Not a problem.
- One to look just like Bosanna?
Sure.
So. Strum her up, right here!
Here?
- Yeah.
How's that?
Your bill.
With extras like coat-hangars,
water and mirror
it comes to 25 pieces of gold,
including daylight
it totals 30 pieces of gold.
We'll pay when we leave.
Seram!
No,
here bills are paid every morning.
Here, you miser.
Dammit...
Come here!
Here, they're with the camels.
So it wasn't stuff and nonsense!
I'm confiscating the cigarettes,
your clothes,
everything.
The beggarly rabble!
Your baggage too.
They come to a hotel
and can't pay.
Who put this door here?
Never seen such customers!
STRANGERS, GO HOME!
Shame, shame!
Children!
Get your stones ready!
Hallo!
- Stop it!
Can't you read?
Yes, but slowly.
- Mind out!
Throw - throw - throw!
These people are good, and obedient.
They love you and then stone you,
as they're told.
Why isn't it working?
They've nicked your magic stuff
and fixed you up with counterfeits.
Come, help me.
Defend yourselves till I come back.
Yes.
Come on.
Where are they?
Those three?
First floor,
suite no. 1.
Follow me!
Sabres - ready!
Follow him!
Stop!
Sssh!
One, one, one
Here they are.
Open up!
Open up at once!
What a noisy hotel.
Hej rup!
Now we've got you.
Where are they?
Where are you?
Come on, out!
We know, you're there!
Hear that?
Silence!
They've got them.
They'll be right down.
This'll be something.
Make way!
You wave like this,
hit like this.
Get ready to beat them up!
Now!
Not like that.
So pretty and she steals.
Where've you sprung from?
Easy.
Slithered down,
You're no chimney-sweep.
You're one of the foreigners.
I thought you hadn't noticed me.
Hand back my pouch,
so that you wouldn't make me public
that you are a thief family.
Look, I've got a hat
that does my bidding.
I'll give you whatever you wish
and you hand back my pouch.
The hat can give you anything?
Except for give and money.
How about love?
- It can't do that.
I pretended not to see you
because you're the one I like.
You were the only one I liked.
I thought you'd be peevish
at my ignoring you
and come to me.
And you came.
You angelic little bitch.
You little bitch!
Guards!
Arrest him!
Help!
And that's it, chimney-sweep.
String him up on the rack,
give him the Spanish boot,
sit him on an American stove
and throw him to the German rats.
Catch him!
Move it!
What a time.
Hurry up, you slow-coaches.
Climb up!
I ran ever the roof.
Where's my pouch?
And my harp?
- Guys,
We haven't even got the hat!
They must be looking for somebody.
Over there.
Let's go.
- Yeah.
Halt!
Stát!
Stop! Not you.
Where are you going?
To fertilize the vinyards.
All right.
On your way.
Got them?
- No.
You've disappointed me.
They are crafty rascals.
They'll got a new hat,
another harp,
and have their revenge.
You bet.
They should get the life sentence,
and we'd have some peace.
Got them?
- No.
Well?
I've got them!
Let me see.
Kindly get it in focus.
Very good.
We'll send the cavalry.
- Yes.
I'll warn the customs official.
Hop!
That scoundrel isn't answering.
Leave me in peace.
When I'm milking, I'm milking.
Oh, let's get out of here!
Over the chasm.
Over the chasm!
You bastard,
lift that receiver!
Stop!
No, let's get out of here!
Gone.
Sshh.
Let's go!
I insist on quiet.
Go home, everybody.
That's all.
What'll you have, sweep?
Coffee with rum.
Got any money?
No.
He's got no money
and wants coffee with rum.
But we're not poor, either.
Valuables.
My mates and I,
we paid for them with blood.
What is it?
Some old medals.
I see.
They won't buy you a crumb.
Valueless.
How's that?
They have a great value.
This is for faithful service,
this for bravery,
this for courage,
this for merits,
and here's the War Cross!
Won't buy you a fart.
I'll sell a painting.
A little one.
For how much?
Soup and bread for three.
Let 'em have it!
Now we're in the soup.
A drop of soup'll be fine.
Lucky, we have got it.
I mean generally speaking.
What do we do now?
- Where do we go?
And the dwarfs?
They helped us once,
they could do so again.
Where do we look for them?
- Under the nose-tree.
Where they always meet.
That's easily said,
but what's that tree like?
It's sure to be odd-looking.
A nose-tree?!
Let's go and look for it.
Whoever finds it, calls the others.
Hey, aren't you a nose-tree?
No, a dry apple-tree.
Come here, boys -
I've found it!
I've found the nose-tree!
How did you come by that?
What is it?
The apples brought it on.
There now, it's okay.
Back to what it was.
What a nose!
Look, pears.
What is it?
Just look at yourselves!
You look a sight too.
Where are we?
- Guess!
They have lazy spiders
and a King who steals.
Those are the dwarfs.
We know it's you,
disguised as sea-gulls.
- Sshh.
Why are we in this got-up?
I've got it!
They're little, but so clever
Royal Apples!
A specialty for royal families!
What sort of fruit is this?
Who isn't of royal family,
dies after eating them.
But those of royal blood
grow handsome and healthy.
I'll buy them for Bosanna.
She's lovely anyway,
how lovely will she be then!
How much are they?
- Their weight in diamonds.
Dammit all!
D'you have a sales licence?
- No.
There's a fine for that.
D'you know how much?
- No.
Double the price!
Twice their weight in diamonds.
Got that?
- No.
We hereby confiscate your apples.
Eat up, sweetheart.
They are precious.
I'll come and see you after my bath.
You'll be amazed.
Nurse!
A mirror, quickly!
The old lady had four apples
her old man only two.
What's up?
- Something's up.
Something's always up.
That's how it is.
Or there'd be no history.
- But something unusual.
Something's climbing out -
of the Princess's window!
If she's even prettier,
it'll be suitors, climbing up in!
Help!
Oh, my poor child...
That's no suitor,
looks like a snake.
Like what?
Horrors, ol horrors!
Do something with that snake,
I've got to hold my towel.
That's no snake,
it's her nose.
Her nose?
For heaven's sake!
Yes yes yes
yes yes yes yeah.
It's at the border.
Ouch!
Sorry.
No.
And it's over.
Climbed abroad.
It's just left our country.
- That's a tragedy.
An opportunity to proclaim
State mourning.
Shut the window!
She'll catch cold!
No,
my nose is out there!
It says her nose
taa-ta-taa-ta ta-ta-ta
is making for Vienna.
For the Prater, I bet.
Snuffling for a bit of fun.
Mustn't got onto the big wheel!
Ring up Vienna.
Get off with you!
Hot!
You must be visiting
the thermal springs in Karlovy Vary.
You need do no travelling, lovey.
Everything's right under your nose.
Throw!
Don't spit it out, it's healthy.
It's the best therapy for everything!
Salt!
Salty!
Then we'll be in Salzburg
Oh Salzburg, Salzburg.
I haven't been to Salzburg.
No.
It's nosing towards Germany.
Jawohl.
And it's there.
Germany calling.
If we don't stop poking our nose
in their affairs,
they're threatening war.
Explain to Germany.
How the things are
I'm having our production changed.
Hello, Germany?
Got this straight:
It's not a beezer,
it's our Princess's nose.
Yes, that long unfortunately.
Back to cannon-balls!
Charge the production line,
no more letters!
Come on!
No, a friendly visit.
Freundschaftsbesuch.
Jawohl.
Me too.
Don't shoot!
It's a friendly visit.
Vorwärz!
Marsch!
Ouch!
Call the doctor.
Can't anybody
stop it growing?
Three physicians from the orient
are here.
Bring them in!
Good morning.
We're on the way to Paris,
to Sorbonne University.
We heard your Princess is ailing.
Should you want us to,
we could try -
without guaranty...
to care her terrible sickness.
Of course we want you to.
Look what's grown on her.
After eating apples.
Interesting.
Snakish.
Cabellous.
After eating apples?
- Yes.
We'll try the pear cure.
With Aromatic Rusticana.
What's that?
Horse-radish.
Who? Prague?
Prague? I see!
It's pulled back to Prague.
A right snifty place.
It's getting shorter.
That's for sure.
Yes.
Budapest calling.
Hallo, what cheque?
From Tesek.
Tudom tudom.
Budapest is calling,
It's broken window displays and
just fled away.
- Glory be.
Ouch...
I can't stand it any longer.
Lazy, lovey, it's getting shorter.
The Castle?
This is the Customs-house.
Somebody's knocking.
- Come in!
Come on, in!
I see,
yeah, yeah
It came to a halt at the border.
What are they doing to it?
Now unpleasant!
A customs inspection.
There now lovey,
your nose is nearly home,
it's like other girls' now.
I don't want the customs inspection.
Stop, Liza.
- Ouch!
Show me that!
I recommend another pear
plus Pepper Negrum.
Nigrum.
- More!
What is that?
Black pepper.
It'll bring about a sneeze
as strong as an earth-quake.
A bang like from a cannon.
Come on, home!
- Yes, Boss.
This is terrible.
- It is.
Your therapy is successful, Doctors.
But we need it a bit shorter still.
No way, sorry.
We'll pay well!
E e -
And you'll get gifts, too.
Look.
E e -
They can do miles and not inches?
We'll see!
To the torture-chamber!
Torture can be efficient,
but I'm afraid,
not in this case.
What we head here
is no stolen goods around.
I would help a lot.
Stolen goods?
- That's right.
With stolen goods things around
the medicine doesn't work fully.
You dare maintain
that we of noble blood.
Have been stealing?
You sure nicked something.
Take that back1
Why should be?
There are stolen things here.
We stole them ourselves!
Hand them back, Daddy!
Give it back to them, now!
I refuge to live with this trunk!
I won't!
Hand it back -
but to whom?
We'll see it gets to the owners,
we know them well.
I wouldn't advise that.
The things are more important for us
then a couple of inches
of at extra nose.
The Princess'll get used to it.
Witches have long noses too.
- On the rack!
To the torture-chamber with you,
you horrid old geyser
Catch him,
had string him up on the rack!
Stretch him as a string.
You have thrilling adventures ahead!
Stay well.
Dear Doctors,
I used to be so pretty.
Take those
and help me.
Please.
Thank you.
A couple of daches
and what a difference.
Ah, science is science.
Let's go,
or I'll fall in love with her again.
Stop!
Where to?
- To the mountains,
we're going trout-fishing.
No, to the right!
I want to laze around.
No.
To the left!
We'll strum up an army
and capture Monte Alba.
Then another Kingdom from the north
and one from the south.
And finally - the whole world.
Still haven't got it out of your system?
Aren't you dumb?
Who has that, has everything.
Can command everyone,
forbid everything.
Destroy, give orders, kill...
You...
Stop it.
You've come up with this against me?
Your friend?
Against everybody who resists me!
Sabres - out!
The gifts!
Come on!
The gifts, I said!
Here!
Did we give you gifts?
Yes, we gave you gifts.
Why did we give you gifts?
We wanted
to make you happy.
Why did we want that?
To be happy
for having made you happy.
But did you make us happy?
No.
You wanted to save the world by force.
You held manoeuvres.
You threatened people.
- Threatened your own lives.
And we ask you, mates -
how many people did you get to smile?
How many children?
We dwarfs are patient.
No.
We'll ever be giving you another chance.
Trying to teach you mortals again
and again
how to handle the magic gifts
We've presented you
with.
Maybe you'll come to comprehend
at the million and fifth time.
Or...
The million and sixth time.
Got it!
Life isn't fun
all the time
but some of the time some of the fun
please let be mine!
Your empty pocket
worries you
but you're well-to-do
as long as you have friends!
To have no gold
is not so bad.
To have no heart
is bad indeed.
To have problems
is not that bad.
To be bored...
that's bad indeed!
Is bad!
Life isn't fun
all the time,
but some of the time some of the fun
please let be mine!
Life isn't fun
all the time,
but some of the time some of the fun
please let be mine!
THE END