I was afraid
never not grow
and stay until death Pind'ou.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
My college, maybe two thousand.
Probably something watching.
Well, that interests you, huh? Shit.
Here. And not that you raced
the Vitlichovi for psama.
-No.
Tell-A half Piksla. -Jo.
Drive carefully. Fall.
Do not be afraid to fall.
I can ride.
[squeal of the pig]
Good day.
The largest herds in Europe
Kaderka, Cumát, Rez, Vasak.
Tydýt! Tydýt!
-Resurrection! Pajamas, man.
-Where are you going?
Hey, guys.
Short-quills, Resurrection!
-Nedosáhneš!
Reach. How nothing.
You're the grandfather?
[screams]
Cumát, Don 't stare. Kader, shit.
Vasak, bogey.
The house fallout Sutra, it killed incision.
Why do idiot lesions?
I used a lot
wonderful ideas.
No, no, Resurrection ...
Look at how you look!
-Prelítl the angel.
-Angel!
[guys laughs at him]
Hello, sir Kaderka.
He does that all paths are his.
[the whistle]
Papa says what Petržela
steal, no.
Has everything.
Suddenly you're busy.
You can tailor the fAngle million.
Maybe a million.
People you just come nafackovat.
Do you hear what I say?
-Oh yeah, my ears.
Two-crown lime. Good day.
-How much?
Two-crown.
You did not go into apatyka.
-This is a German or Russian?
-Messerschmidt.
-Yeah?
-Fighter.
When are you two Kacky?
Dad said half Piksla.
If the last save dad to death,
and from him will Rotchild.
With the deals you guys are too.
Cyril!
Come here, yeah ...
[laughter and shouts of soldiers]
[speaks German]
Expecting a Russian?
Where were you for lime?
In the limestone?
-Petržela not home.
-Where do you think I was looking for you?
Fear him on the street.
This gave the two crowns
the pinch?
Julina!
the father: Where's the boy?
-Mother: Ulrich! Ulrich!
Good.
Hello.
SYP-home, Resurrection!
-Namlátil you up, huh?
Leda you.
Brats damnation pakujte now!
Ore no time!
-Have you rode up, Indiana!
-We now go, sir Niklík.
-Goodbye, Mr. Niklík.
-Goodbye.
[kids whistle]
Swim-a mother, I sews doll.
Come-three years, Resurrection!
Would you kick in the seat?
No! No!
[whistle]
Pst. Dad, I'm a dog.
Ago!
Co-pískáš, dick?
-Who took the Resurrection?
Guys, take me with you.
-Can.
-Why?
[screams]
Guys, come on!
Get him!
Ahhh!
-Do you hear?
-What?
-Now again.
-I hear it.
Hear.
-Guns. Cannonade from the front.
-On the ground it is better to hear.
-How much is heard guns?
Fifty-kliks.
-Who said?
-Cmíral. -It 'ox.
Slítni, kill to
Ahhh ...
Come on.
Morons.
See to the most?
It grows like a pig.
Wow, go tanks.
-Complete me.
-Give it to me. -Wait.
Erák gives careful on the bridge.
Russians would have to bombing.
Two, four, six ... Eight of them are.
Perhaps compare the entire village.
I would like to see.
No, twelve. One more.
Thirteen.
I would cellar
left closed. No way.
-When will I see a war, please?
Maybe burn-school.
And it might kill the controller.
-Did you have him stand stupid.
-Someone had to crash!
Shoes are gone.
-The smell is here.
-You 're stinks.
Ulrich, Ulrich, come on!
Nothing's gonna happen.
I'll bash-up.
-Me too.
Do not worry.
Come build a ladder.
What he can bear?
Not carry even pounds!
Rez, buy a fez!
You do Turk,
You can go to war
where you fit into manure.
Then count to five, Resurrection.
Come on, smell or see!
-One, two ...
-Three, four, hundred, thousand, million.
We do not ladder.
Cumát, Don 't stare!
Kader, it says!
Flow into the sacristy.
Hodils to strejcka own business,
altar it's you?
[cries boys]
Get back up. Hear?
Do not worry.
Come build a ladder!
[music]
Oldrich, where are you?
[crying] Mom ...
[music]
Ulrich!
Kill him, and close you.
[whistles]
Brother Chief, I report that the Corps
are ready to exercise.
Thank you. Merge.
[music]
Get away from the hose!
Hurry!
[music]
Bertýna: Ne ... [laughs]
[engine noise]
[airplane noise]
[shot]
Selma!
[Olin whistles]
-Hey, Cyril.
Damn dog-ear, what are litas?
I was with you in štenatama.
Damn, that not sitting at home.
Will shoot.
Ti-Upicnou gamekeeper's lodge, and then what?
-I am not afraid. Are you afraid of?
[music]
Dammit, Oline, you've done?
I got away.
Yeah?
These are newspaper.
And you ran long?
Nafurt. Longer back.
Never.
Well, here you too? Come on.
Mi-drowned puppy, you gave me.
-Come on, dog ear.
Warm your soup.
What would you say
I caught the last five crows?
Soup is like a Mogul.
Cyril, you too ran away
when you were little.
That is not true.
I thought of it.
Complete.
I was pulling the
before you, Oline.
No. Utekls. And did you,
only when you were twenty.
Only when your dad died.
I told you?
Come on.
-Selma!
-Banged her from the car.
Have you seen anybody on the way?
Hurry here you process?
-Who here if you hurry?
-Nobody.
We find a hoe.
We will do her funeral.
Bury it.
He is known that they are gone?
Sent you dad,
you to have omrknul?
Why? I was with boys.
The church.
-Where to bury her?
-U enclosure. A minute.
Nemlátí-man the gates?
-By now you can hear cannons.
-Singer had a lot of money?
-After begging walked.
Those looking for something, Cyril?
You can measure it.
Why do Palis?
To keep warm.
-Do you not cold?
-No.
Go.
-Because what are you doing?
-I play. What did you think?
You do not play.
-Have I ever lied?
-Every time. Always.
Oline, you'll be intelligent.
Guard the bridge.
To them it Rusi
nevykopli into the air.
Would you take something malýho
father to the farm?
What is yours?
You will not be the father.
And not only just after the Old Man.
-That you remember, huh?
-No. You knew him?
To Sun
It was as škrt'a Brno.
Before fertilized by foreign fields
He did it better in my pants.
Take an example of him.
He was honest and hard worker.
From birth to death.
Bring it here again a second time.
There would have to steal one.
[music]
-Not true. Not škrt'a.
-He could manage.
Šlohl what came.
Sixty uhonil hare.
[horse neighing]
I thought that it would not come.
Heck, who's zarýgloval?
Damn, who has been here?
I can place on their
present their asshole,
That climb.
I'll hang out.
Perhaps there is someone else.
See them?
-Hm.
-Remember it.
Because what they came here?
You'll have enough Težkej life.
[music]
- [Olin laughs]
-Shh ...
[music]
Is anyone here?
Hallo! Is anyone here?
Nehulákej. Do not yell.
Where are the wheels?
Cyril, you know
that you come for cars?
It seemed to me that night.
I wonder who's stench
It was vycmuchal.
I thought so.
He is smart as a bishop.
Come help me deal.
This platonák I pulled
for themselves.
Unless we the engine
were together.
Yeah. That I will take with me.
That I did not hold up.
[music, singing]
[music]
They do have their cars.
You're really
after your Old Man.
So I think about it.
Vypiplám one of those puppies.
You'll wink at the wire.
This is someone in your family?
Therefore.
I found it.
Lying on the road.
You smoke?
Ever.
If you find it at dad,
offends you lantern.
Ulrich, Ulrich!
Ulrich, come home, come to bed.
Oline, it's too late.
It's cold, nachladneš to come.
Ulrich, you have no coat,
freeze, come on.
Ulrich, please, come on! You hear me?
-Dad is home?
-Asleep.
-Sleep.
-I 'm telling you, asleep.
-I always say that it was asleep.
-Do not scream. Come on.
-Will I get beaten?
-Get.
I always say you get.
Mom?
-Where were you again, punk, huh?
Fear-ho!
I will deal with it with him.
Or kill him.
So, will it?
For him to go alone?
Bij me.
Bij me!
[mother crying]
Sleep now.
[music]
[music, laughter]
This will need.
That's we need.
Your mare would certainly take.
Sure.
And who said that the Russians
will commandeer a horse?
-Všeci to say.
-Priest to say the Germans.
-This is our need.
-Sending a horse into the woods.
Way back into the rocks.
Guys there will do.
-Guys with horses?
-Who else?
One must remain in the house.
What if burned?
Yeah.
Guys no one will do.
Neither I nor you.
Yeah.
Oldrich. Ulrich!
Anywhere you go, get up.
-He is waiting for you, you hear?
-I do not wake him go, my lord?
No, I was awake.
What are you doing?
You coughed at night?
The žádnejma not going boys.
S volama will not go.
-Even at night you nepotil?
-I told you that I nekašlu.
Nenadeláš your pants?
You go after the old way
over a wooden bridge ...
Everyone will go there.
Hay and oats in your car.
Mama, zapakuj his bread and lumps.
-How will you go?
-The old way
over a wooden bridge.
Everyone will go there.
Hay and oats on my car.
My mother would give me bread and lumps.
[music]
Ulrich!
[an organ]
[music]
What?
[an organ]
Na.
Oats in the morning and gets Evening
two cups. At noon hay.
And water, how much drink.
Listening?
Yeah, listen.
-Do you remember which way you go?
Over-bridge. -Go! -Vijó!
-Take care of the mare care.
-Ulrich, watch yourself.
And if you met the Germans
Say "lch verstehe nicht.
É!
Buuu!
Vijó!
Silence.
Jesus.
[singing]
,,, parturient
Pray for us
Holy Virgin of virgins
Father-God of heaven
-Have mercy on us
-Son, Redeemer of the world God
Holy Spirit-God
-Have mercy on us
Holy Trinity-one God
-God, in which we live
-Have mercy on us
-God, without which we perish
-God, which limits offshore habitats
-Have mercy on us
God, who art in favor of Elias
land rain fertilized
Have mercy on us
-God, our Father
-Have mercy on us
-God, who know the needs of our
God of wisdom
is unpredictable
Have mercy on us
-God, whose power is sovereign
-Have mercy on us
-Forgive us either
-Forgive us, Lord
-Hear us, Lord
-From all zlího
-Deliver 'us, Lord
-From all sin
-From Tvího anger
-Deliver 'us, Lord
The heat-palcivího
-From záhubního drought
-Deliver 'us, Lord
The lack of grass -
-The lack of water
-Deliver 'us, Lord
From crop failures and hunger,,,
Pray, Lord love looks at you.
Since the early-and eternal death
-Deliver 'us, Lord
I would like you cyrda, borrowed.
I would, but do not know,
to pay IRS this year.
Go to the stables.
Calculate how much horse hair.
Ulrich, God,
You really could not?
Kaderka give me the drum,
if he do not pay the debt.
Now on will get my meadow
a few bucks and all.
Should you lend.
What will do?
I got myself what to do.
Do I šporkasu?
She is sick,
needed by the hospital.
Jesus Christ, that's life.
Price Vyvolací thirty crowns.
Forty kacek.
Forty crowns for the first time
forty crowns again
crowns and forty-third.
Vyvolací price 2000 crowns.
Two thousand one hundred.
Do sausages.
Two eleven hundred first
two thousand one hundred again.
Two thousand two hundred.
Two thousand two hundred first
Two twelve hundred again.
Three thousand.
Three thousand first
three thousand for the second time,
and three thousand three.
Vitliška hanged herself, Cyril!
[music]
Pajamas, come on!
Run!
[music]
Sir Vitlich, Mr. Vitlich!
Who are you, smell,
king or a chimney sweep?
Cyril!
Izo!
-Stop it, what you immature?
-Ripe.
To you some kind of helper
he left with the mare.
You know what dad would do.
FMD hit him.
Ceased to fly.
They put most of the water.
Cyril, you were in vrbovne?
At that motorcycle?
What did you say?
You kicked a skeleton, right?
-Do you hear anything?
-No. What?
Departed.
These they towed away,
Russians arrive, in two shakes.
Cyril, pujcíš me a liar?
The woods.
Are you afraid of?
A little funny, huh?
Okay.
Thank you, Cyril.
Izo, come on!
Oldo, Take care!
[music]
[there is also explosions]
- [dogs growl]
-What is it?
Whoa.
We love!
We have you Caple, Resurrection!
Who? You?
When rainfall and dry.
Chachi! Vijó!
Vijó! Vijó!
Whoa! Whoa!
-Resurrection, give up!
-Vijó!
Vijó!
Vasak, now you're a goner!
Vasak, move, or you're dead!
Whoa!
Vasak, Scarecrow!
Pajamas, stop, stink!
When you caught, it will be worse.
When it will be up to?
Whoa Whoa
-Stupid, stop! Not you see sown?
-Dude!
-Despite our rye, Resurrection?
-You do not have to chase me.
-Stop!
-Where are you going? Dude!
-Resurrection!
-Stop, fool!
-Vijó!
Whoa!
-Russians! Russians coming!
-They are the Russians?
-Have you seen the stars?
-I saw the guns.
Four-machine guns.
-Did you see shit. They were bombardáci.
-Wow!
-Ficeli to Brno.
Yeah, Kader? There is Brno?
Since when? Yesterday?
-You still here?
-Guys, let me.
Vasak, I will give you cigártašku do you want?
It contains photo.
Let alone with a picture. You know
how you looked before vejpraskem.
-And I know the motorcycle.
-Yeah?
And yesterday the ladder you know?
-Some have to get slapped.
-But not from Cumáta.
No. From me.
I'll kick your ass.
Vijó!
Ten-slapped, Resurrection!
-Five!
Ten!
Stop, or it will be worse!
Vijó! Vijó! Vijó!
We're our own, Resurrection!
Vijó!
Pajamas, man, kill me now!
What 's wrong?
No.
Drink, there was nothing.
No reason.
He got a full belly.
You do it on purpose.
Vijó!
Yah!
Na.
- [dog barking]
-Silence, it's pie.
Your horse? Ja?
A good horse?
No fear. Chocolate. Na, na ...
This is our horse. Let him!
Leave me! Ouch!
No! Ouch!
Help!
No! No!
[music]
Ulrich, come down, you fall!
Come! Come!
[music]
Daddy, Daddy!
Look, over there!
[music]
See?
Come on, come on, mama.
Do not be afraid and go!
-Ulrich, kicking you.
-Ulrich, take it. Here, take.
-Daddy!
-Vijó!
[music]
Come see, come on.
Do not be afraid and go!
[music]
Vijó!
Dad! Daddy!
Well, go, go small.
Ulrich, go for the carrot.
[music]
[music, prayer]
-I 've been at confirmation.
-What? What?
[music, prayer]
Halt! Halt!
[music]
Go away! Where have you been?
Bells went to Rome.
[music]
[dog barking]
Get away from me!
Why did you nerafla?
Julina!
Maz the car! Check,
if we našmírovaný round.
[music]
[music, boozy vocals]
Dad, I'll go, do you want?
Wipe your nose.
And stay, at 'nespadneš.
Vijó!
[music]
Whoa!
Izo, where they went? Search.
I thought they were dead,
that the war sleep.
[music]
[Shooting]
Tell the wear and now I'll go.
[music]
Dad!
Before you will be twenty
so you have two horses.
[music]
Kuda ty? Lazise!
Stay!
[Shooting]
Russian:
Stop, I say!
[Shooting]
What?
You have seen a horse?
German tfuj.
You Slovak?
Austrijak?
No?
Well, I Ruskij. And you?
-Bohemia.
-How Bohemia? Slovak.
Ne Slovak. Bohemia.
-Here is the Morava.
-Moravija?
What is your name?
Hear, you.
Well, I Vasili, and you?
-Olin.
-How -Olin.
Olin?
These baba?
Olin.
Hold,
Pojd'sem,
Moravija! He Moravija!
Izo, come on. Come on.
Stay!
Four were able to calm me.
I two.
I one.
[music]
German had a knife, Dad,
wanted to kill me.
-I'll kill you!
-No!
[music]
[blowing his horn]
[music, singing, beating bells]
Resurrection.
Ouch!
[music]
[horse neighing]
[dog barking]
Quiet, lzo, quiet!
[unintelligible calls]
[shot]
[calls laughter]
-Stay!
- [shots]
[Russian]
Do not shoot! It's a baby!
Whose are you?
Does it hurt?
Your name Five?
Thirsty?
With me you can not.
Go!
[music]
-What are the stars, Mom?
-Eyes.
-Whose eyes?
-Lord God.
-Do they have so many?
Must-see all the people.
-I me?
-I you.
But now I see.
[music]
Uuu!
Go! Go!
Stop, stop! Whoa!
[music]
-Mom!
Damn dog-ear.
Where Himl Litas?
After kterejch devils trajdáš hell!
I think you zmydlím, stink!
Who loves to look after all the hell?
Do you know that war?
Small beer stupid!
Am I stupid
I did not know?
Všeci guys are in the forest
just you have to wash extraburty!
-Where have you been?
-What I mlátíš?
I'm yours, want you banging?
On the farm they are Russians.
Power forward. Somehow snapped.
Germans I šlohli Julina.
-What you šlohli?
-Kobylí. -Bullshit codswallop.
I'm not going home. Never in my life.
-Where did you come to these hajtre?
-I found him.
The Germans kicked the bridge, you know?
-It is cimpr.
-Hm.
Cyril, do not know what it is?
You better ask what he is.
Wipe your nose.
-Kam went with Julina when it šlohli?
-K Rýnovicum. Through the woods.
Wipe your frgulu.
-Damn, you can not blow his nose?
-I have a handkerchief.
Had not you
blow his nose without šnuptychlu?
-I do not want to spruce.
-You bubble.
-What?
Candle-nose.
The shit you're a legionnaire.
Yeah. Show.
-Where did you get it?
-Got.
-Who gives these bullshit?
-Russia.
-Cyril, what is linenant?
-You were there? -Hm.
You have špíglík?
What should I do with štenatama,
when you return home?
You tell me,
whom it is given.
I can not have a home kennel.
Cover with properly.
To him it is not cold.
And sleep.
-Cyril, the horse is more expensive than a motorcycle?
-Sleep, do not worry.
Hemelku splašíme.
Dragged her away.
On-the mare vyflákli and let
it stuck with the car. -Yeah?
-He did not say anything about me dad?
-No. What would you say?
Or Cumát. Old Cumát.
He walks to you, right?
And what should you talk about?
Nothing.
-Where are you, Cyril?
-Nowhere. I'll be here.
Sleep.
Come on, bitch, you're going!
Going!
[music]
Vijó!
Vijó! Vijó!
[music]
Vijó!
Cyril!
Izo!
[Russian]
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
Stay!
Chyt'ho!
[call in Russian troops]
Thank you.
Grand hall!
Unprecedented spectacle!
World attraction!
Half-woman, half ...
No! No! Aah!
[music]
[laughter soldiers]
[Russian]
Prepare! Fire!
[music]
[laughter soldiers]
[Russian]
Who are you?
Smoke?
How old are you?
This is not for you,
At night you were ...?
Na.
Messer.
Wait here
Andrjuša!
Na.
Eat
A Brno, there?
Aha.
A Prága?
[music]
-I have a bike.
-Hm?
Motorcycle-I.
-Would you?
Hrr hrr hrr ...
-Tydýt!
-Motorcycle?
Well, motorcycles, Sajda. Mine.
-You?
-No, and has Sajda.
-Where?
-There.
-No!
-Run!
Go, go!
[shots]
Well what is it?
Get,
So what?
We go?
[shots]
[music]
Compliment, Frau Singer.
[music, shouting boys]
[gunfire, explosions]
[music, calls in German]
[music]
Throw it to us, pajamas, hurry!
-Give it here!
-Throw it to us, Resurrection!
-Quickly!
-Come on, give it to us! -Come on!
[Shooting]
[music]
Bullocks.
Brats one, steers.
Get back!
Guys!
[Shooting]
[music, laughter]
[shot]
[music]
Ulrich!
Annie!
Hurry! What are you looking at?
[music]
Mom!
Mom! Mom!
[music]
Mom!
[noise of tanks, people cheering]
Whether live the Soviet Union!
Banzai
At 'lives Marshal Stalin!
Whether live Red Army!
Banzai
[music]
Do not run away! Step!
Denunciatory-Bastard!
-How much they paid Singer?
You had made a postman?
-All denounced someone?
-That he did not take you hákoš with you!
-Who will lead her to shed the Germans?
-Bitch!
Twenty-five on your ass!
-String! Rope on his neck!
-Stinky!
What do you stand?
-Now it vyríkáme!
-You kolaborante!
-Where 's my little hákoše?
-Get down, bitch, and pray!
-Bastard, to its knees!
-You can not beg, pig?
I'll show you, Stinky!
These Lump one,
that you are not ashamed!
[music, joy]
Coming!
[cries boys]
-Hold it!
Drop-ho!
[Laughter]
Nikdyjsem be learned,
vjednom the German city
standing at the station wagon.
For hours. Day.
It was a Julina.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org