FANTASTIC PLANET
She stopped moving
Now we can't play
with her any more
Careful! It's Mr Sihn
Look, father.
A female Om and her baby
Is she dead?
I'm afraid so, Tiwa
Why does the babymake noise?
It's aither frightened or hungry
We can't leave him
May I keep him?
Let me, father
I'll take care of him
All right, Tiwa,
we can't let the animal die
He was the Great Master
of the Traag people
He saved my life
and took me into his home
Mother!
See how cute the little Oms is!
His mother's dead.
I want to keep him
He is very pretty, Tiwa
You disturbed your mother's Meditation!
Make that animal behave
or I'll take it away!
Father, he got away.
He needs a collar
Learn to use it Watch
Now put the animal down
It's fun. Let me try
Not so fast
Tne animal is delicate
You might hurt it
Did you name it?
Tiwa, like me
That's not an Om's name
Name it Frisky or Trusty
Watchhim wiggle, the little devil!
I'll name him Terr
I was forgotten!
A baby Om nothing compared
to Meditation!
A weird virtual.
Traags devoted
most of their time to it
It seemed to be chief concern
Oddly enough, the housing unit factory
on our Uva at Goham...
has not met production levels
The machines show unusual wear...
This wear cause the delay
Master Taj, can you explain?
We don't know yet
Meanwhile ve'll use machines
from our reserve...
to meet the schedule
I don't understand
The machines worked
perfectly until now
Have you had similar problems
on other Uvas?
Only machines from our space flight...
to planet Antax 4
have trouble completing their program
Master Sihn, our scientists...
explain this loss as a break
in yhe sensory compensation system
Scientists also notice that animals
brought from planet Terra...
have sovibon
and rather high intelligence
I am not sure that is true
Obviously,
the animal adapts rather well
But is that intelligence?
The little pet you stroke...
between Meditations may well...
surprise you some day
Films made in Terra
show many traces of organized life
This ability to adapt, Master Kon
may indicate advanced evolution
Oms have a much shorter
life span that we
But we must not forget
that they multiply much more rapidly
It the animal is intelligent,
Master Sihn...
we have not yet noticed
Wat we do notice
is the considerable damage...
caused by Oms
on the Uvas of Jext and Telez
The numbers of tame Oms
is easy to control
But wild Oms probably exist...
in much larger numbers
than most of us realize
We de-om the enclaves...
of wild Oms every 3 cicles.
But I wonder if...
that is often enough
Few weapons have a long-term effect
Drastic measures must be taken
New ways to fight them
are being researched
I doubt if they will suffice
Go play somewhere else
I'm very sorry
Imagination was so rich today too...
That Om is a pest!
Plaease, our children
all love those animals
I grew up fast
in that slow world
A Traag week was equal
to one of my years
Iwas only a live plaything
I was sometimes rebellious
Terr loved Tiwa...
Repeat!
" Terr loves Tiwa...
Repeat! "
Tiwa got her learning
from a headphone
Its lessons cut directly
into the brain...
engraved on the memory forever
" Our Planet Ygam has one satellite...
"the Strange Planet.
it is uninhabited
"It is used for Meditation
"Ygam is divided into several Uvas
"Uvas Strop and Yot
are natural and symmetrical
"Urtana,
the largest Uva, is covered
"with blue assonic blocks
"Its temperature range...
"from 8 to 243 laiks...
"making ripocal
exploitation impossible...
"Our Uva, Goham,
has a fepular inland sea...
"stabilizing
the apenosh at about 20 laiks
"Fixations bloks
offset pontic rebation
"Er-shaped globes regulate pressure
"All Uvas under go a cycle
of 3 seasons of unequal length
"The seasons of garus crystalization..."
"An accident enabled me
to acquire the Traags knowledge"
"When the soil peels,
intense vegetation..."
"replaces all nosks
with similar nosks"
I liked the lessons
I tried to get the most out of them
" the cliffs
on the fepular sea are eroded...
" by rains that offten last long "
Tiwa, bring your animal!
Jurgal has his and we'll have some fun
I don't want him hurt
Jurgal's animal is insane!
Once, he almost tore off his ears!
He won't damage your Om.
Come and play!
Come and see!
Let Terr fight,
it will be more fun
Terr will win,
he's a real demon!
Now fight!
He sings well
Terr can sing too
Sing, Terr. go on!
- Hall strangle him!
- He doesn't realize
What a mean animal!
"It is simple to see
a tark's fladed muscles...
" because the animais easily skinned... "
Do you hear the Om?
That's Tiwa's lesson!
She loves Terr so much
that he is with her always
Can he understand what he says?
I don't think so
Anyway, I'll forbid her
to keep Terr during Infos
She must study seriously
" The liscinian muscle
of a trak's leg...
" is a fleshy, fuliform vilok...
The molog is an enviparous animal...
It has more than half a billion lucons
" The entire surface of their walls...
" is made up of little cells...
" separated by leaves
of thin organure "
" Some scientists... "
" today believe it is not organure
but only gambous amalga... "
" an artificial structure... "
Have you got Terr again
during you info?
I told you to stop!
Into the Omhouse!
But father, he doesn't bother me...
And he's so happy
The Infos are for you!
Get back to work!
It was time for the Traag children
to have their first Meditation...
The initiation ceremony
was a major step...
on their road to knowledge
After a while
I lost my intimacy with Tiwa
As shegrew up, she gave up her playthings
Deprived of lessons,
I decided to run away
Mother, I can't find Terr
An my headphones is gone
! use your bracelet
If he's far away, it'll hurt him
Put your bracelet on maximun, please
No mother...
You're pretty stupid
! Like all tame Oms!
You have a collar too
It'a a fake, to fool the Traags
What's that?
The Traags invented it
What?
The Traags made it
! Listen
" Valio, cycle, info 4..."
" You will observe
that Aklon research..."
" in solid pernetrope..."
" works the same as
in plane pernetrope "
" Notice that we look
for festation groups "
Don't worry, it's no dangerous
Where are you taking it?
- I don't know.
- Come with me!
My new friend took me to her people
who lived hidden in the Big Tree.
deep in an abandoned park
As a silly tame Om, my firts meeting
with wild Oms was a failure
Don't touch that case, it's a trap!
Since I brought
the headphone of knowledge...
the wizard opposed me at once!
We've brougth 5 cases, Chief
What? Is that all?
One of them was a trap and Speed is dead
He knew it was a trap
He's a tame Om
He ran away with a Traag device
It taught him to read Traag writing
He knows what's in the cases?
in that one?
Color powder
" Urtana is covered
with blue assonic blocks "
" Its temperature range from 8 to 243 laiks... "
"making ripocal explitation impossible "
Our Uva, Goham,
has a fepular inland sea
" stabilising the
apenosh at about 20 laiks "
" Fixations blocks...
" offset ontic rebation "
" Er-shaped globes regulate pressure... "
Why interrupt the info?
Traag knowledge is bad
We don't need it
We are not tame Oms
It is great offense!
You must battle according to the Law
Bring the combat animals!
You win. Stay with us Oms
of the Big Tree
You can be of use to us
Tomorrow we go on an expedition
It was my first expadition
to steal Traag food
We brought a great deal back
Take heart, the Big Tree isn't far
The Hollow-Bush bandits!
Look out!
Why attack us?
They're from the Hollow Bush
Beware of them
They are thieves
from the other side of the park
The Great Zarek
3000 cycles before Krowp...
" Created the pyramidic civilization "
" From his tomb - they say
he still animates... "
" the ball of Life "
" Projectiles pierce him
but he does not change "
" His mind travels through Ygam's skies... "
" regulary ever since
he led the Traags... "
" to victory againts the Jankos "
" This may well be
how Maditation originated "
" Some believe
that Zarek is immortal ands... "
" that from the flames of time
he reappears in infinitely varied... "
" whirling reality... "
" to combad the Traags will to die "
" Actually "
" driving out the Jankos made... "
" the Traags develop
a spirit of enterprise... "
The Oms are learning
if only we hand more headphones
You know as much as the Traags
I am barely learning to write
Look
Are you sure?
Did you read it right?
All the park walls read " de-om "!
What does it mean?
The Traags want to kill all the Oms!
Long ago...
I saw them de-om the park
It was horrible!
But now on our tree,
there's not much danger
What will we do?
- It had to come
- Anyway, we have time to prepare
We'll post sentries
They'll slaughter us...
to punish us for stealing knowledge
Let us pray to the Strange Planet
Sentries will warn us when they come.
Tomorrow we shall see.
What are you doing on our land?
I came to warn you.
The Traags intend to de-om
De-om!
You don't say!
How do you know?
One of us read it on the wall!
Can Big-Tree Oms
read Traag writing now?
Don't listen to him!
It's a trap to get us out
of the Hollow Bush!
Believe me, the Traags will de-om!
Take him away!
Someone go look at the walls!
Listen!
- Traags!
- Quiet!
I smell Oms here
That vermin!
The Masters should...
de-om more often!
It's not bad to have pet Oms...
They're fun
But all those wild Oms...
They steal
They're dirty
and multiply appallingly fast
Look...
A nest by the valk
See... A whole colony
Let's kill Them
Chief is dead
Stop weeping like children
We must go
where the Traags can't find us
I know a place,
I'll take you there
This road leads
to an abandoned rocket dump
We'll be safe there
I regret that we de-om
only every 3 cycles!
This killing proves
it is not enough!
A Traag murdered!
It's unbelievable!
Are we so weak
that Oms can kill us...
So easily?
Wild Oms are much more numerous
than we thought
The body showed many...
bites and wounds, said Traag
who managed to escape slaughter
bites Oms were very numerous
Every day wild Oms become bolder!
They multiply at a terrifying rate!
Master Sihn,
it is disturbing to note
that your Uva at Telez
is not the only one that has been.
very difficult to de-om
Two other Uvas...
Goham and Urtana...
have hand similar problems...
Near the murdered Traag we found...
two surprisingly well organized lairs
mot disturbing of all was that...
in one of the lairs...
cases were sorted
according to contents
But they were unopened.
How could the Oms
Know what they contained?
It is high time
to take efficient measures!
I suggest we de-om twice a cycle
I also request stric regulation
of the breeding...
and selling of tame Oms
Too often they turn wild again...
and go join the throngs of Oms...
living in parks
and other isolated areas
We must use the new, much-discussed
de-om-ing devices at last
We must exterminate all wild Oms.
And I ask you:
Should we keep our tame Oms?
We are wrong to believe Oms
are merely vicious animals
If we do, we may commit...
an erro de serious consequence
Ygam had..
3 seasons equal to...
15 of our years
The Traag rocket graveyard
was abandoned
There we built our city
We planned to go
to the Strange Planet
Many tame and wild Oms
came to join us
Knowledge asquired
from the headphone...
enable us to reduce...
Traag rockets...
to our size
" Trinur is a metal
that palsifies Matwar
top-grade reculid gives it
a remarkable metallic shine "
We have succeeded, Terr
Two rockets are for testing
Two rockets are ready for testing
- It's only a matter of work and time
- We must hurry!
Many time Om informers say...
that a large-scale
de-om-ing is near!
They may know where we are
Whe must send up
our two rockets at once...
to see if we can live
on the Strange Planet
We cannot wait any longer!
Too bad. I can't go with you
I'm not afraid.
I'm sure you'll succeed
I know you will build...
a new world
where Oms can be happy...
for away from the Traags
The Strange Planet
will be our planet...
a world for our children
You must go!
You must hurry!
You must...
We had discovered
the secret of the Traags
The Spheres of Meditation there
enabled Traags to meet...
beings from other galaxies
and hold strange nuptial rites
This union gave them vital anergy
which they needed...
and enabled them to reproduce
We were afraid...
The statues feet
might damage our rockets
We found
the only weak point of yhe Traags
On Ygam, the de-om-ing was halted
Never have the Traags
been in such great danger!
Our entired civilization is threatened!
The Oms atre taking revenge
They have incredible
scientific knowledge
They must be stopped
It may be too late
Neither Oms nor Traags...
will profit from destruction
We must try
to make peace
" Sine the Sihn era,
the Traag civilization has undergone
a remarkable evolution
" The Oms, instructed
by our philosophy and...
Technology...
now provide the Traags with...
dynamic sitality
and a new way of thinking
Our palnet now has two satellites
one natural and one artficial
The natural one, the Strange Planet...
is keep for Traag Meditation
The artificial one was made by de Oms.
They named it Terr.
" Oms live in huge cities
on the various Uvas "