THIS CHURCH WAS AT ONE TIME THE OBJECT
OF MUCH ABUSE HAVING BEEN BUILT BY
A CO XCOMB CHEEKY ENOUGH TO ALTER
THE GROUND PLAN CONTRARY TO THE RULE.
WE WERE ACQU AINTED WITH THAT MASTER
BUILDER AND WE LIKED HIM WELL,
EVEN INF HE WAS SOME WHAT DISSOLUTE.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
THE CAPRICIOUS SUMMER
This is an unfortunate summer indeed.
Shouldn t the month of June at least
permit us to attend
to our health and cleanness?
Hey, mister!
Get down from the broomatick
I see you are riding.
Where did you learn such manners?
- Pray do not cell me indecent.
I removed my trousers
because the skin too wants to brathe.
I was taught and I follow
the rules of hygiene.
For the benefit of my body.
Being enthusiastic for the present.
You are neglecting things eternal.
The book I laid down
is near enough to be remindful
of what duration means.
It is 2000 years old!
Pay attention to my words, major.
The major has not read your book
an will never read it.
Even if it were older still.
Should he believe the bray
of old asses sounded better?
He has come to fish
and you scare the fish away.
Oh no.
I have come to like these discussions.
Although I do not find them very noble,
I admit them.
As a faint reflex of passion.
What can be more magnificent
than an ever blue sky
and an ever burning red passion?
I am doubtful about the blue sky.
This June is not up to the mark.
Why are you holding back?
As if do not moan hours long?
Being poor I cannot afford
to expres my indignation.
Yet, I feel inclined to curse.
But for your propensity to wrangle
I could be of some help
but you always want to have
the last say.
Better to have the last say
than the last blow...
Oh, you are never idle!
We are discoursing on abstract things
with the canon.
I thing you are talking nonsense
and shouting as if money was at stake.
I have had to listen
to my husband s prating
ever since I married him at seventeen.
For you should know
I was too young when I got married.
I could have chosen better fellows
if Antonín had not thrashed my suitors
got hold of my keys
and plagued me
until marriage became unavoidable.
How can I, major, under such
circumstances
heed your kings
the canon s books and my own health?
It's true, Antonín was very much in love
and of excellent health.
I bet he gave the fellows
a good hidding.
My husband is an unparalelled ass
come sir, let me ferry you.
Those two won t hear a word...
I am ready to bet
they are talking about fire-arms.
You never met the organist, abbé
who used to pinch my hip...
singing merrily at the same time.
I am sure you are not lagging behind
him - in inventiveness,
being much travelled
and highly educated.
The swimming master, you and I
are old enough not to be tempted
to jump over a neighbour s fence.
The canon is a pervert
beware of him.
Oh, this has nothing to do with me.
You are uncanny, major.
Always astraddle, perspiring
casting lightening-glances
you remind me of a sergeant
I used to know rather intimately
when I was young.
Lend me a hand!
That sergeant was as quarrelsome as you.
I offered him everything suitable
to curb his vehemence.
Still, he twisted buttons
in his impatient fingers...
and drank bottle after bottle.
He was in the army-service corps
wearing red breaches, not like you
an old artilleryman.
Regiments wearing red breaches
were recruited form farm hands.
Oh, indeed?
I have never heard such opinion.
Those fellows,
were the darlings of our street.
Your husband to whom you are indepted
for having taken you out
of a hideous suburb
was neither a wagoner nor a gunner
but a sapper.
Don t I know it!
Hint at anything else
and the master will baste you.
Only fools neglect the present
living in the past.
Let us eat nad drink!
Give me fat cheese, venison
birds, lambs, all that is brought
forth alive or hetched from eggs.
Give me fish and the slugs
favoured in civilized countrics.
Give me food
the Earth has revolved again
and it is time to eat.
Have you become a windbag
or a glutton, major?
Showing off with you teeth
or your tongue?
Too much talk makes me uneasy.
Uneasy?
We have hardly begun!
You follow a bad regimen
with too much thinking.
Even while eating
which is another form of gluttony.
Do you want to start another quarrel?
Only because of your bad habits.
If I stuck up to my cars in water
you would pull me out.
Are you not drowning in errors
more fatal than water?
Where is the vinegar?
And salt...
Remember how we used to put
salt on our toast?
Alas!
I remember the Italian campaign.
Why was the first Piave battle lost?
The army was short of mugs.
So that we drank wine from hands.
The soldiers had to punch the casks
with their bayonets
and several regiments
were drowned in wine in cellars.
Much wine was wasted that way
wine which would otherwise have
stimulated thir waning courage.
Show your courage, major
by lifting a quintal.
I could recite some verses
which are immortal though dealing
neither with slaughter nor
weight-lifting.
Do not repeat bookish twaddle!
Silence!
I shall answer youwith this weapon.
The abbé will die from fear!
All right, I have means
to take you down a peg.
Valour burnt high
Though the arms grew weaker...
To blazes with your book of odes!
And by sword and spear
Men died on the ramparts...
The finger gnawing at
an unintelligible line...
Still, those who died were the victors.
Go hang, you interpreter
of shortwinded lines
limping according to rules!
Their life alone took the cunning foe
And they were crowned with eternal
glory.
Enter unhesitatingly!
The abbé and the major
found the water warmish.
Should you be short of anything
shout and I shall be in time...
My husband may be silly
but he knows his rights
and how to protect them.
If he did not, he would be more
than simply... Antonín.
Yes, Antonín - because I am Katherine.
You have acquired some logic
which is disarming.
I am going to leave
because some of these females
always try to drown
in sight of us.
Be smart in case of need
and cauticus if they are not of age.
Being a stalwart man of fifty
you are welcome here, major.
Do you want these women
to go away and leave
my swimming-bath unfrequented?
This would ruin me!
You seem to be too sure
of our tolerance.
All commanders are naturally tolerant!
I am Ernie, the conjurer
and, being sensitive to cold...
The clear sky spells a hot day.
Undress, gentlemen!
Is it you, sir
who are in everybody s mouth?
The fire-eater said to have lived
in Paris
who has arrived from Holland?
I was everywhere.
Like all magicians!
Chaps munching glass.
Producing wigs from their sleeves.
Self confident in spite of
a misshapen chest.
He seems dressed for some other
occasion.
Too extravagant...
He is showing all his limbs
in his pink tights.
Pink is the colour of piglings.
If pink is the colour of pigs
the scientists grey
is the colour of rats.
This is a capricious summer.
It was raining yesterday
and it may be raining today.
Is Dutch weather equally bad?
A little better.
But the sundays are meantly wet.
I am practised in clever feats
which, though physical
are mental as well.
I make things vanish from sight
imperceptibly, by a sleight of hand
the cutcome of much thinkings
and long deliberation.
Will you tell me the time, sir?
I feel something like a chill
between the two hemispheres of my brain.
I hear a ringing as of Easte-bells
and it is the ticking of a watch
within my skull.
This watch was inside your head?
Your artistic skill must be rewarded.
Oh, I never expected to find
so much discernment
in an out-of-the way country.
My public ussually shows
less appreciation, showering on me
uneatable objects.
People are so rude!
But give me my watches back!
I ask no more than to be rude, too.
Time flies and I cannot
hold it back.
Allow me to invite you
to my performance.
Mysteries! Amusement!
A heartrending spectacle!
Reduced entrance-fee
for children and soldiers!
Mr. Ernie is a smart fellow.
Did you see him blush
when the major made
that churlish gesture?
A smart fellow, indeed.
He ate and drank his fill
without paying the entrance-fee.
If that devil of yours were near
he would use his pitchfork on us
A because we fancy women
and are hurrying
to a magical pastime.
You are mistaken, Antonín.
I own no devil
and the devil has no pitchfork.
Pretty girls are deucedly scarce
but they do exist.
Each of them has her instrument
and all of them are present.
That rascally Ernie has roused
the town
with his tricks and his bragging.
What else has brought
so many people here?
I am not used to emotion...
Isn t she pretty, though?
Hasn t she got everything?
Antonín, let us ask her
to remove that... array!
These are fruitless trees.
But nature can be corrected.
Are you ready to pay, gentlemen?
Whispering is a bad habit
objected to by moralists.
Ever since it was sondemned
by the catechism, people abstain
from it
except in churches.
Enough!
The lady is in a hurry...
I wager, dear abbé, I can do it
as expertly without any preparation.
Do not overdo things, sir!
I bet he is not following his nose.
It always shows a deviation
to the right or left.
You are talking rubbish.
Did those somersaults seem imperfect?
If you seek perfection in somersaults...
I've got nothing to say
This is a dark night
and a lot of rascals
want to steal your bath towels
and other articles.
Go to sleep, dear Katherine
I shall be keeping watch.
The couch in the cloakroom
will serve for a vigilant rest.
I'll sleep with one eye open.
Open the door, you depraved lecher!
This accursed vocation
has earned me nothing
but insults and injury.
I could have chosen
forom a tidy bunch of young men
and look what I picked out:
A blockhead and a wencher
chasing after quills
with his home full of feathers!
You are drinking, gentlemen?
Is it you, major?
And you, reverend?
Hurry up, now!
Get this poor girl
some warm milk and dry umderwear!
Lam afraid she has got drowned.
I dived for the poor child
a girl hardly 20 years old
or she would have drowned.
I hear it was Anna, the girl
form the conjurer s caravan.
How come you've drag her
through willow trees here.
And that she had
to jump into the river
to save herself from a shameless rake.
It is nice to have a jilly girl friend.
I know it.
The pink little ears, the red lips...
I say, I know it
but the time's passing by.
All that is too easily forgotten.
Being stupid, women have never
aceomplished anything great
and are ignorant of spiritual delights.
Besides causing degeneration
by interbreeding with the offspring
of noblemen, and begetting
readers of deposit books.
Tonight I found a girl in his bed.
Wasn t she wet?
I heard the clink of glass
the purl of water, but alas!
Oh, gosh, father
now it's clear to me.
They deceived me by drenching
her underwear!
Look at Antonín!
Could such an oaf
win a pretty girl?
Are you sure it was Anna?
Canon Roch is right.
It was some hag carrying firewood.
Though lascivious once
your husband is old now.
I know best how old he is.
This wench did not come from the wook
she came from the caravan.
Yes, Canon, it was Anna!
No inactivity here!
No inactivity at all!
This bird reminds me
of your own chickens.
These are the lamentable confusions
of the ripe age.
Love arising from the transition
of periods.
I can see my obese
but respectable wife killing chicken
to carry them blushing
to Ernie s caravan.
I am ready to forgive her
but I want to be sure
her new passion is a lasting one.
Regone lovers, depart
and for heaven s sake
let it be for ever!
How nice is to count days up to three
How beautiful to wander
from town to town!
How beautiful to conjure up flames
to handle nice round objects!
How beautiful... the a lamps!
The magic hat!
And a steep rope.
Oh, it's so wonderful!
Why are we having such fine nights
and such inclement days?
Because you are a great sinner.
Counsider it a punishment.
Rubbish!
We used to be sinning more
and yet the sun was shining...
I don't think this is the point.
The mutual attraction of sexes
is older than rocks
and I can t see a deluge coming!
Do you never feel the urge
to concur with that creative power
in defiance of your Carthusian rules?
Dear Mr. Antonín, thank you
for coming to my aid.
You are so delicate.
Didn t you catch a cold?
I had a cup of tea
and Mrs. Důrová, aou wife
took good care of me.
My wife indulges in idle talk.
Let her stay in a Ernie s Ark
and don t ever go back to him.
Ernie may be a mediocre conjurer
but he is a good foster-father.
Look at his magic!
Katherine playing the barrel-organ
Anna collecting the money
both of them living with him.
This sorcerer has the devil s help!
I've often been afraid you are not sane.
I see I was justified
in my fear for your sanity.
Treating it as a joke
after your wife has left you!
I wonder how Ernie is going to make beds
with two women
and a single bedroom.
I should have given you this book
the first time we met.
Yes?
Yes, dear Anna, it contains
chaste love stories
suitable for your ears.
Excuse me, I am frying fish
the supper might get burned.
Why, the fish are not fresh anyway
and today is not Friday.
All right, I shall let you hold
the saucepan over the fire.
Ernie is a moulting ape.
And he s knock-kneed too!
But he knows the ropes.
Isn t his lass all right!
For the bed!
OK, now!
In the name of the law!
What are you doing here?
I went to see him.
His ear torn and his face all swollen.
He was reading two books
and seemed in good mood.
He ought to show repentance
and castigate himself...
as they did in good monasteries
Isn t he a monk?
No.
Antonin, you should not give him
such bad advice.
He got his desert.
With his ear nearly torn away
needing a few stitches...
Get ready with your needle!
A physician might spread the rumour
that your ear was not damaged
in defence of the Church.
And cos' it is better to keep
our mouth shut about the whole thing
Let Mr. Důra doctor you.
He is very skilled with needle
as you know.
Anotnín Důra is a gifted man.
Will you have a glass of wine?
I shall need some spirit.
Or some hot water
for my long neglected tools.
You know I try to avoid trouble
and my nearly nevered ear
cannot make me change my attitude.
I returned to Ernie s caravan
and entered into conversation
with Anna who was frying fish.
Did you have supper with her?
I had a morsel of the fish
you caught in the river...
Keep your shameless story to yourself!
I don't want to hear it! I know it!
Be cheerful, abbé, cheerful!
Present you ear with heroic
determination and stop swearing
I might get confused!
Oh, you lecherous poets!
Oh, you confounded literature!
When will artistic writing
turn its back on brothels?
And embrace noble civic virtues?
When shall we be reading
about sale and purchase
about patrictiam
cattle breeding nad a amelioration?
Or a book of poems
about bodily strength
and agitation for a just class-rule?
When will it be?
In some distant time?
I heard you, abbé
droning verses of no educational value
frothing with the violent blood
and cruelty of specialists
who at the very cost of starvation
always try to introcuce
a new, uninteligible beauty.
The major and I say
it is a nonsensical and vulgar one.
And your manners have become
so dissolute that you get into brawls!
Yes, I got hart and you
sewd up the wound.
It is also true
that i Used to sit
on the river bank, reading books.
Books by Shakespeare
Rabelais and Cervantes.
I would lay down my head for them
as I nearly laid down
my ear for Anna.
The battlefield is the only place
to die nobly.
Poets make bad soldiers, anyhow.
Mr. Důra is right.
What I say is:
Distance can be mensured by wandering
just as affluence by hunger
and play precedes action...
Or, are you not convineed, major
that everything has its origin
in the playfulness and courage
of people who have time to spare
to babble like Gods
marshalling things
into an amasing sequence?
I observe, Antonín,
your character is changing
you have just spoken
in favour of potery!
No, no, forsooth!
I never thought of doing it.
Dear madam, near Mülhausen
we got into a snowstorm.
The funnel not drawing
it was cold in the caravan...
You know what foul weather means.
But was your caaravan clean?
Only a well kept home
is pleasant to live in.
I intend to make some coverlets
and cushion, Ernie
to embelish it.
Don t forgot the rug.
Anna burnt a hole in it
with a cigarette.
I reproved her yesterday.
She is damaging wilfully our property.
If she does not mend her was
I shall give her an hour s notice.
Ernie will not leave his caravan
in this weather...
I see you want to stay at home
and that you have hardened you heart.
Is it the very first time
you got the mitten?
Leave sour thougths alone.
Get reconciled with the Canon
who is only and instrument
of providence.
Have you forgotten how we used
to hunt on the river bank
for earth worms who love moisture?
The pleasant conversation
the delightful squabbles we had
which always ended well...
Antonín, all that is coming back!
I have said many times
Anna does not fit into such
surroundings.
Look how puzzled she looks!
Her plate nearly empty!
You should marry her, major
I think she is being ill-treated
by Mrs. Důrová.
Miss Anna, leave the caraven.
Come to us!
Take my swimming bath
take the Canon s books.
What about the major?
I shall kill the conjurer
and got to jail.
Get down!
Come down, mister!
And do not tempt providence
You re going to hurt yourself!
And you'll get nothing for that
Stop that nonsense, come down!
What did I say?!
The conjurer is dead!
He s simulating!
- The bump he got!
Serves him right.
Why did he climb up there!
Let s collect a few crowns
and buy him a hen for his soup.
Don t forget, dear neighbour
we don t hold with collections.
Think what you could buy!
And have a good time...
He is a poor fellow.
He deserves spanking
so that the town is peace]ful again!
You cry too much!
My companion hates murdeous tumbles
as much as blubbering.
Now put on Ernie s tights
for another performance.
A crowd is waiting!
Am I, a respectable citizen s wife
to také part publicly
in deception and subterfuge?
I am used to a decent house
and I shall have it again
because Antonín is calling me back.
I saw him several times
near the caravan, pole
perturbed and ready to tear
the caravan into splinters.
You are right.
You left your hearth for a while
and now you are the martyr...
Go home
before I reach for my stick!
I used to know some verses
fitting the most terrible situations.
Unfortunately I only remember
the first line:
""Také to your heels...""
Don t you know the rest?
No.
But the abbé might.
...she was dancing
in the circus Ferdinand
with a pear in her mouth.
People called it eccentric
and I do think
it was far from becoming.
Fresch lips need no ornament.
Oh, major
Displaying the mechanism of her joints
and the ontraction-of her muscular
system
Anna is the personification
of all that constitutes
the roots of theatrical art
a glorification of God
who created men in his own image.
Anna!
Where have you been?
I stopped at the swimming-bath
it is in shambles!
What have you been doing?
Oh, you have come for your things.
Také them and get out of here!
I decided to forgive you.
You got your desert
for you faithlesspess
living for three days
in an untidy, neglected home
without proper meals
and a good night s rest.
I can no longer be
angry whith you, Anonín.
So much the better.
But my defects
are past remedy.
Today I saw a woman
washing linen in the river.
She was not as pretty as Anna
and yet I felt
I had not changed.
Silence!
You may stay
but mind your tongue!
Oh, how beatiful...
Look where you hit
you might hurt my girl.
Your girl?
Have you lost you senses?
No, because Anna stays here
and you go away.
Let us be lenient
with the weekness of our friends.
Let him live!
Don t kill the major!
Are you all right?
This morning the magician
beat me up with his wand.
I have still more reason
for complaining.
Katherine has returned home!
Thin is an unfortunate summer indeed.
Cast
Unit:
Screenplay
Dramaturg
Artist
Musical Score
Recorded by
Choreography
Song Performed by
Sound Editor
Editor
Stylist
Costume Designs
Settings
Director Assistant
Script
Director of Photography Assistant
Production Assistant
Production
Director of Photography
Directed by
Produced by
Production Unit
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org