FILMEXPORT HOME VIDEO
Presents
DIAMONDS OF THE NIGHT
Based on the Story by / ScreenpIay by
Cast
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Assistant Director / 2nd Cameraman
Associate Producers
2nd Architect
Costumes by / Property Master
Made in Cooperation with
Costume Designer
Make Up
Sound Editor
Film Editor
Production Designer
Produced by
Director of Photography
Directed by
Made by the Creative Group
Come closer to me.
Those branches.
Are you asleep?
If it was downstairs,
we could knock.
I'm cold.
I can't walk it off.
How long is it
since we've eaten anything?
I don't know.
There's no use counting it.
I'll get something today.
You won't get anything!
Sit down to me.
Go aIone.
Wait for me!
She must give me some milk.
I'm also satisfied.
I can see satisfied faces.
Now, we will check, whether
everyone is here and in order.
The cigarettes taste good, eh?
Well, we are standing in Iine
and according to our ranks.
We're going home in a moment,
another day is over.
Careful!
Stand up! Stand up!
Hands up!
And go!
Cheers!
Let us drink brothers,
Iet us live without troubles.
Let's have some kummel,
Iet's have some rye,
Iet our women get furious with rage.
I don't speak German!
You can check everything by telephone
at the police commissariat in Prague.
I live at Jungmann's Square,
in a house with a newsagent's shop
and an Italian ice cream shop opposite.
If it didn't change.
House No. 4.
The army patrol will arrive
at 6 o'cIock,
it will take you to Carlsbad
and the court martiaI will decide.
Saint Peter has closed the gate,
aII the angels are going to bed,
only he must stay awake,
as that oId rascal
and his cupids so small
are going to have a ball.
The mayor is calling me.
Remain seated!
We wiII attack the guards on the way.
- Swear.
- I do.
Quiet!
If everything is ready,
take them out.
Aye-aye, sir! I will see to it.
Come on, out!
Attention!
Aim!
Fire!
The End
Watch more movies for free on
www.FlixTor.to