Watch more movies for free on
www.FlixTor.to
The White Dove
Open the cages!
Is that the lot? What?
For God's sake, what's taking them?
Hurry! Hurry!
Hey!
You wanted to eat it, didn't you?
- You little good-for-nothing!
- This one's half dead.
There's nothing wrong with her.
Fly away, little one.
THAT MORNING CARRIER
PIGEONS FLEW FROM BELGIUM
THEY WERE ALSO EXPECTED
ON A SMALL ISLAND
IN THE BALTIC SEA
Hey! Call everyone,
the doves are here!
Where? Where are they?
What happened, my boy?
Oh, you always
make a fuss, Ulli.
Susanne! Susie!
Do you hear anything?
Can you see them?
You aren't even looking.
I don't have to look.
I know when my dove will be back.
- You're only thinking of yourself.
- No, I bet my dove will get here first.
I'm sure she will.
- What's going on?
- He says his dove will be here first.
You'll see. Just watch.
All we see is you shooting
your big mouth off.
You've made him mad.
They're coming, here they come!
Where, Susanne, where?
Seven...!
Look what I've got...
Where's my dove?
What you'd call an owl,
another might call a nightingale.
Mine is back,
my dove is back!
You scoundrels,
you've hidden my dove.
You lousy...
SUSANNE'S DOVE
WAS DRIVEN AWAY BY A STORM
AND GOT LOST
Good evening.
I hope I'm not intruding.
I'd just like to ask you.
Do you have a balcony
facing the yard?
Yes, over here.
It's Michel's room.
But why...?
Could I speak
to your son for a minute?
Of course. I'll call him.
Michal!
Come here, quickly!
Wait!
Do something!
Ulli!
Fetch Susanne!
Do I have to?
Right now?
Do what I told you!
Hurry up! Go home!
Are you going or aren't you?
And you leave Susanne alone, old man.
She doesn't do anything
at home any longer.
All she does is hang around
here on the beach.
Hasn't your dove
come back either?
That's none of your business.
Susanne, come quick.
Susanne, over there, on the beach.
0-3-303.
What shall we do?
Let's end her pains.
Susanne!
Don't worry about them, Susie,
they're only teasing you.
They're just like children.
Susanne...
Susanne, on the beach.
She's back.
There, on the beach chair!
This one is for you, Peter.
This one is for Paul.
And take this one to Michal.
- But he won't open the door.
- He will, run along.
Misa!
Have you come to kill her?
She's dead, anyway.
Open the door, it's us.
We want to play with you, Misa!
Misa!
Misa! Misa!
He's scared! He's scared!
Come on, Frantisek.
Stand over here.
What's your name?
Michal!
Michal. Get up, Frantisek!
I don't want to.
Nurse, lift him up.
Stand straight, Frantisek!
Nurse, take my findings down.
Heart and lungs.
Skiascopy, no findings.
So you've decided
not to walk, Frank?
Don't you want to play outside,
in the sun?
Don't you want to play
with the other children?
I don't want to!
Martin!
Just a moment.
Are you looking for something?
- I'm looking for a dove.
- Yes? For a dove?
- But it must be a white one.
- A white one?
White ones are hard to find.
Wouldn't another colour do?
- I only want a white one.
- Wait, I have a fine grey one.
- Could I have a look at the pigeons?
- Of course, come with me.
What about this one?
Come here, little one. Don't be afraid.
Looking for stray pigeons:
England
Hungary
Germany
Belgium
Poland
0-3-303...
I'll work until I've paid for her.
No.
I can't let you have her.
Take her!
Martin!
Look!
Satan, go away!
Misa!
Come here!
She's still weak.
She couldn't fly far.
You should be glad.
Hello, boys!
Look what I've got.
- Does she fly?
- Of course!
Let her go, then.
Misa, what are you going to do
when she's well again?
She doesn't belong to you.
Lemonade!
I've got something for you.
What do you think this means?
It's for Susanne.
Someone in Czechoslovakia
sent this to her.
Hey, wait a minute.
What's the hurry?
Where are you off to?
She'll come back.
Let her go, Misa!
''Glow, glow, silver moon...
''I'm getting ready
for my honeymoon...
''Green suit, red boot...
''My wedding day is coming soon...''
Watch more movies for free on
www.FlixTor.to