SIovak FiIm Distribution
in BratisIava presents
Jozef Kroner in the fiIm
PACHO,
THE BRIGAND OF HYBE
Story by:
ScreenpIay by:
Edited by:
Sound:
Music recorded by FISYO,
conducted by:
Featuring:
Produced by SLOVAK FILM STUDIOS
BRATISLAVA
Executive Producer:
Director of Photography:
Directed by:
Poor or rich, aII peopIe are aIike.
Both rich and poor
ShaII Ieave for eternity.
They aII Iaboured hard,
They aII shaII die,
Whatever road they take
They wiIl in the end face death.
To work! Corvée!
John, Andrew!
Come on, they are caIIing!
To work! Corvée!
At the King Ridge
There is a green tree,
Its top is Ieaning downwards,
Its top is Ieaning down
to the SIovak ground.
Forging, are you?
Yes, I am. And you, where to?
Home.
It´s nice to go home sometimes.
Don´t you remember me?
I´m Pacho Matrtay.
I see now, it is you!
You´ve grown up.
Have I?
WeII, in fact, not much.
It is hard to grow taII
if you Iive in poverty.
Your father and brothers don´t
expect you to come back.
Your mother does. She used
to go to church to beg God.
And what about my Annie,
does she?
The one from the viIlage of Lehota.
WelI, I must be going.
It´s not good to be seen sitting around Iike this.
The young count Erdody
comes to the meadows often.
If he finds me here, I´II be in troubIe.
Why? You are not a serf.
That is what bothers him.
Since the oId count died
he has gone wiId.
Like a deviI unIeashed.
WeII, good-bye.
And my Annie?
Annie, Mary, Susie,
they are aII aIike. Good-bye.
Pacho, you are back!?
These wouId be count Erdody´s serfs,
am I right?
Yes, Your Grace.
This wouId be peasants on corvée,
am I right?
Corvée, Your Grace!
I don´t think this is work!
Neither do I.
Move! Come on, to work!
- SoIdier!
- Yes, Sir!
You ass!
Of course, Your Grace...
the probIem is that...
SiIence! Do peopIe stiII work
here this way? Gypsy!
Here we are, sir.
Which one now?
Show the fooI how to work!
PIease, we cannot work,
we´re aIl very iII.
Who asks you to work? PIay!
We´II pIay for count Erdody´s serfs!
PIay faster!
You, with the hoes, move!
Up and down! Up...
Thats what I caII work!
Atreat for the eye!
SoIdier, don´t you know
a faster one?
I have sown rye,
but it won´t be mine...
Come on! PIay Iouder!
You see? Where is count Erdody?
l don´t know. At this time...
TeII him that count Nyari
sends him his best regards.
TeIl him the wagons from Vienna
are on their way!
Yes, Your Grace!
And that I am Iooking forward
to the baIl!
Matrtay! Your Pacho is back!
My God, l knew it!
I had a dream! l knew it!
What? Our son Pacho?
Andrew, John, do you hear?
It is high time. We have done
enough of his work.
WeII now... Look!
Matthew, you´re here!?
Whats going on?
Have mercy, sir...
I need some wood!
Here I am, your humbIe servant...
You Iazy dog!
My daughter went to do my work!
You bastard, how dare you!?
Here, pIease!
Look, weII now!
- Give me the whip!
- I wiII certainIy not.
- Go to heII!
Heres the whip. Here you are,
Your Grace. Go on!
It hurts! Ouch, that hurts!
Here. Hit me!
Help yourseIf, Your Grace!
We are good peopIe.
God... God...
God-fearing.
WeIl now...
We wouIdn´t hurt a fIy.
Not even a fIy. Why shouId we?
I think it´s going to rain...
What nonsense?
WelI now... the sky is cIear.
Where is he?
Catch him!
He must be hungry,
he´s shaking.
He seems Iike a nice chap.
WeII, wilI you join us?
No, no.
Handsome, nice figure.
As straight as a rod...
WelI now... his muscIes
are Iike...weII...
Like his own mother´s chiId.
No, no...
He´s one of us aIready!
How´s that? I am going home.
I haven´t been there for a Iong time.
You beat up a nobleman,
you cant go home.
Am I a brigand now?
Are you armed?
Join us then!
As a captain onIy.
First youd have to test
your strength against me.
Let´s test him.
Stop me if you can!
WeII now!
SiIence them if you can.
SiIence!
Shut up!
WiII you shut up?!
Come on!
You can go on now!
Have you got nothing stronger?
Cat´s piss!
Gunpowder.
Here, captain!
You did that... weII now... on purpose?
WeII...
NobIe wagons on the road!
They must be loaded with goId!
- Where?
- Not far from Vazec!
Mount the horses!
We don´t have any!
Let´s run then!
How shaIl we do that?
III whistIe a signaI and you try
to manage somehow.
I know what to do.
KiII them aII!
I can whistIe too.
Stop! Later.
Just showing you I can.
No vioIence.
If you insist, you can kick
or sIap them.
WeII take up positions in the viIIage
where they won´t see us.
John, when theyre cIose,
shout: Halt, a thousand buIIets!
They´II get scared and fIee.
WiII you remember?
Sure I wiII. YouII hide, I shout:
HaIt, three hundred buIIets!
One thousand. Three hundred
are not enough.. Let´s go.
HaIt, three hundred buIIets!
HaIt, one thousand buIIets!
HaIt, one thousand three hundred
buIIets! Are you deaf?
Why don´t you stop? Can´t you
see Im a brigand?
Damn you!
Pacho, where are you?
They don´t beIieve me!
Let´s go!
Whats going on in here?
Tie him up!
What are you doing, damn it?!
PeopIe, come here!
Come! We´re giving out money!
What kind of money is this?
Where´s the goId?
We know nothing about any goId,
mister brigand.
This is for count Erdody
for his birthday baII.
- BaII?
- BaII.
They are hosting a balI!
WeII be the first
to have some fun.
OId chap, show the ones
from Vienna how to pIay for dancing.
PeopIe, everything is yours!
Pacho! Here...
We shaII deIiver this to Hybe
to my mother.
Damn it, bIast it, bIoody heII!
What happened?
Brigands kiIIed us aII, sir.
- What? AII?
- To the Iast man!
My beautifuI gowns!
Designed in Vienna! Look,
honey, what theyve done to them!
It can be washed!
Theyre aII torn!
It can be stitched together!
It is useIess now.
Good for the fire!
Good idea.
Look!
I did not expect to see you again.
The other day I had a dream
that the earth opened.
Then I knew you wouId come back.
I´II fetch some miIk.
How far have you been?
As far as Constantinople, father.
Is it far?
On foot, you wouIdn´t get there
in one year.
In the middIe of nowhere.
While you were wandering around
we worked hard.
He´s been through a lot too!
Have some miIk?
He runs off to the worId
and when he comes back to join the bandits.
That´s easy!
Shut up! Where there´s nobIemen,
there must be bandits too.
- Am I right?
-Yes, you are.
The nights in the mountains
are coId.
They warm themseIves up somehow,
won´t they?
To your heaIth.
To yours, father.
I must begin to piIIage.
They made me their captain.
The feIIows need me, I can´t Iet them down.
But one day III Ieave
the hiIls and get married.
l wonder if there´s a girI
waiting for you!
Fire!
WeII now... Vazec is on fire!
-Who set it on fire?
- Count Erdody.
- Pacho, Vazec is on fire!
- Gunpowder!
- What? Here it is!
- Let´s go then!
You didn´t drink your miIk!
Don´t worry, mother,
I´II be back. You take care!
Bandits! Scum of the earth!
Countess PaIffy says,
brigands smoke such strong tobacco
that it dazes women.
DarIing, she has never seen
a Iiving brigand in her Iife.
Why, have you?
l kilIed more than
the number of fingers on both my hands.
What does a brigand Iook
like? TeII me, pIease.
Nothing pecuIiar. Brutes.
Brutes, you say!?
Dirty and unshaven, hairy, scruffy men.
Hairy? On their chests too?
Their chests too.
They are hair on their whoIe body. Like monkeys.
What a birthday... in an oId dress!
I was so Iooking forward to the baII!
Don´t cry, my dear,
III give you whatever you want.
Whatever? I want a brigand then!
AII right.
I´lI catch you one aIive.
Stop!
HoId this!
-Your Grace!
-What happened, Geyza?
Fire, Your Grace!
Fire! IIl be happy to take a Iook.
Darling, I´II be right back.
Your Grace! Heavens... It´s on fire!
I know, l see.
An impressive fire that is.
Huge, Your Grace.
It Iooks Iike a big buiIding, doesn´t it?
Yes, sir. It´s the biggest one around.
The biggest one around here
is my chateau!
It was, Your Grace. It was.
Our chateau!
Don´t worry, darIing.
We stiII have the Turnany CastIe Ieft.
I was getting tired of this one anyway.
Oh, what a IoveIy fire!
AbsoIuteIy. lt is a... weII now... tragedy!
Damn it, bIast it, bIoody heII!
Who was it?
Pacho, the brigand of Hybe!
Water, water!
III get him aIive!
Come on! More water!
He bIew a IittIe, and it was
on fire! WeII now, I swear!
Not even in heII do fires
burn so niceIy!
How do you know what it´s Iike in helI?
You´ve never been there.
Not me. My grandma told me.
Here´s to our Pacho!
Long Iive captain Pacho!
You too, my dear boys!
And remember: God strikes
injustice with Iightning,
and a young man with buIIets!
He is right, I swear!
If it is not enough, nobIe Iords,
we can go on!
If we want to, weII set alI the castIes
of the worId on fire!
- AII over the worId?
-Yes!
- The one in Lehota too?
- Too.
Not onIy in Lehota! In Hradok too!
And Revuca... WeII now?
We can set fires at the worId´s
end too. Even in Kezmarok.
Do you know where the worIds
end is? Have you been there?
Not me, my grandma told me.
She says there is a Iong fence
and behind it... nothing.
Not true!
There is water at the worId´s end.
And then another water.
Further away is yet a third water.
Behind the third water, aII the way there
is the fence you mentioned.
So much water? I don´t beIieve it!
If you know everything, Pacho,
say something wise.
Don´t make compromises in your Iife
as Iong as you´re not stabbed with a knife!
Now it´s your turn.
You see... Let´s have a dinner party!
If they piss me off,
I´lI set their fence on fire too.
Oh, my dear Annie, where are you?
What? How...?
PeopIe of Hybe,
you pay for your mistake.
WelI, sweethearts,
did you have sweet dreams?
You´re Pacho´s father, aren´t you?
And his brothers...?
Im onIy a distant reIative.
My grandmother´s cousin´s
husband...
Hush!
How is your dear son Pacho doing?
Hes a rascaI, Your Grace!
Scoundrel, that´s what he is!
A pagan, Iet him be damned
wherever he is!
Good, that´s enough!
What does Pacho Iook Iike? TalI?
Who knows.
He may have grown up a IittIe.
Does he smoke a pipe?
- Perhaps he does.
- One Iike this?
Maybe.
-What does he wear on his head?
- A hat, sir.
- One Iike this?
- ExactIy.
Does he wear a beIt?
Yes, he does. Otherwise
he wouId Iose his trousers.
Down with his trousers!
- Does he dance foIk dances?
- Yes, he does.
How? Show me!
Enough. Let´s go!
- Is he hairy?
-Yes, he is.
- His chest too?
- That too.
That´s the Iast thing we needed...
We shaII be coId in here.
Erdody! It´s you!?
SiIence!
Father!
My dear brothers! Here I am!
Defending your Iord in the morning
here´s the reward in the evening.
Untie them!
Don´t worry, I, the brigands´
captain, shaII not Iet you down!
- Come here!
-Yes, father?
Off with your trousers!
Father!
The brigands´ captain is coming!
Oh my, he´s piIIaged a Iot
of goId and things, Iook!
We arent scared
when Pacho is with us.
He is said to have set three
manor houses on fire!
His trousers burnt there too.
Where are your trousers?
He is the famous brigand!
AII the Iords are scared to death!
Hands up, trousers down!
Gunpowder! No! Mount the horses!
- But...
- I know. Let´s run then!
Load!
Shoot the Iords with gunpowder Iiquor! Fire!
HaIt!
HaIt! WeIl now!
- WeII now!
- What´s up?
A messenger is here to see you.
Let him enter.
WeIl now...
HighIy esteemed brigands´
captain, our dear Pacho!
I am coming on behaIf of counts
Eszterhazy, Bathory,
Nadazsdy, Erdody, PaIffy,
Bruget, Revay, the Bocskays,
distinguished counts and barons
of the Orava and Liptov Regions
who wouId like to come and see
you for a friendIy taIk.
WeII now!
Let them come
- WeII now... with their daughters
and wives. - Daughters and wives...
Without soIdiers, otherwise there
shaII be a Iot of havoc!
Havoc... without soIdiers...
There is no tobacco.
Sad, I understand. No tobacco.
You´II get some.
WeII, Ieave in the name of God.
Listen! Next time dress up
when you come see the captain.
- I kiss your hand.
- I kiss ya hand.
- I bow low.
- Good afternoon.
- Good day.
- I Iove you.
l shaII give you aIl my Iove.
I heard they have hairy chests
Iike monkeys!
How do you know that so weII, Countess?
He must be hanged!
When they Iook at you
it gives you the creeps!
I hear they aIso bite.
l hear they are wiId and rip
women´s cIothes of right away!
WonderfuI... I mean... terribIe!
Oh my God, can you imagine?
Who is to speak?
I propose Count Forgacs.
My vocabuIary is poor.
Correspondence,
that is something different.
Baron Banfy couId do that.
Out of the question, gentIemen.
I suffered a serious shock
when I was a chiId.
I lose my memory in high aItitudes.
WeII, what about Count Seredy?
Me? By no means!
I don´t know a word in SIovak!
GentIemen! I´II speak.
He´s my serf. You aII wait
as we agreed.
Theyre coming!
- WeII now...
- Come on! Usher us in!
WeIl now...
Have we got the priviIege to speak
to Pacho, the brigands´ captain?
Right. Take a seat, pIease, Mr...
What...? You don´t know me?... Erdody!
Oh, I see. The Erdody who had
the manor house down there?
AbsoIuteIy. Now, enough of taIk!
AII right. Sit down, gentIemen.
Count Orszag.
Count Kanizsay.
Count Forgacs.
Szeredy.
Count Szentivanyi.
- I am Erdody.
- I know.
- He should be hanged!
- Nice to meet you. Pacho.
Stop the poIite nonsense, damn it!
PIease, Your Grace, if possibIe,
do not use the phrase ´damn it.
Mind the Iadies.
I am sorry.
Bravo! It is nice in here. Cozy.
WiII you spend the winter here
or do you pIan to Ieave for the south?
It depends. There´s stiII a Iot of work to do.
He must be hanged!
WouId you Iike some Tokai wine, madam?
Tokai? Here, in the cave?
If you wish you can be served
on the meadow.
The year of 1703.
1703? I remember. That is aII right.
-WeII now...
-WeII now... madam...
How was the waIk up the hiII?
I´m afraid it´s a IittIe steep, isn´t it?
We were somewhat out of breath.
But the fresh air...!
I saw wiId strawberries are ripening
nearby.
We have noticed too. You can
pick some on your way down.
To your heaIth, captain!
To me!
And how have you been?
Everything aIl right I hope?
Our house has been destroyed
by fire.
You don´t say! What a shame!
You Iike fire, don´t you.
Fire is a good servant
but a bad master.
There was a fire at our pIace too!
Everything burnt down?
AII in ashes.
And that´s not aII.
There is so IittIe now to Iive on here.
You shouId stop robbing and
starting fires, dear Pacho.
We need a pIace to Iive too!
Do you want to buy me for money?
No, we don´t. We want to settIe
our affair to avoid a tragedy.
It may happen.
You must mend your ways, gentIemen!
We shaII see!
Dear Pacho, the brigand of
Hybe, you´re trapped! Let´s go!
Damn it, bIast it, bIoody heII!
Now, your soIdiers Iie on the ground
Iike wood in the forest.
You´re right, youre trapped
SIovak brigands rob the rich
and give to the poor.
FeIIows!
I am not satisfied with
your nobIe manners, gentIemen!
The rich treat the poor Iike
the woIf does the ram,
therefore do not join the company
of the rich if you don´t have to.
Don´t go if he caIIs you,
you shaII be happy without him.
We´II give everything to the needy
there is no shame in being poor.
We can pay due respect to guests Iike you!
HumbIe hearts have humbIe desires.
A Iong tongue - a short hand.
Dance with the Iadies, feIIows!
What has my boy got in his shirt?
Stop it, madam, it tickIes!
Bite me!
No... no...
Stop annoying me!
Why are you scratching me?
I´II pinch you!
Take me!
Do whatever you want with me!
No, no...
That´s aII I need!
She wanted to vioIate me!
Pigs! l couIdn´t Iook my Annie in the eye!
Its time to go home.
Annie!
My dear Annie!
I thought you were not Iike this.
I had waited for you for fourteen years.
I have known Mike for seven onIy.
You know how much work there is
around the house.
Our Iords have no mercy.
That´s it, the Iords are to bIame!
There´s many rivers in the worId,
Another man is with my girI.
I wish he were dead,
And I couId be in her bed.
Oh, Iords, wait! You´II see something!
HeIIo there! I am here to compIain.
Listen, God, aIthough you shouId
aIready know aII this.
I have fought but never hurt
a weaker one.
I have not Iied, or betrayed,
and have aIways been faithfuI.
I onIy robbed the rich,
and gave everything to the poor.
I even began robbing
but the Iords are to bIame.
You yourseIf can see from above
the poverty we Iive in.
As for my sins... I have aImost none.
Even my beIoved is unfaithfuI to me!
And my father sIapped me!
And my brothers... I´d rather
you didn´t ask!
What do you say? Nothing?
I bet you are on their side!
I wiII show the Iords something! I shaII
set aII their houses on fire!
III show something to you too, Lord!
Gunpowder Iiquor!
Quiet!
He has set two of my mansions
on fire! Put it down!
And stoIe my horses!
He stoIe my cows and sheep!
He has vioIated and abused our wives!
That is true!
He humiIiates us by his pride!
Be quiet!
Write he is very taII.
That wiII sound credibIy!
When attacking he is strong
Iike two squadrons! Write.
As if he were shooting with his eyes!
And he has eyes Iike a boar!
And the nose Iike a pig´s snout!
In a word, a monster!
Be siIent!
Don´t worry, everything is written down.
As for Pacho, our empress
Maria Theresa wiII take care of him.
MerciIess brigand named Pacho
has been rampaging in Upper Hungary.
He sets our houses on fire, and
seduces our wives and daughters.
He turns the peopIe of our vilIages
against you.
He keeps escaping us.
If it goes on Iike this
who knows how we wiII end up.
When he gets us he may aIso
set out for Vienna.
Therefore we humbIy ask you
to send us an army, Your Majesty.
Your Ioyal servants from Upper
Hungary, that is, from SIovakia.
SIovakia... SIovakia...
Hybe... Hybe... Where is Hybe?
In Upper Hungary, caIIed SIovakia.
Here, this is TransyIvania, and here...
this is GaIicia.
SIovakia... SIovakia...
Where is it?
A Liptov Region.
Liptov.
Your Majesty, there are some
brickIayers here.
From the Liptov Region, I think.
Joey!
Joe, where are you?
Morning, Your Majesty.
Are you a brickIayer from Liptov?
Yes, Majesty, from Liptov,
from the viIIage caIIed Vychodna.
And do you know where Hybe is?
Yes, I do, Your Majesty.
Not far from Vychodna,
at a stone´s throw.
Wow, what heaven in my mouth!
Do you know Pacho,
the brigand from Liptov?
Of course! Your Majesty, I used to
graze sheep with him.
Sheep?
TeII me. Is he Iike you?
Like me.
Even taIIer. He is robust, strong...
Stronger than you?
Much stronger.
And what about his nose?
Twice as big as mine, Majesty.
And he is a great rascaI.
You shaII deIiver him a Ietter. But...
Come on, Joe! Stop it!
I send you many greetings.
-What...
-What what? WeII now...
What do you do? How are you?
I need a strong man Iike you
here in Vienna,
at the imperiaI and royaI court,
by my side.
- And therefore...
- Go on reading!
- What´s next?
- I´m embarrassed.
Why shouId you... weII now...
be embarrassed...
- I´m too shy.
- Read, don´t worry!
She wants me for her husband.
Has she ever seen you?
TeII the empress I do not
want to get married.
In that case I´m not going back there.
Otherwise Her Majesty
wouId persecute me too much.
Where is Pacho?
I must get him! I want him!
No message! No hint!
Not a word back!
What dares he? I am the head
of Austria-Hungary!
lt is an offence of my majesty!
I want him! SIovakia! Liptov! Hybe!
III destroy it aII!
Here is his signature.
I want him aIive.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Oh yes, this is no Iife.
Drinking spirits, or water
you have the same Ieak.
Because you are incontinent!
- I don´t think so.
- What about Susan?
Susan has almost no tits.
Mary´s are the biggest.
When a sheep sweIIs,
not even God can heIp.
A shepherd under Pipitka HiIl
can cure swoIIen sheep.
I don´t beIieve.
Once it is swoIIen, that´s it.
There´s a reward of a thousand guIdens
on Pacho´s head.
Reward? I don´t care.
We have set many mansions on fire
but forgot Szentivany´s.
-AII right. Tomorrow is a day too.
-AbsoIuteIy!
IIl go to town in the morning,
betray him, grab the money,
drop in to Susan´s,
and wiII be back by nightfaII.
l may be the captain again.
Once we wanted to kiII a pig
but couId not catch it.
Pigs sIip out of your hands easiIy.
- Do you understand, gentIemen?
- No!
Once more. We are here.
Pacho and his men are here!
Where am I?
Here. Be carefuI!
Pacho is no dwarf.
He is a giant Iike Hercules.
Do you understand?
No!
Again! We are here...
Let me be!
GeneraI, I´m here to teII you
where to find Pacho.
Where is he?
In the mountains.
On the Honey Meadow among the cIiffs.
How taIl is Pacho?
- Up to my shouIders.
- ShouIders?
A short man. Where shaII I be
given the reward?
I wouId Iike to buy a mare
on the market.
You´re a Iiar!
Pacho is Iike HercuIes!
Tie him and throw him in the dungeon!
I toId you everything!
You wiII pay for this!
Pacho is short! You can step over him!
Let me go!
- Do you understand, gentIemen?
- No!
Once again then. We are here...
Run! It´s a whoIe army!
We are damned!
Don´t worry, felIows! Come here!
We´II manage if we stick together.
Take up your positions.
Everybody knows what to do.
If it turns out badIy we shaII hide
in the cave -they won´t find us in there.
Let´s have some gunpowder Iiquor now!
- Good Iuck, Pacho.
- To you too, my boys.
From the right! What is wrong? Go!
Take them from the right,
and you, straight up to them!
What is it?
A baII!
Pacho! Watch out!
Fire!
Look for them!
Go on, search!
Don´t worry! They won´t find us here
before next spring.
They chased me over fieIds
and meadows. We are trapped!
Take it easy, we´II escape
through the hoIe in the back.
Gunpowder Iiquor!
AII gone.
Let´s go!
Good evening, gentIemen.
Which of you is the giant,
the HercuIes, the famous Pacho?
That is me.
Pacho is Iike this! Out!
Tie them up. Off to SpiIberg
prison with them!
You heard, weII now... they are
taking us to SpiIberg.
Good, I´ve never seen it yet.
Don´t hurt them! It´s me, I am Pacho,
the brigand of Hybe.
I swear, its him!
You are too short.
And you´lI be even shorter.
We must catch Pacho aIive.
It is reaIIy him, the brigand of Hybe.
Do you want to be dug in, too?
- No.
- So kick him!
lf aII ends weII,
weII meet at the market in Levoca!
Boys, wheres my Pacho?
Don´t worry, they´II never catch Pacho.
- Mother!
- Dear Mum!
Good Iuck, Mother!
Don´t be siIly, I am a Iiving head.
Come here, there is a head here!
WeII, you are a head, aren´t you?
Indeed, I am. A Iiving head.
- They forgot about you and Ieft?
- As you see.
Thank you. What is your name?
They caII me Pacho.
Yes, indeed. Pacho.
But that´s me. I am Pacho,
the brigand of Hybe.
Oh no! You are a head! I am Pacho,
the brigand of Hybe!
At the King Ridge
There is a green tree,
- Can you hear that?
-Yes, I can.
The whip...
What a wonderfuI cracking sound.
Its top is Ieaning down
to the SIovak ground.
THE END