THE FIREMEN'S BALL
AND LOTTERY
Watch more movies for free on
www.FlixTor.to
Show me.
That's nice, isn't it?
It's very nice.
He'll like it.
Show me.
That's nice.
Give it to me.
I'm sure he'll like it.
Nice, very nice,
but I tell you
we should've given it
to him sooner, like last year,
when he celebrated his
eighty-fifth birthday.
Not now at the last moment.
Well, that's true,
but last year
we didn't know he'd get
cancer this year.
That's just it, now it looks
as if we want to give it to him
quickly before he dies. And
you expect him to be pleased.
We're the only ones who know
he's got cancer. He doesn't.
So he can still
be pleased, can't he?
How do you know he doesn't know,
you asked him?
Well and who should
have told him?
We won't tell and
the doctor won't either.
The doctor won't tell him.
The law says the
doctor can't tell him.
You could have
the worst cancer
and the doctor won't tell you.
That's why nobody believes
doctors.
Don't tell me.
Nobody has to tell me.
Everyone feels it when
their last hour has come.
Nobody has to tell him.
You haven't died yet
so you can't know.
Wait a minute, guys, we won't
get anywhere like this.
If he knows then he knows, and
if he doesn't we won't tell him.
Franta, you are such
a hypochondriac...
Don't you dare ask him where
his cancer hurts or something...
Don't worry, I won't.
What a dumb joke. Vaclav!
Stop screwing around, man.
Well, there is no time
for that now. How stupid.
There was a cake here.
What?
Give it here. It's not for me,
it's for the people!
What do you want me to do?
Mr. Balcar!
Wait, don't talk to him now.
What? Don't talk to me now!
I told you. I was standing here
holding the ladder.
I couldn't see what was
going on behind my back.
How can I know whether
anybody was there or not?
Well? Don't you agree?
Wait, what should we do now?
Well, I don't know.
Just a minute.
Well, I don't know either.
It's just the two of us here.
Only us two, but I really
don't know anything about it.
Somebody must have taken it.
Then search me, gentlemen.
Sit down, Lojzik.
It couldn't have been you.
Look here, I saw it!
-You see too much.
-Look here, don't lie to me.
Vaclav, don't lie.
That foot wasn't there!
Of course it was.
Look, the ladder is standing
by itself.
Stop it. It could fall down!
It won't. Just look,
it won't fall down.
Look here, I don't believe that
you were here the whole time.
You were not here, because
your foot was here like that!
You had it like that. I saw it.
-What are you saying?
-I saw it.
Why do you keep pushing me?
Damn it, I saw it! Here! Here!
Saw it, saw it...You should have
watched the cake and not me!
Who could have taken it?
I didn't!
Somebody who could have left!
I didn't take it.
You better watch it!
I won't work with you any longer
because you're all liars!
But...
You could have gone away
from here...
I'm not staying here with you.
What did you say?
I'm leaving.
I won't stay here. I'm going!
Well, well, Josef... What...
What are you doing?
For God's sake,
where are you going?
Help! Help! Let me...
Let me down! Let me down!
Let me down!
Hurry! Hurry! Hurry!
I...I can't...hold on any longer.
I can't... Let me down! Help!
Let me down, plea...
I...I'm letting go!
Allow me, gentlemen.
I am letting go. I'm...I'm
letting go...I'm letting go.
THE FIREMEN'S BALL
Go, go, go, go, go, you fool.
Guys, we have to look at this
sensibly, don't you think?
There is no point in...
What?
Take a good look at them
and you'll see.
Guys, like this...
Vasek, he's got a lot of
common sense.
Damn it, guys, stop fighting.
It's starting to piss me off.
Wait a minute, I'll count them.
Wait, I'll count them.
One, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, ten, eleven...
Just a minute, gentlemen.
We're going to elect a beauty queen
from around here. You've got girls
from around the world, too many...
Wait a minute.
We won't take them all.
We'll take...well,
how many?
Mother, I had a bottle
of cognac here.
Where?
Here.
And it isn't there?
Look for yourself.
You can see that it's gone.
That's impossible.
It was right here, see?
Did you really put it there?
Of course I did!
I've been here the whole time.
It's not my fault.
There was nobody here.
You didn't watch it.
I did.
You did not!
I'm telling you that I did watch!
What were you watching?
I don't know what you watched there,
but you weren't watching here!
Don't shout at me!
I...I am not shouting!
You call this shouting?
I am telling you quite calmly,
aren't I?
You did not watch.
The bottle is gone!
I should think...
How silly.
Wait a minute. We have to make
our minds up whether
we are going to take two or ten
or twelve or six.
Eight.
-Eight?
-Eight.
Yes, but they must be the most
beautiful we have. Remember.
I understand. I understand.
Do it then.
The most beautiful girls
we have here.
We can't see anything from here, guys.
We'll have to go to the balcony
to see real busts.
Vaclav, look, I only called you
because I had
a bottle of cognac here.
Mother and I were watching it carefully
and now the bottle's gone.
Just look.
And where is it?
That's why
I am calling you,
so that people wouldn't
think it was us...that we...
you know...that we
pinched it.
But Josef...
Where is that headcheese?
What headcheese?
There was a headcheese here.
Well, there was a chocolate ball
here, you know, that was here,
but no headcheese, Vaclav.
Vaclav, well, really...
I was here. No, there was definitely
no headcheese. No!
And where is that
chocolate ball?
Don't talk. Wait a minute.
Chocolate ball...
Chocolate...Mother, come here.
There was a chocolate ball here.
What ball?
A chocolate ball!
There was no chocolate ball.
I tell you...there was...
You are making it up, man!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Perhaps there was
a headcheese.
Vaclav, you know you're right.
It was a headcheese.
Well, that's all right, then.
Excellent.
Everything is all right.
But, damn it,
where is the headcheese?
That's a woman.
I'd call her a queen.
Legs. I want to see legs!
Guys, we're doing it all wrong.
We are looking at their legs and
should be looking at their faces.
The face must be like a picture.
Face like a picture -
they're the worst.
Come and have a look, men.
I like that one,
the one scratching her head.
What do you say to that?
Well...
Otto, Otto!
Put that Blanka Truhlarova
on the list, too.
Who?
Don't ask any questions and
put her down! Blanka Truhlarova!
For Christ's sake, what are you
writing there?
Blanka Truhlarova.
Don't put her there.
She's a nightmare.
Wait, wait, add her to the list.
I did already.
Should I leave her there?
All right, leave her then.
Well, we've got the first.
Mother, they caught on.
Stop that guys.
And who ordered it?
I didn't.
I didn't either.
Well, who did then?
I did. Have a drink.
There's my girl, sitting over there.
He'll want us to add his
Ruzena, too.
Fine, we've got two already!
Which one is she?
See that one there? That's her.
This is from those three men
over there
and you're not supposed
to send them anymore.
Good evening, miss.
Miss...
We came on behalf...
-We're from the ball committee.
-Wait.
Tell her...
Miss...
We are...
If you would...
that you...
like to participate in the
beauty queen contest.
You are quite a decent and
good-Iooking girl.
What do you say?
Don't do this to me, guys!
Wait.
What should I wait for when
I'm talking to you?
Get him out of here, please.
Get him out of here.
Ludvik, come on, come on.
What is it?
Come on, what's wrong with you?
Jesus Christ, why us?
Just you wait, you.
We chose the lady here.
Add our Ruzena to that list
so that she'll leave me in peace.
Ludva, Ludva, she looks so much
like you,
you can't even imagine
how much.
Well, she's my daughter.
I also...I also think so.
Well, don't laugh.
Miss, can we count on you?
Franta, Franta, come here.
Come here, I say!
Vrsecka and Matejickova...
I never knew what good looking
girls we had.
We've got three already.
Franta, don't bullshit,
just write.
What's her name?
Vrsecka and Matejickova.
Otto!
That Blanka I told you,
cross her out!
What for? A moment ago
you told me to put her down.
And now I'm telling you to cross
her out ... definitely.
What should I do then?
Cross her out?
Don't cross out anything!
But she said "cross her out"!
Damn it, what do you want?
Well, cross her out then.
All right, I'll cross her out.
I watched.
You didn't!
I did!
It wasn't my fault. It was yours!
Well, that one there...
Well, Ludvo, Ludvo, will you stop
annoying me?
Frantisek, I won't until you
take our Ruzena.
I can't believe it, mother.
You're so dumb, so dense.
They're the ones stealing it,
damn it. It's them!
Well, you'll see.
Leave me alone. Don't touch me.
Stop it. I tell you, stop it.
Go away. Will you all please
go away? Don't stand there!
What, don't you understand
the Czech language?
What kind of discipline is this?
Go away!
I know a nice castle inn
the vineyard, brook and forest
is whispering there
I know a nice castle inn
now it's called paradise
Near Kokorin, near Kokorin
I like to drink a bottle of wine
is Catherine
And Catherine knows
how to make love
A quick barmaid,
cleverly making her way
Refusing everyone,
she knows what to do
As soon as I enter,
she looks at me
The world turns round
and it's already May
Near Kokorin, near Kokorin
I like to drink a bottle of wine
is Catherine
Cmarada! Is that you?
Well, Cmarada!
Kavrik! Kavrik!
Miss, we are from
the entertainment committee
and we came to ask you
whether or not you would
participate in
the beauty contest...
well, that...
competition...
that competition...
What do you want?
Whether you would like to enter
the beauty contest. See?
Wait.
What is it, gentlemen?
What do you want?
Well, wait, is this your girl?
Come on!
Wait, wait, wait, we'll explain!
Go on, explain then.
Look here, is this your girl?
We want to ask her to enter
the beauty queen competition.
Stop it. Stop it.
But wait.
Go on, man. Explain!
That's what I'm trying to do.
Explain.
I am already explaining
for the second time.
Don't touch me!
Let him explain!
Let me explain!
Go to hell!
I'll show you "shit on the
fire brigade" you hooligan!
Leave him alone, Franta!
Yes, Zindulka! You never even
crossed my mind, man.
But...
You're back from the army
already?
Well, Zindulka...well...
what do you know!
What are you doing there?
Damn it, I can't find that paper,
that piece of paper
with the list of the girls.
Miss, get out of there and
be quick about it! Come on!
I tell you, get out of there!
I'll have to call someone and
that would mean trouble for you,
unnecessary trouble. Please,
come out, will you?
What are you looking for
in my bag?
What business is it of yours
what I've got there?
And why did you pull it out from
under the table?
Everyone is stealing here and you
only watch, you old honest idiot.
Vrsecka.
Vrsecka. Vrsecka!
No, that one was really ugly.
Well, we crossed her out, too.
Matejickova!
Yes, Matejickova, put her down-
Matejickova, well...
All right, but in that case
we've only got one.
Write her down...
Ruzena Metelkova.
I'll write her down.
Yes, but now we've
only got two.
Well, what is it, what is it?
Could I step out now?
Step out now?
Wait. Voting
for the beauty contest
is supposed to take place now.
Yes, that's just it...
I don't know, I don't know...
I'm afraid I might do something
wrong, you know...
Wait. Perhaps nothing will happen
if you come back right away.
Thank you, but in that case
I prefer to hold on.
Attention please!
I ask all the chosen candidates
for the beauty queen contest...
all these comrades should come
to the room behind the bar.
I repeat: behind the bar!
Come in!
Stand over there
by the wall.
Don't worry - they'll improve,
they'll improve.
Good day. I'm the mother.
And I came to have a look at you
and find out what this is all about.
My girl keeps talking about some
beauty queen and I think,
she is young, you know,
inexperienced,
somebody might get the better of her,
so I came to ask...
to see...well, just to find out
what it's all about.
How nice that you came
to have a look.
You're pleased that
we chose her, no?
Well, if you like her,
I'll leave it up to you.
Keep calm, mother,
everything's clean.
Well, I had to make sure.
What's a mother for?
Just don't worry.
Take a good look at us,
you'll see that we couldn't...
Well, I'll call her.
Hana, where are you?
Come here.
Here she is. She's thin,
doesn't get enough to eat...
But if she doesn't want to eat,
it's nobody's fault, is it?
Stay here nicely and
stand up straight.
Here she is then.
She won't leave, man.
She won't leave.
That's all right mother,
you can go now.
Let me stay here. I want to see
what's going to happen.
I want to know what
you're going to do now.
No need not worry - nothing's
going to happen to her here.
And nothing will happen to you
either if you let me stay here.
Come in!
Come in, come in,
don't be afraid.
Go and stand over there
next to the girls.
Come in!
Come in! Come in,
go and stand over there.
Good evening.
Come in. Stand over there
next to...
That's not all. We said eight.
Yes, yes, yes, yes...oh yes.
She was behind the door.
I wasn't chosen.
Everything's all right.
Stand here.
Well, start.
What am I supposed to start?
I'll start myself. I'll help you.
Come on.
Girls, I welcome you on behalf
of the entertainment committee.
You were chosen as
the most beautiful at our ball.
Are you happy?
I wasn't chosen.
I chose her myself.
Now I'll tell you what we
are going to do in a little while
on the stage, okay?
Go on!
Girls.
Tell that old bag to
go away. Tell her to go away.
Somebody go and dance with her.
Go on, take her!
Why me? He can go.
Me again?
Don't argue!
-Don't argue!
-Me again?
May I have the pleasure?
Oh, sorry. Now it's getting
interesting. I'd like to see it.
-Go with him.
-Don't hurt his feelings.
-Go and dance with him, lady.
-Only one round then.
You wouldn't refuse him,
would you? Go on!
Girls.
Attention!
I'll show you a beauty queen,
you dirty geezers!
Get out of here. Get out!
At ease!
Girls, I would like to point out
that the one
that is elected
beauty queen
will be given the honorary task
of presenting this gift to our
former chairman,
who will be
eighty-six years old.
Eighty-six.
Continue.
Well, I'II...I'll show them how
they should walk, yes?
Look here girls, so that you
don't stroll in like a herd...
You understand, yes?
Well, like that.
People will be watching you,
five hundred people
will be watching you.
You must show all you can
so that we're not ashamed of you,
so that they will not tell us
that we chose some...
well, you understand?
Take one step forward.
Turn right.
No, no.
Turn left, turn left.
Good evening...evening...
Excuse me for being late.
I went home to get
my bathing suit.
What?
Bathing suit.
You've got it with you?
Wait!
What are you doing?
Leave her alone.
But I can't let her undress here.
Why not?
They're also in bathing suits.
Hold the door so that nobody
comes in.
Continue.
You told her to bring
a bathing suit?
Tell me, miss, who told you
to bring a bathing suit?
Nobody.
Girls, nobody told you to bring
a bathing suit?
Why didn't you tell the others to?
Nobody told us anything.
Miss, step a little further back,
will you?
Yes, further. further, further,
further. Stop. That will do
Try to hold a pose.
Try something else.
Miss, you over there.
Stand next to her.
Take the same pose as her.
That bathing suit looks
much better,
but everyone should have one.
There's something quite different
about that bathing suit...
All right, all right.
Go back to your places.
And now you can continue
practicing your march.
Girls, attention!
Left! Left! Left!
Left!
A bit lively! Look at me,
damn it!
Well, girls, smile,
look happy, happy...
Happy, happy, one, two,
one, two...
And smile...happily, smile.
Smile, girls.
Left, left, smile.
Send a kiss to the audience.
Damn it, girls, a kiss...there!
A nice kiss.
A kiss, kiss, well,
you know how.
One two, one two,...
Nice, girls!
Get dressed, quickly.
Take your places like before.
Hurry up, hurry up,
I tell you!
Hurry...Jesus Christ...
Come in!
What are you doing here?
Where did you leave that
old woman?
Zeminek took her from me.
You are such an idiot,
such an idiot.
Me again? Me again?
And now, at last, the long
awaited moment has come.
We shall now elect the
beauty queen.
She will then hand over
an honorary present
to our former chairman.
Now I ask the chosen candidates
to come to the stage.
Music!
I tell you, I tell you,
keep calm.
Stand here. I'll tell you
when to go.
Comrade candidates, please
come up here to the stage.
What's the matter
with those girls?
I don't know.
Where are they?
Is somebody going to come
up here?
Ruzena!
Stop this nonsense!
Come up here! Girls!
Clap your hands, mother!
Please don't clap. That does
not belong in the competition.
Why are you clapping?
It's pointless.
Go on, clap your hands!
Please come up here
and stop bowing.
Don't waste any more time!
Not yet.
Now, now.
Damn it!
Next one, please, come up here!
Strike up the band!
Continue, please. Continue!
Go on, go on up there!
Music, what is it?
We're supposed to play alone?
Of course.
I'm going over there!
Bartosova, I see you!
Miss!
Misses!
I wasn't chosen! I wasn't chosen!
I wasn't chosen!
That doesn't matter. Come on,
come on!
I won't!
I wasn't chosen either!
Let me go!
Ruzena, Ruzena, come back!
Ruzena, come back!
No you don't!
We want the queen!
Girls, open the door!
Stop this nonsense! Girls!
Ladies, come out!
Be sensible, I beg you!
Stop being silly!
Ladies, come out!
Quiet!
Come out, ladies!
Be quiet!
Tell them to come out.
Quiet! Stop playing! Quiet!
Stop that! Stop playing!
Will you be quiet! Quiet!
Fire! Fire!
Please pay here! Jesus Christ,
your bill please!
Tell me what you had!
You there, what did you have?
What did you have?
And what did you have?
Have some sense, for God's sake!
Come back! Have some sense!
You ani...animals!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
Come and help us!
No, I don't want to go out,
I don't want to.
I've got my things in there!
Everyone out! Everyone out!
No! Let me be!
Hold him, someone, please!
Hold him!
Make room here.
Stop, granddad. Wait!
Your bill. Young man,
what did you have?
One lemonade.
Let me smell your breath...
seventy-five hellers.
Next one please. Your bill!
Don't let him stand here!
Sit down, old man.
Slowly, slowly...
Slowly, well...
go a little further, lady.
I'm standing here so that he
doesn't see his house on fire.
You would let him watch it.
Turn him around. How stupid.
Turn around, granddad.
Sit down, sit down!
Slowly...like that...
He's looking anyway.
Well, it's no wonder - his house
is on fire.
Are you cold, granddad?
Let's get closer to the fire,
okay?
Get up, granddad.
We're moving closer.
Damn it, man, I'm hot!
Sit down, granddad. You won't
feel cold here.
Damn it, don't look over there
all the time!
Granddad, I'm borrowing your table.
Girls, don't look at the fire
and come on!
Give me some beer and take out
the cups.
Give me that plum brandy and
something to open it with.
Come and stand over here. There's
enough for everybody.
Waiter, two beers please.
Take your place in line,
take your place.
Granddad, have some.
You're cold.
Give us our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespass against us
and do not lead us into
temptation
but deliver us from evil.
Amen.
Father, give me the helmet.
I won't, I won't.
I'll give you a scarf.
It'll be cold in the morning.
But what will I look like in
a scarf? Like an old woman.
You're an old man, aren't you?
I am.
Well, then,
what's the difference?
Yes, but you are an old man,
So we'll put it there.
Keep it. It's beginning to freeze
and you're sweating.
Bye.
You'll get sick -
just keep it.
-All right. Thank you.
-Button up your coat.
Tell them to send
someone in the morning.
I will. Good night.
And watch carefully, father!
We've got another...
Thank you very much.
Anyone else, please?
Thank you.
Thank you very much, too.
Thank you, you are very kind.
I'm collecting...
give something...the poor man,
let him win something too.
He lost everything
in the fire.
He has nothing.
Thank you.
Father! Father, come here!
He's not moving, damn it!
What is it, lady? What's up?
Those people are collecting
lottery tickets for the one
whose house burned down.
So?
Well, it should be stopped.
Come here!
Well, why?
Because the prizes
were all stolen.
Come here!
We can't leave him like that.
I'm chasing the boys away.
They're showing up without ties.
Such hooligans.
Am I supposed to
leave him there in his drawers?
Have some sense.
That's impossible.
But what will we do with him
if he's got nothing else?
I agree - he can't help it.
Then what am I here for?
Well? What for? In that case
I don't need to be here at all.
It's useless...absolutely...
Excuse me, excuse me.
Granddad, allow me to thank
all those present here,
in the ballroom,
on your behalf.
And allow me, on your behalf,
to hand over to Mr. Havelka
the beautiful result
of our...our...
Collection.
Yes, sure, collection, but
I thought that the collection
was the result of our...
Goodness!
Of course, also goodness,
but that's not it.
That's something else.
It's on the tip of my tongue
but I can't remember. Our...
Kindness?
Of course, kindness too.
Kindness, goodness...
but that's still not it. It is...
Solidarity?
Just say it, you idiot.
Solidarity...yes, solidarity.
That's the right word for it.
And therefore allow me
on your behalf to hand over
to Mr. Havelka,
with whom we sympathize,
this beautiful expression
of our solidarity.
That's not money. Those are
only papers.
Those are the lottery tickets.
For these you can win
a lot of nice things
in the lottery.
But I need money. I don't need this.
I need money.
But this is like money, Dad.
Just a moment, please.
It'll be alright.
Everything will be alright.
Quiet, please!
Friends! Please give me
your attention.
Something unpleasant
happened to us.
I don't want
to make a big deal out of it here.
Somebody took a number of
prizes from our lottery.
We cannot continue.
We will now put the lights out.
It's going to be dark.
The one who took
the things will bring them back.
Not yet! Don't put
the lights out! Not yet!
I have not finished yet!
Put the lights back on!
Don't switch them off!
What...what's that?
A misunderstanding!
Some jokers! I said
quite clearly: It will be dark
when the lights go out
and whoever took the things
will bring them back and
not the other way around!
Not the other way around!
Once more! Lights out!
Put that chair in the right
place! Come on!
Put something under his head!
Carefully, carefully. Boys,
carefully.
Put something under his head.
A bit further, a bit further.
Put something...
wait, lift him up.
Take the tie...
Yes...
Put him down, like that...
You old idiot, you...
Stop it! Stop it!
Why did you return it?
Stop it, please!
Why did that fool return it?
But what?
He shouldn't have returned it!
He shouldn't...
It will make everyone laugh.
It looks as if we had taken
and eaten everything!
Don't get excited, damn it.
Give him a break!
What break?
He's an idiot and...
and shouldn't
have returned it.
He did and we must
deal with it.
Let him have a rest and
stop worrying!
What are you going
to do about it?
We'll solve it somehow,
but not by quarreling.
I can't bear it, Joska...
that scandal.
What scandal are you
talking about?
It will shame the whole
fire brigade.
Don't quarrel!
It's hopeless.
Shut up! I'll tell you
something. If you were
in the same situation, you
would have returned it too,
because you're honest.
Never! In this situation,
never. Remember that.
The good name of the
fire brigade means more to me
than any honesty, you pighead!
The name of the fire brigade...
I'll tell you what our
good name depends on.
Our good name depends
on how
we handle the lottery.
What are we going to do about it?
That's quite clear.
What's clear about it?
To you everything is clear.
Of course. What will you do?
The lottery has been stolen.
Gentlemen, there is one fact:
If the people stole it,
they cannot win it.
Don't talk like that, Joska.
What about those people who
bought the tickets honestly
and didn't steal anything?
They should have stolen.
Whoever didn't steal
must understand it
as if he just
didn't win anything.
Stop this nonsense.
Something else is at stake.
What should we do with
those who stole
and did not buy any tickets?
That is really sleazy.
That's impossible.
We'll find out,
we'll find out.
But how will you find out
who it was?
Everyone's gone.
Wait a minute, boys,
wait a minute.
We must consider that everyone
at our ball bought at least
one ticket. There is no thief
without a ticket.
Yes, that's where we must start,
That's it.
Alright, we'll start from there,
but the people are waiting there
so we have to tell them.
What do you want to tell them?
I don't know
what you would tell them.
You remind me of Jesus Christ -
You want to explain something to
somebody all the time!
The lottery is gone. All the
people were there.
Everyone is under suspicion,
so they should keep their mouths shut.
And that's important, that all
of them are under suspicion.
That is not true!
But there is something to it.
True, true.
It's not true.
Alright, but somebody must
tell them, damn it.
What should we tell them?
That they are all
under suspicion.
Guys, I don't know about you.
I could tell them myself
that it's nothing, but I think
it's pointless.
I don't know. Pointless?
Well...no point to it.
The people know well enough
if they took it
that they couldn't win it
and they also know
that they are all under
suspicion.
People are not stupid. No,
they are not stupid.
Gentlemen, don't underestimate
those people.
Don't underestimate them.
We must trust the people.
Yes, not underestimate.
Really...I'd prefer five fires
to that.
Why did that fool return
this headcheese? Why?
Stop it! Stop it!
Quiet. Wait!
What is it?
Quiet.
What is this?
Quiet!
Somebody go and have a look.
Chairman, you must forgive us
for coming a little late.
But you know...
after the fire...
But all the more if it comes
from our hearts, right boys?
I give you the present
you justly deserve.
Please, take it.
Friends, I would like to thank
the fire brigade of which
I have been the chairman
for many years...
I would like to thank all of you
for this present and honor.
I am very happy that at
the end of my life,
I have received such
a great honor.
Thank you all
for the kind help
and support
you gave me in my work.
You have helped me achieve this honor
of being awarded this precious present,
this beautiful present...
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/6x95m
Help other users to choose the best subtitles