Shadows of a hot summer
It happened by the end of the summer 1947
Rikina!
Come on.
-You'll be better off here.
-Was it you, Mr.Baran?
-The doctor is not here.
-This is from Terezka.
Everyone brings cheese or eggs,
But we hardly get to see any
money from you people.
Hold on.
Cheese and cheese, all the time.
Once again, his horse is here.
Thank you.
-And in autumn...
-You'll bring us wool. I know.
Why do you leave your horse stinking
in front of my shop?
I brought some sheep cheese.
No smoking in my shop.
Eleven kilograms?
Eleven and a half.
Right, twelve.
-It's kinda smelly.
-I'll sell it elsewhere, then.
Wait, I'll buy it.
One kilogram of salt, two kilograms
of sugar, two packets of tobacco,
candy for the kids,
You are thirsty, eh?
So am I.
Boy, boy, you're living a good life.
Meat is scarce. And selling venison
meat earns a lot, right?
-Or did you shoot a boar?
-I hunted one down.
-You could do it yourself, in this heat.
-Stop joking, Beran.
-You know there are charges against you.
-Are there? Anonymous? -Do you think so?
I wonder why you keep tolerating
his partisan ways.
Two years after the end of the war.
So you have charges but no witnesses.
Otherwise you'd have me jailed by
now, the kind of people you are.
Do we know each other
so little, Ondrej?
Why do you tell me this, Mr.Grygar?
You act like you've never shot
at anything in your life.
Good morning.
Dad, could we give Lucy a ride?
-Ok.
-Come on.
Good morning.
Get down, kids.
Just a minute and
we'll go on home.
-Good morning.
Welcome, Ondrej.
Wine, cold water
and juice for the kids.
Can you see him, the sheepman?
He smells of cheese,
but he drinks his wine with water.
One shot of brandy
would kill him.
-Anyone know him?
-Some Beran from Bukovy Hill.
Do you remember Tereza Jezova?
-From Podtate?
-Right.
He married her.
It was before the war.
-I'll switch it off.
-She wasn't bad.
Poor thing, she'd deserve
a better man,
than this smelly sheepman.
I believe he sleeps with
his sheep in the muck.
Haven't you heard them?
Wait outside.
Don't tell them to go away.
Better crawl in a pile
of dung yourself.
Moooo! Sheepman.
Ondrej, do you still have
any plum brandy left?
Why?
I haven't made enough in winter.
My stock is getting thin.
Hurry up! Soon it'll get dark
and a wolf will come
-and eat your little sheep.
-You could make some profit.
There'll be a new plum brandy
in six months time,
There will be enough of it
and the prices will be low.
-your little Tereza Jezova
-Leave him alone, Josef.
-How many plums do you have?
-It's poor.
-Sixty trees.
-Yeah, you and your type
lounging with a woman
while there was a war.
-Leave him.
-Let go!
Tell you what. If, in this drought,
you yield more than 6 litres
of plum brandy
I'll give you for each extra litre
two litres of my own.
So you won't sell?
-You're not afraid to leave her
alone, Beran? -I'll sell in winter.
It will be as expensive as
a cognac in winter.
But you're afraid of this.
Aren't you?
Stop making mess here!
Look,
this hand has killed so many Germans.
-Wimp.
-Hm.
You'd let me shit on your head,
wouldn't you.
I'll gladly meet you when
you're sober.
Lukas said he'd walk.
He was crying.
Really.
Stop it, Rikina.
He kept on calling Rikina
to go with him.
But she ignored him. She only
obeys you, doesn't she?
Thank you, Mr.Beran.
Don't be angry with Lukas.
He thinks you should have beaten
up that fella.
Wait till we're home, son.
The water's too cold for you.
Now, now, don't act like
you're a hero.
Come on.
Quiet, Rikina.
Stay here.
Tereza?
There's nothing we can do, son,
we gotta ride down again.
We had some vermin here, Rikina.
You go home.
Rikina.
Come on.
Take your time.
We've got enough time.
I'll be back soon.
Who is it?
-Who's there?
-Rafaj was stabbed. In the pub.
-Which Rafaj?
-Pavel Rafaj. Stabbed with a knife.
-Like animals.
-We need a doctor, quick.
-Here.
-Go to bed.
And you don't stay in the pub.
-Good evening, doctor.
-Where have you been, Pavlina?
-Just ... to see a friend.
-A friend, right?
Good night.
How many of them are there?
About five, I guess.
Including this Holy Willie.
The Bandera guerillas, right?
Why didn't you tell
the police?
If they let you go to town.
Right.
I could have run away.
But why? They have my Tereza
and my kids.
The captain would know how to
handle this.
-This situation.
-Captain Grygar?
Lucky I didn't tell him.
These people are no bunch of
poachers, doctor.
Come here, I have something
to heal your face.
Remember our place, how it
looks like.
The house is in the middle
of a grazing,
You can see everything from there.
There's no way you can
come there unobserved.
And no way to run away.
-Here, taste this.
-It's not about running away.
The wounded one is probably
some high ranking officer.
He said that if he sees a
suspicious move
They'll bake the kids in the oven.
A man like this. Shit.
And you're supposed to heal him.
Eh...
-What is this?
-My patent.
Juniper, rowanberry, wild plums.
Got a cigarette?
Ask him.
He took my rolling papers too.
I think you should have told
the police.
They'd send the army and that
would do it.
Noone wants to end up
on the gallows.
They don't care about anything. Either
they shoot their way through, or they die.
They don't care.
I need a lot of boiling water.
I'll have to open the wound.
But I have no anesthetics.
Do you understand me?
Two men should hold you.
At least.
Tereza, pass me that little
dark bottle.
Don't smoke here.
I'm telling you not
to smoke here!
-Come on!
-Mom, little Petra has wet herself.
-Change her diaper, Lukas, please.
What's the doctor doing here?
-He's looking after the sick man.
-A guerilla?
-Where's daddy?
-He's sleeping.
Sleeping?
He was awake the whole night.
He's tired, Lukas.
Will he get better?
Yeah.
Leave him be, Tereza.
There's enough of them
to look after him.
It's not so bad.
But it will take a week before
he can walk again.
A week?
Maybe more.
Sieben Tagen.
Tereza, where can I lie
down for a while?
Go upstairs, to the room
where Ondrej sleeps.
I've got to get some sleep.
What did they want?
First they wanted you.
-Me?  -Yesterday, when they brought
the wounded one.
Now they want more.
Civilian clothes, food, money.
And a map.
Said it's up to me to get all
this in a week's time.
-Then they'll be gone.
Yeah, gone. I'd like to see that.
The wounded one, my friend,
will be here for a week at least.
In case he was not infected
during the operation.
Which is likely.
If he's lucky,
it will take a few extra
days for him to,
start walking again.
They brought him in, they can carry
him away, too.
Yeah, they can. You go and tell them.
I'll have to sell my plum brandy
to get all that they want.
Ondrej, did you consider what
would happen
if someone came to see you ?
Noone ever comes to see us.
Maybe in Easter.
But it can happen.
Only if they came looking for you.
For me?
If they come looking for me,
it will take some time. And they
won't search for me here.
To feed them and you for such
a long time ...
I'll have to kill a sheep.
I'm afraid a week is too much.
What if the guy gets alright,
and they'll really leave?
Will they leave us alone?
What do you think, doctor?
Say it again?
Nothing.
Mooo!
Lukas?
Come here!
Come on!
It's time you learn
how to scythe.
You've seen enough of me to
know how it's done.
Keep the bottom on the ground
and turn around.
You'll be good in it.
Try again.
Why don't you tell them
to leave?
You keep them here and
serve them.
Even though they killed Rikina?
Because you're scared!
I know you are!
Yesterday in the pub you
were scared too!
You let them do what they want!
And you, you heal them!
Want a cigarette?
I've bummed one from Terezka.
Here.
Don't be angry with the boy.
He's a good son.
Lukas?
Come, eat something.
-...and he ran and hide.
-Grodski!
Did you want anything?
Lukas!
Stop yelling.
-Doctor...
-What is it?
Go and stay with Tereza,
she's alone in there.
I'll be back soon!
You can't do that, Lukas.
We can't call anyone here.
Lukas,
what you said to your father
is too complicated.
Sometimes even the strongest man
can't do anything.
There are five of them.
They have guns.
-nothing can stop them.
-One of them is sick.
That's still four.
You all just serve them.
There's nothing we can do
about it, son.
We just have to live
through this.
I wouldn't let them.
At least, I'd run away.
I wouldn't do anything for them.
But what about your mom?
And what about little Petra?
You're doing us wrong.
And you're hurting your dad.
How much have you got?
Twenty five litres.
You'll sell it all?
One litre more or one litre less...
Wild plum brandy?
Hm...
Fertig.
Pour some hot water
on my hands.
Where do I get the money now?
Come on.
It's better than if they
got drunk.
We've made a little
disinfection here.
I like the sun but this is
too much.
Lukas!
Come here.
Why?
Just come.
You'll learn how to milk.
-You...
I'd like to see you in my place.
Hit it with a stick. On its head.
You don't hit animals. You've
said that yourself.
-It depends which animal.
-No animal.
Never hit a dog. Especially not
with your hand.
A dog which is afraid of his master's
hand is good for nothing.
It's an insult for him. It's
an insult for a horse too.
Crack the whip in the air
or just hit it really light.
Otherwise it won't obey you.
But you have no choice with the ram.
It can only understand a stick.
-It's you or the ram.
-Do I have to hit it in the head?
Other places will hurt it.
Come.
You'll learn it.
But don't pull so hard.
Poor sheep.
Ondrej?
Wait.
Ondrej!
If any of you touches Tereza
again, I'll kill you.
You can shoot us if you want to.
-We need to bring the feed in.
-Hm.
What do you want to do, Ondrej?
What do you mean?
Look!
Just like your old man.
-I know you well...
-We have to wait till he gets better.
Ondrej.
I'll get everything they want.
and in a couple of days,
we'll be fine again.
Where do you get the
money for that?
Good morning.
-Have you gone crazy?
-How much do you pay?
What a damage. Coulnd't you
wait one more month?
How much do you think I'll pay
for this slink?
-Good enough for stuffing, that's all.
-It's up to me, when I shear my sheep.
And you pay me as much as
you want.
But hurry.
Give me twenty more packets
of tobacco ...
And two hundred ...
cigarettes.
Beer for you, Mr. Grygar?
Yes.
What, are you opening a
tobacconists' up there?
Or a clothes shop?
Maybe, since you've sheared
your sheep so early
you should buy more from
the jew?
You gotta dress them sheep,
now that they're naked.
You sniff like a dog.
Why don't you try to find
the doctor instead?
Tereza,
would you have any...
You'd better go upstairs.
I'll bring it for you.
Doctor, what is Ondrej
going to do?
I don't know.
You don't know him so well.
I don't believe he'll leave
it like that.
He'll think of something.
But there is now way he can
fight them, is there ?
I'm afraid there isn't.
He's not afraid of anything.
He's crazy enough.
A mountainman. Stubborn
like a ram.
Yeah, like a ram.
It's not that there are
four or five of them.
It's that these people are trained
to kill. Understand, Tereza?
They are capable of doing things
Ondrej has never heard of.
You tell him that.
It wouldn't help. As if you
didn't know.
You know what is worst?
That they don't care about
anything anymore.
They've lost everything,
and I don't think they have
anything ahead of them.
Poor men.
-I am so sorry for them too.
-Hm?
Tereza, Tereza.
What are you doing here?
-Is it your forest?
-No.
There are others who'll
take care of you.
I'll just answer that pub
talk of yours.
Hey, hey...
We know very well who was a partisan.
And we know who wasn't.
-So you better try it elsewhere.
-Mind your own business.
I'll just hit you.
Ondrej,
I can't do it anymore.
I am so scared.
Everything will be fine again.
What will happen when they leave?
What do you mean?
We will have peace, like
we used to have.
So why did the officer
say that?
Say what?
That you must understand,
That you'd do the same if
you were him.
God knows what you've heard.
I can hardly understand what
they're saying.
I understood very well.
He acted straight because
he has a bad conscience.
He apologized in advance for
what will happen.
No. He apologized for
being here.
Why didn't we move to the village,
to old Kristek's house.
Why didn't you listen to me.
This would never have happened.
Did we have any bad times here?
Mr. teacher has sent me to find
out what's up with Lukas.
He is sick. Come and see him.
I fell off a ladder.
-Did you bleed?
-Me?
His nose was bleeding.
But only a little.
Yeah, my nose.
Francek Skypala brought an adder
to school yesterday.
-So stinky. And he threw it on me.
-Was it alive?   -Yeah.
I'll beat him up.
Alright.
I have to go.
When are you coming back?
-The holidays will start soon.
-He will stay in bed for a few days.
He'll be back after sunday.
-Goodbye then.
-Give my greetings to Lojzik.
Now...
Do you have to mend the roof now?
Why not?
You said the drought will last
untill winter.
There's enough time for that.
Call Lukas.
-What for?
-He'll join me,
-so he can see how it's done.
-Why do you keep teaching him these things?
-He'll fall down.
-Why should he?
Call him.
You won't give him a break,
will you?.
First, it's scything, then
milking, shearing ...
-He's still a child.
-A child?
Soon he'll be a man. And he
will be the farmer.
You gotta give them that. They
are disciplined.
I guess it's in their blood
after all those years.
I gave them everything.
But the officer insists
on a map.
A detailed one, so that they can
find their way to the south.
South?
They're trying to get
to Austria.
And then further, maybe.
I have some maps.
At home.
I know I can't go there myself,
but I can give you my keys.
But what about Anezka?
You must go early. She's at the
service at half past four.
She's not home by then.
Alright.
Ondrej!
Ondrej Beran, wait a while.
Where is Rikina? I brought
her something.
It's a little stinky, but the
dogs like it that way.
-Good morning. Anything else?
-Why so early? -I'm in a hurry.
-Go!
-Can you give me a ride?
-How is it going up in the hills? Peaceful?
-Too peaceful.
There is a report of Bandera guerillas
operating in the region.
I thought the Slovak army has caught
them. They said that in the papers.
Really? Since when do you
people read papers?
I know that a guerilla has made
their way all the way here.
At Becva, they killed a hunter
and his whole family.
Only his wife survived. They
shot her in the shoulder.
They thought she was dead,
so they let her be.
I would have known about it if they were
here. I know about everything around.
I believe that.
And that's why I need you.
I got an order to search
the area.
I've got enough men, but noone knows
the hills like you do
-What about the partisan fella?
-Yeah, that one. For sure.
I need you, Ondrej.
I have to cut down the beeches.
So?
When do you plan to do it?
Alright, great.
We'll be there tomorrow.
Seven in the morning.
Tomorrow.
Lukas will sleep upstairs.
With me and the doctor.
-Why?
-To keep you from your silly ideas.
I don't want to.
You will sleep upstairs and
that's it!
Alright.
When you finish your meal, Lukas,
we'll take your bed upstairs.
Have some soup.
Lukas?
Here. What do you want to do
when they took your gun?
I'll think of something.
Quiet, let's not wake up
the doctor.
Mr.Hrabovsky from Vapenku has
a dog, a daughter of Rikina.
Tell him to give you a puppy.
Not a male. A female dog.
She will be like Rikina.
-But give her a different name.
-Why?
So that she doesn't end up
like Rikina.
It would be sad here,
without a dog.
One more thing I want to tell you,
stay here.
You were born here.
Just like me,
your grandfather
and his grandfather
Where would I go?
We're far away from people
but someone must live here, too.
Even here, someone must
work on the land.
Sleep now.
-Why did you tell me all that?
-Every thing has its time. Sleep now.
Good night, daddy.
Good night, son.
Nobody move!
-Daddy!
-Wait. Ondrej!
Hide!
-There's one more.
-He's run away.
It's good now, Tereza.
Dad!
-Ondrej...
-Wait, show me.
It's not serious.
-Tereza, don't pull.
-It hurst like hell.
-Lukas, bring me my suitcase.
-Hurry.
Hot water.
Daddy, watch out!
Ondrej Beran will farm no more.
Why didn't he tell me?
He couldn't have done
anything else.