The Parson's End
Step right up, ladies and
gentlemen,
A show to top all shows,
A drama of passion and love,
Love and passion...
Enough of that, girls.
Get going and sing!
Thirteen outlaws stabbed
a lord,
The blood flowed red
around the sword,
Where are the actors? He
always shows the actors!
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Get into your costumes!
As for acting,
Friends, acting must be done
with feeling, with sincerity.
For example, when I laugh,
I mean it! See?
And when I cry.
It's with feeling naturally.
You there. Look natural.
That's it, exactly.
...love and passion, that's
the fashion.
The maiden Anna, sweet as mama,
loved her Tony, brave and brawney.
You mean I wear this?
Shut up!
The boss knows what he's doing!
Anna's folk approve.
They don't know he's not so smart
That he's fallen for Majka.
The local tart.
Who are all these people?
What are they doing here?
Oh, those are only observers
and advisers.
What?
They're going to check whether
we have fun.
The blood flowed red
around the sword.
Everything is absolutely true
to life and absolutely fictional.
You'll see a teacher scrape and smile
and hide his free mind all the while.
Just make sure it's clean.
There are children around.
People ought to love each other.
On the other hand, don't go easy
on anyone who doesn't deserve it.
Okay, so we'll toss a preacher
in, right?
Far away in a distant land dwelt
a solitary man
Who was to save them all.
Little does he know,
what God has prepared for him.
Bless you, Father, our little
one here...
Father, don't run away. Would
you give him...
The sacrement of Holy Baptism?
Sorry. Granny, but the priest
is out...
That's all right, you'll do as
well as anybody, Sexton.
But really, I can't. You'll
have to wait for the priest.
But what if the good Lord
calls him before then?
You, say something, tell the
Father why...
That's the child's father?
Lordy, no, she don't even
know who the father is.
Please, Father, please...
Well...well..Go on into the
baptistry.
God bless you, Father.
If only we had you back home.
Our parsonage has been empty
for years.
Listen to him yell...and a while
ago I  thought we'd lose him.
Give him a drink!
How can I, Grandma?
You should have been ashamed
in the first place!
The Father won't watch.
He's drinking!
Is he?
Just a minute, Father.
Couldn't you come for our
patron Saint's day?
So we could go to mass in
our own village church?
God bless you, Granny.
Make it snappy, the wedding
party's due.
Did you give the altar boys
clean robes?
Yes, Father.
What's that?
He asks if you are the sexton.
What's he saying?
Let him finish.
Oh what?
You're to line them up for
the ceremony.
The master of ceremonies is drunk.
The mademoiselle here...and you
come here...
there you are...
the sea-sick gentleman...
Up you go...
The mother of the groom...
...and the bride stands by
the groom...
Hurry up, make it snappy.
Dearly beloved...
I don't want to mary him!
I'm not the bride, my mother is!
The sexton misunderstood!
The sexton?!
All's well that ends well.
Here, Father, for christening
the baby.
What am I to do with it?
Take it, Father, please.
Well, Ma, what do you say?
Are we a happy family or
aren't we?
And what the hell is eating you?
Why don't you talk to her?
Isn't she your girl?
This will kill you, Louie.
Down the hatch!
Just so he doesn't pass out on us.
He can take it, teacher boy.
This is what our whole life
will be like someday.
Just one big happy celebration!
That public address system I
had installed.
A sign of prosperity, culture,
and people will love each other.
Except for Louie here, he's
an anachronism.
I mean, our society has
eliminated hobos.
We ought to find him a job.
He's no good at anything,
but getting drunk.
Make sure they're good and
greasy!
Granny, here, since you
can't come down.
Come here. What's up down there?
Everyone's having fun, ain't they?
But I've got to go.
Wait a minute, sugar.
Nobody's ever got time for me.
You keep stuffing me like a pig.
Go to hell with your damn food.
I want some company.
And what is your main subject?
The problem of commitment in art.
An esoteric question, true,
but a complex of phenomena
integrated with creative activity.
Avant garde trends...
Say, teacher, that PA system is
really something!
Yes, it will really be fine.
People really ought to love
each other.
Are they taking him to the pigsty?
When he comes to, he'll wind up
in the haystack.
Do you know how many drunks have
burned to death in haystacks?
No great loss if Louie should
catch fire.
True - but he is a human being
all the same.
Beautiful music, isn't it?
Granny wants you to come up
and see her.
All right, later. After I get
my work taken care of.
Here, give her something to
elevate her mind.
And this, John, is for you.
Very intereting, most educational.
Why do you keep giving him books?
He's the town idiot.
John Christian is actually very
interested in scientific atheism.
In who?
The belief that there is no God.
You mean, like, Johnny's an
atheist?
My book about God.
Religion - the un-scientific
belief of the past.
And she brought forth her
firstborn son
and wrapped him in
swaddling clothes
and laid him in a manger.
Where's Tonik?
Am I his keeper?
Tonik! Where are you?
...as it is written...
...behold, thy King
cometh,
sitting on an ass.
What's the matter, Granny?
What's going on down there?
They're just having fun.
Fun!
I'll bring your dinner.
At half past four?
I'll be busy later on.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Help! Help! I'm dying!
What's the matter, Granny?
I'm dying! Help!
It must have been the sausage.
I'll call the teacher.
How far is it to the next
village, son?
Who...who are you?
The new priest.
We never had a priest.
Now you do, son.
Where does it hurt, Granny?
Everywhere, everyplace,
teacher boy!
And nobody to talk to...
You want a bite to eat?
Me here dying, and she says eat!
The last rites, if anything.
How about a doctor?
God bless you, my children.
Oh, Father, you're a Godsend!
You've got to give me the
last rites.
You aren't serious, Granny!
When a body's at death's door,
everything's serious.
The last rites is something
precious.
You really need it?
I haven't been to confession
for years!
You wouldn't condemn me to...
Granny, you've been flat on
your back all those years.
But I sinned anyway...
in thought and word.
The last rites is a holy matter.
Wouldn't it do if we said a
prayer together?
You think it'd help?
The power of sincere prayer
is immense.
Don't take it so hard, teacher.
She does it to be on the safe side.
You'd better send for the doctor.
Saddle a horse, this time of day?
See, John, the deep roots of
superstition?
Children, neighbors! I'm not
dying anymore!
The power of sincere prayer.
I call it the power of...
suggestion.
Where's the priest?
Somebody said there's a priest!
I - I want to confess my sins.
I'm a sinner, God, I'm a sinner.
You said it buddy!
I have to reform.
It's been here for years. It's
yours, it's too small for me.
No friends, I can't stay, really.
It doesn't look like much. But
we'll fix it up for you.
Lovely village. Everyone so
busy...
Yes, we are improving things.
But it's all for our happy future.
And for the people, mainly for
the people.
Because the people are against,
I mean, with us.
Truely lovely.
Help!
Never a dull moment.
The church here is better than
in the next village.
Stay here, Father. We really
need you.
But friends, I was headed for the
next village.
See? The Father was headed for...
Stay with us, Father. Surely,
it's all the same.
We've been needing you...
...weddings, funerals,
christenings...
...instead of the teacher just
registering them in the book.
If you get the urge at night,
you won't have to go to the church.
We all need to improve
ourselves, badly.
And if you need anything, holler.
I'll put some flowers on the altar.
What's up? Where is everybody?
In chruch. Singing.
In church?
And you? Did you do your homework?
Well, how much is six times five?
Six times five is...is
This is impossible. You'll fail.
Even God won't help you pass,
if you go on like this.
Sit down!
I don't know...
Saint Wenceslas, prince of
Bohemia...
Your hat!
I see you're hard at work.
Fine, fine.
You know, I always say that
above all, we need culture.
Naturally, I don't mean
superstition. God forbid, not that.
I'm opposed to superstition myself.
I stick to the faith instead.
I knew we'd get along.
People ought to love each other.
On the one hand, I'm an atheist...
On the other, a little religion
can't hurt.
It refines our sensibilities.
What would the future be without
sensibility?
An emotionless future is no future.
That singing is lovely.
Yes, aside from its significance,
liturgy has its poetry as well.
Poetry, that's it, stick to poetry.
I mean, you'd better stick to
the church.
I'll take care of civil matters.
I'm a clergyman. Worldly matters
are not my affair.
Father, the children especially.
I was always interested in
the future, above all.
And that means children.
And I'll take care of them, too.
What is it, my good man?
I want to go to confession.
They called it an inflammation
at the hospital.
I know the urologist there...
Father, I've sinned, every day.
With the baker, the blacksmith,
and two I don't even know.
Once, or frequently?
Lots of times. But I deeply
repent...
Where is he going?
Mother told me to come and say I've
committed the seven mortal sins
I was lazy, proud,avaricious,
envious and immoral.
Look, son, tell your mother I'll
hear your confession some other time.
Aren't you feeling well, Father?
No, my dear friend.
It's just that the cup of
bitterness sometimes overfloweth.
Look, Father, what I brought you.
The Savior's eyes follow you
everywhere.
What happened?
They used to do arithmetic
and now it's soccer.
They ought to teach them to
be good...not rougnecks.
We've got the Father, to keep
their soul heatlhy.
Leave their souls out of it!
Father, I'm a music lover myself,
but the children are my affair.
They come here on their own. They
say they have civics in school
instead of music.
That's a lie!
Sometimes they had theory, and
they didn't like that,
and I don't have an ear
for music...
Well, really...
See? Do you want me to teach
them to sing off-key?
You and me, we want
the same thing.
for people to love each other,
help each other.
Our opinions differ only in
details.
What details?
Like is there or isn't there
a God.
So why shouldn't we help
each other?
I'm all for it. I just won't
back down on my principles.
Naturally! Principles are
principles!
But look at it from the
philosophical viewpoint.
I work with children on the
verge of adulthood.
Whereas you work with their
elders,
on the verge of death.
Yes. We are all on the verge
of the same thing.
Yes. The future.
Yes. Death.
Forever and ever, amen.
You look down at the mouth,
Father.
You don't get much rest,
do you?
Blackjack.
Don't waste the sign of the cross.
As long as I've got you.
Nobody gives a shit for me anyway.
Twenty.
Even God won't help you.
Twenty-one!
Damn it, who taught you to
play blackjack?
Johnny will have to run to
get some more pennies.
Now the preacher can polish his
crucifix till he's blue in the face.
Where will we put it when it rains?
Let's move the criminals from
the pigsty to the woodshed.
That's none of my business. Talk it
over with the police force here.
And now we'll play for the TV set.
Not that, Granny.
They only show a bunch of
bullshit anyway on TV.
Granny, that's too much.
Take it back. I don't believe in
getting rich gambling. I'm a preist.
A swell priest you are.
Priests like you are few and
far between.
I wasn't always a priest.
You're a reformed sinner?
That's why you're so
understanding.
Didn't Jesus say that one
reformed sinner
meant more to him than ten
righteous men?
Did he say that?
Sure. Don't you read
your bible?
Of course. Daily, Granny.
Well, Granny, I've finally
found some time.
Why aren't you watching TV?
Is it broken? Let's see.
Without it...
You're completely cut off from
the world, Granny.
The TV works, but my eyes aren't
worth a shit, teacher boy.
I should stand you in the
corner for that word.
Bullshit.
Granny, really now!
There is so much vulgarity
these days.
And yet we were never better
off than today.
Were we ever better off, Granny?
Nope.
See? And yet you keep carrying on
this way...
At least listen to the most
important news.
The government met in session
and resolved...
Are you asleep?
Granny, the govenment...are
you asleep?
No, I'm no. I'm thinking.
How about a little game?
Good idea. Chess?
Fine game. Sharpens the wits.
I don't need 'em sharp.
I need some fun.
That's it. There's eight times
eight squares.
Black, white, black...
And now the chessmen.
This is the pawn.
The working class of chess
and the most important.
With people like you, friends,
everything is possible.
Your lives aren't easy.
Your callosed hands feed millions,
and yet there is enough to spare to
buy a splendid machine like this.
You might ask, why a fire truck?
True, we've done away with fires.
But it will serve as a warning
to anyone who might want to
cause a fire.
People ought to love each other
and not cause fires.
Under the rule of this beautiful
fire engine.
We will never have another fire
in our village.
Fire! Fire!
Water pressure must be low.
Nonsense. New-fangled nonsense.
Buckets were fine when I was a girl.
Should we go get the buckets?
Nonsense. Don't panic. Everything is
under control. We have a fire truck.
What should we do, Father?
Pray.
There's no depending on anything
these days.
A miracle. It squirts!
The good Lord sent us a miracle!
But the hottest of flames, friends,
are the flames of sin in your hearts.
When I see that the best of
you are no
better than thieves and adulterers,
I am sad.
Where are your resolutions?
Your promises to atone?
Words, words, words.
I ask myself, what makes people
submit to temptation
again and again?
I look at myself and I know.
People behave as if being human
meant having privileges only.
Being human means, above all,
having duties.
Not to be prideful,
but humble, helpful and modest.
So let us repent and pray to God.
God, punish me, I am a sinner.
It's a blessed land, John.
Especially since you came, Father.
You're a good boy, John, like
John the disciple.
I know you're fond of me.
You know, I never knew how much
a pastor means to his sheep.
I'd like to be a real priest.
A proper one.
But you are!
I'm not, John.
I know. You're actually more
than a proper priest.
Reverend Father,
can you spare a moment?
I've mass to serve at ten in
the next village.
Your believers are patient.
They'll wait.
I'm in favor of a dialogue, Father,
but not if you're always ahead.
You must admit that this is a threat
to my privileged postion in the village.
Dialogue has to be useful.
To whom?
Whom? All of us, of course.
Do you know of anything useful
to everyone?
What?
What? Eh? Anything that our
town council decides.
It represents us and decides for us,
and there is nothing more perfect,
than our town council.
There is nothing more perfect
than man.
Nothing more imperfect. Don't
you believe that in man?
Man has his faults, but in
essence, man is good.
Man is, in essence, evil.
He only has his good attributes.
See? I told you we agree.
So why shouldn't we lead the village,
hand in hand towards the happy future?
...the devil taketh him up
unto an accordingly high mountain,
and showeth him all the
kingdoms of the world...
and said,'All this will I
give Thee if thou will kneel
and worship me,'
What I mean, Father, is that
I'm all for dialogue,
if you recognize my leading
position in the village.
It's a fact anyway, there's
no changing it.
If we agree, Father, you
won't be badly off yourself.
I leave it all in the hands
of God.
A man in uniform steps in.
Strict with the poor man
and his kin.
With the brass buttons of
the sentry,
Damn pigs! Somebody's going
to break his neck one day.
Are you hurt, man?
Let me smell your breath.
You've been drinking, sir!
Heavens, no.
It was the Blood of the Lord.
See the pretty color you made?
All right come with us.
Lord, no, no...
His lungs are shot, his
guts are torn.
His eyes have ceased to
wiggle,
...hear the outlaws
giggle.
Those piges are a public nuisance.
We'll have to do something
about them.
We'll discuss it.
...hear the outlaws giggle.
Who's in favor?
...hear the outlaws
giggle.
All right, old boy, all right.
Amnesty! Amnesty!
The town council is setting
you free.
Since it's the patron saint's
day.
I wonder, isn't releasing
criminals a bit premature?
The sooner we'll catch them
again.
Where are you going? Halt!
So you insist you haven't
been drinking?
But my nose knows.
At least two quarts!
Some things are beyond your
nose, sir.
Like transubstantiation.
Trans...who?
Transubstantiation.
Look you, cut that out...
that kind of language.
It won't go you any good.
That's right.
You've been drinking!
But I drank the
Blood of the Lord.
You can think you drink
anything you want.
As for me, you drank wine, and we
don't recognize any blood of the Lord.
But we do. Our law does!
What law? Our law recognizes no
such nonsense.
According to the law of the Chruch,
wine turns into blood.
We'd be the first to know if
the law transforms anything.
That's right. If something has alcohol
in it, it an alcoholic beverage.
But the laws of our state...
Get out!
Easy boss.
I'll show you, you and your laws!
He always squirms out of
everything.
Never mind,
we've got our eye on him.
You work too hard. That's why
your head aches.
I like my work, John.
But giving out the Holy Sacrament
is too much for me -
You are so pious,
so deeply religious.
But you have to go now.
-Must I?
-You must.
All right, but first take
that painting to the rectory.
Dearly beloved.
The promise of matrimony is
binding and permanent.
There is still plenty of
time to reconsider.
Do you want to think it over?
And so I ask you before God.
Anna, do you take Tonik to be your
lawful husband of your own free will?
I do.
And I ask you, Tonik,
do you take Anna
to be your true and faithful wife
of your own free will?
Tonik, you're drinking too much.
Leave me be!
The Father is the smartest. He
doesn't have to worry about
getting hooked.
Is this a wedding or a funernal?
Or take the teacher here. How did
you manage so long without women?
Hard to tell.
Can't say I wasn't lonesome
sometimes.
What's the matter? Is there
anything  I can do for you?
God bless you one and all.
I don't know that your condition
is the right one to be
calling on God.
Even a saint sins seven
times daily.
But you're far from sainthood.
But I only sin once..from
morning to night.
The Lord is my Shepherd,
I shall not want...
...in green pastures,
He leadeth me...
As for doing away with sin,
you're not doing so well.
I try at least to be compassionate.
I help wherever I can.
And what about me?
From the public address system,
to the fire truck...
I do what I can.
I work and slave and
drink only water,
and yet people don't...
Maybe because you do too much
for everybody.
Try doing something for just
one person once.
Father, I'm unhappy.
Tonik - are you hurt?
But Tonik, you're married!
The others were too.
But with you, it's different.
Tonik, are you in there?
Please, Majka...
God, you're drunk.
Cut that out.
Let go of me!
Turn him loose!
You slut! You whore!
I'll kill you!
Leave Grandma's veil alone!
I hate you, you bitch!
Why the vulgarity?
Can't they say it without
words like that?
You flithy whore. I'll show you!
Damn it, where is everybody?
Are you all drunk already?
And it's only five o'clock.
Aren't you ashamed, Mary Magdalene?
Tempting a married man?
It was him, not me!
A kick in the behind is what
she needs.
Where is the priest?
What do you think, Father?
...and when they had set her in
the midst he said unto them...
He that is without sin among you,
let him cast the first stone.
Go and sin no more.
Can you spare me a moment, Father?
Excuse me. I know that people ought
to love one another.
This is a question of justice.
How about the poor girls who
wouldn't dream of...
...at least not as openly.
Not for our deeds, but by your
mercy, forgive us, Lord
No. This is too much.
If you think that choir singing and
altar boy-ing will teach you
arithmetic,
you're wrong. Wrong.
God won't save you, Jude.
I know, there is no God.
Only one thing can save you.
- I'll study well, now -
- That won't help you either.
I'm going to talk to Jude in the hall.
I want it perfectly quiet in here!
Kokes, you're in charge.
Quit bawling.
You've one more chance.
When will you be back, Father?
I don't know, John. I may
be transferred to another parish.
They can't. You stil have a
mission here.
Mission?
I go where God sends me.
Good morning, Father.
God bless you, son. What is it?
What did you tell the Reverend
Father?
What did you tell him?
That Majka said for him to
come to the haystack.
Who told you to say that?
Aren't you ashamed, picking
on a little boy?
God bless you, Father.
God bless you, Majka. What
is it?
What? I don't know.
You wanted to see me.
I always want to see you.
I was so ashamed. You must
think I'm awful.
We're all sinners.
We all need forgiveness.
The Father is in the haystack
with Majka!
When I confessed it to you,
I felt better.
I know. Majka. I understand.
Reverent Father!
Run! Run! Run!
She tricked you into coming and
now the whole village is after you!
Jesus, that's a lie!
Honest, Father,
it isn't the truth.
Father, it's not true!
Come on out!
Majka, Father!
They are in there!
We know you're there.
Your flock wants to talk to you.
Fire! Fire!
Run everybody!
Let's get out of here. Fire!
It isn't true, Father, I didn't...
It's isn't true, Father.
What's going on?
I don't know, Granny.
Fire, I suppose.
Fire, what the hell. Let it burn.
Here's Grandpa. I'll put him
back again when you're through.
I wonder if he'll recognize me,
up in heaven?
What kind of nonsense is that?
No nonsense, sugar.
It's pretty bad.
If only the Reverend Father
was here.
God knows what they were really
doing in here.
Maybe she has sung her catechism
with him.
Find anything?
Still nothing?
Nothing.
They must have burned to death.
This shouldn't have happened.
No one wanted this to happen.
Poor girl, she was good to
everybody who asked her.
They could have even gotten married,
if it weren't for the church.
Here he is. Alone.
Why was he alone?
His lung are shot, his guts
are torn.
His eyes have ceased to
wiggle,
hear the outlaws giggle.
What's all this about. Out!
Two distinguished gentleman
of the cloth,
white-skinned, black-skinned,
bishops both.
Instruments of heaven's might.
Arrive in a carrage in the night.
Have you seen the Reverend Father?
The Reverend Father!
Impossible!
Reverend Father! A miracle!
Where are you going?
I have to leave, friends.
I'm called away.
Father Granny is calling you.
She's really in a bad way.
You have to come to her!
And who is this, then?
Louie the vagabond!
Louie! Louie the vagabond! It was
What was it you were saying brat?
Making up stories about the
Reverend Father?
It wasn't my idea!
Whose was it?
Teacher, the Reverend Father
is alive!
Thank God! It wasn't him!
You see where alcohol can lead
neighbors!
Such a promising fellow, and
see what drink has done!
Oh it hurts...
Oh Father, oh Father.
And wouldn't a little prayer
do again?
No, Father, not this time.
I was faking that last time.
- Faking?
- That's right. But this time,
it's bad.
Give me the last rites, Father.
Please, Father, please...
John, how long would it take
to get the deacon from town?
Father please, don't
leave me alone.
You remind me of somebody.
a little of my old man,
and a little of Jesus.
It must be that Jewish
face of yours.
Please, Father...
Stay here, light the candles.
Unfortunately, the church
here is unoccupied.
We have so few priests.
Oh, we have enough of them.
Do you hear an organ playing?
I hear it, but I don't
understand.
I really don't understand.
Perhaps my chauffeur stopped
at the wrong village.
Incredible!
A church full of believers...
singing!
Your church is in the perfect
order, I believe.
And so many generations.
I beg your pardon?
I don't understand.
Well, Excellency, my Latin
is pretty poor.
But you aren't so old yet.
Help yourself, help yourself.
You aren't so old, please,
the consecration.
Anno milesimo..one
It is a long time ago.
You can go home now, John.
What does he say?
You look familiar...
Help yourself.
You look familiar...That's it!
At St. Roche's!
Well, I...
Excellency...
I'm not a priest.
What are you, then?
A sexton.
What does he say?
I am at a loss of words.
Try a dictionary, then.
You have no servants?
Not even a maid?
Don't forget to pack your bags.
You're going to the police
station with us.
Take off that robe.
Just one thing.
May I assist you at mass tomorrow?
You're out of your mind.
A hundred years' worth of sacrilege
and he has the audacity...
I know, I wanted to make up for it.
The authorities will see to you,
But God will be the one.
Perhaps God will be merciful.
Hope and pray.
Excellency, I don't know if I dare...
Something else?
Could I apply to attend seminary?
The sinful pride of it!
I mean, after I am punished. I've
been considering it for a long time.
I wasn't much of a believer,
but I've come to see how
much we all need
faith and consolation.
Dear Son, God closes the door
to no one.
I can only say, go and pray.
Father, please, my sister is dying.
The Last Sacrament, Father, please!
I'd like to, but...
I'll go myself.
Oh Father, she'll be pleased.
She's unconscious.
Extreme unction?
Yes, I'll go myself.
And you stay here and pray for
your sinful soul.
Open up!
Gentlemen, we'll have to stay here.
There's not enough room in
my house.
Of course, I don't know why.
You gave us the first tip.
What's this? Clean it!
No, I only reported that
the priest
drives when he's been drinking.
I didn't know you'd...
- It's a good thing.
If you'd known something and
not reported it...
Yes, of course.
But I'm against all of this.
I only wanted to scare him,
but not to ruin him.
So you're on his side?
Oh no, not that!
Then watch your step or we'll
come and pick you up too.
Me? What for? Why?
We'll find something on you,
don't worry.
On anybody, in fact!
How terrible!
Do you know what you've done?
Christenings...well, no child
died, that can be fixed.
But Last Sacraments,
weddings...
You've made Sodom and Gomorrah
of this village.
No, not Sodom. Not me!
Well, at least your
conscience is clean.
Father...Father.
Reverend Father...
Father, I didn't send Jude,
really I didn't, honest Father.
Honest, Father. I, didn't send
him, ever.
I like you, Father, lots.
I love you so much!
All right, Majka, but now -
I know you're a priest.
I don't want anything, just so
you're not mad.
Father, I know you're a priest, I
mustn't think of you that way...
Is anyone there?
Father, who is that in your bed?
A bishop.
God, and who's he?
Another bishop.
They even brought a sexton along?
Shh! No.
Why are they looking for him?
There isn't any sexton here.
Yes there is.
Where?
Here.
Where, here?
Shh! It's me. I'm no priest,
I'm a sexton.
Jesus, you aren't a priest?
What's you name?
Albert.
Albert...
My God!
Get thee behind me, Satan!
Retreat, evil apparitions!
Scandalous!
Where am I? In a den of sinners?
Or the home of a clergyman?
Haven't you seen the Reverend
Father?
We'll expose him before the public.
Hadn't we better wait?
Until after mass?
No, we'll strike now. It's
a matter of strategy.
Our Father is in well with
the church -
Two bishops at the patron
saint's day mass.
Two of them!
Beloved in Christ.
You have gathered to celebrate
the day
of the sanctification of your
church,
the day of your village's
patron saint.
In the name of the law, I
arrest you.
Do you know who I am? I am Joseph,
first bishop of the province!
Come with us.
Oh, God be with us...
Revolution!
Wait! Stop! Turn him loose!
That's not him!
Over there!
Father, they're after you!
That isn't what I wanted to
happen.
Wait, I'll give you a hand!
Stop!
My God, what have I forsaken
thee?
What a horrible fall...
like a fallen angel.
May we ask God to forgive him?
I've forgiven him already.
He was a sinner, but there was a
longing in him.
Who knows how God will judge
our deeds.
Can he be stricter than people?
This isn't what we wanted.
He was a good man. On the one
hand we didn't agree with him, true,
but on the other hand people
ought to love each other.
Let me voice our regret over
this tragic, deadly, accident...
but I know better than all of
you, that life goes on!
And we have brave deeds and
a happy future ahead of us.
Twelve black outlaws in
prison for their sins.
Number thirteen is on the
loose and goes on killing!
Titulky opsat do BlackCrispin;
milovat KG :o
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org