Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Karol, look out, he's behind you!
- Attack from the left!
- Shoot, damn you, shoot!
You know the one
about Hitler coming to heaven?
- Don't shout!
Speak English!
- The wheels! Quickly!
- Oh, mum...
- Look out - he's attacking!
- Tell them at home...
Oh...
Heaven Riders
Screenplay:
Staring:
also staring:
Music:
Sound:
Edit:
Director of photography:
Director:
You snore, student!
Not yet.
May I test the guns?
No sign of anti-aircraft guns...
The Jerries must all be on leave.
Or perhaps the war is over...
- Stop it, Titch!
- I got to get warm...
Fireworks ahead of us!
Keep your hats on - we are slipping!
- Give it the works!
- Don't shout, Titch!
It's all right,
Belinda's got their scent!
- They are ours - their port engine
is a bit rough...
Stand still, Belinda -
you'll get under the wheels!
Are you all right?
Well...?
Everything's fine.
Come on, Belinda!
Damn you...
Where are you going, Titch?
Don't be silly!
- Gentlemen - I've had it!
That coffin will never see me again!
Tell the intelligence officer
to go to hell!
He's never been across the Channel
and now he's throwing his weight about.
Off you go, Titch!
- What?
Oh - yeah.
Wait - you get in first, Student!
Darlings - tell her to look at the road!
I've survived the Jerries and now...
What have they cooked up now?
I'll tell you later.
- You don't have to.
He reads so beautifully.
What did he say?
- David's in the sink...
If I'm to die, I've got to eat!
I'll get that jerry yet...
- Don't worry, we'll find him.
Where are you from?
- I'm from Cracow.
We three are from Czechoslovakia. -
Captain... Paul!
They are still bombing.
Which squadron are you with now?
- We've four units of our own already.
- We want to finish our run here -
our squadron
has been posted to the coast.
- This is the Duke of Norfolk -
our second pilot.
We are training him, aren't we?
His daddy will then buy him a bomber...
We'll be assigned to patrol duty.
See you, boys!
- Give my love to Wawel!
- God bless!
- Good luck!
How many runs do you have to make?
- 200 hours.
- We do, too.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
The call of duty...
Good luck!
- Good luck!
Hurry up, Tommy!
The pants are a bit long
but the shirt will do...
Take the shirt and shut up.
What else have we got?
I'd still like to know what happened...
- The engine's on fire -
we are getting into the floats. -
That was the last message received...
- Add some water to the gravy, Student!
It's almost done, boys!
- If they catch you...
- They can lock me up -
but surely not for long...
This will do for me!
She looks like your wife, doesn't she?
Not really.
Bye, bye,
we're off to the dance!
You'll have to keep an eye on me -
I am parched!
- Don't overdo it...
You call this beer?
It needs a shot of whisky!
- Slow down, will you?
She acts as cool as a cucumber
but she's really keen...
- For Christ's sake, Titch!
- So what?
She doesn't understand - do you?
Drink fast - cheers!
Cheers!
Tommy, you bad boy!
- Hallo!
- Got some money?
Let's go, then...
Student, tell this chap
to mind his step!
- Titch, put the brakes on!
- Why should l?
I knew how to dance
while he was still a babe in arms.
Shall I bash your teeth in?
Get stuffed!
Wait a minute!
We aren't going anywhere!
My love...
Where are you going?
- Wait!
It's really incredible
that I've got you...
Sometimes I think I'm dreaming...
It can't be true!
You are... a dream!
A dream I never want to wake up from.
A dream?
Come and catch me!
You don't even ask
how I fared yesterday.
- Well - and how did you?
- Don't ask!
- Give me a Czech girl anytime, eh?
- Of course -
they've got what it takes...
- What are you doing on Sunday, Titch?
- Why?
- Pat has asked me to her house.
- We'll have none of that!
- Why not?
- I can't let you go on your own -
you've got to keep them
at arm's length...
Belinda, you'll be a bridesmaid!
- Sometimes I feel just like at home!
- We'll need some car away seeds!
- If only we could get
a letter...
From home.
Two lines would do...
Are you sure it's not a hen?
Belinda's got her!
Take cover! Belinda!
The gamekeeper -
he's been waiting for us!
He's heading this way!
That's all we need right now...!
And alert!
What shall we do?
- Divert his attention!
We'll send Belinda across...
- Yes, and he'll shoot her!
I told you he was after us, didn't l?
- So you did - but how do we get away?
To hell with the gamekeeper!
There's nothing for it...
Don't be silly! -
To lose our leave
because of a stupid pheasant?
- Well, what do you want to do?
- We'll swim for the airfield!
I risk my life for him, and he...
Belinda will catch a cold...
Who stole my boots?
Have you got my boots?
Tastes funny...
- Damn that gamekeeper!
I'll get even with him.
I am wet through...
- You'll cool down soon enough...
In the air.
I have no one to say good-bye to.
What a mess -
what does he want now?
- He's asking whether you don't want
to take this off?
- Stick two bottles of beer
into you boots!
We'll be thirsty!
It's your turn now.
The Jerries will get the jitters...
Paul - I've got a funny feeling...
- Premonition, what?
- During a raid, fear makes you sick...
- Really, Paul, I have cramps...
Hurry up! For Christ's sake -
hurry up!
Get out of my way!
Hurry up for Christ's sake!
It's the tinned food they serve us -
I'll never make it!
Get out - or I won't be able
to help it...
Look out, Titch!
You've got him!
- Keep out of my way -
and speak English!
I always warned you -
keep away from a girl's family!
They've got you now. -
You sold your soul for a Sunday lunch.
Now the young lady
will play the piano...
Does this come out of a tin?
- Titch, for heaven's sake!
You are lucky I am keeping an eye
on you!
What did he say?
- He wants a horse.
- I see.
Stop that play under the table
and translate properly!
What did he say?
- That there is nothing like a horse.
- I see.
Look here, tell him
I used to be a jockey!
- Yes. And I made the Thurn-Taxis water
ditch!
- I don't know.
By all means...
Don't be silly, Titch!
I don't need you here...
Cheers!
The body - the carriage -
good breeding always shows!
Must be a puller, eh?
Yes. The horse of today
is either good or bad -
but the best no longer exists!
... the French riviera.
We'll make straight for the brothel
"Emma with the beard"!
I'll book three Turkish odaliss!
Do you think they'll keep you, Titch?
- You bet, I won't lift a finger
till the end of my days!
Unless I model fashions...
"- For a house of "haute couture" -"
or in a factory for rubbers?
We are on fire!
Gunners - do you want to get off now?
I'd never jump into the dark anyway!
We are slow -
we'll never make it by dawn!
Are you listening to Christmas carols?
He fixed the radio so he can pray!
God doesn't exist, Tom!
Paul, we have a fighter trailing us!
- What type?
- A Messerschmidt 109!
- I see.
Tell the boys!
I can see a second!
- Wait till they get closer -
you've only got small shot...
Did you see that, Titch?
You'll be my witness!
- Yes, for a beer!
Come on, boy, come on...
Dirty swine!
What did he say?
I'm hot...
- Don't worry - you'll be all right!
And that's that.
I'm hot...
Who's on guard?
Don't worry, we've got an escort worthy
of Churchill...
Paul - we can' t leave him -
he can' t jump!
- Skipper to Stg. Novak -
abandon aircraft immediately!
- Bullshit!
Go, Titch!
- Go!
- Leave me alone! Let go!
Hold on and cover yourself up!
Look out -
I' m landing!
Get out quickly!
Through the back!
Hurry!
Water...
Drink...
Don' t be sad, Belinda.
... the Fuehrer can guarantee the future
for the Czechs.
Faithful to the glorious past
we are returning to the Reich...
Come here, Belinda, doggie...
I wish Minister Moravec came in -
we could have a good laugh!
How many have you downed?
- I am not sure - may be two -
on night flights they only count
those that go down in flames.
Do you want some fruit?
- I don' t even enjoy the bread here...
This place is supposed to have been
built by a king for his mistress.
- And the pantry now serves
as dissecting room, what?
That's a progress!
Come again, will you?
Well - it' s nice, what?
I travel fast -
I'm on my way to see a lady.
One has to eat fast, talk fast,
grab anything that goes. -
There's a war on, you know...
- How do you talk to her, Titch?
- A passionate man doesn't waste words!
This serves instead of a calendar!
I'm learning English at last...
This is the only method that suits me.
How is Pat, Titch?
She doesn't write...
- I don't know.
I never really knew her.
And with my English...
I am sure she's busy.
Do you sleep well?
- Yes.
I almost forgot! -
Do you know where we have been poaching?
- No.
- The preserve belongs to an aunt
of Frank's...
And she went and complained!
- So what?
- Frank sends you a permit to hunt. -
Valid for a whole year.
- Thanks.
I can hear our planes.
We're now on meteorological research
flights.
I've marked down where we can pinch
vegetables...
And eggs.
Tommy is out of it -
he's been appointed instructor.
The wireless operator on test-flights
had a date
and Tommy volunteered for the job.
For a beer...
- They hit a balloon.
- We should make a flag of our own.
They're not supposed to bury you
without one.
That's in the regulations.
- I managed to get some red and white
cloth.
This will do for the triangle.
You'll see you'll soon find something!
Frank will leave us soon. -
He'll get a promotion...
He's done his turn.
Others only talk about flying...
It's getting rather hot in Russia now.
What do you think of Stalingrad?
Great, what?
How about going for a walk?
I'm not looking forward
to this autumn.
Everything's a mess.
- Titch - Pat has another friend, what?
- Well - you were away for a long time.
She never had any girl-friends...
After all - we are all here today
and gone tomorrow...
- Do I know him?
- You do. -
He saved you life.
- My life? He should have left me there!
- It's all over anyway.
She is going to marry an Englishman.
- Why didn't I stay at home?
I'd have crammed Latin grammar
in comfort!
- Don't be silly!
The president will meet us
when we return!
There will be girls with flowers...
- Yeah... We'll get a medal
and a tobacconist's...!
- How could they forget this?
- We'll see!
I don't need any help!
You are a pain in the neck.
Hey, Belinda, what's that?
The moment we stop watching you...
Get out of my way!
We'll - what's the toast?
I'm thirsty.
Welcome back.
Thanks.
- Well - did the old man agree?
- Yes. Frank is leaving next week -
Jimmy will take your place -
and you'll be our wireless operator.
I hope you still remember
your instructions from training course.
- Of course I do!
Now we are together again!
Stupid!
I hope they keep our supper for us.
- Student!
It makes me think...
I once took a girl our boating
on the river.
It rained - but we didn't mind...
And I said to her...
For heaven's sake, boys, a submarine!
Quickly, Paul, she's submerging!
A German jumped out!
Look out, Jim - a Messerchmidt!
He's right behind us!
Fire, for Christ's sake, fire!
Make for the dinghy, I'll help you.
No! My boat! No!
Go away!
- Hold on, Titch!
Can you see any of the others?
You! You killed them!
- Where are the others?
It's oil - oil in his lungs!
- Titch, where are they?
They are bringing my horse.
I need my cap!
- Titch!
- Let me go! Let go...
Why are you holding me?
- Have a drink! You must!
- Let go!
- Titch...
Why are you holding me?
An airplane!
Do you hear?
I have to go...
- Shut up, Titch!
- I have to go!
- Shut up!
- It's ours!
It's one of ours!
- Turn the wheel!
They're on our frequency now!
It's ours!
Titch, do you hear?
It's one of ours!
- I can't any faster.
- Faster!
- But I can't!
I can't! I can't!
Titch!
Titch...
Our Father, Thou art in Heaven...
I'll help.
- No, I'll do it alone.
END
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player