a film based on Mark Twain's
“Adventures of Tom Sawyer”
Good morning.
Coming along, Apolena,
coming along?
How come, how come,
how come you're so early?
Why don't you keep
the schedule?
Wenceslaus! Wenceslaus! Wenceslaus!
How are you, Station Master?
- Same as always.
Wenceslaus!
What can I do for you, Dear?
Did you tell Patočka to stop
at Doctor's?
It's Wednesday. The Doctor's day
to visit his sister.
For God's sake!
That shrew hasn't died yet?
I totally forgot.
But I did tie a knot.
Tom! Tom!
Yes, Auntie.
- Thomas!
- Yeah?
- Don't forget to say Hello!
- Yes, Auntie.
Wherever Mark Twain traveled,
fleeing from tax collectors
and dear friends and
even dearer relatives,
they told him stories.
That's how this one must have
landed in his notebook,
because it actually happened
in our childhood
and in our little town.
Mr. Patočka, stop!
- What's the matter?
- Stop.
- Well, what is it?
- It's Wednesday.
Oh, yeah, that's right.
Ah, the Doctor.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
Climb right in.
Don't forget to lock up properly.
And open up to nobody.
You can rest easy, Doctor.
Everything will run smoothly.
- Your umbrella, Doctor.
- Thanks.
Good morning.
Off we go!
Guess what I got you today?
- Sugar cone.
- Thanks.
BOYS WlLL BE BOYS
Screenplay
Starring
Music
Lyrics
Played by the Film Symphony Orchestra
Conducted by
Set Designer
Costume Designer
Choreography
Make–up
Wardrobe
Properties
Assistant Set Designer
Assistant Director of Photography
Assistants to Head of Production
Assistant Director
Continuity
Film Editor
Sound Editor
Head of Production Team
Director of Photography
Directed by
Script Editor
Produced by
Main Script Editor
Tom!
Where can the boy be?
Stephen, where's Tom?
I don't know, Mommy.
Mommy!
He's in the pantry.
Stealing your jam.
- So here you are.
- I'm not really, Auntie!
I'm just opening the window.
- Pantries should be well aired.
- I'll show you well aired…
Wenceslaus!
Here I am!
I'm coming!
Tsk, tsk!
Wenceslaus!
Be right over!
Won't we…
Ow!
Wenceslaus!
He has to come back.
The teacher checks if
we have all our things.
Run along, then.
- See you, Mom.
- Bye–bye. Got your lunch?
- Yes, I do.
- Good.
Leave that, Wenceslaus,
and come here already!
Put up the stop sign and don't forget
the Principal's newspapers.
Certainly.
I'll wear my cape.
Your cape? What for?
It's going to rain.
Rain from what?
There's not a cloud in the sky.
Clouds pop up quickly!
Hold it!
Go.
I'm going.
- Got your lunch?
- I do, I do.
See you, Dear.
Off you go.
Bye–bye, bye–bye.
I couldn't get it.
Uncle…
- I don't know anything.
- You're great. Thanks. Bye.
Bye.
Off to school, are we?
Wouldn't you rather
go for a swim?
No.
Just 'cause you have
to go to school?
Yeah, well, yeah.
Aren't you going just
because of a certain girl?
Mind your own business, will you?
Am I minding yours?
Isn't that broad's name Becky?
If you say broad again…
Broad, broad, broad!
If you don't shut up I'll…
You'll what?
I'll tie up one hand behind my back
and lick you with the other.
You just try!
Stop making me mad
or I will!
- Coward!
- What did you say?
Coward loves Cry–Baby!
What did you…
- Take that back!
- No I won't!
- Take it back!
- I take it back!
- Louder!
You'd better!
Broad! Broad! Broad!
Cry–Baby!
Křapka, I see everything
even when I'm not there.
Go stand in the dunce corner!
Ah, Master Thomas!
Have you slept your fill?
Where did you get off to, Kind Sir,
for so long? Well?
Did your auntie's alarm clock
stop working again?
Or did you have to wait until she
brought buns from the bakery?
No, I had to settle a score
with Huck.
What was that? What did you do?
I was settling a score
with Huck.
And can you tell us what score?
Huck insulted someone.
Let's see.
Huck insults someone and
Master Thomas has to fight him.
Not only do you hang around
the greatest rascal in town
and come late to school,
you are so impertinent
you don't even bother
to make up an excuse.
Can you guess what
I'm going to do now?
Give me a beating.
Brilliant thinking.
And do you know
why I'm going to do it?
'Cause you're bigger than me.
And now go and sit
in the girl section.
- You're to sit with the girls!
- You…!
Sit beside me, Tom.
Does it hurt a lot?
No, but I can't sit,
or I wouldn't see through her.
A beautiful exercise book.
You deserve a blue card
for such good work.
And he who has the most
of these cards gets what?
Gets a book.
Correct. A book.
From the Inspector.
Next week, already.
I wonder who it'll be.
I know who it won't be, though.
I could name at least one for sure!
- What did you write down?
- Nothing!
- It must be something!
- Nothing interesting.
But I am interested, truly.
That stupid book from the stupid
inspector will be mine!!! Tom.
- You're lying.
- I'm not!
Want me to swear I'll get it?
When I do, I'll give it to you.
You won't stop, will you.
You'll just keep bothering me.
I won't, I won't, I won't.
No, no, no!
One corporal punishment is enough.
Now we'll think of something
more interesting.
When the others go for an after
school swim, you'll stay in
and work out your
favorite math exercises.
Could I, please, rather have
some more corporal punishment?
Have you worked it out?
No, Sir. I don't think
it can be solved…
Oh yes it can.
Try harder.
I have plenty of time.
We can stay till evening.
- Where did you find the ladder?
- In the bushes.
There's another one there.
Quick, before he wakes up!
Watch it!
Thomas!
You scoundrel!
Open up at once!
Who is it?
It's me, Principal, Sir.
That rascal must have
locked me in.
I was marking some
exercise books and…
- Calm down, dear colleague!
- I'll calm down.
Tom, eh?
That's him all over.
But the key wasn't in the lock.
On the other side, I mean.
I opened up with my own key.
- Mmm hmm! Really?
- Yeah.
But I swear, Principal, Sir,
that scoundrel was here.
He sat right here!
Right here!
Do you feel somewhat
tired lately?
Or, overworked?
No, Principal, Sir. When I catch
that rascal I'll…
…talk to him.
I know, I know.
Do calm down.
Mainly, preserve your health.
No sense getting worked up…
…over it!
I'll punch a hole through him!
Oh, I'll rip him up!
Sharpen knives and scissors!
Save your voice, nobody lives
in these parts.
Sharpen knives!
Want a beating?
Get out of here!
You're wearing some odd boots!
Sharpen knives and scissors!
Sharpen scissors.
People's Savings Bank
Watch out—in the window!
Who was whistling?
Not those two rascals again?
I'm whistling.
Can't I whistle while I work?
Don't run with the watering can.
Walk slowly, so you water
the beds properly.
It seems to me that you are just
hopping around those vegetables!
Understand?
That's his own mother being so
beastly, believe it or not.
I'd rather have my aunt
be so beastly to me.
Look, Apple Strudel!
- Apple Strudel! See that pump?
- Yeah.
Go into the garden
and take over, will you?
When I'm done eating.
Stuff yourself fast, then!
Keep pumping till you count up
to a hundred.
Pump all the way to a hundred?
You'll get some marbles.
Look at that rainbow!
All right then.
…seventy–eight, seventy–nine…
Heavens, still pumping?
What are you doing here, brat?
Good afternoon.
I'm pumping up to a hundred.
I'm up to eighty–six.
- Eighty–seven, eighty–eight…
- Where's Joe?
Joe!
You rascal!
You wait, you'll be sorry!
Just wait till I catch you!
You're asking for it!
I bet our Joe's with that boy
of yours, the rapscallions.
- Are you speaking to me?
- Yes, to you.
- Meaning our Tom?
- Who else?
Who's the biggest rogue around?
Dear Mrs. Wagner, Tom is
a lively boy, I admit,
but I'm sure he is at home by now.
My boys always behave as they should.
No! No! No!
- Quiet! Quiet!
- Let me go!
Tom, boys!
Let me go!
Untie me!
- Silence!
- No! No! No!
It's burning me!
I'll never snitch again!
Leave me alone!
- Too late, little boy!
- I have to do number two!
If you have to die,
make it dignified!
No, let me go!
Finish the clearing tomorrow.
What's going on?!
You black–guards, you wait!
If I catch you here again,
your own mothers won't recognize you!
Some games!
Could have set the forest on fire.
Who were they?
They were… It was…
Don't you dare!
- Well?
- I don't know who, Mr. Nekuda.
- Scissors,…
- Sharpen scissors and knives!
…sharpen knives!
Sharpen scissors and knives!
- Sharpen…
- Greetings, Sir.
…scissors.
Some kids were messing
around the garden,
sniffed out one of the ladders.
I had to hide it again.
Damn it!
We'll have to get moving.
Greetings.
- See you tonight at the quarry.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Tell Pajdák.
We'll never betray each other.
We'll always stay together.
- That we swear.
- That we swear!
That we swear!
♫ Let our banner fly. On, on, on. ♫
♫ Telling all the girls… ♫
Fire!
Blasted math is on fire!
Now I've got nothing to study from.
You can have mine, Tom.
Looks like somebody's in our way.
Those brats again.
Let's scare them off!
- Go on!
- Leave it to me!
What was that?
I think it's almost midnight.
We'd better go!
Hurry up!
Call this dynamite?
It's like soft soap!
Who'd guess it would get so soggy
in just a few years?
So.
That's odd.
How about drying it up?
Sure. On your stove!
We'll have to postpone it!
I'll go and hide.
Mother won't be so mad in the morning.
- Bye.
You rascal!
Is this any time to come home?
- Owwwwww! Mommy!
- You devilish little rascal!
Keep still!
I have to stay up till all hours!
Auntie's still up.
I'll sleep in the waiting room.
How about you?
I'm staying with a very nice farmer.
- Want to come with me?
- All right, then.
You naughty boy!
Where've you been?
Stop!
I've been worried to death.
Stay here!
Wenceslaus!
If you don't punish Tom this time,
I would really begin to think
you don't know how to raise him.
Here's a belt, go on!
I'll punish him, Dear.
And you go to bed!
- To bed!
- I'll punish him, Apolena.
- Come along!
- I've gotta see this!
- Where are you going?
- I'll punish him!
I'll punish him!
Great!
No, Uncle, please, no…!
That's enough, Wenceslaus!
Do you hear?
That hurts!
I always do things properly, Dear.
So it's you nesting up here at night!
Get out!
Now!
You urchin!
Just you try to come back!
I don't keep you busy enough.
I let you play on Saturdays
and you've misused my goodwill,
been up to no good.
All that is going to change.
Start stirring.
Well stir! Stir!
When you've whitewashed the fence,
you can go for a swim.
In the end, you'll find
work is fun.
Fun, my foot.
Did you say anything?
No, nothing.
Tom, have you borrowed my ladder?
It's disappeared.
And somebody borrowed Valetta's, too.
How could a little boy
carry away a big ladder?
And for what?
Come on, start already!
What if I whitewashed a half today
and a half next Saturday?
No, my little shirker.
And no arguments, either.
You can't talk me out of this now!
I'll have to wash
all this laundry again.
Tsk, tsk! Tsk, tsk!
You have to whitewash that fence?
That's hard work.
It's you, is it?
I'm going for a swim.
Are you coming?
No, you have to work.
Calling this work?
Well, isn't it work?
When did you last whitewash
a fence?
I've never whitewashed one.
I'm not surprised.
You can't be trusted with
a job like that.
Wenceslaus!
Make sure not to help Tom!
The fence is his business.
See, she wouldn't even entrust it
to him.
Let me have a try, Tom.
Auntie's very particular
about her fence.
Please.
Go for a swim!
Why don't you go for a swim?
I'll be ever so careful.
Let me have a go at it.
Auntie could look out of the window.
She's not looking!
I'll let you have a bite
of my apple strudel.
You can have it,
and a dead rat on a string.
Not even for a live one.
But if you give me
your pink “praise” card,
the one the teacher
gave you yesterday.
One's no good to you anyway.
It won't get you the book.
Or don't bother.
It's not worth that stupid card.
I'll get it!
Don't use up all the paint!
- Hi, Tom!
- Hi, Thomas!
Bad luck, Tom!
Not at all.
I've never been this well off.
But you've got to
whitewash the fence!
Sure!
We're off to conquer Castle Pockstein.
So what.
Anybody can do that.
And you think anyone
can't wave a brush around?
- Hand it over!
- Not so fast!
I only hand it out in exchange
for teacher's “praise” cards.
You have two, don't you?
Three, blue ones.
I have three too,
and a pink one.
Want the pink one?
I asked first.
How many planks for three blue ones?
Three planks.
Just watch!
How many for my pink one?
Five planks.
I've got a pink one too.
So you get five planks.
There you go, Gentlemen.
Good morning!
- Sit!
- Tom!
Take your hands
off the wheel, dammit!
Auntie!
Can I go and play now?
How much have you painted?
- The lot.
- I'm going to have a look.
- Auntie!
- Boys!
Into the latrine, quick!
Don't lie to me!
You know I can't bear lies.
I'm not lying, Auntie.
I gave it two coats,
to make a good job of it.
You see how good you can be.
But you don't often want to be.
- Look at his hands!
- What?
He's got no paint on him!
The boys did it for him.
And, Mommy…
Come here, Tom!
Show me your hands!
You, shame on you!
Telling tales and fibbing.
Good boy, Tom.
Go and play.
And you—home!
You'll darn socks all day.
- No!
- No?
You'll kneel on dried peas, then.
LADIES
Apolena Dear, is that you?
I'm not sleeping, of course I'm not.
I'm tidying up.
Oh, it's you.
It seemed… That is, I thought
that someone was knocking on the door.
You want to go some place?
Yes, to Újezd.
Nobody takes this train.
Most days it doesn't stop.
What do you want, then?
- A ticket, I expect.
- Yes.
Hey, Pakrčka!
Hello, Wenceslaus.
Here!
- Wait, Lad! Hey, stop!
- Stop!
You wave too,
he thinks we're making fun of him!
Stop!
Take it easy, Wenceslaus!
Off we go!
Mom! Behind you!
Scram!
What are you doing?
I'll hit you for this!
Come here, my baby.
OK, boys.
Where are you off to?
Nowhere in particular.
I need four more blue cards
and some pink ones,
to have more than Máca.
They still hand out their dumb cards?
Teacher thinks it's clever.
You think you could get that book, Tom?
I'll get it all right.
Maybe I could get some cards for you.
How? You've never been to school.
Yes I have! Once.
Do you want them or not?
- But that's the Principal's Office.
- That's right.
Who did you think has them?
The Janitor? Yeah, the Janitor!
Where are you, cowards?
Morning, Your Grace.
Come closer, help yourselves!
Four will do for me, or five.
Or I'd better take eight, or ten.
I'll take a few too.
I was never given any.
There.
Five more pink ones for you
and five more pink ones for me.
Isn't it great, Your Grace?
♫ Welcome. Welcome.
Welcome to us. ♫
Good.
Máca!
- Máca!
- Máca! Máca! Máca!
- You didn't bow.
- I did bow.
Please, Sir…
One, two, three, four…
Down!
Thank you.
What is all this?
- He's asking what it means.
- What?
He's asking what this means!
Aha.
Get up, children!
As a history lesson we presented
a tableau
on the Conquest of Castle Pockstein.
Legends tell of a hidden treasure
guarded there by Philomena
and Fire Dog.
We left out the Fire Dog
for pedagogical reasons.
Excellent!
I thank you all.
- Now I think we can start.
- Yes, Inspector.
I'll do it myself.
Dear attendees, dear children.
Our most honoured guest,
Inspector Shibranyi,
has dedicated a book to the best student.
Personally signed…
So who has the largest number
of pink and blue cards?
So who will be the lucky owner
of this wonderful book?
- The other way round.
- Pardon?
- The book.
- Oh, sorry.
Here, please!
- Ahh, Voříšek!
Let us see how many you have.
Five blue, three pink.
And Máca?
The best boy in the class.
I have seven blue ones.
Yes, seven blue?
Eleven in all.
Does anybody have more?
- I do.
Twelve blue cards.
- No!
- And ten pink.
- Excellent!
I have that many too, Sir.
Two exemplary boys in one class!
Congratulations.
But I only have one book.
What do we do?
I'll show you…
I know what we'll do.
Instead of a book
they get a good beating.
Till they confess
how they got those cards.
Turn the key! Turn it!
- Bring in their parents.
- Both of them?
- Both.
- Right.
Boys! Boys!
Why cry now, they can't see you.
Joe, come and watch!
Saved!
We won't cry, they will!
- What's the hammer for?
- Well, what would a hammer be for…
We'll find the treasure.
Tapping the wall's the best way.
I've taken some wine,
let's have a good time.
Wait!
I'll get something too.
- Good afternoon.
- Am I clever?
- Eggs, great!
- What a bite!
How are we today, Station Master?
Same as always.
And you?
- Just the same.
- I know.
- Get going.
- Here we go!
Why not leave that case here
and go home for a cart?
No, it's quite light.
Just some paint from Újezd.
- My compliments, Sir.
- Greetings, Sir.
Good afternoon.
Hey, Peter!
Come and help me with this suitcase,
if you're not too busy.
Of course I'll help you.
Naturally.
There.
Damn!
It's all right!
Think you're carting potatoes,
you idiot?
- Good afternoon.
You call this well hidden?!
Let's go.
Hurry!
- Thomas!
- Pity I couldn't give you the book.
They're looking for you.
They won't find me.
We're going to Pockstein,
to find the treasure.
I'll be a rich man.
I want us to get engaged.
I'm busy right now.
It doesn't take long.
You give me a kiss
and we're engaged.
Somebody could see us.
There's nobody around.
What if there is?
I said there wasn't.
- But… Oh no!
- Oh yes.
- Oh no!
Close your eyes, then.
- Oh yes!
- Oh no!
- Oh yes.
- Oh yes!
Oh no, no!
It's better with you than with Ann.
You've been engaged to Ann?!
But it was no fun at all.
Honestly.
- I don't care for her any more.
- Liar, you do!
- I swear I don't!
- Don't swear!
- I swear!
Becky!
What's the matter?
Why are you crying?
A wasp stung me.
I've never got engaged.
She'd cry, and I'd have to ask her why.
- That would make me fed up.
- A boat, boys!
Now we're definitely buried.
They'll find the boat and our stuff
and they'll think we drowned.
Amen.
Unless that cry–baby
policeman's daughter
quacks about us going to Pockstein.
What did you say she does?
Quacks?
Leave it, boys!
The eggs are in you pockets!
♫ Don't stand there, come along. ♫
♫ We three are the best of the lot, ♫
♫ the pick of the bunch. ♫
♫ Don't stand there, come along. ♫
♫ We're off to find glory and riches ♫
♫ just as the story–books say. ♫
♫ Let our banner fly. ♫
♫ On, on, on. ♫
♫ Telling all the girls, ♫
♫ That we are sailing on. ♫
♫ We are sailing on! ♫
♫ He, you and I. ♫
♫ Don't stand there, come along. ♫
♫ For all the treasures in the world ♫
♫ that await us! ♫
And now we're the lords of Pockstein!
We are the Pocksteins!
As a history lesson
we presented a tableau
on the Conquest of Castle Pockstein.
Legends tell…
…of a hidden treasure,
guarded there
by Philomena and the Fire Dog.
We left out the Fire Dog
for pedagogical reasons.
But we're not leaving it out.
The Pockstein Fire Dog.
Jose Pockstein—Hand Dripping Blood!
Tom Pockstein—Black Lightning!
I wonder why the grown–ups
take just a lick of wine
and are up to all sorts of things.
I don't feel a thing.
As if I'd drunk water.
D'you hear?
Snoring.
Wait, wasn't that a light?
Where do you see a light?
Up there.
Seeing white mice, too?
Whoever'd climb up here in this weather.
I saw a light.
There was nothing there.
Quickly!
- But I swear I saw a light.
- I said you couldn't have! Climb up!
- Say what you like, I saw a light!
- Yeah, right. A light!
Here's the hiding place.
Lined like a fortress,
don't worry, Boss!
All right.
I smell smoke.
Just sniff!
Are you a dog or what?
Hurry up, I want to be home!
When it starts raining
there won't be a clue.
- Finished?
- Yeah.
Come on then!
And now none of us comes here
for a week.
My, what a flash!
They'll be sniffing about
but we'll just see to our business.
We meet here in a week's time.
- Then we'll divvy up.
- We'll divide it up nicely!
- It's starting to pour!
Come on! Come on!
You say three kids did it?
Definitely not.
Three, maybe.
But old crooks.
They've drowned.
Our Joey has drowned!
They've drowned!
Apolena, they're dead!
Our little angels.
They found the capsized boat.
A white coffin, Father.
My idea.
If they don't find them soon
we'll give them all a funeral.
How can they have a funeral
if we don't find them?
A symbolic funeral.
We'll put their things
inside the coffins.
- Good morning.
They still haven't found them?
Where are they searching now?
Under the weir.
Sir!
Poor little orphan.
That's not Tom's cap,
it's mine!
Don't begrudge a dead boy your cap!
No!
Sir!
A shirt.
That's dear Joey's.
My poor boy!
He's somewhere out there
with nary a shirt on.
Tom, maybe Pockstein spent
all his riches.
Maybe there's nothing here.
Who cares about a treasure,
let's go for a swing!
Huck!
Now you're staring, eh?
Who's that for?
Tom, we're engaged.
You don't say! And aren't you
only imagining it, maybe?
He gave me a kiss, so there.
Are you sure? Are you sure
you're not imagining it?
If you'd been engaged,
he'd have told you where he is.
He didn't tell you.
You don't know a thing.
Where is he, then?
Wouldn't you like to know!
Don't be so nosy!
- 2,200, 2,300, 2,400, 2,500…
- 3,020, 3,070, 3,170, 3,270…
I give up!
I didn't run away from home
to spend my time doing addition.
Now you've mixed me up!
How much did I say?
Asking me?
Let's just share out anyhow.
I don't care if I get
a thousand more or less.
Me neither.
One blue pack for me,
one for you, one for Joe.
One big one for me,
One old man for you,
one for Huck, one for me.
You know what
I don't get, boys…
Pockstein used the same money we do.
Just the same.
Oh my!
…our beloved boys,
with whom we all lived
in love and friendship.
They were part of our lives.
We lose so much by their departure.
All the more painful the loss,
they were our most talented
and most diligent pupils.
We were proud of them.
Our pride and joy, our example.
Never shall we forget
our three noble, splendid boys.
He's making me cry!
- I'll clap!
- No!
Look at the girls!
What are they wearing?
Wedding gowns or something.
I like it.
In the spring of their lives
they have left us.
Forever.
Tommy!
- Me?
- It's them!
And they're alive!
Thomas!
My poor little boy!
Tommy!
Joey, my little angel,
you've come back to me!
Joey! Joey!
- What is that there?
- Money.
- What money?
- From that savings bank!
They stole it?
Boys?
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Get lost!
How did you come to this?
We found it.
It's eight hundred thousand.
We counted it.
Found it? Where?
We found it,
and if we tell you where
do we get a reward?
Of course you do.
Even though we're minors?
I'll see to it that you do.
Quickly, where?
Hold!
Get going, fast!
Get ahead of them!
We frightened them off.
I know who this belongs to.
I didn't kill him!
Who did?
Ležátka.
He thought the fool had taken the money.
That he came earlier and he just
stashed it away.
We didn't know those brats found it.
The chicken was delicious.
Apolena made a dish of paprika.
- And you stuffed your belly.
- That's right.
Off you go.
- Be well, Wenceslaus.
- You too.
Wenceslaus!
Did you tell Patočka to stop
at the Doctor's?
- The Doctor's sister leaves today.
- I totally forgot.
But I did tie a knot.
Tom!
- Yes, Auntie.
- Thomas!
- Yeah?
- Don't forget to say Hello.
- Yes, Auntie.
- Mr. Patočka!
- What is it?
- Stop!
- What for?
- It's Wednesday.
- What?
- Oh yeah, Wednesday!
Ah, the Doctor.
Good morning!
My Dear.
- Good morning.
Good morning.
Climb right in!
'Morning.
Don't forget to lock up properly.
And open up to nobody.
You can rest easy, Doctor.
Good morning.
This is the boy who drowned.
The basket, Doctor!
Thank you.
I have some chocolate for you today.
- Why don't we go?!
- Off we go!
- See you, then.
- See you, Tom.
Who throws stuff at people
taking a quiet nap?!
THE END