CZECHOSLOVAK WEEK in FILM
18. III.
The first Slovak full-length feature
film was premiered in Bratislava
Beware!
Information Commissioner
Doctor Belué summed up the film
as the joint work of
Slovak and Czech filmmakers.
The Speaker of the Slovak National
Council, Doctor Lettrich.
Artists who worked on the film.
The film Beware! was also
premiered in Prague.
While the first Slovak film
is screened in cinemas,
Slovaks are already making a second
film in the Tatras, The Devil's Wall.
Vaclav Wasserman directed
this skiing comedy.
Karol Kréka behind the camera.
Watch more movies for free on
www.FlixTor.to
Komérno has huge shipyards.
However, they cannot keep up
with the demands,
made on them lately.
Work in the old workshops.
Construction of new ships
is of vital significance
for our economic contacts
with other countries.
The cornerstone of one
of the most important objects
of our economy.
It was ceremonially laid
by Minister Lauéman,
Commissioner Doctor Pul
and the General Consul
of the Soviet Union, Demjanov.
The first blast furnace
in Slovakia is in Tisovec.
Deputy Prime Minister §iroky
emphasised in his speech
that putting the furnace into operation
is a further proof of progress,
brought about by the nationalised
industry and economic plan.
Consecration of the furnace.
The Deputy Prime Minister then
ignited the first fire in the furnace,
which will supply the Podbrezové
Ironworks with iron.
United States of America.
Reynolds airplane,
a former bomber,
is being prepared at the
New York airport.
Its crew wants to break the record
for round-the-world flight,
set by Howard Hughes in 1938.
The pilot, Captain Odom.
Navigator Reynolds
and flight engineer Carroll Sallee
bid farewell before their flight
from New York to New York.
After 11 hours, after refuelling
in Newfoundland,
the airplane lands in Paris.
As it was not allowed
to fly over the Soviet Union.
The crew had to fly 6,400 kilometres
further than Hughes.
The plane took the Pathé newsreel
with these shots to New York.
After another 36 hours
the plane landed in Tokyo.
Before that, it stopped in Cairo,
Karachi, Calcutta and Shanghai.
Reynolds Bombshell landed
the following day in New York.
The flight took 78 hours and 55 minutes.
The tired crew beat Hughes's
record by 12 hours.
Stefénik's Week
of Czecho-Slovak Brotherhood
was ceremoniously opened
in the Prague Municipal Hall.
The importance of étefénik
and his liberation activities
performed together with President
Masaryk and Doctor Benes
in World War I, were summed up
by editor-in-chief Sychrava.
Vice-chairman of the Czechoslovak
Veterans' Community.
Minister Doctor Drtina
represented the Government.
The Speaker of the Slovak
National Council
and Czechoslovak Society
Doctor Lettrich.
Spoke on Czechoslovak brotherhood.
which is the motto of Stefénik's Week.
We give a part of his speech.
Czechs and Slovaks created
a joint state by making huge sacrifices.
They will build it together
and sustain it together.
The Czechoslovak Republic
guarantees peace. gives protection,
guards our rights and freedoms.
Progress, development, civilisation,
prosperity,
and thus will create the conditions
for the happiness of the people.
We live and fall by the common state.
We have to be prepared to make
any sacrifice for it.
We have fought and died for it.
If necessary, we will fight
for it again
voluntarily, from our conviction.
and if need be, even die for it.
Berlin.
The crime rate shot up
dramatically in Berlin.
Military police of all
four superpowers
organised a raid together with
thousands of German security guards.
On the first day they
arrested thousands of Germans.
But let many go after interrogation.
However. it seems that they
caught many of the worst criminals.
New weapons were shown
at the American Army Day.
This vehicle fights against fire.
A huge howitzer with missiles
that can destroy the strongest bulwark.
Mother planes release
small fast fighters.
Paratroopers are largely
emphasised.
Tons of military material are released
on parachutes after the soldiers.
Leading statesmen fight for peace.
Why are weapons prepared
that compel us to think of war?
Don't we all sincerely want peace?
We will show you a highly
cultural sport in Paris.
Women's roller skating race.
You will see how ladies can change.
One can get very upset at sports.
No wonder that some lose their temper.
especially when they lose.
But enough is enough.
Sometimes even the referee is weak.
And his trousers too.
Well. ladies' sport.
The Slovak Film Institute
presents
Palo Bielik and Jirina Stepnickova
in the film
BEWARE!
Based on the drama “The Shepherd's Wife”
by Ivan Stodola
Screenplay DY:
Cinematography:
Music:
Recorded by the Film Symphony
Orchestra, conducted by O. Parik
Sound:
Make-up:
Editor:
Executive producer:
Starring:
Made by the Slovak Film Production,
Bratislava 1946
Directed by:
Before the First World War Slovakia
was called Upper Hungary.
What was good and big enough
belonged to the lords.
Hill people had to work hard.
“A Slovak is not a human being!"
Hailed one slogan.
Many oppressed Slovaks
ran away to the world.
Some were successful, others vanished
into thin air.
Through their destiny, they fulfilled
the sad history of emigrants.
This is the story of Ondrej Muranica,
who was one the millions of Slovaks
wandering the world
in search of bread...
Beware!
Coming from the low end!
He escaped again!
Load up!
Everything.
The shepherd's share as well.
It's already the fifth.
It's a pity.
I'll get him!
Take it! Take some for sheep tenders too!
Quickly!
And what shall I give the boys to eat?
I thought about it, too.
The high lord said
they could drink sheep milk.
The bear allegedly steals your sheep.
It's necessary to compensate the lord
for the sheep and the lost profit.
And a shepherd is not a man?
Mi§o, take what belongs to us!
I warn you, shepherd Ondrej,
you'll regret it!
You can't take what belongs to us!
It's impossible to live like this.
With a master like this.
we'll never have anything.
Lords have always existed
and will continue to exist.
Who knows?
Tell your man if it happens again,
he'll have to go.
Ondrej cannot help it,
the bear takes his sheep.
Why doesn't the lord shoot the bear'?
You can't order him.
He knows what he's doing.
Does he live from your work
or do you live from his?
He takes your field
and sends your man to jail!
Mom, what shall we do now?
Ondrej will tell you.
Mom. can I go with you?
Dad!
My son!
- And mom?
- She's coming.
It's sharp.
- It's for the bear.
- And will you kill it?
Iwill...
And how?
Wait.
This way.
The farmer visited us.
What again?
The lord doesn't believe that the bear
takes the sheep. He wants to lock you up.
He wants to take our small field too.
Why?
He can do whatever he pleases.
What can you do against him alone?
I already know what I'll do.
Miéo, take this sheep to
the master's hall.
Let him choke on it,
if he doesn't believe me!
Stop it!
Gypsy, tune the violin!
There's a gentian for Mrnéa,
and give my regards to him.
A little cheese for mom and tell her
to take good care of herself.
- God bless you.
- Good-bye.
- Come!
- I'll stay with my father.
- Good.
- Good-bye.
At the hall, they only have banquets,
dinner after dinner,
and we don't have anything to eat.
We have bad times.
Only we can help ourselves.
We have to maintain discipline,
and not escape like today's
young people.
Agents permanently recruit people
to America.
America, America...
The locals run away
and foreigners barge in.
Well, if one leaves then so will another.
The strong blood flows out,
the weak stays here.
Sleep well.
- God bless you!
- May God help!
Welcome Mi§o!
Did you bring cheese?
Ondrej sends you cheese,
and also some herbs.
And who did it to you?
The master.
I brought him a message from Ondrej,
and he answered like this.
A new era of hope is coming
sometime soon.
Beware! Come on!
Beware!
Women, back off!
It's not a childbirth, the guy needs
a drink.
Ondrej...
Didn't I say so?
He'll be fit within a few days.
No, it shouldn't be like this.
They say in America, it's different.
Who knows?
Masters are everywhere.
They are.
But fellow-countrymen earn well there.
Maco Korefi wrote.
He has sent money to his wife,
he works in the mine.
Underground.
He doesn't even see the sun.
And who knows if he'll return.
Why not! And he brings home
a few dollars.
I wish I could earn a few thousand.
to help my family.
To buy some plough-land...
lt's possible only in America.
Could you change a mountain
into a dark mine?
Do you really prefer working here
for free, just for sheep milk?
Good afternoon!
What are you bringing us?
We are coming for the bear's skin.
The master wants it!
He took the sheep out of my wage,
I killed the bear,
the skin is mine!
So you won't give it us willingly!?
No, I won't!
If you don't. we are going to take it!
Then take it!
Right.
Then get out of the shed!
This very day!
The handle must be smooth.
Try it.
It's good.
Now, I'm going to show you how
my father killed the bear.
He aimed, then he smashed!
And the bear was killed.
Will you show me how? Then go!
And where is the bear?
Over there!
What have you done?
They wanted me to kill the bear.
Ondrej killed the pot
instead of the bear!
He'll be no better than his father.
You'll see, one day he'll kill a bear too.
You brigand of brigands.
I wish it weren't worse!
And I'll mend those cookers.
And what next?
I'll go to America.
- To America?
- Yes, to America.
Well, good-bye!
Bye.
Wait, I'll go too!
When I return, we'll build a
new house,
you'll have a nice garden
in front of the house
and I'll be a shepherd again.
That's easy for you to say.
But what will happen to us?
Have you thought about it?
- You've got a son.
- That's just it!
I want you to live better.
We will. if you stay.
If you leave, I'll end my life.
Mom, do you hear how much
she loves me?
The cross shows God's love.
Don't be afraid.
We'll be back in two years.
Everything is going to be alright.
We will have a farewell dance.
Mom, why didn't you tell him?
He obeys you!
All is in vain, he'll leave.
- For America?
- Come what may.
- He cannot leave!
- He'll leave and he'll return.
So, take courage!
Look at Mi§ko!
But he's unmarried.
I'm not afraid of the master!
I'm not afraid of being,
I'm not afraid of living,
I'm not afraid of the master!
Yankees are dancing.
They're saying good-bye but
how will they return...
Eva, my wife!
Mountain, don't feel sorrow for me!
Since I'm coming back
to you from beyond the sea.
Now a prayer for Dad.
Dear God, save my father,
deliver him from evil,
and bring him back to us soon
in good health. Amen.
I can't, Ondrej.
I can't breathe here.
I've got terrible chest pain.
Let's get out of here!
We'll go, Miéko.
We'll find a betterjob.
- God bless you, my fellow-countrymen!
- Bless you. Mr. Gregor!
How do you like it here?
It's good. thank you.
I think it was better with the sheep.
You'll get used to it.
The first five years are the worst.
- Good-bye my friends!
- Good-bye Mr. Gregor!
If you are going to write home,
send greetings to my homeland.
All right!
I live with Miéo. I earn good money.
After the next salary
I'll send you some money.
If God helps me, I'll be back soon.
I'll be back soon...
I'll be back soon.
There are lots of our countn/men,
our engineer is a native from home.
His name is Gregor.
I think of you all the time,
of you and mother,
of Ondrejko and all of you at home.
Beware!
Ondrei!
Halloo!
A terrible disaster has happened!
A dangerous situation!
The wall didn't hold!
Halloo!
You must go right away!
Can you hear me? Right away!
And get rid of evennhing!
None of the papers should be found!
Ziliak!
Mommy...
Mr. foreman!
Our Father. who art in heaven...
as we forgive those
who trespass against us
and lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
Amen.
Can't you pray?
- I can.
- So, then!
Our Father, who art in heaven.
hallowed be thy name...
Our Father. who art in heaven...
...in heaven...
-... in heaven!
What's the matter with my son?
I locked him up so he could learn
how to pray.
Ondrejko can pray.
In Hungarian?
No, the way we learnt from
our parents.
What are you thinking about?
Whether or not kids in America
go to school too?
Of course.
And they also learn Hungarian there?
Of course not!
They learn in the language they speak,
in American.
Why do they teach us a different
language than the one we speak?
The masters have decided it.
They say they want you
to be more clever.
If you want to catch a bird
you have to lure with a nice sing...
I am not that kind of bird!
Eva, come a bit closer!
What again?
You won't be moving this field
next spring.
Mara Garaj will get it.
They have you for a cheeky Pan-Slavic.
- Is that all?
- I'll also give you some advice.
Mara will get it because she
sent her son to Hungary.
If you send your son to Hungary,
the master will leave you the field,
and you could work at his hall.
That's how things work.
Don't worry, he'll feel good.
My son also went to school in
Budapest for six years.
And when he returned.
you couldn't talk to him.
He rejected you even more!
My Ondrej won't have a Hungarian name,
even if I have to starve!
Nothing.
Ifeel like choking...
If the light is on
nothing can happen to you.
We've already been here for 34 hours.
It's a shift.
It's already dawn up above.
And the guys are going on a new shift.
Why don't they make themselves heard?
We can't hear them yet.
They are far. But they'll come.
Get out fast!
We've got to leave.
The wall is starting to crack.
Out! Out!
Quickly. quickly out!
There's danger of an explosion.
It's risky to stay here.
We have to...
We can't leave them there!
We've got to rescue them!
Ondrej is waiting!
The letter has left. I wrote that
the money would arrive.
I'll add the last salary and I'll send it.
I can't fool Eva.
Now you know why
I have to get out of here.
And why I have to live.
I don't want to die here like a rat!
Out! Even ifl have to dig
a thousand meters!
Out!
Let's pay tribute to those
who died there.
Rejoice, our Lord Jesus Christ
was born,
rejoice, a floret blossomed out
of a rose.
Lord Jesus Christ was born,
from a pure life,
from the royal dynasty.
Miéo. welcome home!
And Ondrej?
Alone?
Alone.
Were you there?
Iwas.
Did you close his eyes?
I can't believe he's dead.
Who are you?
What's your name?
He hasn't said a word yet.
- This way.
- Thank you.
How can I repay this?
We are human beings,
to help each other.
Wasn't Ondrej my best friend?
You shouldn't do it.
People will speak badly of us.
- We shouldn't care!
- And mother?
Mother?
She believes Ondrej will come back.
I'm alone, you're alone...
You'd better go!
MOBILIZATION ORDER
There's a war!
Boys are joining the army!
Before I leave, we'll get married.
If you don't have anything against it.
My child...
Ondrejko, dad has come back!
Hey boy, you have grown up!
Nice to see you!
Thank you.
How are you, mother?
Are you well?
Well, me?
Thank God we are all together again.
All?
I hope everything will be alright.
We'll finish the house,
you'll go to school and
we'll have a nice life.
And you, mom, you'll come with us.
I'll stay here, my daughter.
If Ondrej returns,
he would find an empty house.
I'm alive!
Me, Ondrej Muranica!
Your results are good.
During the vacation you will see
how it goes in practice.
You'll be sent to measure wood
in the Black Valley.
Thank you.
Born in 1904...
- Your father?
- Allegedly died.
He went to America twelve years ago
and he hasn't come back yet.
Mountain don't feel sorrow for me...
mountain!
My darling doesn't call me anymore.
Married men will have a solo!
Son...
Mother!
Go have fun,
everything is well with me.
Ok. I'll go.
- But go to bed!
- Of course, I'll go.
Then l'm going-
I won't stay late!
Is Ondrej here?
It also seemed to me as if
he had returned.
Mom, why do you call him,
if you know he's dead?
You know very well he can't come.
Mom...
Well, you won't get angry anymore.
Did I offend somebody?
I stayed alone with the child,
Miéo came and helped me.
He treated Ondrejko well.
Forgive me, Mom?
I'll pray for you and for
Ondrejko's soul.
Mom...
Iwish I hadn't come back.
You had to come back
just as you had to go.
They were bad times.
Now it's better for us.
We can live our own life.
Our own?
Me?
For who?
Look, what was left to me.
You've got your hands
and your son.
Go after him and tell him:
my son, you are the continuation
of my life.
All my hope, health and
power is within you.
Everything that the world has taken
from me is in you.
Love your land and don't betray it,
because you'll be lost.
Tell that to everybody,
warn them with these words.
THE END
Watch more movies for free on
www.FlixTor.to