Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
What happened yesterday
doesn't happen every day
As lovely as a dream
And I love her so, ho, yeah
So this great love of mine
turned me into a hooligan
I whisper in her little ear:
What lovely lips you have
And she says: Yeah, man
Why aren't you kissing me?
And I love her, oh, yeah
And I love her so, oh, yeah
So this great love of mine
turned me into a hooligan
I whisper in her little ear:
What beautiful eyes you have
And she says: Yeah, man
You're just kidding me
And I love her so, oh, yeah
LOVES OF A BLONDE
I whisper in her little ear:
What pretty hair you have
And she says: Yeah, man
Why don't you play with it?
And I love her so, oh, yeah
So this great love of mine
turned me into a hooligan
I whisper in her little ear:
What a pretty blouse you have
And she says: Yeah, man
Why don't you take it off?
And I love her so, oh, yeah
So this great love of mine
turned me into a hooligan
I whisper in her little ear:
What a nice skirt you have
And she says: Yeah, man
Why don't you slip it off?
And I love her so, oh, yeah
So this great love of mine
turned me into a hooligan
I whisper in her little ear:
Let's go to the movies
And she says: Yeah, man
it's a stupid movie
God, isn't that just beautiful?
Can I borrow it?
-Just for a minute, okay?
-All right.
Gee, it's so gorgeous.
-Is it gold?
-Of course.
The real thing?
You think he would give me
anything else?
Let me have it for a while.
Did you notice the stone?
It's a real diamond.
A real one?
Yes. Look how it sparkles.
I've never seen a real diamond.
He told me it was.
-He's nice, isn't he?
-Really nice.
Do you have his picture?
What color are his eyes?
Well...they're...sort of...
I don't really know.
Well, then...
You've got to put it higher.
He's half a head taller.
About like this?
That's it. You look
great together.
And what did you give him?
Nothing yet. That's dumb,
isn't it?
It is dumb. You've got to give
him something.
Yes, but what?
Is that yours?
What do you think you're doing
hanging things on the trees?
You can't do that. You can't
just hang things up like that.
You'll dress up the whole forest.
I don't think it's going to
hurt the trees, is it?
No, but a deer could be going
by, you know,
and see a tie on a tree
and get scared.
Have you ever seen a
startled deer?
No.
This is what he does.
See? Did you like it?
We could listen to his bleating
together some time.
What do you say?
Well, how about it?
I don't know.
He told me all about those
animals, see?
Like they don't live together all
the time, like people do.
And the animals do it
only once a year,...
when it's mating time, see?
Then they're single again and
they just live on their own...
without any commitment...
not like people.
Only the wild geese, they're
like people, see?
-They are?
-Yes.
They live together for
up to 120 years.
-They do?
-Isn't that something?
And imagine, when they...
like when he shoots down
either him, see, or her...
-The goose?
-Yes.
Then the other one remains alone,
even for a hundred years.
What about Tonda?
Well...he, when we went away...
we left the tie hanging there
and when we came back, it
was still hanging there,...
so I guess he didn't come.
Will you go out with this guy?
I don't know.
The trouble is, he's married.
-He is?
-Yeah.
Fine, but we can't ignore the fact
that we need the people here.
Of course, that's right.
We need them.
If a girl has a real reason, like
if she has a boyfriend...
she'll get married,
if it's serious.
She'll marry him and then
maybe move away.
We can accept that as
a reason,...
but we can't make her come here
three times in a row...
claiming she's getting married
when she isn't.
So I won't let her go for now.
Only after she gets married.
Keep in mind that the factory
must meet deadlines.
Yes, but for God's sake, they
also need to have a life.
That's a problem.
Look here, if we
look at the map...
then from our point of view,...
it's not advantageous to put
the army in this area,...
to have troops here.
We understand your reasons.
Yes, of course.
We have the same duties and
problems in the army too.
You have yours and we have ours.
Look at that.
So, you have the map.
That's your standpoint, right?
That's your point.
But what you don't know...
is that some 2,000 girls
live in this area.
Girls without boyfriends.
We've got 16 girls to
every boy here.
Girls are like rosebuds.
You get me?
That's youth.
And youth needs
what you used to need.
Comrade Major,...
and myself, and the
others too, see?
-In our youth.
-That's right.
So you have your opinion...
and all you have is a map,...
but I have the lives of all
those young people.
Think about it.
A girl works in the plant...
for eight hours at the machine.
She leaves the factory.
Then what? She gets something
to eat... right?
And then she has nobody
to caress her.
Nobody to kiss her.
So now think what happens if
there's no war for 50 years.
No war. which is what
we're all fighting for.
Including yourself, Comrade Major.
You're fighting for the same thing.
What if there's no war
for a hundred years?
I can only tell you...
that I haven't said my
last word yet.
All can do is pass along
your proposal...
and we'll see what can be
done about it.
Pass it along? To whom?
What does that mean?
WELCOME THE PEOPLE'S ARMY
Battalion.
Follow me, company, three
men abreast. Line up.
All the fuss they made about it.
Yeah, and instead of boys,
we get reservists.
And so good-looking. A bunch
of grandfathers.
Shout it out.
Left, right...
Across the burnt earth
over bloody rivers
The vengeful regiments
march steadily on
Heart, law, eternity
are on our side
We march forward like time
Like a terrible wall of revenge
What a pretty daughter you have
You know very well that
I have a crush on her
Hey, lady, give us your blessing
For she's a girl made for love
What a pretty daughter you have
You know very well that
I have a crush on her
Look at those soldiers
over there.
Look at those girls
over there, man.
Oh, God. Who are they?
They're terrible.
-Why? Are they looking over here?
-Yeah. All the time.
What if they ask us to dance?
Oh, come on.
What's your problem?
Why couldn't it happen?
You're not ugly.
But come on, that's not possible.
No way could I...
Try it. Ask one of them
to dance.
Well, why not?
Look at them. This is just awful.
Let's get out of here.
So let's not look
in their direction.
But we aren't looking their way.
Yes, you keep looking over there.
Please, Andula, stop
looking at them!
Where should I look? They're
sitting right there.
Look here, don't force
yourself on them.
Wait till they show same
interest.
What?
Don't be so pushy. Wait for
them to come over.
Handsome, isn't he?
The pianist. He's handsome,
isn't he?
So, boys?
-Damn it... so?
-What, what... so what.
Well, so... what?
Gentlemen, we should send
them a bottle of wine.
Why?
Okay, then.
Sure, yeah.
Look, girls, they're pointing at
us, and the waiter too.
Let them point. What
do we care?
-So don't look.
-Look at them looking at us.
They can look where they like.
You know, they'll think we're...
You're looking too.
I'm not looking at them...
We're not staring as
stupidly as you.
Stop it.
Look, he's taking it to
they table.
-Why doesn't he bring it to us first?
-Sit down and stop staring.
Jesus, what an idiot.
-This is embarrassing, man.
-That half-wit.
Don't look over there.
At least stop smiling.
-Really, girls, I'm so relieved...
-Me too.
I was worried they were going
to bring the bottle to us.
-I couldn't bear it.
-Don't even mention it, please.
Hey, don't look over there now.
Don't look there now!
-Let's get out of here, girls
-Yeah, we should go.
Courage!
Let's go. Are we going?
-So let's go. Come on!
-I'm not going.
You're crazy.
We can't march over there
like a procession.
-So just the two of us?
-You two go.
Wait. What procession?
There's three of them and three
of us. Is that a procession?
Bring them over here.
Don't be crazy!
So you bring them over, okay?
Either the three of us go, or...
Why me alone?
So we'll all go, like I said.
-I'm not going.
-Now we look like bozos.
Come on.
-Where can we go around here?
-An afternoon dance.
Yeah, that's in the afternoon.
But when you don't want to sleep
yet, where do you go?
To the park or to the woods.
Finish it off, then.
Come on.
-My God, how you hold it!
-Drink up.
It's much worse sipping
it like that.
Bottoms up! Have some
more, Jana.
-I can't.
-Yes, you can. You've hardly had any.
This is good stuff we ordered.
Wine is good for you, girls.
After all, when the
vine's growing,...
it draws nourishment from the soil.
All that iron and humidity
from the air...
and all that sun shining on it.
That's why it's so expensive.
Come on, have a drink.
All of it, like a man.
To the last drop.
See, you can do it.
There you go... all of it.
It was good, wasn't it?
Now you, Marie.
Bottoms up!
I don't want anymore.
I don't like it.
You'll get used to it. They
didn't like it either.
I don't want it.
Shall we go for a walk?
Hey, what is this?
Keep playing.
It was fine.
Hey, you, come here. Yes, you.
Come here for a minute.
-Oh, God, this is pointless.
-Let's go, okay?
Let's just agree on something
an go.
We'll drink the wine and
have some fun, huh?
If you're not interested, we'll
go back to the barracks.
We'll make it work, won't we?
Andula?
We can't stay here forever.
They're looking at us.
Are we going or not?
We'll be back in a minute, okay?
Where are you going?
We'll be right back.
I thought we could
talk a bit more...
and then the time will be right.
And then no problem. We'll
each will grab one and...
-I don't fell like going to the woods.
-They didn't really mean the woods.
People just say,
"Let's go to the wood".
In this weather?
They mean outdoors.
Not in a room.
Did you think they'd let us
in their dormitory?
No way, unless we pretend to
be an army delegation.
There's no way to get in there.
Don't worry, you wouldn't be
the first to slip in there.
-Where're you going?
-I'm going to bed. There's nothing here.
-Don't be stupid, man.
-What's going on here?
Sit down and quit being an idiot.
Listen, can I ask you something?
Have you ever cheated
on your wife?
Why?
Not "why"... yes or no?
Is this a pub or a confessional?
Come on, say it. "I've been
unfaithful" or "I haven't".
It's no big deal, right?
Well, that's different.
Come on, let's go home.
-Don't be an idiot again.
-I'm not. He is.
Sit down. We still
have this bottle.
Now he's an idiot, huh?
Go to hell and sit down,
and... just sit.
What a waste of money!
Give him ten crowns.
Just take the money. I don't
care about the money.
But I care that you sit here and
say nothing the whole time.
Take the money and
leave me alone.
Stop babbling now. You should
have spoken up before.
You two stare like idiots,
while I do all the talking...
and now you tell me these
stupid things.
Gentlemen, this is
truly pointless.
-Where are you going?
-Home. You act like children.
You act like retarded teenagers.
-Let's go.
-This a waste of time.
Well, let's go. You wanted
to go. Come on.
We'll go, but not because of me.
-Good Lord.
-Because of whom, then?
-Who was the first to get up?
-A bunch of idiots, aren't we?
But still, they gave us
the bottle.
Can't we just go and chat?
I'm not going. Those old geezers
will try to drag us to the woods.
-To the woods. Are you scared?
-Why would I be scared?
You must be if you
say it like that.
Gentlemen, another minute
and I'm gone.
-The girls probably left.
-Why would they?
-Because.
-Because why? Why would they leave?
Would they sit with us all
evening to run off now?
And how could they?
I kept an eye on the door.
-Go and take a look.
-Where?
Where they went.
-I can go and have a look?
-Why not?
-Why can't you go there?
You'd go to their dormitory but
you're scared to go there?
There's a difference between a
ladies room and a dormitory.
-So you go.
-I'll do, but we're wasting a bottle.
See, he can't forget the bottle.
Who do you think you are?
Look at us. A bunch of old farts.
We have to pay the price.
You only get it for free at home, and
in your case I doubt even that.
Really, do you want to
come up for a while?
I trust you.
I could make you tea or something.
Would you like that?
-I trust you but...
-But I don't trust you. See...
-Why?
-Don't tell me you're just chatting.
I mean it. We're just
chatting with them.
-You're not.
-We are too.
I'm going right now.
-Come up, just for a while.
-No.
Just to chat, I promise.
No. I have to go.
-Come up, just for a moment!
-No.
Wait. At least let me read
your palm, all right?
Gentlemen, what's going on?
Hey, look at this.
Drink up.
You too. All of it.
You're no better than the
girls. Drink up.
Take the bottle.
Off we go, gentlemen.
Don't drink it all. You'll fall
asleep in the woods.
Let's go.
Finally. Where is Andula?
-Over there. She'll be here.
-Will she?
Where is she?
Where are you going?
What is it?
Boys, I'm off to bed.
Good night, girls.
Oh, come on.
Girls, what's this whispering?
Say it out loud.
-We're going too. Good night.
-Good night.
-Go, then.
-So let's go.
-Come on, then.
-Go, then. The both of you.
Come on. Please, come on.
This is the line of your...This is
your line. And here you see...
-What line?
-Your life line.
And here...I see danger.
I see three middle-aged
men in the woods.
It says here, three men in
the woods, in winter.
-You mean the there downstairs?
-I didn't say that.
Well, I'm not sure. Sometime in
the near future.
Damn it, but you have
a long life line!
Yes, it goes up here.
-And here you have a scar.
-That's nothing.
I have a scar too.
I fell out of a tree.
-This isn't from a tree.
-It's not?
A rock then?
A piece of glass?
It's from a razor blade.
You tried to commit suicide?
Because of my mom.
We don't get along.
Let's go to my room and you
can tell me everything.
-No. I've got to go.
-It was because of your mom?
I only got along with my dad.
They're divorced now.
-Come with me.
-No.
-Mine are divorced too.
-I have to go.
How did it happen?
You cut your...
Well, I thought the
artery, you know?
I thought it was the light vein.
I took a razor blade and it broke,
so I took another one.
I just kept cutting.
And I was crying.
-And the blood...
-Come, let's go to my room.
-No. I have to go.
-Look, I have another scar here.
-No. I have to go. Really.
-Come on.
Take off your coat.
No, I'm not taking
off anything.
Won't you sit down
for a minute?
-No, I'm not taking anything off.
-Why not?
I came up here so you wouldn't
think I didn't trust you.
Can I tell you something?
Then you can go.
No. What's the point?
What's the use?
Come on, tell me.
There's no use. You want to
go and there's no time...
and I need you to sit down...
so we can talk a bit.
So tell me.
All right, I'll tell you.
Come here.
What are you doing?
Why are you scared?
Can't you fight?
Can't you?
So that's why you're scared.
Let me teach you something...
to stop you from being scared when
someone's bothering you.
It's a grip. May I?
Stand here like this.
Take that off. We might wrinkle it.
If someone starts bothering you,
like this for example.
Don't be scared.
I don't want to do anything.
That was just an example.
Don't be scared. Put your
arms around me.
-Now, what do I see?
-How would I know?
-Well, what do I see?
-I don't know.
That's just the thing. Now
I can't see anything...
and that's your ideal opportunity
to defend yourself.
-How?
-With your legs.
Don't be afraid.
-How will you defend yourself?
-I don't know.
With your legs.
And how?
-Kick me.
-Where?
You can either give me a
kick with your knee...
but I'm not going to try that...
or you can kick me
in the shin, see?
-So, I'm bothering you.
-But it'll hurt you, won't it?
Look here, you'd better
take your shoes off.
Come on, take them off
for a minute.
Now kick me.
Nice trick, eh?
-You said I should kick you.
-Yes, in the shin.
Now, defend yourself.
I'll teach you a counter grip.
Come on.
-Kick me in the shin.
-I can't.
I overdid it.
Does it hurt really bad?
You know, I could get
gangrene and die.
-You want me to die?
-No.
So why did you kick
me like that?
I forgive you.
Turn off the light, please.
I can't find you.
But I don't trust you.
I do trust you.
I've never trusted anyone
so much before.
-I told you at least a hundred times.
-No, you didn't.
-Didn't I?
I don't have a girl in Prague,
I don't have a girl in Prague...
Stop it. That's enough.
-Shit, you'll choke me.
-So what?
-I won't be able to finish.
-Finish what?
Finish saying "I don't have a girl
in Prague, I don't have..."
Let me see. Who gave that to you?
-It's from my mom.
-Your mom?
-You have a ring too.
-I got mine from my mom too.
We both have rings
from our mothers.
Why did you say I was angular?
-I said you were angular?
-Yes, you did.
-Well, because you're angular.
-What do you mean?
Some women are round,
like guitar, like this.
And you...look like a guitar too,
but one made by Picasso.
What's that?
A painter.
When painting a woman,...
he painted her eye here...
and her leg somewhere else.
I could tell you about
lots of other pictures.
Or he painted fingers like this.
-That's weird.
-Weird, yeah.
But I'm not like that?
No.
-Is that good or bad?
-What?
That I am like the Picasso guitar?
Well, that's good.
-Hi.
-Show me your hand.
-Why?
-Just show me your hand.
-Where is your ring?
-I don't wear it anymore.
You don't wear it.
Where is it?
-I don't wear it.
-You don't wear it. Where is it?
Well, you didn't show up for
over a month, so there.
So I didn't show up for a
month. Where is the ring.
-It's mine, isn't it?
-So what if it's your?
Where is the ring?
Where is it?
-At the dormitory.
-Then get on and we'll go get it.
Tonda.
Andula says she can't
give you the ring.
-Why not?
-Because she doesn't have it.
-Doesn't have it?
-Ask Andula to come to the window.
-What do you need it for?
-Hey get lost. Call her.
-Andula says she can't come.
-How come?
She doesn't have time.
Get out. what do you want?
-Come here.
-Please, go away. Out.
-What are you doing?
-Don't be scared. Stand up.
Please. Go away.
What are you doing?
What is it?
Don't be scared.
Stop shouting, okay?
What are you doing?
Get out!
-This is my business, not yours!
-It's our business too. Get out!
She's our friend and this
is our room. Shut up.
Get up.
Do you hear me?
Why are you staring at me?
Get up.
Don't touch me. You're disgusting!
You hear me?
You're disgusting,
like a beast.
Go away, please!
Go away. I don't want to
see you anymore.
Girls, look.
A girl's honor isn't just talk.
It really exists.
If you keep treating it
the way you do,...
don't be surprised if boys
treat you badly.
If you go out with a different boy
every day, they talk about it.
Your whole life lies
ahead of you.
You want to be happy.
You want to marry a good boy...
who will love you forever.
But you have to deserve it.
Think about it.
I think you should be looking
for a solution.
Girls, I think the words of
comrade teacher here...
give us much to reflect on.
This deserves a pledge
from each of us,...
a promise to improve ourselves.
I think we should vote on it.
Who's in favor?
Thank you.
Who's against?
Any abstentions?
Are you going to Prague?
Across the meadows ringing
Yippiyippiyee
The echo for me singing
When over the valley
for is rolling
The boys are riding home
When Jimmy moments the saddle
my heart goes shivering
I can see the rider afar
flying away on his horse
Disappearing behind the rock
waving at me
Jimmy boy, I wanna join you
When across the meadow ringing
The echo for me singing
When over the valley
fog is rolling
the boys are riding home
Poppa.
-What is it?
-The doorbell.
Who would ring the bell?
It must have been on TV.
-Good evening.
Does Milda Vasita live
here, please?
He does. You have
business with him?
-Is he home?
-No, he's not.
What do you want?
Do you know when
he'll back?
I really don't. Sometimes early,
sometimes late.
Do you know where
I could find him?
-Gosh, I don't. Momma?
-What is it?
Do you know when Milda is due
home or where he's playing?
I don't. He didn't say where he was
going or when he'd be back.
Hard to say. You should maybe try
and find him on your own.
-May I leave my suitcase here, please?
-Sure.
-Thank you. Good-bye.
-Good night.
Poppa who was it?
Incredible!
She shows up late at night
at his parents place.
Did Milda say he was
expecting her?
I asked nothing and he
offered nothing.
I can't get it off my mind.
With a suitcase.
-Was she young?
-Yes, she was young.
I didn't even know he
was going steady.
Yeah, like the boy is going to
tell you about his girl friends!
Will you stop watching that TV?
I can't stop thinking about it.
I can't do anything. I can't even
sew. Can't get it off my mind.
I'm worried about him.
This is no small matter. Finds
himself a girl God knows where.
Did she tell you where
she lived?
I didn't ask.
He'll end up having to marry her, and
we don't even know where she's from.
You know what happens
with marriages like that.
Six months later it's over.
And the Kids are the
ones who suffer.
He hasn't mentioned marriage and
you're worried about the Kids!
Don't make such a fuss about it.
This is awful.
Poppa, have a look in
her suitcase.
Are you crazy? Open a strange
woman's suitcase?
We might find out something
about her.
Yeah, the suitcase will
tell you for sure.
It's her you should have looked
at, not her suitcase!
I didn't speak to her you did.
Who am I to probe into
her personal life?
You could have taken
a close look.
I did, but I didn't see anything.
What was I supposed to see?
Who knows how this
will turn out?
There's the doorbell again.
Excuse me they locked the front
door. Could you please...
Could you open the door for me?
Wait a second. I'll get the key.
Poppa who is it?
It's the girl.
Miss, wait a second.
Don't run away.
Don't run. Come in for a minute.
I'd like to ask something.
-Come in for a while.
-No, I'd rather go.
Don't be scared. I won't hurt you.
Come in for a while.
I just want to ask
you something.
Please come in.
Take off your coat.
Here's my hat.
Sit over there.
Have a seat.
Sit down, young lady.
Don't be shy.
Did you arrange something
with Milda?
He invited me to come.
But I couldn't come sooner.
I work, you know.
How come he didn't say anything
about your coming?
Poppa, he didn't say
a word, did he?
No, but I didn't speak
with him.
You see? And now you show up with
a suitcase to spend the night?
-Where did you meet him?
-Back home in Zruc.
You came from Zruc?
And you met him there?
-Has Milda been to Zruc?
-Yes, about a week ago.
And you've only known each other
for such a short time?
Yes, Saturday and Sunday.
You see, Milda charms a girl, invites
her home and now what?
Crazy guy.
He is. But it's partly
her fault too.
She shouldn't jump when a
boy invites her to visit.
And she comes to his parents' place
for the night, with a suitcase.
-You have a serious reason to come?
-No.
Just what did you think, showing
up with a suitcase?
Where did you plan to
spend the night?
I don't know yet.
-Where did you plan to sleep?
-I don't know.
Well, it wasn't very smart...
to set off a boy's parents' if you've
only known him for two days.
He didn't mean it. He just said,
"Come and see me."
She took him at his word,
and here she is.
For haven sake,
she's a young girl.
I still don't get it. Where were
you going to sleep?
You can't stay here with us.
Poppa, what do you say?
If he invited her, we'll look after
her until he gets home.
We're not gonna throw her out.
We'll make room for he.
You keep out of it.
That won't work.
What would people say?
A girl comes to see Milda and
we let her stay the night?
I don't care.
Would you kick her out
on the street?
Keep out of this.
I don't know how we'll handle
this. I don't like it.
Haven't I always said
your son is nuts?
Here's your proof.
You could have talked to him.
You could have told him not
to do such stupid things.
He's never done this
before has he?
He isn't old enough
to do such things.
Well, that's true.
We didn't do thing like this.
You're making such a fuss about it.
Nothing happened, right?
We'll fix up a bed for her.
We can't throw her out.
He's an idiot and we can't
do a thing about it.
I'll talk to him tomorrow.
Too late now. He should have
know better before.
Was I supposed to tell him before?
Did I know she was coming?
He should know not to do
such stupid things.
He'll keep telling young
girls to come visit...
and a few days later they'll
show up on our doorstep.
This won't be the last time.
You think I'm with him all the time
to know what he tells girls?
You think that in the old days...
I could pack a suitcase and
leave for a boy's parents'?
Do you know what that meant?
Should she have come from the
country without a suitcase?
You came here instead going
to your own parents'.
You've put us in quite a fix.
I've no idea what to do.
Now, look at Milda. True, he
makes quite a bit of money.
He could handle a marriage financially,
but there's more to it than that.
He need a woman to look after
him, to cook for him.
He brings in the money, but
look at Poppa here.
He's been working for 30 years and
doesn't earn as much as Milda does.
Look how worn-out he is,
the poor guy.
Who's sleeping here?
You're asking me? It's a girl...
can't you see?
Where from?
Don't play stupid. She's come
to see you, boy.
-To see me?
-No, me!
-Who is she?
-Who is she? Look at her.
Should I recognize her by
her foot or what?
-So turn her over.
-How? She's asleep.
-You're a real idiot.
-Who invited her?
-You must have.
-I'm telling you, I don't know.
Jesus, a girl wouldn't just come
to our place for the fun of it.
-You're saying I invited her?
-Stop yelling at me.
Shut your mouth. A girl comes to
see you and you yell at me.
You should know
where she's from.
I don't. She must've
told you.
She met you in Zruc.
Did you play there?
She couldn't have been
there with me.
Listen, this is the last time. Once
more and you're out of the house.
Are you sure she's
not a relative?
Am I that stupid?
You think I wouldn't recognize
our own relatives?
Don't treat me like an idiot.
Honestly. Dad, I don't
invite her here.
Don't you think I would have told
you and Mom if I had?
-Lord, don't make a fool out of me.
-What should I do? Throw her out?
-Throw her out.
-Okay, I will!
Oh, my gosh! Hi!
I didn't recognize you.
-Hi.
I didn't recognize your hair.
I didn't know it was you.
-What was your father saying?
-Nothing.
-He said something.
-He's stupid.
-Are you glad I came?
-You know I am.
And when... How long do
you plan to stay?
It's hard, you know.
You don't write a single line,
you show up,...
and my folks are alarmed.
You can't do that.
-So now you know her, eh?
-Yes, he does.
Why didn't you write?
I wanted to, but somehow
I never had time.
-What did he say?
-That he doesn't know her.
-What else?
-That he never asked her to come.
-Now go to sleep.
-But you had a long talk.
Yes, we talked a long time.
I have to talk to him
from time to time.
-Where have you been?
-Playing.
And then?
Then we went someplace.
-Alone?
-No.
With whom?
-What?
-With whom?
The guys.
-Who else?
-Just the guys.
This is terrible.
This won't do at all.
You'd like that, wouldn't
you, miss?
But you wouldn't get much
sleep here. Come on.
And don't argue with me.
You'll sleep in our bed.
That'll be better.
-Don't push me, damn it. I'm going.
-Go.
I can keep an eye on you.
-I can't sleep here at all.
-You'll sleep here just fine.
It's like sleeping on the
edge a table!
It's not my fault. Where
should I have put him?
-I could have sleep out there.
-You think I'd let you?
-What's gonna happen?
-Sleep with a girl at home? No, sir.
Poppa will survive.
He stinks like a barrel.
Don't breathe on me.
This is terrible.
Give me some blankets.
If you were a decent father, you'd
slap him for coming in so late!
-He wouldn't come in this late...
-Jesus, listen...
I'll get under the covers
and that's that.
No way. And don't do
this ever again.
-For a girl...
-It's not my fault. Is it?
Yes, it is. You've ruined my evening.
You asked her to come.
You know very well I didn't
ask her to come.
-She wouldn't lie.
-Oh, please.
I'm going out there.
Don't you dare or
I'll slap you, too!
Damn it, will you
stop yelling?
How should I know what
I did or didn't do?
Very nice! So what do you do
when you go out on tour?
I play.
So how come you don't
know what you did?
-Do you get that drunk?
-Stop barking. For goodness' sake.
I have to tell him.
Then tell him later.
But he still deserves a few
good slaps from you.
You come over here. I'll sleep
here and we're all set.
Do whatever you want.
Don't stretch out or I'll
smack you one!
That's much better.
-Why do you do these stupid things?
-I haven't done anything stupid.
Is it my fault she came
here? Is it?
-You invited her.
-Hardly.
-She just shows up with a suitcase.
-Momma, be quiet and leave me alone.
Well, it's the truth.
And here we are like
sardines in a can.
-That's it... I'm sleeping out there!
-Don't you dare!
-Then stop it!
-You think I'd let you sleep with her?
I won't sleep with her. I'll sleep
in the kitchen and that's that.
One more second and I'll
toss you out of this bed!
Gladly! Do it!
-Out you go. Hurry up!
-No way. Who gives orders around here?
-You're sleeping here.
-Okay. Don't get upset.
That would be great! What
would the neighbors say?
I have no covers.
You're driving me crazy!
You'll be the end of me.
Wretched boy.
You're terrible. You'll
be the death of me.
-For God's sake. Will you go to sleep?
-Who'll take care of you then?
Mom, go to sleep. I'll do the
dishes for you tomorrow.
I can't wait.
Are you okay now?
I was almost asleep and
you start up again!
Please go to sleep!
You think I feel good about this?
He scolds me for being rude to
you and he's rude himself.
Watch out or you'll
get smacked.
He takes after you
you're all alike.
Jesus, you're driving me nuts!
Will you sleep now, please?
You'd like that. Wouldn't you? I'm
all worn-out from the two of you.
Instead of a good night's
sleep. We argue all right.
Please be quiet. She'll wake
up and we'll be in trouble.
I don't give a damn about her.
She ruined my evening.
Good for you that his
parents are so nice.
His father is nice.
Really nice.
When will you be
going back again?
I'll be going back from
now on...
THE END
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/5umwr
Help other users to choose the best subtitles