Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
"Adela Has Not Had Dinner Yet"
Every Wednesday
Kuratko, Nick's helper,
delivering mail, noticing
the harvest of defeated evil,
thus commented to the point:
What a day again!
Clean it up, please!
Always the same.
When the chestnut is too hot for the police
the low ranks must handle it.
Skotenka, Skulteparik, Kamrik.
Who will be the lucky one?
Director of Police, Prague City.
Where is that?
In Vienna. So...?
Mysterious disappearance in an
important family
come immediately, will pay any price.
Interesting case!
We have not sorted out
the King's gang yet!
- Can you handle them alone?
- Sure, it's only one gang!
- Shall I pack your bags?
- Yes.
First some necessary information
about those Antipodeans.
Of course, I was right.
They use some kind of Slavic language. Well,
I'll have plenty of time to learn it aboard the ship.
- Interesting people!
- Will you use your usual perfect disguise there?
I will just melt into the crowd!
"Czech Quick and Easy"
Prague Terminal!
Beer! Beer! Drinking water!
Mr Carter! Welcome to Prague!
I'm the Director of Police, Knight Franz von Kaunitz.
...Hot dogs... hot dogs...
- Commissar Ledvina!
Josef Ledvina.
- I assume my arrival has been kept strictly secret.
- But of course!
The most famous
American detective's in Prague!...
Can't keep a secret here...
To your success, Mr Carter!
- No denying it... Pilsen's the best!
- Pilsen?
Famous local beer.
The liquid bread of the Czech nation.
- That's some baggage!
- Please!
Present from my friend Edison!
- Why would you drag that with you?
- A modern detective must move with the times!
Technology is his friend!
A few drinks will achieve
the same result, too...
- To the point, gentlemen!
- Thank you!
- Mr Carter, this is an unusually mysterious case.
- That's the only type that interests me!
This happened in the bedroom of the wife of Duke Tuna.
She refuses any involvement of the police because of that.
This lady has therefore asked me
to engage you;
she is a great admirer of yours.
- She's sure you'll be able to explain the disappearance.
- Whose disappearance?
The lady will explain everything.
Here, a gesture of her gratitude...
A preliminary one...!
I work alone. However, I'm a stranger here and
cannot get by without some information.
Of course; that's why you'll have Commissar
Ledvina at your disposal.
A man Prague holds no secrets from!
- OK. Tomorrow.
- Investigation at the crime scene,
...this afternoon a sightseeing tour!
- Sure!
Let's go sightseeing, then!
Eureka! It's weeping!
- The plant is weeping!
- Congratulations, sir!
- Did he arrive?
- Yes, sir! He's staying at the Hotel Paris.
He has conferred with the Director of Police,
is sightseeing now and tomorrow will start investigating!
Good! If he wants to investigate,
he must open the jail of my Adela!
Of course, sir! By tomorrow night,
Adela will be back in your hands!
I didn't cut you off
a hangman's rope for nothing!
If only that American dick knew
he's paving the way for my revenge!
He's full of himself...
Can't handle us, though!
No way, sir!
Keep him in sight;
even a mosquito can sting!
My people aren't asleep, sir!
Very old castle.
From the Dark Middle Ages, surely.
Very dark!
That's why we put gas lights here!
- And the statues, are they hand-made?
- Of course, everything's hand-made here.
What wouldn't we do for the tourists!
All the talking's made me thirsty!
Have you drunk Pilsen before? No? Please!
So?
Another famous place; frequented by King Wenceslas.
But mainly they sell great sausages here.
And Pilsen?
Beautiful! One can just smell the history!
Yeah, it's just breathed out!
If you're interested in history,
this is a historical date.
Plekovsky was born...
Where is the stalk....
That terrible dream again...
You won't escape my revenge,
you old Satan!
5 o'clock; we're going home!
Thanks, Commissar!
Prague is a hard city to sightsee...
The old palaces,
the great cathedrals...
And we have not even visited
at the "Pinkas's"...
There's a bartender
there who just cuddles the beer!
- Every Wednesday.
- Let's go home...
The Lady's awaiting you.
Fit again...
Well, Commissar; pay me back.
- Hit me. Go on!
- As you wish!
- You don't box?
- No, we slap.
In this country,
I can't get by without you.
"You've won, Nick Carter!"
whispered the scoundrel.
"Say hello to the devil, Gardener"
said calmly the great detective.
Soon the criminal's face, contorted with hatred,
disappeared in the smelly swamp.
That was the end of the king of crime,
known in New York as The Gardener.
What a pity my dear Gert has not
lived to see the end of The Gardener!
My dear!
You talk about Gert as if he were dead!
Until that famous detective's had his last word,
you must keep hoping!
You are so kind...
have you forgiven Gert?
Sure. Such a little transgretion...
But I think Carter won't be around this morning.
- Why? - Apparently he got extremely tired
from all the sightseeing!
- Lady!
- Yes!
Oh, he's not tired!
Tell him to come in!
Excuse me, please;
I am supposed to be chairing a meeting
of a Committee for Protection
of Widows and Orphans!
He's so excentric!
Welcome, sir!
When dear Gert disappeared so mysteriously
behind those doors,
I put some radical measures in place,
so until your arrival
the crime scene was not disturbed.
- Praiseworthy foresight!
- I learned that from you!
My favourite reading:
Dante, Goethe and Nick Carter!
Sign of good taste!
The key!
Your testimony first.
I'll talk to Miss Karyn later.
Yes... at any time...
Here, I played his favourite song to put him
to sleep for the last time.
To put him to sleep?
He wouldn't sleep without it.
This was his favourite corner.
He loved the smell of flowers.
This is the only thing left of him.
- Yes?
- Nothing but his collar.
- Gert was a... dog?
- Yes. Only he understood me!
Sure. A dog's man's best friend, after all.
Please tell me everything.
That fateful evening,
I was getting ready to go to bed
at about 11,
helped as usual by my assistant.
Gert was doing the same.
When Karyn left the room, I locked all the
windows and doors, as Gert was terrified of robbers.
I made sure he was set up for the night,
not knowing I was seeing him for the last time.
- Sorry, sir...!
- Feelings like these require no excuses.
Thank you! Then I sat down
and started singing Gert's favourite
good-night song from Mozart.
It's my favourite, too!
The lady was ringing the bell madly.
I quickly ran over
and could hardly comprehend
at first what had happened.
But then I saw:
There was only Gert's collar!
Gert had disappeared
as if into thin air!
We looked everywhere... without luck.
Gert had gone!
Only then the Lady had pronounced
the saving word: "Carter!"
- Thanks, Miss! I have no more questions!
- Really? Pity....
- Good-bye, Miss Karyn!
- Yes!
- She's certainly fallen for you!
- Commissar! We're not at the pub!
How long ago...
Mysterious case.
- Dog?
- Disappeared!
- I know that even without you!
- Not that dog! The Italian! Sausage!
- It was here a moment ago!
- Enough! I'm in the middle of an investigation
and you are still only concerned about those...
What's that?
Paper! Greasy paper!
National Newspaper. My Italian was wrapped
in that newspaper.
It fell out of that flower! It ate the Italian
and spat the paper out!
An experienced crime investigator
does not jump to conclusions!
It must've eaten the dog, too!
- A daring hypothesis!
- Just look at it how it's perked up!
You bastard!
You like eating others' food, huh!
Don't let carried away by anger!
Now you'll find out by interrogation
how did this plant get here.
And I'll borrow this for my laboratory.
Looks like you're in demand,
my little one!
- Thank you! - Please order a big portion
of the Italians for my room!
Will do!
- Good afternoon! The Italians!
- About time. Put them on the table.
We were waiting for fresh ones, sir!
They'll just melt in your mouth!
And the smell! Just try it!
As you can see, it was no-one
of my personnel.
Yeah? And how about
that dwarf that's disappeared?
There's a black sheep in every flock....
Get the hell out you....
shepherd!
At your service!
Have you discovered anything new
in the palace, Commissar?
Nothing! No-one knows how the
plant got there.
We have lost the battle,
but we'll win the war!
This needs fresh air,
some draught beer,
and all will be well again!
Eat, Adela, eat!
You haven't eaten for a long time!
Lucky the dog was so big and meaty!
It doesn't pay for him to pee
on my leg!
At least we know now
what you can do!
So, has the detective
sniffed anything out yet?
Chloroform, sir!
Sorry, sir!
To be frank, I don't wish to
meet Nick!
Impossible, sir,
I have his everys step under observation!
Bravo!
Here, hold this!
Now I'll start the revenge!
Grandpa! Look, grandpa!
The General Butterfly, grandpa!
Admiral, my dear, Admiral!
- And what've you caught, grandpa?
- Nothing much; I'm an old man after all...
But you look so healthy, grandpa!
- What's this? I don't know this...
Well, let's see... - "Hosalba Dexteri"...
on a Czech paddock,
Rare, yet explicable.
Tiny seeds of this plant have been
brought to Egypt in the digestive system
of Pastejrik Kostrbaty - the favourite food source
of Raroch Vltivy, which winters there
and then transfers them on its beak
back to our homeland!
Almighty Nature!
I see you are also a botanist!
Baron Robert von Kratzmar?
Private doctor of Faust University
in Wienerschnitzelberg?
Oh my god! Such an honour!
Let me introduce my granddaugter
Miss Kvetuse Bockova.
And my name's Albin Bocek, retired professor
of botany and zoology.
You are the author of the collossal work
"Flowers of the Jindrichohradec area"?
- Sins of one's youth, Baron!
- Leave the Baron, my dear colleague!
I'd be honoured
if you would autograph this copy.
But of course! I'd be delighted to welcome
the Baron...
colleague, in my modest abode.
We'll look through some books,
drink some coffee and eat some apple pie,
that Kvetus has made. May I hope
my dear colleague?...
Books, coffee and apple pie?
I can't wait! See you tonight!
That mysterious plant! The solution
to the dog's disappearance...
- The dog's eaten!
- But Commissar! A sausage is not the same
as a dog the size of a calf!
There is no plant big enough
to manage such a big bite!
True, I did know someone who...
No! Impossible! He's been dead
for a long time!
The fresh air certainly does miracles!
The aromatic gardens, the lilacs....
- What's that?
- Olomouc cheese. Nicely decomposed.
Europe is decomposing...
Grandpa! The Mineral Butterfly!
- General, my darling! I mean... Admiral!
- Yellow Butterfly, grandpa...
Quiet...
My girl... you're home!
The gentlemen kindly ordered a cab.
This is Mr Josef Ledvina, the maker of stripes
and this is Mr Nick Ledvina, Czecho-American,
currently visiting the old country.
By the way, have you happened to meet
young Matejka in America?
He's the stepson of my sister-in-law.
I haven't had the pleasure.
I work as a Magician. Walking out into
the street I had left my work hat on
...and the misfortune was done.
No, Mr Magician!
It was all due to my collector's weakness...
I am a bit shaken up... excuse me....
Gentlemen - please, sit down!
Professor, may I ask a question relating to your field?
It concerns an exotic plant.
Exotic plant? My friend! I only know the
Czech plants! But if you wait here for an hour,
you will be answered by the foremost expert
in just that area!
- In the meantime, I'll bring some dandelion wine!
- Dandelion?
It's a true elixir of youth! I have some every day and
being almost 80, my heart beats like a bell still!
- And liver like a rock!
- What else awaits me here?...
Commissar! Who's that?
- Some boy... and he's drawing graffiti
on the wall. - Or a masked dwarf!
- Always alert, Commissar! That's why
you'll go down to the pub. - Sure!
- And you won't let the street out of your sight!
- Well, they have some rubbish on tap there,
but it still beats some dandelion poison!
Welcome, dear collegue Baron!
What a visit!
I'll take him to the study, my girl.
- Have you wiped the dust off there?
- Of course, grandpa!
Mr Magician, may I show you
my butterfly collection?
I'd be honoured....
Let us celebrate science,
but mainly botany!
- Are you also a poet?
- Sometimes I tease the Muse!
- But permanently I'm involved only with
God's plants! - You've been busy!
The gem of Kargasovice paddocks:
Peterka Pidlakova!
- Plum jam Pidlak!
- Amazing!
- I know. You have even more beautiful
butterflies in America. - Yes, we do!
Well, we're a country of unlimited opportunity!
But I've found the most beatiful butterfly here!
- Watch the step, collegue Baron!
- Good evening, sir!
Your servant, Miss!
- The pride of my glasshouse!
- You didn't need to....
Every inch of this place is warmed up
by the touch of the female hand!
Kvetus's good at housework...
and not just using her hands!
Last year she made a whole drum of sourkraut!
And now, would you bring the coffee, my girl.
Come and join us!
This is the Czech-American magician.
- Pleased to meet you!
- Excuse me, Baron; have we met before?
- Gentlemen, to the table!
- What's wrong, Baron?
Migraine. An inherited curse of my family!
- You need some dandelion wine!
- No, no. Only the solitude of my bedroom
will deliver relief. Terrible illness
tortures my family for centuries!
Yes, degenerative diseases like this
are no fun!
I'd be honoured if you and Kvetus
came to visit me at home. You'll see an unusual
sight - feeding of a carnivorous plant!
- Carnivourous! Amazing! I'll look forward to that!
- No more than myself!
So, day after tomorrow at 3 pm
I'll send my cab!
- Baron! - After you, boy!
- Thanks, sir!
Do you know who was at the old dummy's house?
You idiot! Carter was there!
Why am I paying your spies? Why?
I'll take the cost of this stick out of your pay!
- See you later, Miss!
- See you, Nick, on Friday; you promised!
- We'll have strawberry dumplings!
- The sweetest strawberies are your lips!
- You may pick them, Nick!
- Kvetus, come and rub my back!
Bye, Nick!...
When you've squeezed that sore,
I'll tell you who I've seen here.
I'd like to know how he found me...
It's obvious, he wants to take over my victim!
- You must act fast!
- Murder him, sir?
- No! You'll deliver him alive! I want to feed!
- Feed? Where, sir?
- On Carter!
- Who does the Baron remind me of?
Nice Baron! When he thinks no-one can see him
he's as rude as an old criminal!
Criminal?
- Our saviour!
- What's that?
The Criminal Bible!
An album of international crooks.
- I'm not disturbing you?
- Not at all!
Pardon!
No! That's impossible!
- But it is him! - Who?
- The Gardener!
The most mysterious criminal of this century.
His true identity and his origins are not known.
He earned the nickname "Gardener" by his
botanical experiments. Commissar!
He appeared out of the Amazonian jungle
where he'd lived with the local Indians.
As you see, marked by a cross.
The local shaman introduced him
to a carnivourous plant the locals used
to sacrifice the hearts of their captive enemies.
When it got sick and lost its appetite,
it got cured by an extract made out
of the magician,
and he became his successor.
Later on, in the USA, he grew a fast-sprouting
bean, and would use it to get lifted to
apartment windows so he could rob them.
In California he married a widow of an Apple King
and then got involved in fruit growing.
The result of his experiments?
A heavy-duty granny smith!
Universal heritage! He put asleep the famous
actress Bara Sernarova by the use of
a thorn from a special rose.
But he did not hesitate to use her.
Terrible...
And is this rose available on the market?
No. Thank god, it's not!
All these plants have been the secret
of his devilish glasshouse!
Only I stopped his rule of terror!
I surrounded him and pushed him to a swamp,
where he ended his miserable life.
Or so I believed till last night,
when we stood face to face.
I have no doubt it's him who smuggled
a carnivourous plant into the bedroom
of Duke Tuna's wife.
The plant that ate her dog.
Which concludes the case of Gert, the dog.
- Congratulations!
- Just a moment! The best comes last.
- Commissar!
- Observe well!
Look at that, Baron Kraztmar!
You're not trying to say that...
Exactly! Baron Kratzmar and The Gardener
are one and the same man!
- A close friend of Lady Tunova, a scientist,
a philantropist? Impossible!
- You've said yourself The Gardener drowned!
- I must have been wrong then!
Then? Perhaps you are mistaken now, too!
Mr Carter, we are all fallible.
Excuse me. I'm expected at an execution!
Not my own, of course!
Good bye.
Just a moment!
This is a sensitive case!
May I expect your co-operation?
Mr Carter, you work alone, don't you?
I respect....
You flirt!... Good-bye!
Watch out for bombs!
- What's that?
- A present from my friend Roentgen.
- A ticket! Interesting!
Commissar! We're off! - Where to?
- To the night club!
- Always ready!
And now, the secret of Night Prague!
An artiste incognito!
Yes! Irma the Cat!
- This is Virgin!
- This is... - Eagle! - This is Eagle!
Invited to the artiste's change room.
Act as per instructions!
- Yes! Yes!
- Virgin's disconnecting!
Very interesting!
You've written these words to me:
Do you know what you don't know?
What do you know that I don't know?
- This!
- Miss Karyn!
- Yes.
- So you are living two lives?
Just two?
A cat has seven lives.
Thanks.
A detective must keep a clear head.
You have that... and not just clear...
but also classically perfect head!
But...my reputation...
I mean, your reputation!
- I don't care! - No!
- Yes!
Prove that you're a man!
Or aren't you?
Excuse me!
And what about this?
Or...
- Now you can throw yourself at me...
- Yes!
So that's it!...
- You fell in your own trap!
- You dog!
We'll get to the dog, too!
First, tell me how the carnivourous plant
...found itself in the Lady's bedroom.
- I know nothing!
- But I think you do!
- You need to be tough with such as her.
- A gentleman treats a woman as a lady, Commissar!
- As you wish!
Damn!
Well...
Who brought the monster to the bedroom?
Please, don't! It's from Paris!
I did. I brought it inside.
And Baron Kratzmar
gave it to you, didn't he?
- Yes. - And why?
- So he could use Gert as an experiment
...with Adela. - Adela?
- That's what he called the plant.
- And what experiment?
- He trained Adela in such a way so as
to maximize its carnivourous abilities
by listening to Gert's going to sleep song.
- Poor Mozart! And why did he select Gert?
- Because... I don't know.
Thank you!
Well?
Stop! Because... the dog was
the size of a human.
So this was just a rehearsal...
The next victim, or rather the next lunch...
...is to be a person, isn't it?
- Yes!
- Do you know who?
- Yes.
- So, who is it?
- OK...
- It's...
- You traitor!
- Hands up!
- Please, as you wish!
And fast!
- Armour!
- So we've lost!
No we haven't!
A present from my friend Alfred Nobel!
Thanks very much!
Get down!
Stop! Stop or I'll shoot!
Pretty strong tobacco...!
- Hands up! Or I'll shoot!
- Excuse me!
- Good evening, Kvetuska!
- Nick! What are you doing here?
Friend and I are playing Cops and Robbers.
In the sewage pipes? You men!
You're like little kids!
I must run. Before the beer gets flat;
Grandpa would tell me off. Good night!
So, by the strawberry dumplings
at 12 o'clock!
Always ready!
What are we to do in the cupboard?
I'll suffocate here!
It's necessary. There are too many
ears and eyes around us!
- Here there's too much naphtaline!
- Commissar, we're going to attack!
- First I'll take a look at the Baron's.
- You might as well get your funeral organized!
Not necessary. If he's sure I'm here,
he won't be expecting me.
- You're going to split in half?
- Sort of. You'll be the first half.
- I'd rather stay in one piece.
- But you will. Only not as Commissar Ledvina.
- What's that?
- Work clothes. - This?
- Once more: When I leave, you will...
- I'll make myself visible by the window,
...so it appears you're still here.
- Right!
- It's not safe for you outside, Mr Carter!
See you later! - Let's hope so!
Would you happen to have a match?
You're under arrest, Gardener!
Hi, Robert! So you're the most mysterious
criminal of the century!
- Franz, you know everything, don't you?
- Not me, Mr Carter!
We've got him, sir! In a barrel!
High time! I won't charge you
for that broken stick!
- Our Diogenes! Open it!
- Yes, sir!
- You won't stop my revenge now, you bastard!
- What to do with him, sir?
- Adela hasn't had her dinner yet!
- Let her work on her appetite!
Tomorrow she'll have two courses for lunch!
Carter will be the second one!
- The second one?
- And what about the Miss, sir?
- She's yours!
- Thank you, sir!
I'll prepare such fate for her
that's worse than death!
- And then I'll sell her to a South American bordello!
- That's it! Sweet dreams!
- You sniffing bastard! - Come sir,
an injured thumb must be fixed right away!
If we rub a carbon pole with a fox's tail,
student Carter...
You don't like electric shocks, little one....
I'm to be the second...
but who's first?
No; I'll strike at the right time.
Little bit of patience, pardner!
That'll be some day tomorrow!
Can't see myself
eating strawberry dumplings...
Good evening!
Welcome, Nick.
You look like you're coming straight
from a magician's performance!
- Yes. And sorry I'm coming through the window.
- That's the American way of life! Sit down!
Thanks. Alas, my attire makes it
impossible to sit comfortably.
You can speak loudly;
Grandpa won't wake now.
I came to apologize.
I can't have dumplings tomorrow.
You must. You are not going
to spoil Grandpa's big day!
Big day?
The Baron's invited him to his palace.
He promised to show him plants that eat meat.
Grandpa...
...will be the first course!
- Beg your pardon?
- Nothing. Go on.
Grandpa's looking forward to it. And me too,
the nice Mr Baron's invited me, too!
South American bordello...
I'll come to have some dumplings, Kvetuska.
- Can you keep a secret?
- I'm a daughter of Jan Zizka's nation!
Well, I am, or rather I'm not...
Magician Ledvina.
I'm Nick Carter,
the famous American detective.
The MOST famous one... and...
what's a detective?
Do you want to save your Grandpa's life?
You're sucking my blood
for the last time today....
Let's raise our glasses
to a successful tomorrow!
- You can drink from the bottle.
- Thank you, sir!
Sir!
Before Adela shows what it can do,
we'll have a cup of tea. Sit down, please.
- Would Miss like some sweet dreams?
- Oh yes!
I'll suggest a cup of tea
from mysterious Tibet.
Sweet dreams are a reward for its sour taste.
And my colleague? Ceylon, Chinese...
...Indian, Darjeeling?
- Do you have rosebud tea? No?
I'll leave it up to you then.
Help yourselves to sugar! My Rose Kratzmarentzis
is not yet able to do such precise tasks.
- Amazing!
- Just a joke! Let's not get our tea go cold.
Excuse me, dear colleague, but how did you
manage to achieve such amazing results?
How?
Oh my god! What am I seeing?
A report card from Jindrichuv Hradec High School!
- A school I taught at in my youth!
- Do you know that that school
was attended by a student, who would not recognize
a leaf of Supatka Jeleni from its stalk?
- No! - You let him fail.
- I did the right thing, then!
Poor student! Everyone laughed at him!
Even Fanynka Mrchackova.
Do you remember her? Well developed for her age.
She used to carry stuffed animals to your cupboard.
- Those were the days!
- The poor boy swore he would avenge himself
using your own weapons! Not only he drilled
botany like mad, he even became a criminal,
to obtain the means for his expensive experiments!
What a hard job that was!
Keep calm, colleague!
And what was the student's name?
Matej Kracmera? I don't remember!
Then look at me!
- You are?...
- Yes!
Baron Robert von Kratzmar,
the flunked student Kracmera!
The time of revenge has come!
Here, you can eat the Fail mark, old man!
And be quick, Adela's hungry!
You'll be in good company there!
Keep chewing! Enjoy!
Always ready!
- The game's over, Gardener!
- The sleuth!
- But what devil saved you from the swamp?
- This one!
The surface had closed over me,
when I felt the firm bottom below.
Just the tiny opening of this smoking utensil
kept my contact with life!
It was a fragile connection,
but it allowed me to hang onto life.
And this will ensure the noose for you!
- I'm giving you a raise!
- Should I use her now or later, sir?
- One after the other!
First, we'll feed Adela the detective. - Yes, sir!
That guy needs a truck to move him!
Sorry about that!
- Just a moment!
- Thank you!
Say hello to the devil, Gardener!
- Materiel fatigue! What now?
- Do I get three guesses?
- No need!
- How primitive!
But how effective! Enjoy the view!
Soon you'll see the ground from up close!
But that's not going to be quite the same!
- How're you doing?
- Thank you, good so far!
Remember, Commissar: To admit one's defeat
is also a victory of a kind.
So in fact we've won! Romped it in!
That's impossible.
- Are you seeing what I'm seeing?
- Stay calm, Commissar! Always ready!
- What's that?
- A solar gun.
A present from my friend Laser.
A test run first.
- Even heaven's against us!
- So what's new? A present from my friend Messer.
- Robert!
- Yes...
Mr Carter!
No doubt you're coming to congratulate me!
- Thank you! - Mr Carter! Gert,
meet America's most famous detective!
Director, introduce him to the gentleman.
A message from Egypt. Urgent!
The Great Pyramid... disappeared?
When's the next Orient Express departing?
There's no other way, Kvetuska.
The Great Pyramid's calling me
...and it's not interested in what my heart says.
- I understand, Nick. Only you can solve such a mystery.
Commissar!
You can still decide to come!
It's kind of you,
but what would I do in Egypt?
They might have Pilsen, but they're bound
not to know how to pour it!
Professor!
I'll never forget your dandelion wine!
- And if you ever meet Ladislav Matejka
in America... - That's me!
Larry Matejka, Czech-American!
"Egyptian Quick and Easy"
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org